<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity and Time Management on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/productivity-and-time-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity and Time Management on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:41:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/productivity-and-time-management/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Know Thyself: Unveiling Your Unique Strengths and Personality Traits</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/know-thyself-unveiling-your-unique-strengths-and-personality-traits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/know-thyself-unveiling-your-unique-strengths-and-personality-traits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the quest for personal and professional growth, understanding our unique strengths and personality traits can be incredibly enlightening. Today, I want to share my insights from various personality paradigms and how they shape my approach to work and life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cliftonstrengths-harnessing-core-talents&#34;&gt;CliftonStrengths: Harnessing Core Talents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CliftonStrengths assessment has been instrumental in identifying my core talents. Here are my top five strengths:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Input&lt;/strong&gt;: I have an insatiable curiosity and a constant desire to collect information. This strength fuels my drive to learn and gather knowledge from diverse sources.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intellection&lt;/strong&gt;: My love for deep thinking and intellectual discussions is a hallmark of this strength. It allows me to explore complex ideas and engage in thoughtful analysis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learner&lt;/strong&gt;: The process of learning excites me. Whether it’s acquiring new skills or understanding new concepts, I thrive in environments that offer continuous growth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ideation&lt;/strong&gt;: Creativity and innovation are my playgrounds. I enjoy brainstorming and generating new ideas, which often leads to novel solutions and approaches.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytical&lt;/strong&gt;: I have a keen ability to dissect problems and examine them from different angles. This strength helps me make informed decisions based on solid data and evidence.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more on CliftonStrengths, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gallup.com/cliftonstrengths/en/home.aspx&#34;&gt;Gallup’s CliftonStrengths&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Lessons: 32 Things I&#39;ve Learned So Far</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/life-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/life-lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are 32 things I’ve learned from life, so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You are not your thoughts. There is a “you” behind and above your inner voice/monologue/dialogue. Pay attention to what you pay attention to. Think about what you think about.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We always only have the present moment. Focusing too much on the future leads to anxiety. Focusing too much on the past leads to depression. Wherever you are, be fully there, now! (Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/400hFeH&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Power of Now&lt;/em&gt; by Eckhart Tolle&lt;/a&gt; [affiliate link here and throughout] for more on this.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It’s OK not to be OK. Feeling anxious, depressed, angry, etc. is fine. However, avoid the trap of feeling anxious about how anxious you feel, feeling depressed about how depressed you feel, etc. (Learned this from &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/404talb&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Happiness Trap&lt;/em&gt; by Russ Harris&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you never make mistakes, you’re not learning/growing as well as you could be. Perfectionism is a deadly prison. Break free with “good enough” and “always learning.”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You are stronger than you think you are. You are weaker than you think you are.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ask more questions. Ask better questions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God is not a thing among things. There is an “infinite qualitative difference” between God and everything that is not God, everything that exists.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus of Nazareth is the living Lord of all. ___ is not.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beware of overconfidence in what the Bible (or any other sacred text, for that matter) “clearly”does or does not say.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God is devoted to the poor and powerless. Those who speak and act on God’s behalf should speak and act &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; the poor and powerless.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To do better with people, ask them questions about themselves. (Read the classic &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3QlSsrR&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/em&gt; by Dale Carnegie&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can’t out-exercise your appetite forever. &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/4018XfY&#34;&gt;Eat food. Mostly plants. Not too much.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get enough sleep. You probably don’t get enough sleep.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lift heavy things.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Go outside. Take a walk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open a Roth IRA. Invest consistently in low-cost mutual funds or lifecycle funds as soon as you can. (Learned this from &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/48Uc65D&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Will Teach You to Be Rich&lt;/em&gt; by Ramit Sethi&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reading is a superpower. You can learn from as many other lives and lifetimes as you want. &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/46YrOdW&#34;&gt;Learn how to read&lt;/a&gt;. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/46Dgm7J&#34;&gt;learn how to learn.&lt;/a&gt; Then, learn whatever you want!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always read with a pen or pencil in your hand. If you really want to learn from a book, buy a physical copy and annotate the heck out of it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You always have to earn and keep your audience’s attention. Before/while communicating, ask yourself “Why should they care? What’s in it for them?”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Humans are incredibly good at misunderstanding each other. Before/while communicating, ask yourself “How might I be misunderstood? How might I be misunderstanding others?”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remember that you and your loved ones are all going to die. What do you want to be known for?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eulogize people BEFORE they die.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Everyone should go to therapy for at least a few months.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“Slow is smooth. Smooth is fast.” Feeling nervous/stressed/angry/etc.? SLOW DOWN, especially if you’re in front of other people.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Courage is a choice, not a feeling. No matter how nervous you are, you can always ACT courageously.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Everyone is trying to figure it out as they go along. Do you often feel like an imposter? Join the club!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Act like you’ve been here before. Act like you’ve done this before. Act calm, comfortable, and confident, if for no other reason than to help the people around you feel calm, comfortable, and confident.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leadership is service. Leadership is the willingness to make a decision for the good of the group even when it’s awkward or uncomfortable to do so.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Focus on what you can control.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Journal. What do you really want? What are you afraid of? What’s the most important thing you need to get done today? Get a notebook and write it down!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In many domains, 80% of the outcomes/effects come from 20% of the inputs/causes. Find the “vital few” things that have outsized impacts, both positive and negative, on your life. Double-down on what’s helping you. Get rid of what’s hurting you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use smoked paprika. You’re welcome.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master the Art of Interpersonal Relationships with &#34;How to Win Friends and Influence People&#34;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/master-the-art-of-interpersonal-relationships-with-how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 12:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/master-the-art-of-interpersonal-relationships-with-how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dale Carnegie’s timeless classic, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3K0VcaM&#34;&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, has been a bestseller for decades, offering insights and advice on improving interpersonal relationships. The book’s practical principles have helped millions of readers excel in their personal and professional lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’ll summarize the key points from Carnegie’s work and provide you with a solid foundation to start mastering your own relationships. If you find these ideas helpful and compelling, I highly recommend reading the entire book!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Useful Websites: My Favorite Online Resources</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/most-useful-websites-my-favorite-online-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 19:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/most-useful-websites-my-favorite-online-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;general--thinking&#34;&gt;General / Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Untools: &lt;a href=&#34;https://untools.co/&#34;&gt;https://untools.co/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;James Clear: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/&#34;&gt;https://jamesclear.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Farnam Street: &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/&#34;&gt;https://fs.blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Your Logical Fallacy Is: &lt;a href=&#34;https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/&#34;&gt;https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Your Bias Is: &lt;a href=&#34;https://yourbias.is/&#34;&gt;https://yourbias.is/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fitness--health&#34;&gt;Fitness / Health&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Darebee: &lt;a href=&#34;https://darebee.com/&#34;&gt;https://darebee.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading--writing&#34;&gt;Reading / Writing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;QuillBot: &lt;a href=&#34;https://quillbot.com/&#34;&gt;https://quillbot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;12ft Ladder: &lt;a href=&#34;https://12ft.io/&#34;&gt;https://12ft.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open Library: &lt;a href=&#34;https://openlibrary.org/&#34;&gt;https://openlibrary.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;PDF24 Tools: &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.pdf24.org/en/&#34;&gt;https://tools.pdf24.org/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unsplash: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/&#34;&gt;https://unsplash.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Noun Project: &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenounproject.com/&#34;&gt;https://thenounproject.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-development&#34;&gt;Software Development&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stack Overflow: &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/&#34;&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;O’Reilly: &lt;a href=&#34;https://learning.oreilly.com/&#34;&gt;https://learning.oreilly.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;roadmap.sh: &lt;a href=&#34;https://roadmap.sh/&#34;&gt;https://roadmap.sh/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;cheat.sh: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cheat.sh/&#34;&gt;https://cheat.sh/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DevHints.io: &lt;a href=&#34;https://devhints.io/&#34;&gt;https://devhints.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learn X in Y minutes: &lt;a href=&#34;https://learnxinyminutes.com/&#34;&gt;https://learnxinyminutes.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baeldung (for Java/Spring): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baeldung.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.baeldung.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What would you add to this list? Let me know!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s time for another social media fast!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-for-another-social-media-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 15:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-for-another-social-media-fast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After listening to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blinkist.com/en/books/deep-work-en&#34;&gt;the Blinkist summary of Cal Newport’s &lt;em&gt;Deep Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (I’ve read the book, this was just for a refresher), I’m convinced that it’s time for another 30-day fast from Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think I’ll still keep &lt;a href=&#34;https://micro.blog/joshuapsteele&#34;&gt;my micro.blog up and running&lt;/a&gt;, but between &lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com&#34;&gt;running Anglican Compass&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/&#34;&gt;sprinting for some last-ditch clarity on my increasingly frustrating dissertation&lt;/a&gt;, I need all the extra bandwidth I can get!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need to get in touch for some reason, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/contact/&#34;&gt;use the contact form on my website&lt;/a&gt;. You can also &lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/joshuapsteele&#34;&gt;sign up for my very occasional email newsletter here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They Say, I Say Writing Templates</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 17:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOURCE: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3eOMlXF&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;They Say / I Say: The Moves that Matter in Academic Writing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 4th edition (affiliate link). Perhaps the most helpful and practical book on academic writing!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;disagreeing-without-being-disagreeable&#34;&gt;Disagreeing Without Being Disagreeable&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While I understand the impulse to A, my own view is B.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While I agree with X that Y, I cannot accept her overall conclusion that Z.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While X argues Y, and I argue Z, in a way we’re both right.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-template-of-templates&#34;&gt;The Template Of Templates&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent discussions of A, a controversial issue has been whether B. On the one hand, some argue that C. From this perspective, D. On the other hand, however, others argue that E. In the words of F, one of this view’s main proponents, “G.” According to this view, H. In sum, then, the issue is whether I or J.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balderdash! 12 Suggestions for Overcoming Writer’s Block (From Andrew T. Le Peau’s “Write Better”)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 13:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writer’s block sucks. I’m currently facing it with regard to &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/&#34;&gt;my dissertation&lt;/a&gt; and I’ve decided to hit pause on research and writing until I regain access to my library carrell at Wheaton.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I’ve come across some helpful advice on overcoming writer’s block in Andrew T. Le Peau’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ZuTZC3&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Writer Better: A Lifelong Editor on Craft, Art, and Spirituality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book is &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; with helpful and practical advice on writing, rewriting, publishing, etc. To whet your appetite, I’d like to share some of Le Peau’s tips for conquering writer’s block. These all come from chapter 7, pages. 72–80.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Writing Templates</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/helpful-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 14:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/helpful-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following templates come from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/33TJdor&#34;&gt;They Say / I Say: The Moves That Matter in Academic Writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-what-they-say&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing What They Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A number of $$$ have recently suggested that $$$.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It has become common today to dismiss $$$.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In their recent work, Y and Z have offered harsh critiques of Dr. X for $$$.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-standard-views&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing Standard Views&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;American today tend to believe that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Conventional wisdom has it that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Common sense seems to dictate that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The standard way of thinking about topic X has it that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is often said that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My whole life I have heard it said that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You would think that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many people assumed that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making What They Say Something You Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me achieve my home gym dream</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-achieve-my-home-gym-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 18:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-achieve-my-home-gym-dream/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to put together a basic home gym in our basement apartment. Mainly, I’m interested in doing squats for now. Then, I’ll expand to deadlifts and benchpress. Our ceilings are too low for overhead presses, however.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I just ordered the Valor Fitness BD-9 squat rack from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I still need a decent Olympic bar and Olympic plates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Rapoport&#39;s Rules for Better Conversations and Disagreements</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 17:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading Walter Sinnott-Armstrong’s excellent book, &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2BNTlTq&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Think Again: How to Reason and Argue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In it (on pages 25–26), I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Rapoport%27s_Rules&#34;&gt;“Rapoport’s Rules.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First formulated by mathematical psychologist Anatol Rapoport and discussed by Daniel Dennett (&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2NmrH4m&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 31–35), here they are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1: You should attempt to re-express your target’s position so clearly, vividly, and fairly that your target says, “Thanks, I wish I’d thought of putting it that way.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What blogs are you reading?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m using the RSS readers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inoreader.com/&#34;&gt;Inoreader&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://reederapp.com/&#34;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe to the following blogs:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ayjay.org&#34;&gt;Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog&#34;&gt;Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://seths.blog&#34;&gt;Seth’s Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://calnewport.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Study Hacks – Decoding Patterns of Success – Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com&#34;&gt;James Clear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bakadesuyo.com&#34;&gt;Barking Up The Wrong Tree – How to be awesome at life.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://appademic.tech&#34;&gt;The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcsweeneys.net&#34;&gt;McSweeney’s Internet Tendency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com&#34;&gt;Lifehacker – Do everything better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are you reading?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me StickK to my writing habit</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need to finish &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/&#34;&gt;this dissertation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I’ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it’s been a bear to get back on!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a fantastic wooden pencil (Mitsubishi 9850)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to give a quick shout-out to this fantastic pencil: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2QcXI2B&#34;&gt;the Mitsubishi 9850&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Mitsubishi-Pencil-pencil-hardness-K9850HB/dp/B001BKZVWU/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=li3&amp;amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;linkId=e6e38efe0138c6a5bb4092270163728e&amp;amp;language=en_US&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B001BKZVWU&amp;amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;language=en_US&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;l=li3&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B001BKZVWU&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s cheap, writes well, erases well, and looks great!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more on wooden pencils, read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-wooden-pencils/pt/633&#34;&gt;this JetPens guide to the best wooden pencils&lt;/a&gt;. And, while you’re at it, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-pencil-sharpeners/pt/710&#34;&gt;JetPens’ recommendations for the best pencil sharpeners&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s the Template I Use to Take Notes on Books I Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 19:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed from &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2M5AHsy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/em&gt;, by Mortimer J. Adler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;bibliographic-data&#34;&gt;BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA:&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Author(s):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Editor(s):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translator(s):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Title and subtitle:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Title and subtitle of any larger work that contains the source:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pages:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Volume:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Issue:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edition:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;URL and date accessed:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Publisher:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Place:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Date:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;interpretation&#34;&gt;INTERPRETATION:&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kind of Book (Practical or theoretical?):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Subject Matter:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Problems Attempted to Solve:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary (What is the book about as a whole?):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Outline of Source:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key Terms:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key Propositions/Arguments (What is being said in detail, and how?):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/&#34;&gt;I catalogued a bunch of different takes on Jordan Peterson, before giving my own take&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since that post, two other pieces about Jordan Peterson have been written that I’d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;jordan-peterson-custodian-of-the-patriarchy-by-nellie-bowles-new-york-times&#34;&gt;“Jordan Peterson, Custodian of the Patriarchy,” by Nellie Bowles (New York Times)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/18/style/jordan-peterson-12-rules-for-life.html&#34;&gt;Nellie Bowles writes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peterson, 55, a University of Toronto psychology professor turned YouTube philosopher turned mystical father figure, has emerged as an influential thought leader. The messages he delivers range from hoary self-help empowerment talk (clean your room, stand up straight) to the more retrograde and political (a society run as a patriarchy makes sense and stems mostly from men’s competence; the notion of white privilege is a farce). He is the stately looking, pedigreed voice for a group of culture warriors who are working diligently to undermine mainstream and liberal efforts to promote equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Four Tendencies: 4 Ways You Can Play to Your Personality Strengths</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 18:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In both my personal and coaching conversations recently, Gretchen Rubin’s personality framework called “The Four Tendencies” has really seemed to resonate with people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, I thought I would take a few minutes to share it with you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;gretchen-rubin-explains-the-four-tendencies&#34;&gt;Gretchen Rubin Explains the Four Tendencies&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, here’s a six-minute video of Gretchen herself explaining the Four Tendencies and their relevance to changing one’s habits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LIgvEOVT9OE&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-do-you-respond-to-inner-expectations-and-outer-expectations&#34;&gt;How do you respond to INNER EXPECTATIONS and OUTER EXPECTATIONS?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the key question that drives the framework. Here are the possible answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hate Running? Try Rucking Instead</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 16:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(DISCLAIMER: You are, of course, more than welcome to try rucking, even if you also love running.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;rucking-gt-running&#34;&gt;Rucking &amp;gt; Running&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took me a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; time to “fall in love” with running. It did not take me nearly as long to fall &lt;em&gt;out&lt;/em&gt; of love with running!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And yet, even though I’ve long enjoyed &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/&#34;&gt;doing kettlebell swings&lt;/a&gt; and doing &lt;a href=&#34;https://stronglifts.com/5x5/&#34;&gt;the 5×5 weight-lifing workout&lt;/a&gt;, I did begin to miss the benefits of cardio training.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to make of Jordan Peterson? Some takes, then my own.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: Read my post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/&#34;&gt;“Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I remember correctly, I first heard of and listened to Jordan Peterson on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2017/08/31/podcast-335-using-power-myths-live-flourishing-life/&#34;&gt;an episode of The Art of Manliness podcast&lt;/a&gt;. (Or perhaps it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/06/12-rules-for-life-jordan-peterson-interview/&#34;&gt;this episode&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;however-i-could-be-mistaken-because-petersons-been-popping-up-in-conversation-all-over-the-place-in-my-circles&#34;&gt;However, I could be mistaken, because Peterson’s been popping up in conversation all over the place in my circles.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blog posts, podcast episodes, conversations with friends – Peterson has been popping up everywhere, so it seems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do More Better: Tim Challies&#39; Excellent Little Book on Personal Productivity Could Change Your Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tim Challies begins his book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2ufosG4&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do More Better: A Practical Guide to Productivity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with a bold claim: “I believe this book can improve your life.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, after reading the book, which is just 120 pages long including endnotes!, I believe that Challies makes good on his claim.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=1941114172&amp;asins=1941114172&amp;linkId=61476ee8a72a820b76e43d746b704020&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As far as explicitly Christian approaches to personal productivity go, Challies’ &lt;em&gt;Do More Better&lt;/em&gt; stands alongside &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2uf5r6A&#34;&gt;Matt Perman’s &lt;em&gt;What’s Best Next: How the Gospel Transforms the Way You Get Things Done&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While Perman’s book is fantastic and thorough, Challies’ book has the advantage of being MUCH shorter (120 pages vs. 383 pages).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Need to Develop a Writing Habit. Do You?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because good writing = good thinking, I believe that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; could benefit from developing the habit of regular writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, because I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Am a Ph.D. student about to begin work on his dissertation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Edit a blog (&lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/&#34;&gt;Rookie Anglican&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write this personal blog&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need to develop the habit of regular writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Up until now, I’ve largely relied upon writing in fits and starts, when the Muse descends, as it were.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting back on the &#34;Getting Things Done&#34; Productivity Bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 22:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting Things Done (“GTD” for short) is a wildly popular personal productivity system invented and popularized by David Allen. However, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com/getting-things-done-ten-years-in-1795707084&#34;&gt;Nicole Dieker at Lifehacker pointed out in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, “You don’t hear a lot of people talk about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; productivity system anymore.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think that’s a shame, because it’s a very effective system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I first tried Getting Things Done after reading “&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2tMiX1w&#34;&gt;What’s Best Nex&lt;/a&gt;t” by Matt Perman, and then reading “&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2HvNJxv&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt;” by David Allen (in its newly revised 2015 edition) shortly thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This One Simple Trick Helps Me Read Faster as a Ph.D. Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 06:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading is the closest thing that human beings have to a superpower. We can learn, from other minds, from other times, just by looking at symbols on a screen or a page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But, I mean, come on. Who has enough time to read? I don’t know about you, but I’ve got a stack of books a mile high that I’d like to work my way through.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, there’s a bunch of good advice out there about &lt;strong&gt;finding more time to read&lt;/strong&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fs.blog/2013/09/finding-time-to-read/&#34;&gt;this post from Farnam Street&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/26/how-to-read-more-books/&#34;&gt;this post from The Art of Manliness&lt;/a&gt;). In fact, finding more time to read is one of the main reasons why you should learn the basics of personal productivity and time management (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/category/productivity-and-time-management/&#34;&gt;my posts about productivity and time management&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go to Sleep and Have Some Kids: What the Bible (Psalm 127) Says about Productivity</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 12:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-productivity-in-psalm-127&#34;&gt;Personal Productivity in Psalm 127&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love Psalm 127. Not because it makes me feel great, necessarily, but because it hits me like a ton of bricks whenever I read it (like I did last night, during evening prayer).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the Psalm opens:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ps-127-1&#34;&gt;Unless the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; builds the house,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;indent-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;indent-1-breaks&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ps-127-1&#34;&gt;the builders labor in vain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ps-127-1&#34;&gt;Unless the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; watches over the city,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;indent-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;indent-1-breaks&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ps-127-1&#34;&gt;the guards stand watch in vain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but it’s easy for me to think that my success or lack thereof completely depends on me and the intensity of my efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Pray Before You Read and Write: A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 09:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to share with you the following prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study, based on &lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.preces-latinae.org/thesaurus/Varia/CreatorIneff.html&#34;&gt;Oratio S. Thomae Aquinatis ante studium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, which Thomas Aquinas would pray before studying, writing, or preaching.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We prayed it responsively before class (Patristic and Medieval History and Doctrine) with Dr. Piotr Malysz at Beeson Divinity School, and I’ve since turned back to this prayer often!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study&#34;&gt;A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O God, Creator of all that is, From the treasures of Your wisdom, You have arrayed the universe with marvelous order, And now govern with skill and might. You are the true fount of light and wisdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Books Every Christian Should Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 03:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OK, OK. I get it. Claiming that every Christian should read these 5 books is a bold claim.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But, honestly, I think that these reading recommendations stand up to the scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wracking my brain trying to come up with just the top 5 books that a busy Christian should read if she wants to learn the essentials about:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Productivity and Time Management&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bible Study&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Theology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And, I think I’ve arrived at a pretty good shortlist if I do say so myself. If you &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/understand-remember-read-4-questions-ask-reading-book/&#34;&gt;read and understand&lt;/a&gt; these 5 books, you’ll be well on your way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An 80/20 Approach to the Christian Life: 2 Reasons Why Christians Should Care About the Pareto Principle</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 12:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you want to live a more meaningful and purposeful Christian life, but you feel like it’s hard enough just to get everything done on your to-do list each day?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m right there with you! That’s why I’ve made “&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/category/productivity-and-time-management/&#34;&gt;Get Your Act Together (Productivity and Time Management)&lt;/a&gt;” the first of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/start-here/&#34;&gt;Steps to Find Purpose and Meaning in Life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I think I’ve found something that can help. I’d like to introduce you to the “&lt;strong&gt;Pareto Principle&lt;/strong&gt;,” also known as “&lt;strong&gt;the 80/20 Rule&lt;/strong&gt;,” the “law of the vital few,” or the “principle of factor sparsity,” if you want to get all technical about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principles: 10 Imperatives for the Good Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 16:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why write out a list of principles?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For one thing, it’s my birthday. And, although I’m only in my twenties, I’m feeling a bit reflective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For another, I’ve just been given a copy of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2yQpytf&#34;&gt;Principles: Life and Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2yQpytf&#34;&gt; by Ray Dalio&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Dalio (ix),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Principles are fundamental truths that serve as the foundations for behavior that gets you what you want out of life. They can be aplied again and again in similar situations to help you achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts You Should Listen To</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 15:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;podcasts-an-introduction&#34;&gt;Podcasts: An Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although podcasts (think “iPod” + “broadcast”) have been around for over a decade, we’re living in a bit of a golden age – or a least a Rennaissance – of the medium. For the uninitiated, here’s a nice video about what podcasts are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oerm5Q&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oerm5Q&lt;/a&gt;_9u2A&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently, podcasts are one of my very favorite ways to consume information about a wide variety of topics. Sure, gun to my head, I’ll choose books over podcasts as a way to learn. However, unlike books (or videos), you can easily listen to podcasts while doing other things – whether folding laundry, washing dishes, or going for a run/walk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is The Well-Equipped Christian Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 23:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had a problem finding a reliable resource for recommendations?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Certain Google searches are a piece of cake, but the “best resources for ______” ones can be hit-or-miss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And don’t even get me started on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_fatigue&#34;&gt;decision fatigue&lt;/a&gt;. As a serial over-thinker, I start to hate myself a little bit after reading through the upteenth list of “5 Best ____s.” It makes it so hard to make a decision! Then, when you pick something, you end up doubting your decision. Not fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Ridiculously Helpful Markdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 14:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been dragging my heels on learning Markdown for awhile now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know, Markdown is:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightweight_markup_language&#34; title=&#34;Lightweight markup language&#34;&gt;lightweight markup language&lt;/a&gt; with plain text formatting syntax designed so that it can be converted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML&#34; title=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;HTML&lt;/a&gt; and many other formats using a tool by the same name.&lt;sup class=&#34;reference&#34; id=&#34;cite_ref-8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown#cite_note-8&#34;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Markdown is often used to format &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/README&#34; title=&#34;README&#34;&gt;readme files&lt;/a&gt;, for writing messages in online discussion forums, and to create &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formatted_text&#34; title=&#34;Formatted text&#34;&gt;rich text&lt;/a&gt; using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plain_text&#34; title=&#34;Plain text&#34;&gt;plain text&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_editor&#34; title=&#34;Text editor&#34;&gt;editor&lt;/a&gt;. [Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Want To Be Remembered?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you know what the worst thing about &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;death&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s not the &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;dying&lt;/span&gt; itself – its the &lt;strong&gt;separation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is, we don’t suffer the most from our own deaths (a one-time occurrence), but from suffering the deaths of others (repeatedly). Instead of living relationships, we are left with distant memories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A sad reality, to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-if-however-we-could-use-death-to-our-own-advantage&#34;&gt;What if, however, we could use death to our own advantage?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced this is the truth behind Ecclesiastes 7:2 –&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Take Seth Godin to Church</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie. My first reaction when I saw the cover of this book? &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0502.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0502-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;no-of-course-youre-not-indispensable-what-use-could-this-crap-possibly-be-to-the-church-or-to-me--simultaneously-a-pastor-and-a-pastor-in-training&#34;&gt;No! Of course you’re not indispensable. What use could this crap possibly be to the Church, or to me – simultaneously a pastor and a pastor-in-training.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, however, &lt;strong&gt;I read the book&lt;/strong&gt;. And I suggest you do, too!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=1591844096&amp;asins=1591844096&amp;linkId=6dde24820eeb48d4ecb7e52c6696d9b0&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=0066c0&amp;bg_color=ffffff&#34; style=&#34;width: 120px; height: 240px;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;  &#xA;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: affiliate link. I get paid if you make a purchase.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sethgodin.com/sg/&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;, bald marketing extraordinaire, is convinced that a paradigm shift has taken place. I’ll quote from his annotated table of contents (which, by the way, I wish all books had):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are you afraid of?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 20:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m scared. Are you?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specifically, as I wrote in my journal this very morning:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m scared – I’m scared of wasting my life, I’m scared of not being worth anything outside of the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fear drives so many aspects of our lives – from how we dress, to how we raise our children, to how we elect our leaders. And, if we’re honest with ourselves, fear can play a large role in what/whom we worship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kettlebell Swings: Back Balm for the Sedentary [Seminarian]</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 23:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love books. Books, however, do not like my back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Can you relate?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s not sitting around reading books all day, but I imagine plenty of you out there suffer from back pain/fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me share a time-saving solution I’ve recently found: &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/kettlebells/how-to-do-the-perfect-kettlebell-swing&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;two-handed kettlebell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;swings.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-3810&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34; id=&#34;attachment_3810&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px&#34;&gt;![Our small kettlebell family](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0472-e1464220672909-300x225.jpg)&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34; id=&#34;caption-attachment-3810&#34;&gt;Our small kettlebell family&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can these cannonballs with handles help your back?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, the kettlebell swing is one of the many exercises out there that activates your &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posterior_chain&#34;&gt;posterior chain&lt;/a&gt; – the muscles along the back of your body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
