<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Justice on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/social-justice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Justice on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 14:34:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/social-justice/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Bible Is Clear about the Poor, Oppressed, and Marginalized</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-bible-is-clear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 14:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-bible-is-clear/</guid>
      <description>The Bible is clear about the poor, the oppressed, and the marginalized.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p><em>&ldquo;The Bible is clear&hellip;&rdquo;</em><br>
<em>&ldquo;The Bible says&hellip;&rdquo;</em><br>
<em>&ldquo;The Bible is for/against&hellip;&rdquo;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>How often—especially within American evangelicalism—do these phrases become rhetorical battering rams for partisan talking points?</p>
<p>Let’s be honest: <em>the Bible is not a monolith.</em> It is a library of ancient, inspired texts written across centuries, cultures, and genres. &ldquo;What the Bible says&rdquo; on any given topic often depends heavily on who’s reading, how they&rsquo;re reading, and what they bring to the text.</p>
<p>And yet—amidst the diversity of voices and genres—there is a steady and unmistakable chorus that rises from Scripture, if you&rsquo;re willing to hear it: <strong>God sides with the poor, the oppressed, and the marginalized.</strong></p>
<p>This is not peripheral. It’s not a minor subplot. It’s a core theme, echoed by the Torah, the prophets, Jesus, and the early church.</p>
<p>If we read the Bible &ldquo;from below&rdquo;—from the perspective of the least, the last, and the lost—we encounter a God who delivers slaves from Egypt, warns kings against injustice, and identifies himself with the hungry, the sick, and the imprisoned.</p>
<p>Consider just a small sampling:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>“You must not mistreat or oppress foreigners in any way. Remember, you yourselves were once foreigners in the land of Egypt. You must not exploit a widow or an orphan&hellip;”</strong><br>
<em>Exodus 22:21–24</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>“Don’t rob the poor just because you can, or exploit the needy in court. For the Lord is their defender. He will ruin anyone who ruins them.”</strong><br>
<em>Proverbs 22:22–23</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>“He has shown you, O mortal, what is good. And what does the Lord require of you? To act justly and to love mercy and to walk humbly with your God.”</strong><br>
<em>Micah 6:8</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>“He has brought down the powerful from their thrones and lifted up the lowly; he has filled the hungry with good things, and sent the rich away empty.”</strong><br>
<em>Luke 1:52–53 (Mary&rsquo;s Magnificat)</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>“The Spirit of the Lord is upon me&hellip; He has sent me to proclaim release to the captives&hellip; to let the oppressed go free.”</strong><br>
<em>Luke 4:18–19 (Jesus quoting Isaiah)</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>“Blessed are you who are poor, for yours is the kingdom of God.”</strong><br>
<em>Luke 6:20–21</em></p></blockquote>
<p>This isn’t &ldquo;liberal theology.&rdquo; It’s just <em>Bible.</em></p>
<p>So the next time someone claims “the Bible is clear,” it’s worth asking: <em>Clear about what?</em> Because when it comes to God&rsquo;s concern for the vulnerable, the Bible speaks with thunderous clarity.</p>
<p>And if your version of Christianity conveniently forgets the poor—or worse, vilifies them—then it&rsquo;s not Jesus you&rsquo;re following. It&rsquo;s an idol dressed in Scripture’s clothing.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>For Further Reflection:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>When you think of God&rsquo;s priorities, do they align with the voices Scripture consistently lifts up?</li>
<li>How might your politics, theology, or way of life change if you centered the poor and marginalized the way Jesus did?</li>
<li>Where do you see the Spirit at work today—still bringing good news to the poor and setting the oppressed free?</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
