<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Engineering on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/software-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Engineering on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 21:08:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/software-engineering/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Essential Reads for New Software Developers: The Effective Engineer and The Missing README</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/essential-reads-for-new-software-developers-the-effective-engineer-and-the-missing-readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 21:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/essential-reads-for-new-software-developers-the-effective-engineer-and-the-missing-readme/</guid>
      <description>Are you stepping into the exciting world of software engineering, or considering whether to take that leap? You’re not alone. This field attracts countless individuals worldwide, fueled by an ever-increasing demand for technological solutions, the promise of high salaries, and a keen interest in problem-solving.
However, it’s essential to understand that coding and programming skills, while crucial, are just one part of a broader equation. Equally important is the bigger picture of how software development fits into the wider professional and business environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discover Learn X in Y Minutes: An Invaluable Resource for Programmers</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/discover-learn-x-in-y-minutes-an-invaluable-resource-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 12:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/discover-learn-x-in-y-minutes-an-invaluable-resource-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>As a programmer or someone aspiring to be one, you’re always on the lookout for valuable resources to help you learn new languages and tools. Today, I’m excited to introduce you to learnxinyminutes.com, a must-visit website for anyone interested in coding. This site offers concise, code-focused tutorials for dozens of programming languages and essential tools, making it a perfect learning companion for beginners and experienced coders alike.
Quick and Efficient Learning Learn X in Y Minutes understands that time is precious, which is why it provides:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Linux: Top Commands Every New Computer Programmer Should Learn</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mastering-linux-top-commands-every-new-computer-programmer-should-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 17:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mastering-linux-top-commands-every-new-computer-programmer-should-learn/</guid>
      <description>Are you new to the world of computer programming? If so, learning Linux commands is an essential step in your journey. Linux is a powerful and versatile operating system used by developers across various fields.
In this blog post, we’ll cover the most important Linux commands that every new computer programmer should learn to level up their skills.
(Want to learn even more about Linux? Check out Linux Pocket Guide: Essential Commands and The Linux Command Line: A Complete Introduction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anything: Software Engineering Questions from a Coding Bootcamp Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 14:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</guid>
      <description>I’m posting my answers to these software engineering questions here, just in case anyone else finds them helpful! (Also, it gives me another link to share when I get asked these kinds of questions.)
How did you become interested in software engineering? I wrote a bit about my coding bootcamp journey in a previous post.
Part of my interest in software engineering is/was related to the particular path my journey took.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Coding Bootcamp Journey: How a Pastor Became a Programmer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 17:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>When I changed my major from Mechanical Engineering to Bible shortly before my first semester of college, I realized that what I was studying was not going to make me rich.
So, throughout undergrad, seminary, and into a Ph.D. program in theology, the notion of “bi-vocational ministry” (serving the church while also making money outside of the church doing something else) was on my radar screen.
In fact, for a few months between finishing seminary and starting my Ph.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Testing: Possibilities, Problems, and Principles</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/software-testing-possibilities-problems-and-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 21:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/software-testing-possibilities-problems-and-principles/</guid>
      <description>Note: Throughout what follows, I am heavily indebted to two books in particular: Unit Testing: Principles, Practices, and Patterns by Vladimir Khorikov (Manning Publications, 2020) and Effective Software Testing: A Developer’s Guide by Mauricio Aniche (Manning Publications, 2022). In fact, this overview of software testing should be viewed as a distillation of Khorikov and Aniche.
![Khorikov-UT-HI.png](https://res.craft.do/user/full/032236cd-2bcc-fa12-9dfe-e5564a597e07/doc/836657DD-FF3A-4CE5-8565-F6945FE45D6A/21ECE62D-593E-4825-A549-6312F555D284_2/ZCHd2JrecxcxPA1c35H2wTV0FrAzdktnxui31U1rO00z/Khorikov-UT-HI.png)Khorikov-UT-HI.png![Aniche-HI.png](https://res.craft.do/user/full/032236cd-2bcc-fa12-9dfe-e5564a597e07/doc/836657DD-FF3A-4CE5-8565-F6945FE45D6A/ED1FC92B-C9A0-4CDC-B13D-5AA3940FF3E7_2/FE2KZaydLyYRh1ydJKyDIvx4y3gaQLh82funASwXFqoz/Aniche-HI.png)Aniche-HI.png--- Software Testing, Our Field’s Least-Sexy Superpower Coming into software development from a background in the humanities, automated software testing struck me as a kind of superpower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT: Write a Viral Blogpost about Why to Become a Software Engineer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/chatgpt-write-a-viral-blogpost-about-why-to-become-a-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 14:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/chatgpt-write-a-viral-blogpost-about-why-to-become-a-software-engineer/</guid>
      <description>Are you considering a career in software engineering but not sure if it’s right for you? Here are just a few reasons why becoming a software engineer is a great choice:
High demand and good pay: Software engineering is a rapidly growing field, with many companies actively seeking qualified candidates. According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, the median annual wage for software developers was $107,510 in 2020, and employment of software developers is projected to grow 21% from 2020 to 2029, much faster than the average for all occupations.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
