<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technology on Joshua P. Steele</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/technology/</link><description>Recent content in Technology on Joshua P. Steele</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 19:39:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/technology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anyone Can Use AI Tools: Here's How</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anyone-can-use-ai-tools-heres-how/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anyone-can-use-ai-tools-heres-how/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you drowning in tasks, yearning for more hours in a day, or simply itching to supercharge your creativity? What if I told you that a digital sidekick exists—one that’s awake 24/7, tailored to boost your efficiency and spark ingenuity? No, this isn’t science fiction; it’s the transformative power of AI tools at your fingertips.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think AI is only for tech gurus and coding aficionados? Think again. AI is breaking down the ivory tower, becoming an invaluable asset for everyone from marketers and writers to busy parents. If you’re intrigued by the idea of harnessing AI to make your life more productive, more balanced, and yes, even more fun, then you’re in for a treat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avoiding Online Scams: A Simple Guide for Non-Tech-Savvy Internet Users</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:24:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Online scams can touch anyone’s life. They don’t discriminate based on how tech-savvy you are or how often you use the internet. We’ve all heard stories—maybe from a friend, a family member, or even in the news—of someone getting tricked online, often with distressing consequences. It serves as a stark reminder of the darker side of our digital world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is why it’s crucial for every one of us to understand online scams—how they operate, how to identify them, and most importantly, how to avoid becoming a victim.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>