<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 19:39:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/technology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anyone Can Use AI Tools: Here&#39;s How</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/anyone-can-use-ai-tools-heres-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/anyone-can-use-ai-tools-heres-how/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you drowning in tasks, yearning for more hours in a day, or simply itching to supercharge your creativity? What if I told you that a digital sidekick exists—one that’s awake 24/7, tailored to boost your efficiency and spark ingenuity? No, this isn’t science fiction; it’s the transformative power of AI tools at your fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think AI is only for tech gurus and coding aficionados? Think again. AI is breaking down the ivory tower, becoming an invaluable asset for everyone from marketers and writers to busy parents. If you’re intrigued by the idea of harnessing AI to make your life more productive, more balanced, and yes, even more fun, then you’re in for a treat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you drowning in tasks, yearning for more hours in a day, or simply itching to supercharge your creativity? What if I told you that a digital sidekick exists—one that’s awake 24/7, tailored to boost your efficiency and spark ingenuity? No, this isn’t science fiction; it’s the transformative power of AI tools at your fingertips.</p>
<p>Think AI is only for tech gurus and coding aficionados? Think again. AI is breaking down the ivory tower, becoming an invaluable asset for everyone from marketers and writers to busy parents. If you’re intrigued by the idea of harnessing AI to make your life more productive, more balanced, and yes, even more fun, then you’re in for a treat.</p>
<h2 id="ai-tool-recommendations-chatgpt-notion-and-dall-e-2">AI Tool Recommendations: ChatGPT, Notion, and DALL-E 2</h2>
<p>Let’s start with the AI elephant in the room: ChatGPT! It’s the AI tool I use most often and it’s probably the best place to start for AI beginners.</p>
<p>So, if you haven’t already done so, head over to <a href="https://chat.openai.com/">https://chat.openai.com/</a> to start using ChatGPT for yourself. It’s as easy as chatting or texting with a friend.</p>
<p>Other AI tools that are good places to start for beginners include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft Bing’s Chat (search and chat): <a href="https://www.bing.com/">https://www.bing.com/</a></li>
<li>Notion (all-in-one notes and productivity): <a href="https://www.notion.so/product">https://www.notion.so/product</a></li>
<li>DALL-E 2 (image generation): <a href="https://labs.openai.com/">https://labs.openai.com/</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="how-to-use-ai-mastering-the-subtleties-of-prompt-engineering">How to Use AI: Mastering the Subtleties of “Prompt Engineering”</h2>
<p>You’ve heard the phrase “It’s not what you say; it’s how you say it,” right? In the world of AI, it’s both what you say and how you say it that count. This concept crystallizes into what we call “Prompt Engineering”—the art and science of effectively instructing AI to get the response you’re looking for.</p>
<p><strong>Prompt Engineering</strong> is crucial because even sophisticated models like ChatGPT-4 rely on the context and clarity provided by your prompt. A poorly-structured or ambiguous prompt often results in equally confusing or lackluster responses. Therefore, learning to master your prompts can be the difference between a frustrating experience and one that feels like you’re interacting with a truly helpful digital assistant.</p>
<h3 id="practical-tips-for-prompt-engineering">Practical Tips for Prompt Engineering</h3>
<ol>
<li><strong>Be Specific:</strong> If you’re looking for a detailed answer, make sure your prompt outlines this expectation. For example, instead of asking, “Tell me about coffee,” you could say, “Explain the difference between Arabica and Robusta coffee beans in terms of flavor and caffeine content.”</li>
<li><strong>Set the Format:</strong> If you’re after information in a particular structure, guide the AI by stating that upfront. For example, “List the steps to create a simple Python program to say ‘Hello, World!&rsquo;”</li>
<li><strong>Ask for Revisions:</strong> If the AI’s first attempt doesn’t quite hit the mark, use that output as a stepping stone. You can say, “That’s a good start, but can you elaborate on X?” or “That’s close, but can you rephrase that in simpler terms?”</li>
<li><strong>Be Interactive:</strong> Don’t be afraid to have a back-and-forth with the AI. These tools are designed for interactivity. Feel free to ask follow-up questions or seek clarifications just as you would in a conversation with a human.</li>
</ol>
<p>By understanding and applying these principles of prompt engineering, you’ll be able to maximize the capabilities of AI tools, making them far more valuable in your personal and professional life. It’s like learning to speak a new digital dialect—one that can unlock doors you didn’t even know existed.</p>
<h2 id="the-most-important-ai-tool-tip-iterate-iterate-iterate">The MOST Important AI Tool Tip: Iterate, Iterate, Iterate!</h2>
<p>I’m repeating myself and making this its own section because it’s so important. One of the very best things about these new generative AI tools is that you can iterate with them.</p>
<p>That is, you can go back-and-forth with the AI tool, asking for improvements, revisions, clarifications, etc.!</p>
<p>At first, this might not seem like a big deal, but it really is the KEY for getting AI to produce good, helpful content for you.</p>
<p>For example: Ask ChatGPT to write an email to your boss asking for a raise. If you don’t like what it gives you back, then use this opportunity to get specific about what you want. Too formal? Not formal enough? Don’t just ask for more money, but also better hours? List reasons X, Y, and Z why you deserve the raise?</p>
<p>Hell, just the back-and-forth process alone is beneficial, because it forces you to get clear and get specific!</p>
<p>Bottom line: Don’t give up on an AI tool if its first response doesn’t blow you away. Instead, leverage the tool’s capabilities, and take the opportunity to clarify your desires and thoughts, by ITERATING. Go back-and-forth with these tools and you’ll be impressed with where they can take you!</p>
<h2 id="ai-reading-recommendations">AI Reading Recommendations</h2>
<p>Want to learn more about AI tools and how to use them?</p>
<p>I’d like to introduce you to three incredibly insightful articles by Ethan Mollick over at <a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/">“One Useful Thing.”</a> They’re packed with practical knowledge and will get you started on your AI journey.</p>
<h3 id="how-to-use-ai-to-do-practical-stuff-a-new-guidehttpswwwoneusefulthingorgphow-to-use-ai-to-do-practical-stuff"><a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/how-to-use-ai-to-do-practical-stuff">How To Use AI to Do Practical Stuff: A New Guide</a></h3>
<p>In <a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/how-to-use-ai-to-do-practical-stuff">“How to Use AI to Do Practical Stuff,”</a> Ethan delivers a comprehensive overview of the major generative AI players on the market today. He doesn’t just stop at naming them; he delves into writing, images, idea generation, video, coding, learning, and other categories, showing how AI tools can assist you in ways you might not have imagined. Start with this article to get ideas flowing.</p>
<h3 id="onboarding-your-ai-internhttpswwwoneusefulthingorgpon-boarding-your-ai-intern"><a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/on-boarding-your-ai-intern">Onboarding Your AI Intern</a></h3>
<p>Imagine having an intern who never sleeps and is always eager to help. In <a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/on-boarding-your-ai-intern">“Onboarding Your AI Intern,”</a> Ethan walks through the various considerations involved in thinking of new generative AI tools like a digital intern of sorts.</p>
<p>At first glance, you might think an intern is unnecessary for your workflow. But take a moment to reflect on the myriad tasks you perform in a given week. In this era of digital transformation, with an influx of AI tools, I’m confident that there are tasks you can offload to an AI intern, giving you more time to focus on what truly matters.</p>
<h3 id="how-to-use-ai-to-do-stuff-an-opinionated-guidehttpswwwoneusefulthingorgphow-to-use-ai-to-do-stuff-an-opinionated"><a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/how-to-use-ai-to-do-stuff-an-opinionated">How to Use AI to Do Stuff: An Opinionated Guide</a></h3>
<p>In <a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/how-to-use-ai-to-do-stuff-an-opinionated">“How to Use AI to Do Stuff: An Opinionate Guide,”</a> Ethan gives an updated (summer 2023) overview of recommendations for AI tools in various task categories. It’s a quickly-evolving landscape, but hopefully reading through these pieces will help you come up with a shortlist of new tools to experiment with!</p>
<hr>
<p>Do you already use AI tools in some capacity? Are certain questions or obstacles holding you back? Please let me know in the comments below!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Online Scams: A Simple Guide for Non-Tech-Savvy Internet Users</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online scams can touch anyone’s life. They don’t discriminate based on how tech-savvy you are or how often you use the internet. We’ve all heard stories—maybe from a friend, a family member, or even in the news—of someone getting tricked online, often with distressing consequences. It serves as a stark reminder of the darker side of our digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why it’s crucial for every one of us to understand online scams—how they operate, how to identify them, and most importantly, how to avoid becoming a victim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Online scams can touch anyone’s life. They don’t discriminate based on how tech-savvy you are or how often you use the internet. We’ve all heard stories—maybe from a friend, a family member, or even in the news—of someone getting tricked online, often with distressing consequences. It serves as a stark reminder of the darker side of our digital world.</p>
<p>This is why it’s crucial for every one of us to understand online scams—how they operate, how to identify them, and most importantly, how to avoid becoming a victim.</p>
<p>In this guide, I’ll demystify the most common types of online scams and equip you with practical knowledge to stay safe. Regardless of whether you’re a digital native or just someone who occasionally checks emails or shops online, this guide will offer valuable insights to help protect you and your loved ones.</p>
<p>Let’s begin this important journey to digital safety.</p>
<h2 id="understanding-online-scams">Understanding Online Scams</h2>
<p>In the broadest sense, an online scam is a fraudulent scheme performed by a dishonest individual, group, or company in an attempt to obtain money or something else of value from unsuspecting internet users. They can happen virtually anywhere online, from your email inbox to social media platforms, online marketplaces, and even dating sites.</p>
<p>Here are a few common types of online scams that you might encounter:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Phishing Scams:</strong> Perhaps the most common type of online scam, phishing occurs when a scammer attempts to trick you into giving out your personal information. They might send you an email that appears to be from a legitimate company asking you to login to your account, and when you do, they capture your username and password.</li>
<li><strong>Lottery Scams:</strong> These scams operate by telling you that you’ve won a huge amount of money in a lottery or sweepstakes that you never even entered. To receive your “winnings,” however, you’ll be asked to pay a fee or provide your banking information.</li>
<li><strong>Tech Support Scams:</strong> Scammers posing as tech support personnel from a well-known company claim to have detected issues with your computer. They’ll attempt to gain remote access to your machine, potentially stealing data or installing harmful software.</li>
</ol>
<p>These are just a few examples (for more examples and advice, <a href="https://usa.kaspersky.com/resource-center/threats/top-scams-how-to-avoid-becoming-a-victim">checkout this piece from Kaspersky</a>). Scams can come in many forms, and scammers are always evolving their tactics. However, understanding these common types of scams is the first step toward protecting yourself.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-identify-online-scams">How to Identify Online Scams</h2>
<p>While online scams can take various forms and evolve over time, there are certain red flags you can look out for to help you identify potential scams:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Unsolicited Contact:</strong> Be wary if you receive unexpected emails, messages, or calls from people or organizations you don’t know, especially if they’re asking for personal or financial information.</li>
<li><strong>Too Good To Be True:</strong> If an offer seems too good to be true—like a huge lottery win from a contest you never entered—it probably is. Scammers often lure their victims with promises of large financial gains.</li>
<li><strong>Pressure Tactics:</strong> Many scammers try to create a sense of urgency to pressure you into making quick decisions without giving you time to think or verify the information.</li>
<li><strong>Requests for Sensitive Information:</strong> Legitimate companies will rarely, if ever, ask for your personal or financial information through email or text message.</li>
<li><strong>Grammar and Spelling Mistakes:</strong> While not always the case, many scam messages contain poor grammar and spelling. This can be a telltale sign of a scam, as legitimate companies typically proofread their communications carefully.</li>
</ol>
<p>Here’s an example: Imagine you receive an email that looks like it’s from your bank. The email states there’s been suspicious activity on your account and you need to confirm your details immediately or your account will be closed.</p>
<p>But there’s something off about the email—the bank’s logo looks a bit blurry, there are a couple of typos, and they’ve addressed you as ‘Valued Customer’ instead of your name. All of these signs point to a potential phishing scam.</p>
<p>By recognizing these signs, you can better protect yourself from falling victim to online scams.</p>
<p>(Learn more about <a href="https://www.mcafee.com/learn/how-to-recognize-an-online-scammer/">how to recognize an online scammer here from McAfee</a>.)</p>
<h2 id="how-to-protect-yourself-from-online-scams">How to Protect Yourself from Online Scams</h2>
<p>Knowing how to identify potential scams is only part of the solution. Here are some practical steps to protect yourself from becoming a victim:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Secure Your Devices:</strong> Ensure that all your devices are protected with the latest security software, web browsers, and operating systems. Regular updates can help protect against the latest threats.</li>
<li><strong>Be Cautious with Links and Attachments:</strong> Do not click on links or download attachments from unknown sources. They could lead to malicious websites or install malware on your device.</li>
<li><strong>Use Strong, Unique Passwords:</strong> Use complex passwords and change them regularly. Consider using a password manager to help keep track of your passwords. (I LOVE, use, and <a href="https://1password.com/">highly recommend 1Password. Check them out!</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Enable Two-Factor Authentication:</strong> Where possible, enable two-factor authentication for your online accounts. This adds an extra layer of security by requiring a second form of identification beyond just your password.</li>
<li><strong>Verify Before Sharing:</strong> Don’t share personal or financial information unless you’ve verified the person or organization requesting it. If you receive an unexpected request, contact the company directly using a phone number or website you know is legitimate.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Informed:</strong> Scams evolve constantly. Staying informed about the latest scam tactics can help you stay one step ahead.</li>
</ol>
<p>Remember, online safety is a continuous process. By adopting these practices, you can browse the internet more confidently and securely.</p>
<p>(Want more advice on how to protect yourself? Read <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-au/topic/protect-yourself-from-online-scams-and-attacks-0109ae3f-fe61-4262-8dce-2ee3cd43bac7">this piece from Microsoft</a>.)</p>
<h2 id="what-to-do-if-youre-a-victim-of-an-online-scam">What to Do if You’re a Victim of an Online Scam</h2>
<p>If you suspect you’ve become a victim of an online scam, it’s essential to take action promptly to minimize potential damage. Here’s what you should do:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Report the Scam:</strong> Depending on the nature of the scam, you can report it to your local law enforcement agency, your bank (if money was taken from your account), or an appropriate online platform. In the US, you can also report scams to the Federal Trade Commission through their website.</li>
<li><strong>Secure Your Accounts:</strong> If the scam involved any of your online accounts, change your passwords immediately. If you used the same password on any other accounts, change those as well.</li>
<li><strong>Monitor Your Accounts:</strong> Keep an eye on your bank accounts, credit cards, and other financial accounts for any suspicious activity.</li>
<li><strong>Contact a Credit Reporting Agency:</strong> If the scam involved your personal identity or financial information, contact one of the credit reporting agencies to place a fraud alert on your name.</li>
<li><strong>Seek Support:</strong> It can be distressing to be a victim of an online scam. Reach out to your friends, family, or professional counselors to help manage any stress or anxiety.</li>
</ol>
<p>Being a victim of an online scam can feel overwhelming, but by taking these steps, you can work to mitigate the effects and prevent future scams.</p>
<p>(The Federal Trade Commission has some good advice about <a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/articles/what-do-if-you-were-scammed">what to do if you were scammed</a>.)</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>In the digital age, online scams are an unfortunate reality that we must all be prepared to face. Yet, with understanding and vigilance, you can significantly reduce your risk of becoming a victim.</p>
<ul>
<li>Remember to stay skeptical of unsolicited contact, especially if it promises vast rewards or pressures you into fast action.</li>
<li>Take the time to verify information before acting on it.</li>
<li>Maintain strong, unique passwords and use two-factor authentication wherever possible.</li>
<li>Protect your devices with updated security software, and be cautious when clicking on links or downloading attachments.</li>
</ul>
<p>Being scammed can feel violating and disheartening. It’s important to remember that if you are scammed, it’s not your fault. The individuals perpetrating these scams are the ones to blame. If you’ve been scammed, don’t hesitate to report it and take steps to protect yourself from further harm.</p>
<p>By spreading awareness and sharing information about online scams, we can all contribute to making the internet a safer place. Feel free to share this post with anyone who might benefit from it. Stay safe out there!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
