<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <image>
      <title>Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/default-social.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/default-social.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 16:22:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/opinion/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Josh&#43;? On the use of the sign of the cross (plus sign) in clergy signatures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/josh-on-the-use-of-the-sign-of-the-cross-plus-sign-in-clergy-signatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 13:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/josh-on-the-use-of-the-sign-of-the-cross-plus-sign-in-clergy-signatures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is, admittedly, a half-baked opinion. However, I need to get back in the habit of blogging/writing regularly, so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the use of the sign of the cross in clergy names/signatures—unless it’s done in official ecclesiastical communication or immediately after a blessing or prayer for the recipient—is pretentious. It’s showy. At the very least, it conveys or connotes pretentiousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I’m not making a claim about the *people* who use crosses in their signatures, their inner thoughts, or their intentions. For all I know, every single clergyperson out there says a prayer of blessing for their recipients every single time they use the sign of the cross in a signature. I’m also not writing this about any person in particular.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is, admittedly, a half-baked opinion. However, I need to get back in the habit of blogging/writing regularly, so here goes.</p>
<p>In my opinion, the use of the sign of the cross in clergy names/signatures—unless it’s done in official ecclesiastical communication or immediately after a blessing or prayer for the recipient—is pretentious. It’s showy. At the very least, it conveys or connotes pretentiousness.</p>
<p>Note that I’m not making a claim about the *people* who use crosses in their signatures, their inner thoughts, or their intentions. For all I know, every single clergyperson out there says a prayer of blessing for their recipients every single time they use the sign of the cross in a signature. I’m also not writing this about any person in particular.</p>
<p>I’m merely observing what I take to be the *connotation* of a particular speech act.</p>
<p>It’s one thing to use a signature with the sign of the cross in, say, a letter to a parishioner that you end with “May the Lord bless you and keep you.” In that case, it’s more obviously functioning like a written replacement for the sign of the cross that one would make with one’s hand if one were giving a priestly blessing in person.</p>
<p>However, apart from the immediate context of a blessing or prayer, I dare say that <a href="https://qr.ae/pNA4ts">most people just think it’s a plus sign</a>. Perhaps a typo when one meant to hit backspace? A new subscription service for personal communication? Or maybe the new-and-improved version of so-and-so now that they’ve turned a corner in their life and things are looking up?</p>
<p>I’m not saying that we clerics need to stop using the sign of the cross in our signatures altogether! A poor connotation for something (say, wearing a clergy shirt in public) doesn’t mean we should abandon it. I’m just suggesting that we should be more judicious in its use.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
