<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 11:37:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pages/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy of Ministry</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/philosophy-of-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 11:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/philosophy-of-ministry/</guid>
      <description>Every Christian is a theologian.
I consider it my life&amp;rsquo;s work to help &amp;ldquo;everyday Christians&amp;rdquo; grow in their knowledge and love of God so that we all can put our gifts to good use by joining with God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive work in the world. In biblical terms, I&amp;rsquo;m called to &amp;ldquo;equip the saints for the work of ministry&amp;rdquo; and to &amp;ldquo;build up the body of Christ&amp;rdquo; (Eph. 4:12).
Now, on the one hand, this means that I’m not supposed to do all the work of ministry myself!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Story</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/my-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 22:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/my-story/</guid>
      <description>(Note: for a much briefer profile of what I&amp;rsquo;m like and what makes me tick as a worker, read this self-assessment.)
From Childhood to College God’s faithfulness to me is linked with his faithfulness to my parents. They both grew up in nominally Roman Catholic homes, and came to relationship with Christ shortly before my birth. When I came along, their church environment was a mixture between conservative Baptist and non-denominational.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/now/</guid>
      <description>These days, I&amp;rsquo;m:
Living in Toledo, OH (my hometown!) Raising 3 kids with my wife Enjoying my work as a software engineer Trying to lose weight (current weight: 240lbs; goal: 200lbs) Working on home repair, DIY projects (next up: installing a water-powered backup sump pump) Buying too many books (like The Highly Sensitive Person: How to Thrive When the World Overwhelms You) Buying too many tools (like this amazing little &amp;ldquo;Superman&amp;rsquo;s fingernail&amp;rdquo; skin wedge pry bar from Ares) Last updated: 2024-08-06</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wish List</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 19:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wishlist/</guid>
      <description>I want…
To be a good husband To be a good father To be a good friend To solve people’s problems To build what people use To write what people read To never stop learning Finances To have control over my time “The ability to do what you want, when you want, with who you want, for as long as you want, is priceless. It is the highest dividend money pays” (Morgan Housel, The Psychology of Money, 83).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Tools and Resources</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 01:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>A &amp;ldquo;tool&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;anything that can make your life better.&amp;rdquo; I love tools, whether physical or digital. And I love books, because they&amp;rsquo;re some of the best tools out there!
Lifestyle Tools Coffee Maker: OXO 9-Cup Coffee Maker Coffee Grinder: Capresso Infinity Conical Burr Grinder Water Bottle: Owala FreeSip, 24oz Previous: Iron Flask, 64oz Fitness Tools Squat Rack: REP Fitness PR-1100 Power Rack Previous: Valor Fitness BD–9 Squat Stands Bench: Amazon Basics Flat Weight Bench Barbell and Weights: Fitness Gear 300lb.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/</guid>
      <description>Joshua P. Steele, &amp;ldquo;The Rev. Dev.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m Josh Steele, a pastor-turned-programmer (&amp;ldquo;Rev[erend]&amp;quot;-to-&amp;ldquo;Dev[eloper]&amp;rdquo;) who solves problems with a programmer&amp;rsquo;s eye for detail and a pastor&amp;rsquo;s heart for people.
As a software engineer, I work mainly on backend development in Java for a cybersecurity company. But I&amp;rsquo;m also an ordained Anglican priest (currently resigned from active ministry) with three Bible/theology degrees.
Currently living in Toledo, OH, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a wife, three young children, and an addiction to buying books and tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio (About Me)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 17:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>CV Read my curriculum vitae to learn more about my education and experience.
Workplace Self Assessment To learn more about what I&amp;rsquo;m like as a worker, from the kinds of people I work best with to the transferable skills I bring to the table, read my results from the &amp;ldquo;Flower Petal Exercise&amp;rdquo; in What Color is Your Parachute?
Essays Read a collection of my academic essays.
Sermons Read or listen to an archive of my sermons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essays</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/essays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 21:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/essays/</guid>
      <description>Wheaton College Graduate School (2017 - ) (Here&amp;rsquo;s the elevator pitch for my dissertation proposal: &amp;ldquo;Scriptural, But Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion.&amp;rdquo;)
The Guilt of Karl Barth: Strengths and Weaknesses of Barth’s Römerbrief Reading of Romans 9:30–10:21 The Tree of Religion: Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge in Genesis 2:4–3:24 When will Thy Kingdom Come? The Timing and Agency of the Kingdom of God in the Lord’s Prayer Theological Hermeneutics Essay: The Hermeneutical Implications of Scripture&amp;rsquo;s Theological Location Beeson Divinity School (2013-2016) To Be or Not To Be Religious: A Clarification of Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s and Dietrich Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s Divergence and Convergence Regarding Religion A Crucicentric Credo What Does It Mean To Be Human?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 21:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/cv/</guid>
      <description>(For a brief profile of what I&amp;rsquo;m like and what makes me tick as a worker, read this self-assessment. You can also view my resume on LinkedIn.)
EXPERIENCE Software Engineer II - Proofpoint February 2023 - Present Led the design and development of a major user provisioning integration project, demonstrating leadership and technical skills. Authored scripts for system testing and delivered a technical presentation on the system. Mentored and trained new developers, showcasing leadership and interpersonal skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 10:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/sermons/</guid>
      <description>( Click here to view all posts that have been categorized as sermons on my blog.)
Why Haven&amp;rsquo;t You Torn the Sky Open Yet? Your browser does not support the audio element. Isaiah 64. November 28, 2020 (First Sunday of Advent). Preached at Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL (via Zoom).
Who Really Cares about the Trinity? Matthew 28:16-20. June 6, 2020. Preached at Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL (via Zoom).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 17:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can email me at &amp;ldquo;joshuapsteele&amp;rdquo; at the domain of my personal website!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
