<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sermon on the Mount on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/sermon-on-the-mount/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sermon on the Mount on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <image>
      <title>Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <url>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</url>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 16:22:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/sermon-on-the-mount/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are the Beatitudes “Renunciations” (Verzichte)?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Discipleship&lt;/em&gt; (DBWE 4), Dietrich Bonhoeffer frames all of the Beatitudes in terms of Jesus’ disciples living in &lt;em&gt;renunciation&lt;/em&gt; (Verzicht) and &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; (Mangel).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, for Bonhoeffer, Jesus is only speaking to his disciples in the Beatitudes (he makes this argument on the basis of Luke 6:20ff.). And the disciples’ renunciation and want are &lt;em&gt;caused&lt;/em&gt; by Jesus’s call to discipleship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus sees&lt;/em&gt;: his disciples are over there. They have visibly left the people to join him. He has called each individual one. They have given up everything in response to his call. Now they are living in renunciation and want; they are the poorest of the poor, the most tempted of the tempted, the hungriest of the hungry. They have only him. Yes, and with him they have nothing in the world, nothing at all, but everything, everything with God. (DBWE 4:101).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In <em>Discipleship</em> (DBWE 4), Dietrich Bonhoeffer frames all of the Beatitudes in terms of Jesus’ disciples living in <em>renunciation</em> (Verzicht) and <em>want</em> (Mangel).</p>
<p>Interestingly, for Bonhoeffer, Jesus is only speaking to his disciples in the Beatitudes (he makes this argument on the basis of Luke 6:20ff.). And the disciples’ renunciation and want are <em>caused</em> by Jesus’s call to discipleship.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Jesus sees</em>: his disciples are over there. They have visibly left the people to join him. He has called each individual one. They have given up everything in response to his call. Now they are living in renunciation and want; they are the poorest of the poor, the most tempted of the tempted, the hungriest of the hungry. They have only him. Yes, and with him they have nothing in the world, nothing at all, but everything, everything with God. (DBWE 4:101).</p></blockquote><p>Bonhoeffer also writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>Therefore, “Blessed!” Jesus is speaking to the disciples (cf. Luke 6:20ff.). He is speaking to those who are already under the power of his call. That call has made them poor, tempted, and hungry. He calls them blessed, not because of their want or renunciation. Neither want nor renunciation are in themselves any reason to be called blessed. The only adequate reason is the call and the promise, for whose sake those following him live in want and renunciation. (DBWE 4:101).</p></blockquote><p>Although Bonhoeffer is willing to frame all of the Beatitudes in terms of want and (especially) renunciation, he takes issue with August Tholuck’s distinction between some of the Beatitudes speaking of want “and others of the disciples’ intentional renunciation or special virtues” (DBWE 4:101; cf. Tholuck, <em>Commentary</em>, 64). Not, note, because Bonhoeffer has a problem with framing the Beatitudes in terms of renunciation and want, but rather because he thinks that “Objective want and personal renunciation have their joint basis in Christ’s call and promise” (DBWE 4:101–2).</p>
<p>In this connection, Bonhoeffer has a lengthy footnote:</p>
<blockquote><p>There is no basis in scripture for constructing a contrast between Matthew and Luke. Matthew is not interested in spiritualizing the original Beatitude (Luke’s form), nor is Luke interested in politicizing any original Beatitudes (Matthew’s form) referring only to “state of mind.” Need is not the basis of blessedness in Luke, nor is renunciation the basis in Matthew. Rather, in both, need or renunciation, spiritual or political matters are justified only by the call and promise of Jesus, who alone makes the Beatitudes into what they are, and who alone is the basis of calling those matters blessed. Catholic exegesis, starting with the letters of Clement, wanted to have the virtue of poverty declared blessed, thinking on the one hand of the paupertas voluntaria [voluntary poverty] of the monks, on the other hand of any voluntary poverty for Christ’s sake. In both cases the mistake in interpretation lies in seeking to make some human behavior the basis for blessedness, and not solely Jesus’ call and promise. (DBWE 4:102n2).</p></blockquote><p>So, for Bonhoeffer, Christ’s call is clearly central—not human behavior. And yet, Christ’s call seems to cause the human situations in view in the Beatitudes.</p>
<h2 id="heres-how-bonhoeffer-frames-the-beatitudes-in-terms-of-want-and-renunciation">Here’s how Bonhoeffer frames the Beatitudes in terms of “want” and “renunciation.”</h2>
<ul>
<li>Blessed are the poor in spirit -&gt; “those who live thoroughly in <em>renunciation and want</em> for Jesus’ sake” (DBWE 4:103).</li>
<li>Blessed are those who mourn -&gt; “those who are prepared to renounce and live without everything the world calls <em>happiness</em> and <em>peace</em>” (DBWE 4:103; cf. DBWE 1:184).</li>
<li>Blessed are the meek -&gt; those “who <em>renounce all rights of their own</em> for the sake of Jesus Christ” (DBWE 4:105).</li>
<li>Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness -&gt; “Disciples live with not only renouncing their own rights, but even <em>renouncing their own righteousness</em>” (DBWE 4:105).</li>
<li>Blessed are the merciful -&gt; “these followers of Jesus live with him now also in the <em>renunciation of their own dignity</em>, for they are merciful” (DBWE 4:106).</li>
<li>Blessed are the pure in heart -&gt; “Those who <em>renounce their own good and evil</em>, their own heart, who are contrite and depend solely on Jesus” (DBWE 4:107).</li>
<li>Blessed are the peacemakers -&gt; those who “<em>renounce violence and strife</em>” (DBWE 4:108).</li>
<li>Blessed are those who are persecuted for righteousness’ sake -&gt; “In judgment and action <strong>those who follow Jesus will be different from the world in renouncing property, happiness, rights, righteousness, honor, and violence.</strong> They will be offensive to the world. That is why the disciples will be persecuted for righteousness’ sake. Not recognition, but rejection, will be their reward from the world for their word and deed.” (DBWE 4:109, <strong>emphasis added</strong>).</li>
</ul>
<p>According to an editorial footnote, Eberhard Bethge’s notes</p>
<blockquote><p>say that “everything is renunciation; nothing is Christian doctrine of virtue. Difference between ‘active and passive’ (making ethical distinction) is invalid” (22). As early as lectures of 1935 and 1935–36, Bonhoeffer sees the Beatitudes summarized in Matt. 5:10f. (DBWE 109n43).</p></blockquote><p>Now, because I’m working on how Barth and Bonhoeffer read Genesis 1–3 and Matthew 5–7, I’m especially interested in the resonances between what Bonhoeffer has to say about the “pure in heart” renouncing their “good and evil.”</p>
<p>However, on a broader level, I’m curious where he got this thoroughgoing emphasis on “renunciation” (Verzicht) from.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Beatitudes</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 19:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I said in my previous post, “&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/&#34;&gt;Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount&lt;/a&gt;,” I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, when interpreting the Sermon on the Mount, the best place to start is at the beginning! This means beginning with the Beatitudes in Matthew 5:1–12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beatitudes-matt-5112&#34;&gt;The Beatitudes (Matt. 5:1–12)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 When Jesus saw the crowds, he went up the mountain; and after he sat down, his disciples came to him. 2 Then he began to speak, and taught them, saying:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I said in my previous post, “<a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/">Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount</a>,” I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.</p>
<p>Of course, when interpreting the Sermon on the Mount, the best place to start is at the beginning! This means beginning with the Beatitudes in Matthew 5:1–12.</p>
<h2 id="the-beatitudes-matt-5112">The Beatitudes (Matt. 5:1–12)</h2>
<blockquote><p>1 When Jesus saw the crowds, he went up the mountain; and after he sat down, his disciples came to him. 2 Then he began to speak, and taught them, saying:</p>
<p>3 “Blessed are the poor in spirit, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.</p>
<p>4 “Blessed are those who mourn, for they will be comforted.</p>
<p>5 “Blessed are the meek, for they will inherit the earth.</p>
<p>6 “Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they will be filled.</p>
<p>7 “Blessed are the merciful, for they will receive mercy.</p>
<p>8 “Blessed are the pure in heart, for they will see God.</p>
<p>9 “Blessed are the peacemakers, for they will be called children of God.</p>
<p>10 “Blessed are those who are persecuted for righteousness’ sake, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.</p>
<p>11 “Blessed are you when people revile you and persecute you and utter all kinds of evil against you falsely on my account. 12 Rejoice and be glad, for your reward is great in heaven, for in the same way they persecuted the prophets who were before you. (Matt. 5:1–12, NRSV).</p></blockquote><h2 id="heres-lukes-version-of-the-beatitudes-luke-62026">Here’s Luke’s version of the Beatitudes (Luke 6:20–26)</h2>
<blockquote><p>20 Then he looked up at his disciples and said:</p>
<p>“Blessed are you who are poor, for yours is the kingdom of God.</p>
<p>21 “Blessed are you who are hungry now, for you will be filled.</p>
<p>“Blessed are you who weep now, for you will laugh.</p>
<p>22 “Blessed are you when people hate you, and when they exclude you, revile you, and defame you on account of the Son of Man. 23 Rejoice in that day and leap for joy, for surely your reward is great in heaven; for that is what their ancestors did to the prophets.</p>
<p>24 “But woe to you who are rich, for you have received your consolation.</p>
<p>25 “Woe to you who are full now, for you will be hungry.</p>
<p>“Woe to you who are laughing now, for you will mourn and weep.</p>
<p>26 “Woe to you when all speak well of you, for that is what their ancestors did to the false prophets. (Luke 6:20–26, NRSV).</p></blockquote><h2 id="so-what-should-we-make-of-the-beatitudes">So, what should we make of the Beatitudes?</h2>
<p>Of course, the differences between Matthew’s and Luke’s versions of the Beatitudes have prompted considerable discussion within biblical studies.</p>
<p>As Jason C. Kuo notes in his “Beatitudes” article in <em>The Lexham Bible Dictionary</em>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Some believe that only a few of the Beatitudes originate from Jesus Himself. Based on an examination of the background and the overlapping beatitudes between Matthew and Luke, Davies and Allison suggest that only three are original—“Jesus utters three paradoxical beatitudes: blessed are the poor, blessed are those who mourn, and blessed are those who hunger” (Davies and Allison, Matthew, 435). Others, however, suggest that at least eight of the nine can be traced to Jesus Himself. Hagner contends, “To assert that only three go back to Jesus assumes criteria that are too restrictive and presumes to know more than we can know” (Hagner, Matthew, 90). Blomberg suggests the possibility that “both Matthew and Luke might be excerpting from an original set of eight Beatitudes and eight woes” (Blomberg, Matthew, 98).</p></blockquote><p>With all due respect to these “Matthew vs. Luke” discussions, I’m much more interested in how people have gone about making sense of the Beatitudes in the context of the Sermon on the Mount in Matthew 5–7.</p>
<p>Again, here’s Kuo:</p>
<blockquote><p>A number of different approaches can be employed in interpreting the Beatitudes. They have been typically understood as primarily (1) pronouncing rewards for the virtuous, (2) signaling reversals for the unfortunate, or (3) combining elements of the two (Powell, “Matthew’s Beatitudes,” 460).</p></blockquote><p>Here’s how Warren Carter summarizes the interpretive debates in his “Beatitudes” article in <em>Eerdmans Dictionary of the Bible</em>:</p>
<blockquote><p>There has also been considerable debate about how to interpret Matthew’s beatitudes. Do they promise eschatological rewards for the virtuous who manifest these characteristics in their lives, or do they proclaim God’s reversals for those who find themselves in these unfortunate circumstances? Are the Beatitudes ethicized “entrance requirements” exhorting readers to a way of life by which they might enter God’s reign? Or are they “eschatological blessings” announced on those who already encounter God’s reign in part? Or is it possible to read them in one consistent way? To “mourn” in Matt. 5:4 does not necessarily seem to be a virtue, while to be a “peacemaker” is not a situation that needs reversing. (p. 159).</p></blockquote><p>In my opinion, that’s a really interesting observation to make regarding “mourn” and “peacemaker.” Are we perhaps trying to parse things out too finely if we try to make the Beatitudes fit into a single interpretive framework?</p>
<p>After all, I agree with Kuo that, regardless of which framework we go with, we need to remember to keep the focus on “the kingdom of God.” As Kuo puts it:</p>
<blockquote><p>Regardless of the approach, the Beatitudes provide a framework for the people of God to understand what it means to be a part of the kingdom. Turner notes, “The theological purpose of the Sermon on the Mount in general and of the beatitudes in particular centers in the kingdom of heaven” (Turner, “Whom Does God Approve,” 36). In conjunction with the Sermon on the Mount, members of the kingdom are to be salt and light (Matt 5:13–16), providing an example as a “contrast community” (Bailey, “Model for Community,” 86) in the world. The Beatitudes—with their pronouncements of blessings as rewards and reversals—communicate a value system that is of the kingdom of God. Finally, as Davies and Allison conclude, the Beatitudes “bring consolation and comfort to Jesus’ heavy-laden followers … putting into perspective the difficulties of the present,” giving believers a “hope that makes powerlessness and suffering bearable” (Davies and Allison, Matthew, 467).</p></blockquote><h2 id="what-about-barth-and-bonhoeffer">What about Barth and Bonhoeffer?</h2>
<p>For me, it’s still early days in trying to make sense of Barth and Bonhoeffer. Nevertheless, I’m comfortable with claiming that they both take a “synthetic” and “christological” approach to the Beatitudes.</p>
<p>“Synthetic” as in “not analytic.” As Merriam-Webster puts it: “attributing to a subject something determined by observation rather than analysis of the nature of the subject and not resulting in self-contradiction if negated.” (Compare/contrast “analytic,” as in: “being a proposition [as “no bachelor is married”] whose truth is evident from the meaning of the words it contains.”)</p>
<p>This is the language that Barth uses to describe the Beatitudes:</p>
<blockquote><p>the sufferers of this world cannot pride themselves on the fact that their lives have this transparency, that the kingdom, Jesus, is in fact near to them. The declaration that they are blessed is a synthetic and not an analytic statement, referring to the objective thing that characterises their existence from above and not from below. To them, too, the new thing is said when they are called blessed in relation to their misery. Neither they nor their misery create the fact that they exist in that light of Jesus. It is simply the case, and they are called blessed simply because of that which is indicated by their misery: “The poor have the gospel preached to them” (Mt. 11:5). (CD IV/2, 191).</p></blockquote><p>A bit later, Barth writes: “It is also clear that in so far as it entails suffering it is not an enviable situation. In this connexion, too, suffering is not joy. Again the beatitude is a synthetic and not an analytic statement.” (CD IV/2, 191).</p>
<p>So, for Barth, the Beatitudes are statements of self-evident truths. Instead, they are statements that are made true by the particular relationships between Jesus and the people in question.</p>
<p>Although Bonhoeffer doesn’t use the “synthetic vs. analytic” language, he seems to be saying much the same thing in <em>Discipleship</em>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Therefore, “Blessed!” Jesus is speaking to the disciples (cf. Luke 6:20ff.). He is speaking to those who are already under the power of his call. That call has made them poor, tempted, and hungry. He calls them blessed, not because of their want or renunciation. Neither want nor renunciation are in themselves any reason to be called blessed. The only adequate reason is the call and the promise, for whose sake those following him live in want and renunciation. The observation that some of the Beatitudes speak of want and others of the disciples’ intentional renunciation or special virtues has no special meaning. Objective want and personal renunciation have their joint basis in Christ’s call and promise. Neither of them has any value or claim in itself. (DBWE 4:101–2).</p></blockquote><p>Two things strike me as interesting about that paragraph. First, note how Bonhoeffer is willing to use Luke’s parallel to make a conclusion about whom Jesus is speaking to in the Beatitudes. I think I disagree with Bonhoeffer here, because, in Matthew, the Sermon on the Mount seems to be addressed to both the disciples and the crowds—the boundaries between the two groups being, in some sense, still up for grabs.</p>
<p>Second, in the penultimate sentence (“The observation that…”), as the editors note, Bonhoeffer is taking issue with Tholuck’s interpretation of the Beatitudes:</p>
<blockquote><p>Tholuck observes: “These eight beatitudes are arranged in an ethical order. The first four are of a negative character.… The three following … set forth what attributes of character are required in the members of that kingdom” (<em>Commentary</em>, 64). (DBWE 4:101n6).</p></blockquote><p>You can hear the “entrance requirements for the kingdom” coming through loud and clear in Tholuck. To me, both Barth and Bonhoeffer push back against the “entrance requirements” view, without thereby committing them to a single interpretive framework at the expense of the others.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 22:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-order-to-help-situate-my-discussion-of-barths-and-bonhoeffers-readings-im-trying-to-get-a-better-grasp-of-the-various-interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount&#34;&gt;In order to help situate my discussion of Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s readings, I’m trying to get a better grasp of the various interpretive approaches to the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, the most exhaustive Sermon on the Mount “interpretive taxonomy” that I’ve found has been from Grant &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/37oTuuA&#34;&gt;Osborne’s &lt;em&gt;Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Zondervan Exegetical Commentary on the New Testament; Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2010), 159.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.</p>
<h2 id="in-order-to-help-situate-my-discussion-of-barths-and-bonhoeffers-readings-im-trying-to-get-a-better-grasp-of-the-various-interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount">In order to help situate my discussion of Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s readings, I’m trying to get a better grasp of the various interpretive approaches to the Sermon on the Mount.</h2>
<p>So far, the most exhaustive Sermon on the Mount “interpretive taxonomy” that I’ve found has been from Grant <a href="https://amzn.to/37oTuuA">Osborne’s <em>Matthew</em></a> (Zondervan Exegetical Commentary on the New Testament; Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2010), 159.</p>
<p>Here are the approaches that Osborne lists, as summarized by Jason C. Kuo in his “Sermon on the Mount/Plain” article in <a href="https://www.logos.com/product/36564/lexham-bible-dictionary"><em>The Lexham Bible Dictionary</em></a> (Bellingham, WA: Lexham Press, 2016).</p>
<ol>
<li>A <strong>medieval</strong> approach—two levels of ethics with a higher set of standards for clergy and monastic members.</li>
<li><strong>Luther’s</strong> approach—the sermon discloses our depravity and brings us to repentance.</li>
<li>An <strong>Anabaptist</strong> approach—the sermon is a call to pacifism.</li>
<li>A <strong>liberal</strong> approach—the sermon is a paradigm for the social gospel.</li>
<li>An <strong>existentialist</strong> approach—the sermon is not absolute, but a challenge to personal decision.</li>
<li><strong>Schweitzer’s</strong> approach—the sermon is an “interim ethic” leading to a temporary set of codes to follow.</li>
<li>The <strong>dispensational</strong> approach—the sermon is limited in scope to the “future millennial kingdom” and applies only to the Jews, not to the church.</li>
<li>The “<strong>inaugurated eschatology</strong>” approach—believers should attempt to follow the commands, but full observance will only happen after Christ returns.</li>
<li>A <strong>wisdom</strong> teaching approach—Jesus was expressing His convictions using wisdom forms.</li>
</ol>
<p>Now, of course, the question is how best to situate Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s approaches!</p>
<h2 id="have-you-come-across-any-other-interpretive-frameworks-for-the-sermon-on-the-mount-that-you-would-add-to-this-paradigm">Have you come across any other interpretive frameworks for the Sermon on the Mount that you would add to this paradigm?</h2>
<p>Kuo notes D.A. Carson’s discussion (which can now be found in his Matthew commentary in <em>The Expositor’s Bible Commentary</em>, revised edition, volume 9, 155–57).</p>
<p>Carson notes:</p>
<blockquote><p>The attempt to understand the Sermon on the Mount within a unified theological grid has not produced consistent results. Schweizer lists seven major interpretive approaches; Harvey K. McArthur (<em>Understanding the Sermon on the Mount</em> [New York: Harper, 1960], 105–48) lists twelve.</p></blockquote><p>Carson then proceeds to list:</p>
<ul>
<li>a. Lutheran orthodoxy (Osborne’s #2)</li>
<li>b. realized eschatology, moral road map (Osborne’s #4?)</li>
<li>c. “a set of moral standards used catechetically within Matthew’s community”</li>
<li>d. Anabaptist-Mennonite: applies to “all believers in every age and every circumstance” (cites Hauerwas’s Matthew commentary). (Osborne’s #3)</li>
<li>e. Existential: personal decision, authentic faith. (Osborne’s #5)</li>
<li>f. “Interim ethic” (Osborne’s #6)</li>
<li>g. Evangelicals and others, “interpret the Sermon on the Mount as an intensifying or radicalizing of the OT moral law” (cites Stott’s <em>Message of the Sermon on the Mount)</em></li>
<li>h. Classic dispensationalism: “law for millennial kingdom first offered by Jesus to the Jews.” Has faced numerous challenges, revised by J. Dwight Pentecost and John Walvoord. (Osborne’s #7?)</li>
</ul>
<p>Note that Carson critiques all of these approaches as he goes along. He then briefly covers “several scholars [who] have narrowed the focus.”</p>
<p>What’s Carson’s view? He maintain’s that “[t]he unifying theme of the sermon is the kingdom of heaven.” The Sermon on the Mount</p>
<blockquote><p>“provides ethical guidelines for life in the kingdom, but does so within an explanation of the place of the contemporary setting within redemption history and Jesus’ relation to the OT (5:17–20). The community forming around him, his ‘disciples,’ is not yet so cohesive and committed a group that exhortations to ‘enter’ (7:13–14) are irrelevant. The glimpse of kingdom life (horizontally and vertically) in these chapters anticipates not only the love commandments (22:34–40) but also grace (5:3; 6:12; 7:7–11; cf. 21:28–46)” (157).</p></blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
