<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Anglican on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/anglican/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anglican on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <image>
      <title>Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <url>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</url>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 09:06:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/anglican/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Stir the Pot?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/dont-stir-the-pot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/dont-stir-the-pot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pondering the &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t stir the pot&amp;rdquo; reaction that reliably happens every time we publish something on women&amp;rsquo;s ordination—most especially anything in &lt;em&gt;favor&lt;/em&gt; of women&amp;rsquo;s ordination—&lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com/&#34;&gt;over at Anglican Compass&lt;/a&gt;, where I&amp;rsquo;m the Managing Editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: This post is not a subtweet of anyone in particular. It&amp;rsquo;s just me thinking out loud about a phenomenon that keeps occurring.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every time we post something about women&amp;rsquo;s ordination, a controversial issue has been whether or not doing so needlessly &amp;ldquo;stirs the pot,&amp;rdquo; as in &amp;ldquo;causes trouble, unrest, dissent.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m pondering the &ldquo;don&rsquo;t stir the pot&rdquo; reaction that reliably happens every time we publish something on women&rsquo;s ordination—most especially anything in <em>favor</em> of women&rsquo;s ordination—<a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">over at Anglican Compass</a>, where I&rsquo;m the Managing Editor.</p>
<p><em>(Note: This post is not a subtweet of anyone in particular. It&rsquo;s just me thinking out loud about a phenomenon that keeps occurring.)</em></p>
<p>Almost every time we post something about women&rsquo;s ordination, a controversial issue has been whether or not doing so needlessly &ldquo;stirs the pot,&rdquo; as in &ldquo;causes trouble, unrest, dissent.&rdquo;</p>
<p>On the one hand, some argue that this issue has already been debated to death. From this perspective, continuing to post about women&rsquo;s ordination simply exacerbates a condition that would be better off left alone—<a href="https://anglicancompass.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/">the “dual integrities” diocesan-level division on women&rsquo;s ordination that currently characterizes the ACNA.</a>. On the other hand, however, others argue that, since this issue is not settled, it&rsquo;s perfectly appropriate to blog about this.</p>
<p>The issue, then, is whether or not women&rsquo;s ordination is worth talking about, at least among Anglicans in public.</p>
<p>My own personal view is that it <em>is</em> worth talking about the Anglican debate over women&rsquo;s ordination in public. Though I concede that needless provocation (“stirring the pot”) is vicious, I still maintain that there is an important difference between <em>causing</em> or <em>exacerbating</em> a division and <em>describing</em> one.</p>
<p>For example, it would be vicious to take pot shots across the divide and try to get everyone to think either that (1) all egalitarians/mutualists completely ignore Scripture and tradition and choose to follow cultural trends instead, or that (2) all complementarians/hierarchicalists/patriarchalists hate women and want to keep them out of positions of power and influence. This would be <em>stirring the pot</em> and exacerbating our divisions.</p>
<p>However, I think it is an importantly different endeavor to try to help people on both sides of the debate see where the others stand. To remind the egalitarians that it&rsquo;s unfair to say that all complementarians hate women. To remind the complementarians that it&rsquo;s unfair to say that all egalitarians prioritize cultural trends over Scripture and tradition.</p>
<p>Some might object that giving both sides of the debate airtime means that we&rsquo;ve abandoned the truth in one direction or the other. But given that this is an important and ongoing division within the ACNA, between conservative and orthodox Christians, this seems like necessary work. It strikes me as unduly tribalistic to either pretend like the other side doesn&rsquo;t exist, or to condemn anyone who would listen to arguments from the other side as a dangerous traitor.</p>
<p>Furthermore, some might object that this work has already been done. By and large, I would agree. But just because almost every facet of the debate has already been covered in various settings—books, articles, etc.—doesn&rsquo;t mean that we don&rsquo;t have room to grow in understanding of our differences. There may be nothing new under the sun, and yet we still keep writing and talking about other things. Why not women&rsquo;s ordination as well?</p>
<p>On the issue of women&rsquo;s ordination, we obviously disagree with one another—both within the ACNA and within the Anglican Communion. And yet I&rsquo;m not quite sure that we fully understand one another. From my limited perspective, it&rsquo;s worth &ldquo;stirring the pot&rdquo; until we at least reach full, respectful understanding—even if we never reach full agreement on this side of eternity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;They laughed when I became an Anglican, but when I started to pray!&#34; 27 Anglican Headline Ideas</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading my way through &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2KdNASw&#34;&gt;the new (4th) edition of Robert Bly’s classic &lt;em&gt;The Copywriter’s Handbook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. On pages 33–36, Bly offers “38 Model Headlines for Your ‘Swipe File.&amp;rsquo;” Here are some headlines ideas that came to mind, all geared to an Anglican context (&lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicanpastor.com/&#34;&gt;due to my work at AnglicanCompass.com&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are Anglicans so angry?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I use the Book of Common Prayer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I become an Anglican?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do Anglicans believe?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why “Clarity &amp;amp; Charity” is the best way forward for the Church in a pluralistic age&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Announcing an ancient way to reclaim your days and years for God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t become an Anglican!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now do the Daily Office with just this booklet and a Bible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 5 Anglican books you should own NOW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the BCP—Once difficult, now easy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A feast for the senses: The richness of Anglican worship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I was about to give up on the Church when I was introduced to the Anglican tradition”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FREE booklet helps you pray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to avoid the biggest mistakes you can make when visiting an Anglican church&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The WORST Article in the Thirty-Nine Articles. Hint: It’s NOT what you think!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anglican clergy’s best-kept secret&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re looking for people who want to leave Anglicanism better than they found it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s never too late to start doing the Daily Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sick of iChurch and McChurch? Give Anglicanism a try&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will your church pass the Word &amp;amp; Sacrament test?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 reasons why you should NOT become an Anglican Christian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why most people leave the Church—and what you can do about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crazy as it sounds, the Daily Office could save your marriage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 reasons why written prayers are better than extemporaneous prayers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 questions to ask when you visit an Anglican church&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you can create a personalized discipleship plan—for FREE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where’s #27? Read the title for this piece.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m reading my way through <a href="https://amzn.to/2KdNASw">the new (4th) edition of Robert Bly’s classic <em>The Copywriter’s Handbook</em></a>. On pages 33–36, Bly offers “38 Model Headlines for Your ‘Swipe File.&rsquo;” Here are some headlines ideas that came to mind, all geared to an Anglican context (<a href="https://anglicanpastor.com/">due to my work at AnglicanCompass.com</a>).</p>
<ol>
<li>Why are Anglicans so angry?</li>
<li>How do I use the Book of Common Prayer?</li>
<li>How can I become an Anglican?</li>
<li>What do Anglicans believe?</li>
<li>Why “Clarity &amp; Charity” is the best way forward for the Church in a pluralistic age</li>
<li>Announcing an ancient way to reclaim your days and years for God</li>
<li>Don’t become an Anglican!</li>
<li>You can now do the Daily Office with just this booklet and a Bible</li>
<li>The 5 Anglican books you should own NOW</li>
<li>Using the BCP—Once difficult, now easy</li>
<li>A feast for the senses: The richness of Anglican worship</li>
<li>“I was about to give up on the Church when I was introduced to the Anglican tradition”</li>
<li>FREE booklet helps you pray</li>
<li>How to avoid the biggest mistakes you can make when visiting an Anglican church</li>
<li>The WORST Article in the Thirty-Nine Articles. Hint: It’s NOT what you think!</li>
<li>Anglican clergy’s best-kept secret</li>
<li>We’re looking for people who want to leave Anglicanism better than they found it</li>
<li>It’s never too late to start doing the Daily Office</li>
<li>Sick of iChurch and McChurch? Give Anglicanism a try</li>
<li>Will your church pass the Word &amp; Sacrament test?</li>
<li>3 reasons why you should NOT become an Anglican Christian</li>
<li>Why most people leave the Church—and what you can do about it</li>
<li>Crazy as it sounds, the Daily Office could save your marriage</li>
<li>5 reasons why written prayers are better than extemporaneous prayers</li>
<li>7 questions to ask when you visit an Anglican church</li>
<li>Now you can create a personalized discipleship plan—for FREE</li>
</ol>
<p>Where’s #27? Read the title for this piece.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “Via Media”? Or the “Middle Ground Fallacy”?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-via-media-or-the-middle-ground-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-via-media-or-the-middle-ground-fallacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At this point, this is just a sketch. But I’m wondering how we Anglican Christians ought to be careful to keep our precious “via media” (“middle way”) mentality and methodology separate from what’s known as the “middle ground” fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-via-media&#34;&gt;The “Via Media”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Donald McKim in the &lt;em&gt;Westminster Dictionary of Theological Terms&lt;/em&gt;, the “via media” is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Lat. “the middle way”) Term used to describe the identity of Anglicanism as a middle way between Roman Catholicism and Protestantism. It was coined by John Henry Newman (1801–90) during the Oxford movement (337).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At this point, this is just a sketch. But I’m wondering how we Anglican Christians ought to be careful to keep our precious “via media” (“middle way”) mentality and methodology separate from what’s known as the “middle ground” fallacy.</p>
<h2 id="the-via-media">The “Via Media”</h2>
<p>According to Donald McKim in the <em>Westminster Dictionary of Theological Terms</em>, the “via media” is</p>
<blockquote><p>(Lat. “the middle way”) Term used to describe the identity of Anglicanism as a middle way between Roman Catholicism and Protestantism. It was coined by John Henry Newman (1801–90) during the Oxford movement (337).</p></blockquote><p>The glossary in the back of <em>The Study of Anglicanism</em> gives a bit longer definition:</p>
<blockquote><p>Via Media: ‘the middle way’, a designation for the stance of Anglicanism between Roman Catholicism and one form or another of Protestantism. The significance of the term is ambiguous, since on occasions extreme or radical Protestantism (Anabaptism) is taken as one pole, in which case Anglicanism shares the ‘middle way’ with e.g. Lutheranism; on other occasions the designation is intended to contrast Anglicanism with more central forms of Protestantism, e.g. Puritanism (qv), Presbyterianism, and what J. H. Newman called ‘popular Protestantism’ (506).</p></blockquote><p>Now, as Paul Avis notes in his  <em>In Search of Authority: Anglican Theological Method from the Reformation to the Enlightenment</em>,</p>
<blockquote><p>There was no settled ‘Anglican’ platform in this period, let alone a generally recognized concept of a via media between Rome and the Reformation: the Church of England saw itself as within the family of Protestant Churches, but also as the exemplar among them of apostolic, primitive Christianity, liturgical and episcopal (133).</p></blockquote><p>Nevertheless, despite the historical debates about the “via media,” it has emerged, I think, as a hallmark of the Anglican way of doing theology. Indeed, it’s one of my favorite things about being an Anglican!</p>
<p>And yet, how do we keep this “via media” separate from what’s known as the “Middle Ground” fallacy?</p>
<h2 id="the-middle-ground-fallacy">The “Middle Ground” Fallacy</h2>
<p>According to the fantastic website, <a href="https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/middle-ground">YourLogicalFallacyIs.com</a>, the “Middle Ground” fallacy is:</p>
<blockquote><p>You claimed that a compromise, or middle point, between two extremes must be the truth.</p></blockquote><p>They elaborate:</p>
<blockquote><p>Much of the time the truth does indeed lie between two extreme points, but this can bias our thinking: sometimes a thing is simply untrue and a compromise of it is also untrue. Half way between truth and a lie, is still a lie.</p></blockquote><p>And here’s an example:</p>
<blockquote><p>Holly said that vaccinations caused autism in children, but her scientifically well-read friend Caleb said that this claim had been debunked and proven false. Their friend Alice offered a compromise that vaccinations must cause some autism, just not all autism.</p></blockquote><p>If you’d like to learn more about this fallacy, check out <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argument_to_moderation">the Wikipedia page for the “Argument to moderation” (<em>argumentum ad temperantiam</em>)</a>, which is also known as:</p>
<ul>
<li>false equivalence,</li>
<li>false compromise,</li>
<li>(argument from) middle ground,</li>
<li>fallacy of gray,</li>
<li>equidistance fallacy, and</li>
<li>the golden mean fallacy.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="as-i-said-this-is-just-a-sketch-an-open-question">As I said, this is just a sketch, an open question.</h2>
<p>So, I welcome your feedback in the comments below.</p>
<p>Can we carve out a middle way between the via media and the middle ground fallacy?</p>
<p>What if there aren’t always “very fine people on both sides”?</p>
<p>What if the truth isn’t always somewhere in the murky middle ground between two opposing positions?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Ordination Debates in Anglicanism: The 2017 ACNA Report and the 2003 AMIA Report</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/womens-ordination-debates-in-anglicanism-the-2017-acna-report-and-the-2003-amia-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/womens-ordination-debates-in-anglicanism-the-2017-acna-report-and-the-2003-amia-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I became an “egalitarian” in college, before I became an Anglican in seminary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s taken some time for me to get used to the different contours of the women’s ordination debate within Anglicanism. Growing up, the debate was all about particular Bible verses and whether or not women could teach and preach. However, in Anglicanism, although those same questions/arguments are present, I hear much more about whether or not women can administer the sacraments as priests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I became an “egalitarian” in college, before I became an Anglican in seminary.</p>
<p>It’s taken some time for me to get used to the different contours of the women’s ordination debate within Anglicanism. Growing up, the debate was all about particular Bible verses and whether or not women could teach and preach. However, in Anglicanism, although those same questions/arguments are present, I hear much more about whether or not women can administer the sacraments as priests.</p>
<p>Over at Anglican Pastor, where I’m the Managing Editor, we recently published a three-part interview with Rev. Tish Harrison Warren, who is a priest in the Anglican Church in North America [ACNA].</p>
<p>In <a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/ask-an-anglican-pastor-an-interview-with-tish-harrison-warren-pt-2/">part 2 of the interview</a>, Tish answers some questions about women’s ordination.</p>
<p>This prompted some negative reactions from some of our readers, and it’s caused me to revisit <a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/">the 2017 ACNA Holy Orders Task Force Report</a> as a starting point for coming to grips with the specifically <em>Anglican</em> debates about women’s ordination.</p>
<p>I still think that <a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce.pdf">the ACNA Report</a> is a fine starting point for this purpose. However, I’m disappointed that, in the “Evangelical” portion of Section 4: Arguments For and Against, the ACNA Report relies heavily upon <a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/AMIA_2003_Womens-Ordination-Report.pdf">this 2003 Anglican Mission in America [AMIA] Report</a>—so much so, in fact, that the ACNA Report simply quotes at length from the AMIA Report when it comes to the exegesis of specific biblical texts.</p>
<p>(See pages 269–74 of the ACNA Report and pages 37–105 of the AMIA Report to see what I mean.)</p>
<p>Nothing against the careful work shown in the 2003 AMIA Report, but it’s odd to me that the ACNA Report relies so heavily on a document that it categorizes underneath the “Books not in favor of women’s ordination” section in its Bibliography for Further Study. (See pages 303–305 of the ACNA Report.)</p>
<p>Perhaps the ACNA Report’s conclusion that “The result is a ‘text jam.&rsquo;” is perfectly justified, but I would have liked to see a little bit more direct exegetical work in this section of the ACNA document!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Attracts People to Anglicanism? Here&#39;s My Take</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 21:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based upon my work over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/&#34;&gt;Rookie Anglican&lt;/a&gt;, I was asked by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teloscollective.com/&#34;&gt;The Telos Collective&lt;/a&gt; to write a blog post about the different ways that people are coming into Anglicanism. What’s drawing them in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teloscollective.com/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-subversive-cultural-resonance/&#34;&gt;read my full post over at the Telos Collective blog&lt;/a&gt;, but here’s a taste:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anglican Christianity, precisely because of its weirdness, can remind us that, in the words of Brad Harper and Paul Louis Metzger in Exploring Ecclesiology, “The church is a cultural community. It is Christ’s eschatological kingdom community, itself a culture that engages other cultures from Christ’s kingdom vantage point” (p. 207).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Based upon my work over at <a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/">Rookie Anglican</a>, I was asked by <a href="https://www.teloscollective.com/">The Telos Collective</a> to write a blog post about the different ways that people are coming into Anglicanism. What’s drawing them in?</p>
<p>You can <a href="https://www.teloscollective.com/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-subversive-cultural-resonance/">read my full post over at the Telos Collective blog</a>, but here’s a taste:</p>
<blockquote><p>Anglican Christianity, precisely because of its weirdness, can remind us that, in the words of Brad Harper and Paul Louis Metzger in Exploring Ecclesiology, “The church is a cultural community. It is Christ’s eschatological kingdom community, itself a culture that engages other cultures from Christ’s kingdom vantage point” (p. 207).</p>
<p>No “culture of this world” can be equated with the culture of Jesus Christ. This is, I suggest, the important sense in which Christians (and not just Anglican ones) should not be “seeker-sensitive.”</p>
<p>And yet, on the other hand, the very mission of the church seems to demand that Christians be “seeker-sensitive” in the best sense of the phrase. This is because the gospel, though it does contain a powerful critique of a world alienated from God, is only “good news” to the extent that it resonates with (and does not merely refute) the cultures in which it is proclaimed.</p>
<p>So, perhaps we Anglicans need to do a better job of being “seeker-sensitive”—in the sense of resonating with the culture(s).</p>
<p>“Resonating” with the culture, however, does not necessarily mean “approving.” Instead, the church’s resonance with the cultures around it will frequently be “subversive” (again, see Scot McKnight’s previous piece).</p>
<p>Toward that end, I’d like to consider some ways in which I’ve noticed the Anglican tradition subversively resonating with the culture(s) around it—especially those in the United States of America in recent years.</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://www.teloscollective.com/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-subversive-cultural-resonance/">Continue reading over at the Telos Collective blog</a>.</p>
<p>Then, let me know whether you think I got it right or not! What’s attracting people to Anglicanism?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Reasons Why I&#39;m an Anglican Christian</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 05:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/RA-Logo-Black-Transparent-Background-200x167.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I an Anglican Christian? Here are 3 reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-anglicanism-as-a-refuge-from-fundamentalism&#34;&gt;1. Anglicanism as a Refuge from Fundamentalism&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, for me, Anglicanism has been a refuge from fundamentalism. Now, to be sure, we do have our own fundamentalists within the Anglican Communion! But, compared to some “ingrown enclaves” I’ve experienced in my Christian upbringing, Anglicanism has been a breath of fresh air. It has been an ecclesiological space for healing as I seek to “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patheos.com/blogs/rogereolson/2012/08/on-not-throwing-the-baby-out-with-the-bathwater-a-message-for-abused-ex-fundamentalists/&#34;&gt;not throw the (gospel) baby out with the (fundamentalist) bathwater&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/"><img loading="lazy" src="http://anglicanpastor.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/RA-Logo-Black-Transparent-Background-200x167.png"></a></p>
<p>Why am I an Anglican Christian? Here are 3 reasons.</p>
<h1 id="1-anglicanism-as-a-refuge-from-fundamentalism">1. Anglicanism as a Refuge from Fundamentalism</h1>
<p>First, for me, Anglicanism has been a refuge from fundamentalism. Now, to be sure, we do have our own fundamentalists within the Anglican Communion! But, compared to some “ingrown enclaves” I’ve experienced in my Christian upbringing, Anglicanism has been a breath of fresh air. It has been an ecclesiological space for healing as I seek to “<a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/rogereolson/2012/08/on-not-throwing-the-baby-out-with-the-bathwater-a-message-for-abused-ex-fundamentalists/">not throw the (gospel) baby out with the (fundamentalist) bathwater</a>.”</p>
<p>Why/How?</p>
<h1 id="2-anglicanism-has-theological-breadth">2. Anglicanism has Theological Breadth…</h1>
<p>This goes hand-in-hand with my previous reason. Anglicanism has been a refuge from fundamentalism thanks in no small part to its “theological wiggle room.” The greatest strength of Anglicanism – and also the source of much of its angst – is its theological breadth. As a Ph.D. student in theology, I appreciate the fact that it doesn’t feel like I’m walking along the edge of a knife, to the right or left of which my positions would quickly become <em>verboten</em> by the Anglican powers that be.</p>
<p>Instead, it feels like I’m operating on a field of acceptable Anglican theological convictions/positions.</p>
<h1 id="3-within-a-tradition">3. …Within a Tradition</h1>
<p>However, that “field” does have boundaries, for which I am grateful!</p>
<p>And, for Anglicanism at its best, those boundaries largely coincide with the overarching tradition of the Christian Church as she has been sustained and guided by the Holy Spirit throughout the centuries.</p>
<p>So, on the one hand, I’m grateful for some theological wiggle room, as it were. On the other hand, I’m grateful that it’s not “just me and my Bible” as if I had to try to figure everything out anew!</p>
<p>The same Spirit, whom I trust to illuminate my mind and heart as I read Scripture, has provided the Church with teachers and leaders throughout the ages. This doesn’t mean that the “tradition” should be adopted wholesale, unthinkingly, and uncritically – far from it! But, the traditions of the Church ought to be received humbly and prayerfully.</p>
<p>So, to sum up: <strong>I’m an Anglican Christian because, with its theological breadth within the overarching Christian tradition, Anglicanism has provided a salutary refuge for me from fundamentalism.</strong></p>
<h1 id="why-are-you-an-anglican-christian">Why Are You an Anglican Christian?</h1>
<p>I could mention other reasons why I’m an Anglican Christian – such as the emphasis on the habitual rhythms of the Christian life (e.g., the <a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/dailyofficebooklet/">Daily Office</a>, the liturgical <a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/what-time-is-it-an-overview-of-the-church-calendar-and-liturgical-year/">calendar</a>, etc.). However, I’m going to stick with these 3, because I want to hear your story!</p>
<p>If you’re an Anglican Christian – why?</p>
<hr>
<p><a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/top-3-reasons-why-im-an-anglican-christian/">This post originally appeared on Rookie Anglican</a>, the blog I created to help make Anglican Christianity accessible to Anglicans and the Anglicurious.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
