<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Immigration on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/immigration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Immigration on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 09:20:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/immigration/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When the Government Can Kidnap Without Trial, None of Us Are Safe</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/government-kidnap-without-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/government-kidnap-without-trial/</guid>
      <description>If the government can take people without due process, none of our rights are safe. Why habeas corpus and due process matter for all of us.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine waking up to find out that your neighbor—a legal immigrant who works hard, pays taxes, and has never been charged with a crime—was taken away in the middle of the night by government agents. No warrant. No lawyer. No hearing. No chance to defend themselves. Just gone.</p>
<p>Then imagine the government claims they’re a danger—but refuses to show any real evidence. And instead of bringing them to a courtroom, they ship them off to a prison in another country.</p>
<p>That’s not a dystopian movie plot. It’s happening <em>right now</em>. And it should terrify every single one of us.</p>
<p>Because when the government can <strong>kidnap without trial</strong>, and lock people up without letting them <strong>have their day in court</strong>, then <em>none</em> of our rights are safe.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-is-due-process">What Is Due Process?</h2>
<p><strong>Due process</strong> is the basic idea that the government can’t take away your life, your freedom, or your property without following fair procedures. It’s what protects the principle that you are <strong>innocent until proven guilty</strong>.</p>
<p>At a minimum, it means:</p>
<ul>
<li>You get to know what you’re being accused of.</li>
<li>You get a chance to respond.</li>
<li>You have access to a lawyer.</li>
<li>A neutral judge hears the case.</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s your <strong>right to a fair trial</strong>. Without it, everything else collapses.</p>
<p>The Fifth and Fourteenth Amendments to the U.S. Constitution guarantee due process:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/constitution/amendment-5/">Fifth Amendment</a></strong>: “No person shall… be deprived of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law.”</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/constitution/amendment-14/">Fourteenth Amendment</a></strong>: “nor shall any State deprive any person of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law; nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Notice the language: <em>“No person.”</em> Not “no citizen.” Not “no American.” Just <strong>person</strong>. That includes immigrants—documented or undocumented. It includes you. It includes me.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-is-habeas-corpus">What Is Habeas Corpus?</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Habeas_corpus">Habeas corpus</a></strong> is the right that lets you <strong>demand your day in court</strong> when the government locks you up. It forces the government to explain why you’re being held—and gives you a chance to challenge it.</p>
<p>It’s your protection against being “disappeared” into a jail cell with no explanation, no trial, no accountability.</p>
<p>The Constitution is clear about it:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/constitution/article-1/#article-1-section-9-clause-2">Article I, Section 9, Clause 2</a></strong>: “The Privilege of the Writ of Habeas Corpus shall not be suspended, unless when in Cases of Rebellion or Invasion the public Safety may require it.”</p></blockquote>
<p>There’s no rebellion. And no actual invasion. So why is the government throwing people in foreign prisons without giving them access to a courtroom?</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="about-that-invasion-excuse">About That “Invasion” Excuse</h2>
<p>Lately, politicians and government officials have started calling immigration an <strong>“invasion”</strong> to justify rounding people up without trials. But this isn’t about armies or enemy combatants—it’s about families, workers, and asylum seekers.</p>
<p>And there’s no real evidence backing up the claim.</p>
<ul>
<li>No court has declared an invasion.</li>
<li>No credible threat to public safety has been proven.</li>
<li>Many of the people being detained are <strong>legal residents</strong> with no criminal history.</li>
</ul>
<p>This is not about protecting national security. It’s about using fear, racism, and political theater to bypass the rule of law.</p>
<p>Calling it an “invasion” doesn’t make it one. But it <em>does</em> give the government an excuse to test how far they can go without resistance.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-this-should-scare-you">Why This Should Scare You</h2>
<p>You might think: <em>Well, I’m not an immigrant. I’ve done nothing wrong. This doesn’t affect me.</em></p>
<p>But here’s the truth: <strong>if the government can take away someone else’s rights without due process, they can take away yours too.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>If they can imprison someone without trial, they can imprison you.</li>
<li>If they can call someone a criminal without proving it, they can do the same to you.</li>
<li>If they can send someone to a foreign prison without a hearing, they can send you there too.</li>
</ul>
<p>This isn’t just about “those people.” It’s about <strong>whether we still believe no one is above the law.</strong></p>
<p>Without due process and habeas corpus, every other right—freedom of speech, freedom of religion, the right to vote, the right to privacy—becomes meaningless. There’s no judge to intervene. No courtroom to make your case. No way to push back.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="this-is-a-line-in-the-sand">This Is a Line in the Sand</h2>
<p>This isn’t about left or right. It’s about whether we still believe in <strong>justice</strong>, <strong>accountability</strong>, and <strong>the rule of law</strong>.</p>
<p>If the government can toss the Constitution aside when it’s politically convenient—if it can skip trials, ignore evidence, and detain people in secret—then we are all just <em>one accusation away</em> from losing our freedom.</p>
<p>A government that can <strong>kidnap without trial</strong> is not protecting you. It is testing the limits of its power.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-you-can-do">What You Can Do</h2>
<p>You don’t need to be a lawyer or an activist to stand up for justice. Here are real steps you can take:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Talk about it</strong>. Share this post with your friends, your family, your community. Most people don’t know this is happening.</li>
<li><strong>Call your representatives</strong>. Use <a href="https://5calls.org/">5calls</a> to find your representatives and ask them: What are you doing to protect due process and the rule of law—for everyone?</li>
<li><strong>Demand transparency</strong>. Pressure lawmakers to investigate the use of offshore prisons, secret detentions, and any denial of basic legal rights.</li>
<li><strong>Support civil rights organizations</strong>. Groups like <a href="https://www.aclu.org/">the ACLU</a>, <a href="https://www.humanrightsfirst.org/">Human Rights First</a>, and <a href="https://www.immigrantjustice.org/">the National Immigrant Justice Center</a> are fighting back in court.</li>
<li><strong>Vote accordingly</strong>. Don’t support politicians who stoke fear and ignore the Constitution. Know where your candidates stand.</li>
<li><strong>Stay informed</strong>. Read trustworthy reporting. Don’t let fear-based headlines erase the humanity and rights of others.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><strong>Speak up. Stay loud. Stay human.</strong></p>
<p>Because if we lose due process and habeas corpus, we lose the entire rule of law.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#39;t Follow Jesus and Hate Immigrants</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/you-cant-follow-jesus-and-hate-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 16:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/you-cant-follow-jesus-and-hate-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can’t follow Jesus and hate immigrants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this does NOT settle every question of immigration policy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, if you’re a follower of Jesus, consider your overall posture toward immigrants. If you call yourself a Christian, I want you to think about this seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What comes into your head and your heart when you think of immigrants and refugees? Fear? Anger? Disgust?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if the immigrants are in your country legally? What if they’re your brothers and sisters in Christ? Does that make any difference in what you think and feel about them? Or are they still primarily “illegals” who are “ruining this country”?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You can’t follow Jesus and hate immigrants.</p>
<p>Of course, this does NOT settle every question of immigration policy!</p>
<p>But, if you’re a follower of Jesus, consider your overall posture toward immigrants. If you call yourself a Christian, I want you to think about this seriously.</p>
<p>What comes into your head and your heart when you think of immigrants and refugees? Fear? Anger? Disgust?</p>
<p>What if the immigrants are in your country legally? What if they’re your brothers and sisters in Christ? Does that make any difference in what you think and feel about them? Or are they still primarily “illegals” who are “ruining this country”?</p>
<p>If you think that a given immigration policy or system is a mess and that X, Y, or Z should be done about it, what are your motivations? Are you concerned about the welfare of the immigrants themselves, many of whom are quite poor and powerless? Or are you acting out of fear and self-interest?</p>
<p>Some may object, saying that while Christians are called to love immigrants, we still need to protect our borders and uphold laws. And it’s true that immigration policy is complex, and nations have a responsibility to maintain order and security.</p>
<p>However, the question here isn’t about the specifics of policy but about the posture of our hearts. As followers of Jesus, our first responsibility is to love others—including immigrants—as those made in God’s image. Upholding laws and protecting our country should never justify fear, hatred, or dehumanization.</p>
<p>Others may argue that showing hospitality to immigrants and refugees could lead to an unsustainable burden on our resources or change our cultural identity. While practical concerns about resources are valid, Scripture repeatedly calls us to care for the vulnerable, trusting that God will provide.</p>
<p>Moreover, the kingdom of God is not confined by national or cultural boundaries! As citizens of this kingdom, our identity should first and foremost be shaped by our faith, not by our nationality.</p>
<p>The Bible actually has quite a bit to say about immigrants, sojourners, and refugees. In fact, you can even read the entire storyline of Scripture through these lenses. Here’s the tiniest of tastes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When a foreigner resides among you in your land, do not mistreat them. The foreigner residing among you must be treated as your native-born. Love them as yourself, for you were foreigners in Egypt. I am the LORD your God.<br>
(Leviticus 19:33–34, NIV)</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Cursed is anyone who withholds justice from the foreigner, the fatherless or the widow.<br>
(Deuteronomy 27:19, NIV)</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I was a stranger and you invited me in…<br>
(Matthew 25:35, NIV)</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>For here we do not have an enduring city, but we are looking for the city that is to come.<br>
(Hebrews 13:14, NIV)</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Do not forget to show hospitality to strangers, for by so doing some people have shown hospitality to angels without knowing it.<br>
(Hebrews 13:2, NIV)</p></blockquote>
<p>As M. Daniel Carroll Rodas explains in <a href="/files/Carroll_Immigration_DictionaryOfScriptureAndEthics.pdf">a helpful article on “Aliens, Immigration, and Refugees”</a> (click that link for a PDF of the article):</p>
<ul>
<li>Both the Old and New Testaments offer rich teachings on migration, emphasizing that refugees and immigrants are made in the image of God.</li>
<li>Many biblical figures, like Abraham, Moses, and Jesus himself, were displaced persons.</li>
<li>Old Testament laws protected the vulnerable, including immigrants.</li>
<li>Jesus’s teachings further challenge believers to see the outsider as someone who can lead them to a deeper faith.</li>
<li>The New Testament epistles also call the church to care for those on the margins, reminding Christians that they, too, are “strangers” in the world.</li>
<li>Biblical teachings on migration should shape how Christians act toward immigrants today, promoting “human flourishing and the common good” through both personal behavior and societal involvement</li>
</ul>
<p>(Source: M. Daniel Carroll R., “Aliens, Immigration, and Refugees,” <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=Dictionary+of+Scripture+and+Ethics&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=fe86bbace8a5c59f7354c6bde6fc84eb&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Dictionary of Scripture and Ethics</a></em>, Grand Rapids, MI: Baker Academic, 2011, 58).</p>
<p>You can’t follow Jesus and hate immigrants.</p>
<p>Next time you’re reading the Bible, keep an eye out for terms like “alien,” “stranger,” “resident alien,” “foreigner,” and “sojourner.”</p>
<p>The next time you think or speak about immigrants, ask yourself: Do your words reflect the heart of Jesus or the harsh rhetoric of political discourse?</p>
<p>Consider how the kingdom of God cuts right across ethnic and national boundaries, reshaping our loyalties to all nations, tribes, etc.</p>
<p>As followers of Jesus, we are called to reflect His love and compassion in every area of our lives, including how we treat immigrants and refugees.</p>
<p>Take time to examine your heart and attitudes, and ask how you can embody Christ’s radical hospitality.</p>
<p>Engage with Scripture, seek out opportunities to welcome the stranger, and challenge rhetoric that dehumanizes or divides.</p>
<p>Let’s commit to being voices of love, grace, and justice in a world that so desperately needs them.</p>
<h2 id="resources-on-scripture-and-immigration">Resources on Scripture and Immigration</h2>
<p>The following bibliography is from M. Daniel Carroll R., “Aliens, Immigration, and Refugees,” <em>Dictionary of Scripture and Ethics</em> (Grand Rapids, MI: Baker Academic, 2011), 58. (Again, <a href="/files/Carroll_Immigration_DictionaryOfScriptureAndEthics.pdf">the PDF is here</a>)</p>
<ul>
<li>Brettell, C., and J. Hollifield. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=Migration+Theory%3A+Talking+across+Disciplines&amp;crid=2X0CWCPHERXT6&amp;sprefix=migration+theory+talking+across+disciplines%2Caps%2C198&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=d9b25e15f9aab25b87dcddac62ca0c13&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Migration Theory: Talking across Disciplines</a></em>. 2nd ed. Routledge, 2008.</li>
<li>Carroll R., M. D. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=Christians+at+the+Border%3A+Immigration%2C+the+Church%2C+and+the+Bible&amp;crid=32MV5KEGRWYR2&amp;sprefix=christians+at+the+border+immigration%2C+the+church%2C+and+the+bible%2Caps%2C124&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=a8ce589e7b8f5e2125749678778e8cde&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Christians at the Border: Immigration, the Church, and the Bible</a></em>. Baker Academic, 2008.</li>
<li>Groody, D., ed. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=A+Promised+Land%2C+a+Perilous+Journey%3A+Theological+Perspectives+on+Migration&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=8c9b33c40387d2d71b96e96a65713f08&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">A Promised Land, a Perilous Journey: Theological Perspectives on Migration</a></em>. University of Notre Dame Press, 2008.</li>
<li>Hanciles, J. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=Beyond+Christendom%3A+Globalization%2C+African+Migration+and+the+Transformation+of+the+West&amp;crid=38OIWY4STEBQ6&amp;sprefix=beyond+christendom+globalization%2C+african+migration+and+the+transformation+of+the+west%2Caps%2C673&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=178a4a4633ddd5301321234bf602c21c&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Beyond Christendom: Globalization, African Migration and the Transformation of the West</a></em>. Orbis, 2008.</li>
<li>Hoffmeier, J. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=The+Immigration+Crisis%3A+Immigrants%2C+Aliens%2C+and+the+Bible&amp;crid=13TZXIB2DU4RA&amp;sprefix=the+immigration+crisis+immigrants%2C+aliens%2C+and+the+bible%2Caps%2C120&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=3e0b0dbfe1d2dbd481e0567c7d25fc0b&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">The Immigration Crisis: Immigrants, Aliens, and the Bible</a></em>. Crossway, 2009.</li>
<li>Miller, P. “Israel as Host to Strangers.” In <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=Israelite+Religion+and+Biblical+Theology%3A+Collected+Essays&amp;crid=145DSSZTE5ND6&amp;sprefix=israelite+religion+and+biblical+theology+collected+essays%2Caps%2C190&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=6d6f1d1724384c9477dd5574fa34b2a9&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Israelite Religion and Biblical Theology: Collected Essays</a></em>, 548–71. JSOTSup 267. Sheffield Academic Press, 2000.</li>
<li>O’Neil, W., and W. Spohn. “Rights of Passage: The Ethics of Immigration and Refugee Policy.” <em>TS</em> 59 (1998): 84–106. <a href="https://theologicalstudies.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/59.1.5.pdf">(PDF here)</a></li>
<li>Pohl, C. “<a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0953946806062287">Responding to Strangers: Insights from the Christian Tradition</a>.” <em>SCE</em> 19 (2006): 81–101.</li>
<li>Pontifical Council for the Pastoral Care of Migrants and Itinerant People. <em>The Love of Christ towards Migrants: Instruction</em>. Catholic Truth Society, 2004. <a href="https://www.vatican.va/roman_curia/pontifical_councils/migrants/documents/rc_pc_migrants_doc_20040514_erga-migrantes-caritas-christi_en.html">(Available online here)</a></li>
<li>Ramírez Kidd, J. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alterity-Identity-Israel-Alttestamentliche-Wissenschaft/dp/3110166259?&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=bbe64a940be396a893d5b8d03fe9fc69&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Alterity and Identity in Israel: The “Ger” in the Old Testament</a></em>. BZAW 283. De Gruyter, 1999.</li>
<li>Rivera, L. “Toward a Diaspora Hermeneutics (Hispanic North America).” In <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=Character+Ethics+and+the+Old+Testament%3A+Moral+Dimensions+of+Scripture&amp;i=stripbooks&amp;crid=34829867BOH7H&amp;sprefix=character+ethics+and+the+old+testament+moral+dimensions+of+scripture%2Cstripbooks%2C164&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=b3b0e3fd17b6cf98ae2c7b668f1aaf93&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Character Ethics and the Old Testament: Moral Dimensions of Scripture</a></em>, edited by M. D. Carroll R. and J. Lapsley, 169–89. Westminster John Knox, 2007.</li>
<li>Smith-Christopher, D. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=A+Biblical+Theology+of+Exile&amp;i=stripbooks&amp;crid=3I3GTYYYNMGKG&amp;sprefix=a+biblical+theology+of+exile%2Cstripbooks%2C129&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=29c3b70bc2d70885233a11b32565b929&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">A Biblical Theology of Exile</a></em>. OBT. Fortress, 2002.</li>
<li>Soerens, M., and J. Hwang. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=Welcoming+the+Stranger%3A+Justice%2C+Compassion%2C+and+Truth+in+the+Immigration+Debate&amp;i=stripbooks&amp;crid=1WRXSCMO496VJ&amp;sprefix=welcoming+the+stranger+justice%2C+compassion%2C+and+truth+in+the+immigration+debate%2Cstripbooks%2C189&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=087500d1ab68a09c911379f9f43c620d&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Welcoming the Stranger: Justice, Compassion, and Truth in the Immigration Debate</a></em>. InterVarsity, 2009.</li>
<li>Waters, M., and R. Ueda, eds. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=The+New+Americans%3A+A+Guide+to+Immigration+since+1965&amp;i=stripbooks&amp;crid=2N3PT4EQRVX3L&amp;sprefix=the+new+americans+a+guide+to+immigration+since+1965%2Cstripbooks%2C168&amp;linkCode=ll2&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=da3fcf14437d7adf247477a032177eab&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">The New Americans: A Guide to Immigration since 1965</a></em>. Harvard University Press, 2007.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
