<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fascism on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/fascism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fascism on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <image>
      <title>Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <url>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</url>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:53:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/fascism/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>14 Characteristics of Fascism: Umberto Eco on Ur-Fascism</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/14-characteristics-of-fascism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 11:49:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/14-characteristics-of-fascism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s try to define (or at least describe) fascism, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fascism: &amp;ldquo;a populist political philosophy, movement, or regime (such as that of the Fascisti) that exalts nation and often race above the individual, that is associated with a centralized autocratic government headed by a dictatorial leader, and that is characterized by severe economic and social regimentation and by forcible suppression of opposition&amp;rdquo; (Merriam-Webster)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notoriously difficult to define, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nybooks.com/articles/1995/06/22/ur-fascism/&#34;&gt;Umberto Eco nevertheless highlighted 14 aspects of what he called &amp;ldquo;Ur-Fascism&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s try to define (or at least describe) fascism, shall we?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Fascism: &ldquo;a populist political philosophy, movement, or regime (such as that of the Fascisti) that exalts nation and often race above the individual, that is associated with a centralized autocratic government headed by a dictatorial leader, and that is characterized by severe economic and social regimentation and by forcible suppression of opposition&rdquo; (Merriam-Webster)</p></blockquote>
<p>Notoriously difficult to define, <a href="https://www.nybooks.com/articles/1995/06/22/ur-fascism/">Umberto Eco nevertheless highlighted 14 aspects of what he called &ldquo;Ur-Fascism&rdquo;</a>:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Cult of Tradition</strong> – A syncretic belief in ancient truths, rejecting modern interpretations.</li>
<li><strong>Rejection of Modernism</strong> – Viewing the Enlightenment and rationalism as the root of moral decline.</li>
<li><strong>Cult of Action for Action’s Sake</strong> – Valuing action over reflection, leading to anti-intellectualism.</li>
<li><strong>Disagreement is Treason</strong> – Suppressing dissent and critical thinking as threats to unity.</li>
<li><strong>Fear of Difference</strong> – Exploiting xenophobia and racism to unify the in-group against outsiders.</li>
<li><strong>Appeal to a Frustrated Middle Class</strong> – Mobilizing those feeling economically or socially displaced.</li>
<li><strong>Obsession with a Plot</strong> – Promoting conspiracy theories to justify aggression against perceived enemies.</li>
<li><strong>Enemies are Both Too Strong and Too Weak</strong> – Portraying adversaries as simultaneously formidable and feeble.</li>
<li><strong>Pacifism is Trafficking with the Enemy</strong> – Viewing life as perpetual warfare, dismissing peace efforts as betrayal.</li>
<li><strong>Contempt for the Weak</strong> – Glorifying strength and dismissing compassion as weakness.</li>
<li><strong>Everybody is Educated to Become a Hero</strong> – Promoting a cult of death and martyrdom.</li>
<li><strong>Machismo</strong> – Elevating aggressive masculinity and denigrating non-conforming sexual behaviors.</li>
<li><strong>Selective Populism</strong> – Claiming to represent the unified will of the people, dismissing individual rights.</li>
<li><strong>Newspeak</strong> – Employing an impoverished vocabulary to limit critical thought.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
