<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Introversion on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/introversion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introversion on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <image>
      <title>Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <url>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</url>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 16:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/introversion/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Make Friends as a Tired Introvert in Your 30s? A Dad&#39;s Honest Ask for Advice</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/how-do-you-make-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 16:08:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/how-do-you-make-friends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m putting this out there because I&amp;rsquo;m genuinely stuck, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping some of you have been where I am and can offer some wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my situation: I&amp;rsquo;m in my 30s, married with three young kids, and I work from home in northwest Ohio. On paper, my life is full—and in many ways it is. But I&amp;rsquo;m also dealing with some significant loneliness and isolation that I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to shake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m putting this out there because I&rsquo;m genuinely stuck, and I&rsquo;m hoping some of you have been where I am and can offer some wisdom.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s my situation: I&rsquo;m in my 30s, married with three young kids, and I work from home in northwest Ohio. On paper, my life is full—and in many ways it is. But I&rsquo;m also dealing with some significant loneliness and isolation that I can&rsquo;t seem to shake.</p>
<p>I have a couple of old friends who live in other states, and I&rsquo;ve built up some online acquaintances over the years, but when it comes to real, local, in-person friendships? I&rsquo;m coming up short. And it&rsquo;s affecting me more than I necessarily thought it would.</p>
<h2 id="the-perfect-storm-of-friendship-challenges">The Perfect Storm of Friendship Challenges</h2>
<p>Looking back, I can see how I ended up here. Most of my meaningful friendships throughout my adult life formed around two main contexts: education and church. I had college friends, seminary friends, and PhD student friends. I connected with fellow parishioners and other ministers. These were natural communities where relationships could develop organically.</p>
<p>But life has shifted a lot. I left my PhD program, <a href="/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/">resigned from active ministry in my denomination</a>, and <a href="/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/">switched careers to work as a full-time software engineer</a>. While my family still attends church and I&rsquo;ve made some acquaintances there, I haven&rsquo;t developed any close friendships yet.</p>
<p>Add to this the fact that I work from home (which I genuinely love, but it eliminates those casual workplace connections), and I&rsquo;m dealing with anxiety and depression (currently working with a therapist and on medication). As an introvert with some social anxiety, large or loud social events aren&rsquo;t particularly appealing to me, which eliminates a lot of the typical &ldquo;just put yourself out there&rdquo; advice.</p>
<p>And then there&rsquo;s the elephant in the room: the current political and social climate. I&rsquo;m genuinely stressed about the direction our country is heading—the slide toward authoritarianism, the constant barrage of troubling news. Now, I&rsquo;m not looking for friendships that revolve around politics, but I also don&rsquo;t want to feel like I have to completely hide my real concerns about what&rsquo;s happening in the world. The challenge is that when you&rsquo;re meeting new people, you have no idea where they stand on these issues at first, and discovering a fundamental mismatch in worldview can be&hellip; well, awkward, to put it mildly. It adds another layer of complexity (or an excuse to just not try!) to what&rsquo;s already a difficult process.</p>
<h2 id="what-im-looking-for">What I&rsquo;m Looking For</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m not entirely sure what the answer is, but I know what I&rsquo;m hoping for: genuine, local friendships with people I can actually spend time with in person. I&rsquo;d love to find people who share some of my interests—books and reading, tools and home repair, auto work, DIY projects, shooting, coffee, craft beer, soccer, running. I&rsquo;m hoping to get more into woodworking and pickleball too.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m primarily thinking about individual friendships, though my family could also use some family friends—other parents dealing with similar life stages and challenges.</p>
<h2 id="where-im-asking-for-help">Where I&rsquo;m Asking for Help</h2>
<p>So here&rsquo;s where you come in. If you&rsquo;ve navigated similar challenges, I&rsquo;d love to hear your advice:</p>
<ul>
<li>How do you make genuine friends as an adult, especially when your previous social contexts have disappeared?</li>
<li>What&rsquo;s worked for you as an introvert trying to build meaningful connections?</li>
<li>Are there specific strategies that work well for parents with young kids?</li>
<li>How do you balance the need for friendship with the reality of anxiety and limited social energy?</li>
<li>Any northwest Ohio folks reading this who want to grab coffee and commiserate about how hard adult friendship can be? :)</li>
</ul>
<p>I&rsquo;m not looking for surface-level networking or forced social situations. I&rsquo;m looking for the kind of friendships where you can text someone when you&rsquo;re having a rough day, or call when you need help with a project, or just hang out without it feeling like work.</p>
<p>Maybe I&rsquo;m being too idealistic, or maybe I need to adjust my expectations. But I figure there have to be other people out there dealing with similar stuff, right?</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;ve got thoughts, advice, or even just want to share your own friendship struggles, I&rsquo;d love to hear from you in the comments or drop me a line. Sometimes just knowing you&rsquo;re not alone in something makes it a little easier to figure out.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading, and thanks in advance for any wisdom you&rsquo;re willing to share.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
