<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>research on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tag/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 17:52:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tag/research/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth’s Gesamtausgabe (“Complete/Collected Edition”): A List of Works</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-gesamtausgabe-complete-collected-edition-a-list-of-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-gesamtausgabe-complete-collected-edition-a-list-of-works/</guid>
      <description>Note that, as of 2019-01-26, 54 volumes of the Gesamtausgabe have been published.
Unfortunately, only the first 45 of these are available in the Digital Karl Barth Library.
*I&amp;rsquo;ve marked volumes unavailable in the DKBL with an asterisk.
According to the publisher, TVZ:
Seit 1971 sind im Theologischen Verlag Zürich mehr als 50 Bände der Karl Barth-Gesamtausgabe erschienen. In ihr werden Barths Texte kritisch ediert und so präsentiert, dass sie für die wissenschaftliche Beschäftigung, aber auch für einen grösseren Interessentenkreis lesbar und zugänglich werden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A List of Karl Barth&#39;s Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</guid>
      <description>To make this list, I&amp;rsquo;ve used the data available in the Digital Karl Barth Library. I&amp;rsquo;ve just taken the tables of contents in the sermon volumes of Barth&amp;rsquo;s collected works and put them all in one place.
The only way to display the dates correctly in Markdown is to write these up as code blocks, as I&amp;rsquo;ve done below.
Predigten 1913 (GA I.8) 1. und 5. Januar (Neujahr): Prediger 1,9 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spirit, Flesh, Restoration, and Sublimation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 18:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s an intriguing passage in Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s Letters and Papers from Prison where he discusses the relationship between &amp;ldquo;spirit&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flesh,&amp;rdquo; in the context of discussing &amp;ldquo;restoration&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sublimation,&amp;rdquo; in the context of discussing lyrics from certain hymns and songs that were meaningful to him in prison.
Here it is, from a December 19, 1943 (the Fourth Sunday of Advent) letter to Eberhard Bethge:
In recent weeks this line has been running through my head over and over: “Calm your hearts, dear friends; / whatever plagues you, / whatever fails you, / I will restore it all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth and Bonhoeffer on Religion&#39;s False God(s)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-religions-false-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 19:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-religions-false-gods/</guid>
      <description>In The Epistle to the Romans, Barth writes the following concerning the false image of God at the heart of religion:
What men on this side resurrection name ‘God’ is most characteristically not God. Their ‘God’ does not redeem his creation, but allows free course to the unrighteousness of men; does not declare himself to be God, but is the complete affirmation of the course of the world and of men as it is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth&#39;s Reversal on the &#34;Knowledge of Good and Evil&#34;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-reversal-on-the-knowledge-of-good-and-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-reversal-on-the-knowledge-of-good-and-evil/</guid>
      <description>I argue that, although Barth’s interpretation of the Genesis passages changed between The Epistle to the Romans and the Church Dogmatics, his mature readings of Genesis 2–3 still support his overall theological critique of religion as idolatry, the self-justifying positing of false gods.
Specifically, in Romans (240–57, esp. 246–51), Barth interpreted “the knowledge of good and evil” as the divine secret that humans are merely humans.
The prohibition of eating from the tree of knowledge thereby concealed the creator/creature distinction and was meant to enable a direct relationship between God and humans.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I wish these 2 Barth (and Bonhoeffer) books would come out sooner!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-wish-these-2-barth-and-bonhoeffer-books-would-come-out-sooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-wish-these-2-barth-and-bonhoeffer-books-would-come-out-sooner/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to reading these two Barth (and Bonhoeffer) books coming out from Baker in 2019:
Freedom under the Word: Karl Barth’s Theological Exegesis. Edited by Ben Rhodes and Martin Westerholm. Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer: Theologians for a Post-Christian World. By Wolf Krötke. Translated by John P. Burgess. Freedom under the Word (May 2019) According to Baker:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me StickK to my writing habit</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</guid>
      <description>I need to finish this dissertation.
To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.
Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a bear to get back on!
So, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonhoeffer&#39;s &#34;Definition&#34; of &#34;Religion&#34; in Prison: 15 Facets/Aspects</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bonhoeffers-definition-of-religion-in-prison-15-facets-aspects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 14:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bonhoeffers-definition-of-religion-in-prison-15-facets-aspects/</guid>
      <description>Based upon my own reading of Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s Letters and Papers from Prison [DBWE 8], here is my attempt at a summary list of the facets/aspects of Bonhoeffer’s view of “religion” in prison.
Religion emphasizes inwardness. [DBWE 8:362, 364, 455–57] Religion emphasizes conscience. [DBWE 8:362] Religion is a temporary phenomenon. [DBWE 8:362, 364] Religion is manipulative and exploitative. [DBWE 8:363, 366, 426–27, 450, 455–57] Religion ignores human strength/knowledge/autonomy and instead focuses on human weakness, ignorance, and boundaries/limits/limitations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Karl Barth Software Drama Continues: Inaccurate Page Numbers in Logos</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-karl-barth-software-drama-continues-inaccurate-page-numbers-in-logos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 16:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-karl-barth-software-drama-continues-inaccurate-page-numbers-in-logos/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I wrote about how the Scripture search tool in the Digital Karl Barth Library was broken. Thankfully, it appears to have been fixed (although it still has issues). This means I can search Barth&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Collected Edition&amp;rdquo; (Gesamtausgabe) if needed.
However, I&amp;rsquo;m now having some issues with the copy of Barth&amp;rsquo;s Church Dogmatics I purchased via Logos Bible Software.
Before I complain, let me first say how grateful I am that Logos is MUCH more user-friendly than the Digital Karl Barth Library.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UPDATE: You can now search for Bible citations in the Digital Karl Barth Library again</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/update-you-can-now-search-for-bible-citations-in-the-digital-karl-barth-library-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/update-you-can-now-search-for-bible-citations-in-the-digital-karl-barth-library-again/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote about a problem I found in Alexander Street Press&amp;rsquo; Digital Karl Barth Library: the Scripture citation search function no longer worked!
I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that, though the DKBL is still far from user-friendly, the Bible search works again!
Now we just need some angel investors and programmers to produce a user-friendly version of the Digital Karl Barth Library! :) Any takers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s gone wrong with the Digital Karl Barth Library?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-gone-wrong-with-the-digital-karl-barth-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 15:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-gone-wrong-with-the-digital-karl-barth-library/</guid>
      <description>As I slowly make progress on my dissertation (&amp;ldquo;Scriptural but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion&amp;rdquo;), I&amp;rsquo;m longing for the day when:
Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s Gesamtausgabe (Collected Edition) is finished. They are translated into a critical English edition. They are available within the same database/framework as Dietrich Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s Works in English and German (DBWE and DBW). In the meantime, the Digital Karl Barth Library, provided by Alexander Street Press is the best resource out there for searching the text of Barth&amp;rsquo;s works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Be or Not To Be Religious: A Clarification of Karl Barth&#39;s and Dietrich Bonhoeffer&#39;s Divergence and Convergence Regarding Religion</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/to-be-or-not-to-be-religious-a-clarification-of-karl-barths-and-dietrich-bonhoeffers-divergence-and-convergence-regarding-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 18:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/to-be-or-not-to-be-religious-a-clarification-of-karl-barths-and-dietrich-bonhoeffers-divergence-and-convergence-regarding-religion/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
Christian theologians Karl Barth (1886-1968) and Dietrich Bonhoeffer (1906-1945) inherited a particular understanding of religion. In the broadly post-Kantian milieu, nineteenth-century thinkers such as Friedrich Schleiermacher, Albrecht Ritschl, and Adolf von Harnack defined religion essentially, anthropologically, and subjectively. That is, religion has a particular essence, and is in some manner inalienable from our humanity. The emphasis of this conception is on the experience of the religious subject, instead of the knowledge of religion’s object (let alone its reality).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Works on Karl Barth &amp; Dietrich Bonhoeffer. Are There Others?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/works-on-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 20:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/works-on-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</guid>
      <description>ABROMEIT, Hans-Jürgen. Das Geheimnis Christi: Dietrich Bonhoeffers erfahrungsbezogene Christologie. Neukirchener Beiträge zur systemaschen Theologie 8. Neukirchen-Vluyn: Neukirchener Verlag, 1991. BEINTKER, Michael. “Kontingenz und Gegenständlichkeit: Zu Bonhoeffers Barth-Kritik in ‘Akt und Sein.’” In Krisis und Gnade: Gesammelte Studien zu Karl Barth, edited by Stefan Holtmann and Peter Zocher, 29–54. Tübingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2013. BENKTSON, Benkt-Erik. Christus Und Die Religion: Der Religionsbegriff Bei Barth, Bonhoeffer Und Tillich. Arbeiten Zur Theologie, II/9. Stuttgart: Calwer, 1967.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, &amp; The Theological Critique of Religion: My Reading List This Fall</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-the-theological-critique-of-religion-my-reading-list-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 20:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-the-theological-critique-of-religion-my-reading-list-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
This semester &amp;ndash; my final one at Beeson Divinity School -- I&amp;rsquo;m doing a directed study with Piotr Malysz on the topic of &amp;ldquo;Religion&amp;rdquo; in Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer.
The impetus for this study was a discussion question in Dr. Malysz’s Spring 2015 20th Century History and Doctrine course. On March 24, our third class period on Dietrich Bonhoeffer, our second question for discussion read as follows:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
