<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <image>
      <title>Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <url>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</url>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 17:04:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Find Your Life&#39;s Purpose: Helpful Advice from Daniel Pink</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/how-to-find-your-lifes-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 17:01:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/how-to-find-your-lifes-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TEQL2ZRDRVM&#34;&gt;a Daniel Pink video&lt;/a&gt; that helped clarify and summarize some key insights about finding life&amp;rsquo;s purpose in a really actionable way. The framework was so helpful that I wanted to share it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop asking &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s my passion?&amp;rdquo; Start asking better questions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pink suggests that the classic advice to &amp;ldquo;follow your passion&amp;rdquo; often leads us nowhere. Instead, he offers seven more practical questions that can actually help you discover your life&amp;rsquo;s purpose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I recently came across <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TEQL2ZRDRVM">a Daniel Pink video</a> that helped clarify and summarize some key insights about finding life&rsquo;s purpose in a really actionable way. The framework was so helpful that I wanted to share it.</p>
<p><strong>Stop asking &ldquo;What&rsquo;s my passion?&rdquo; Start asking better questions.</strong></p>
<p>Pink suggests that the classic advice to &ldquo;follow your passion&rdquo; often leads us nowhere. Instead, he offers seven more practical questions that can actually help you discover your life&rsquo;s purpose.</p>
<h2 id="the-seven-questions-that-matter">The Seven Questions That Matter</h2>
<p><strong>1. What made you weird as a kid?</strong>
Think back to what you did for fun at 7 or 10 years old, even if others thought it was odd. Those childhood quirks often point to authentic interests that society hasn&rsquo;t yet conditioned out of you.</p>
<p><strong>2. When do you lose track of time?</strong>
Notice when you naturally enter a flow state. These moments reveal activities that align with your intrinsic motivation.</p>
<p><strong>3. What do people consistently thank you for?</strong>
Ask friends and colleagues: &ldquo;What do you appreciate about me? What do you think I&rsquo;m particularly good at? How do you think I&rsquo;ll leave a mark on the world?&rdquo; Their answers reveal your unique strengths.</p>
<p><strong>4. What&rsquo;s your sentence?</strong>
As Clare Boothe Luce once told John F. Kennedy: &ldquo;A great person is a sentence.&rdquo; Can you summarize your life&rsquo;s purpose in a single, clear sentence?</p>
<p><strong>5. Where can you make your biggest contribution?</strong>
Look around at the people, teams, and communities in your life. What do they genuinely need that you&rsquo;re uniquely positioned to provide?</p>
<p><strong>6. What would you do if money weren&rsquo;t an object?</strong>
This classic question strips away practical constraints to reveal what truly motivates you.</p>
<p><strong>7. What will you regret at 90?</strong>
Most people regret what they <em>didn&rsquo;t</em> do—not being bolder, not starting that business, not taking their shot. What three things might your 90-year-old self regret not pursuing? Flip it: What will make you proud to have accomplished?</p>
<h2 id="the-bottom-line">The Bottom Line</h2>
<p>Purpose isn&rsquo;t something you stumble upon—it&rsquo;s something you actively discover through honest self-reflection. These questions can guide you toward a clearer understanding of what makes your contribution to the world uniquely yours.</p>
<p><em>Ready to dig deeper? Start with just one question and spend some real time with your answer.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
