<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 11:39:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 Things I Love About My Kids</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/10-things-i-love-about-my-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 11:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/10-things-i-love-about-my-kids/</guid>
      <description>Lest my previous parenting post suggest that things are all doom-and-gloom at the Steele-haus, here are 10 things I love about my kids.
I got to baptize all 3 of them as babies, a poignant reminder that they are beloved children of God. They all love books, which warms my nerdy heart. The way Eleanor (1yo) greets me. It used to be a very excited squeal. Now it’s “Ah! Daddy!” Andrew (4yo) has a great memory for stories, especially Bible stories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Love My Kids, But I Sometimes Regret Having Them</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-love-my-kids-but-i-sometimes-regret-having-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 08:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-love-my-kids-but-i-sometimes-regret-having-them/</guid>
      <description>I love my kids, but I sometimes regret having them.
Pardon the clickbait-y title and opening sentence. But are we parents allowed to say that? Are we allowed to feel both of those things at once?
We’ve got a 6-year-old, a 4-year-old, and an almost-2-year-old. And, no, I don’t actually begrudge them their existence! I want what’s best for their lives and futures. And don’t get me wrong; there are moments of laughter, poignancy, joy, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help, I&amp;#8217;m Addicted to Mini Toolkits: The EDC Tool Struggle Is Real</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-addicted-to-mini-toolkits-the-edc-tool-struggle-is-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 16:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-addicted-to-mini-toolkits-the-edc-tool-struggle-is-real/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know what it is about mini toolkits, but I love them.
Actually, scratch that. I know why. It’s the same reason I love buying tools and books, more generally: the illusion of control. I like how having tools (and a great personal library) makes me feel like I’m ready for whatever life throws at me (ha!).
It’s why I liked carrying around a pocketknife as a kid, and it’s why I’m into EDC (everyday carry) and tools as an adult.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can&amp;#8217;t Follow Jesus and Hate Immigrants</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/you-cant-follow-jesus-and-hate-immigrants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 16:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/you-cant-follow-jesus-and-hate-immigrants/</guid>
      <description>You can’t follow Jesus and hate immigrants.
Of course, this does NOT settle every question of immigration policy!
But, if you’re a follower of Jesus, consider your overall posture toward immigrants. If you call yourself a Christian, I want you to think about this seriously.
What comes into your head and your heart when you think of immigrants and refugees? Fear? Anger? Disgust?
What if the immigrants are in your country legally?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christianity and Politics: My 2024 Reading List</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christianity-and-politics-my-2024-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christianity-and-politics-my-2024-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>The relationship between Church and State, particularly the intersection of Christianity and politics, has been on my mind since I first started paying attention during the lead-up to the 2008 USA presidential election. Back then, I was just a high school student, but these themes have stuck with me ever since.
(For those curious, here’s a quick timeline: In 2012, I was studying biblical studies in college. By 2016, I was a seminarian, and in 2020, I was working on my Ph.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Things I&amp;#8217;m Excited About (2024-08-04)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/6-things-im-excited-about-2024-08-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/6-things-im-excited-about-2024-08-04/</guid>
      <description>Sweater weather Losing weight with some help from Zepbound Football season (pulling for the Detroit Lions and the University of Michigan Wolverines) Harbor Freight coming out with version 2.0 of its “meme tool” – now with sockets! Hopefully out before the end of the year Reading The Widening of God’s Mercy: Sexuality Within the Biblical Story by Christopher and Richard Hays when it comes out next week Learning auto repair by working on my dad’s 1999 Dodge Ram 1500 (next up: replacing the governor pressure solenoid and sensor in the transmission, which will hopefully help with the truck getting stuck in low gear!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Improvement Roadmap and Roadblocks</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/home-improvement-roadmap-and-roadblocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 16:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/home-improvement-roadmap-and-roadblocks/</guid>
      <description>We bought our first house in late 2023 and, since moving-in in January 2024, I’ve been chipping away at home improvement projects. Since I’m a software engineer and spend my day in front of a screen, I enjoy working with tools as a change of pace.
Now, some upcoming projects will clearly outstrip my capabilities and I plan to hire professionals:
– Replace roof and gutters
– Replace furnace and central air conditioning</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Know Thyself: Unveiling Your Unique Strengths and Personality Traits</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/know-thyself-unveiling-your-unique-strengths-and-personality-traits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/know-thyself-unveiling-your-unique-strengths-and-personality-traits/</guid>
      <description>In the quest for personal and professional growth, understanding our unique strengths and personality traits can be incredibly enlightening. Today, I want to share my insights from various personality paradigms and how they shape my approach to work and life.
CliftonStrengths: Harnessing Core Talents The CliftonStrengths assessment has been instrumental in identifying my core talents. Here are my top five strengths:
Input: I have an insatiable curiosity and a constant desire to collect information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding a Hat for My Big, Bald Head</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/finding-a-hat-for-my-big-bald-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/finding-a-hat-for-my-big-bald-head/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been on a lifelong journey to find hats that will fit my big ol’ head. Now that I’m bald, and the summer months are approaching, I figured it would be good to find one or two more hats to add to my rotation.
I’ve narrowed this round down to trying the following hats, in case you’re interested (Amazon affiliate links below):
TOO SMALL FOR ME Carhartt Men’s Rugged Professional Series Canvas Mesh-Back Cap (Shadow, One Size) Carhartt Men’s 100289 Odessa Ball Cap (Carhartt Brown, One Size) I’m a sucker for Carhartt and Carhartt brown!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prayers for the Sick</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayers-for-the-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 23:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayers-for-the-sick/</guid>
      <description>(The following prayers come from the 1979 Book of Common Prayer.)
## Contents - [Prayers for the Sick](#prayers-for-the-sick) - [For a Sick Person](#for-a-sick-person) - [For Recovery from Sickness](#for-recovery-from-sickness) - [For a Sick Child](#for-a-sick-child) - [Before an Operation](#before-an-operation) - [For Strength and Confidence](#for-strength-and-confidence) - [For the Sanctification of Illness](#for-the-sanctification-of-illness) - [For Health of Body and Soul](#for-health-of-body-and-soul) - [For Doctors and Nurses](#for-doctors-and-nurses) - [Thanksgiving for a Beginning of Recovery](#thanksgiving-for-a-beginning-of-recovery) - [Prayers for use by a Sick Person](#prayers-for-use-by-a-sick-person) - [For Trust in God](#for-trust-in-god) - [In Pain](#in-pain) - [For Sleep](#for-sleep) - [In the Morning](#in-the-morning) --- Prayers for the Sick For a Sick Person O Father of mercies and God of all comfort, our only help in time of need: We humbly beseech thee to behold, visit, and relieve thy sick servant N.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death in His Grave</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/death-in-his-grave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 20:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/death-in-his-grave/</guid>
      <description>With Holy Week and Easter coming up, I’ve been thinking about music and artwork that I’ve found particularly poignant when reflection on the crucifixion and resurrection.
First, I’ve seen many icons of the resurrection (“anastasis,” in Greek) like the one below.
But I don’t think I fully appreciated the image until I realized it was Adam and Eve that Christ is helping up out of their graves. He’s trampled down the doors/gates of Hell and is taking an elderly Adam and an elderly Eve by the hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Gym Upgrades</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/home-gym-upgrades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/home-gym-upgrades/</guid>
      <description>I’ve often enjoyed lifting weights, but I’ve never enjoyed going to the gym. So, I’ve long wanted a nice home gym.
When we lived in a basement apartment, space was very limited, but I was able to fit a Valor Fitness BD-9 squat rack/stands and an Amazon Basics flat bench in, along with a 300-lb Olympic barbell and weight set from Dicks Sporting Goods.
(If you’re similarly pressed for space, I highly recommend those items above!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem of Ecclesiastical Evil</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-problem-of-ecclesiastical-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 12:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-problem-of-ecclesiastical-evil/</guid>
      <description>You’ve probably heard of “the problem of evil” (if not, here’s an overview). But there’s a specific version/aspect of it that I find even more devastating.
If God is omnipotent (all-powerful), ommniscient (all-knowing(, and omnibenevolent (completely good)…
If the Church is God’s main plan for the redemption of humanity and the cosmos (consider the “body of Christ” paradigm in the New Testament)…
If the gospel of Jesus Christ has had ~2K years to percolate in and through the Church…</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back in the Saddle</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/back-in-the-saddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 21:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/back-in-the-saddle/</guid>
      <description>I know I’m not alone in this, but the past few years have been pretty rough for me.
I’ve gained at least 50 pounds. I had a fun part-time gig as a managing editor come to an end. I’ve come to terms with some long-term depression and anxiety. I had a job offer ripped out from under me. I hit pause on and eventually dropped out of my Ph.D. program. I’ve resigned from ordained ministry in the ACNA, my previous denomination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Truth to Power</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/truth-to-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/truth-to-power/</guid>
      <description>Mark 6:13-29. John the Baptist lost his life for speaking truth to power. Are we willing to speak truth to power? To tell the truth about power and the power of truth? Or will we abandon the truth to obtain and maintain power?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Possibly Unpopular Opinions about Church</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/25-possibly-unpopular-opinions-about-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 13:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/25-possibly-unpopular-opinions-about-church/</guid>
      <description>The following are some of my opinions, held with varying levels of intensity, about church/churches.
Note: These are geared toward Christian churches in the USA. Some would obviously also apply to churches elsewhere. But I haven’t nuanced this entire list for all global church contexts.
Many churches in the USA are too “busy.” They are trying to do too many different things and should instead refocus on the church’s proper priorities (Word and Sacraments).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&amp;#8217;m Resigning from Ordained Ministry in the Anglican Church in North America</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 19:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/</guid>
      <description>After a considerable period of discernment, coupled with my growing disaffection with the Anglican Church in North America, I sense God calling me to step away from ordained ministry in the ACNA and instead to focus on my family and my career as a software engineer.
This also coincides with plans to move closer to family in NW Ohio (where there is not much of an ACNA presence to speak of) and to then pursue church involvement outside of the ACNA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Lessons: 32 Things I&amp;#8217;ve Learned So Far</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/life-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/life-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Here are 32 things I’ve learned from life, so far.
You are not your thoughts. There is a “you” behind and above your inner voice/monologue/dialogue. Pay attention to what you pay attention to. Think about what you think about. We always only have the present moment. Focusing too much on the future leads to anxiety. Focusing too much on the past leads to depression. Wherever you are, be fully there, now!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anyone Can Use AI Tools: Here&amp;#8217;s How</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anyone-can-use-ai-tools-heres-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 19:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anyone-can-use-ai-tools-heres-how/</guid>
      <description>Are you drowning in tasks, yearning for more hours in a day, or simply itching to supercharge your creativity? What if I told you that a digital sidekick exists—one that’s awake 24/7, tailored to boost your efficiency and spark ingenuity? No, this isn’t science fiction; it’s the transformative power of AI tools at your fingertips.
Think AI is only for tech gurus and coding aficionados? Think again. AI is breaking down the ivory tower, becoming an invaluable asset for everyone from marketers and writers to busy parents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Online Scams: A Simple Guide for Non-Tech-Savvy Internet Users</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Online scams can touch anyone’s life. They don’t discriminate based on how tech-savvy you are or how often you use the internet. We’ve all heard stories—maybe from a friend, a family member, or even in the news—of someone getting tricked online, often with distressing consequences. It serves as a stark reminder of the darker side of our digital world.
This is why it’s crucial for every one of us to understand online scams—how they operate, how to identify them, and most importantly, how to avoid becoming a victim.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essential Reads for New Software Developers: The Effective Engineer and The Missing README</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/essential-reads-for-new-software-developers-the-effective-engineer-and-the-missing-readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 21:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/essential-reads-for-new-software-developers-the-effective-engineer-and-the-missing-readme/</guid>
      <description>Are you stepping into the exciting world of software engineering, or considering whether to take that leap? You’re not alone. This field attracts countless individuals worldwide, fueled by an ever-increasing demand for technological solutions, the promise of high salaries, and a keen interest in problem-solving.
However, it’s essential to understand that coding and programming skills, while crucial, are just one part of a broader equation. Equally important is the bigger picture of how software development fits into the wider professional and business environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scriptures to Read on Days of Prayer and Fasting for the Church</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/scriptures-to-read-on-days-of-prayer-and-fasting-for-the-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 12:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/scriptures-to-read-on-days-of-prayer-and-fasting-for-the-church/</guid>
      <description>1 Peter 4:17 For the time has come for judgment to begin with the household of God; if it begins with us, what will be the end for those who do not obey the gospel of God?
Isaiah 58:1–14 Shout out, do not hold back!
Lift up your voice like a trumpet!
Announce to my people their rebellion,
to the house of Jacob their sins.
Yet day after day they seek me</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master the Art of Interpersonal Relationships with &amp;#8220;How to Win Friends and Influence People&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/master-the-art-of-interpersonal-relationships-with-how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 12:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/master-the-art-of-interpersonal-relationships-with-how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</guid>
      <description>Dale Carnegie’s timeless classic, How to Win Friends and Influence People, has been a bestseller for decades, offering insights and advice on improving interpersonal relationships. The book’s practical principles have helped millions of readers excel in their personal and professional lives.
In this blog post, I’ll summarize the key points from Carnegie’s work and provide you with a solid foundation to start mastering your own relationships. If you find these ideas helpful and compelling, I highly recommend reading the entire book!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discover Learn X in Y Minutes: An Invaluable Resource for Programmers</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/discover-learn-x-in-y-minutes-an-invaluable-resource-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 12:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/discover-learn-x-in-y-minutes-an-invaluable-resource-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>As a programmer or someone aspiring to be one, you’re always on the lookout for valuable resources to help you learn new languages and tools. Today, I’m excited to introduce you to learnxinyminutes.com, a must-visit website for anyone interested in coding. This site offers concise, code-focused tutorials for dozens of programming languages and essential tools, making it a perfect learning companion for beginners and experienced coders alike.
Quick and Efficient Learning Learn X in Y Minutes understands that time is precious, which is why it provides:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Linux: Top Commands Every New Computer Programmer Should Learn</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mastering-linux-top-commands-every-new-computer-programmer-should-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 17:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mastering-linux-top-commands-every-new-computer-programmer-should-learn/</guid>
      <description>Are you new to the world of computer programming? If so, learning Linux commands is an essential step in your journey. Linux is a powerful and versatile operating system used by developers across various fields.
In this blog post, we’ll cover the most important Linux commands that every new computer programmer should learn to level up their skills.
(Want to learn even more about Linux? Check out Linux Pocket Guide: Essential Commands and The Linux Command Line: A Complete Introduction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anything: Software Engineering Questions from a Coding Bootcamp Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 14:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</guid>
      <description>I’m posting my answers to these software engineering questions here, just in case anyone else finds them helpful! (Also, it gives me another link to share when I get asked these kinds of questions.)
How did you become interested in software engineering? I wrote a bit about my coding bootcamp journey in a previous post.
Part of my interest in software engineering is/was related to the particular path my journey took.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Coding Bootcamp Journey: How a Pastor Became a Programmer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 17:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>When I changed my major from Mechanical Engineering to Bible shortly before my first semester of college, I realized that what I was studying was not going to make me rich.
So, throughout undergrad, seminary, and into a Ph.D. program in theology, the notion of “bi-vocational ministry” (serving the church while also making money outside of the church doing something else) was on my radar screen.
In fact, for a few months between finishing seminary and starting my Ph.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Want</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-i-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 19:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-i-want/</guid>
      <description>I want…
To be a good husband To be a good father To be a good friend To solve people’s problems To build what people use To write what people read To never stop learning Finances To have control over my time “The ability to do what you want, when you want, with who you want, for as long as you want, is priceless. It is the highest dividend money pays” (Morgan Housel, The Psychology of Money, 83).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logos 10 Bible Software: The Ultimate Theological Learning Tool</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 13:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: If you’re serious about biblical and theological studies, you should invest in Logos 10 Bible Software. Do so via my exclusive partner offer for Logos 10 here!
If I could go back in time and chat with Joshua Steele when he was a Bible &amp;amp; Spanish major in college, there are a few things I’d tell my younger self:
Quit laughing at How to Read a Book by Mortimer J.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Testing: Possibilities, Problems, and Principles</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/software-testing-possibilities-problems-and-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 21:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/software-testing-possibilities-problems-and-principles/</guid>
      <description>Note: Throughout what follows, I am heavily indebted to two books in particular: Unit Testing: Principles, Practices, and Patterns by Vladimir Khorikov (Manning Publications, 2020) and Effective Software Testing: A Developer’s Guide by Mauricio Aniche (Manning Publications, 2022). In fact, this overview of software testing should be viewed as a distillation of Khorikov and Aniche.
![Khorikov-UT-HI.png](https://res.craft.do/user/full/032236cd-2bcc-fa12-9dfe-e5564a597e07/doc/836657DD-FF3A-4CE5-8565-F6945FE45D6A/21ECE62D-593E-4825-A549-6312F555D284_2/ZCHd2JrecxcxPA1c35H2wTV0FrAzdktnxui31U1rO00z/Khorikov-UT-HI.png)Khorikov-UT-HI.png![Aniche-HI.png](https://res.craft.do/user/full/032236cd-2bcc-fa12-9dfe-e5564a597e07/doc/836657DD-FF3A-4CE5-8565-F6945FE45D6A/ED1FC92B-C9A0-4CDC-B13D-5AA3940FF3E7_2/FE2KZaydLyYRh1ydJKyDIvx4y3gaQLh82funASwXFqoz/Aniche-HI.png)Aniche-HI.png--- Software Testing, Our Field’s Least-Sexy Superpower Coming into software development from a background in the humanities, automated software testing struck me as a kind of superpower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT: Write a Viral Blogpost about Why to Become a Software Engineer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/chatgpt-write-a-viral-blogpost-about-why-to-become-a-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 14:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/chatgpt-write-a-viral-blogpost-about-why-to-become-a-software-engineer/</guid>
      <description>Are you considering a career in software engineering but not sure if it’s right for you? Here are just a few reasons why becoming a software engineer is a great choice:
High demand and good pay: Software engineering is a rapidly growing field, with many companies actively seeking qualified candidates. According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, the median annual wage for software developers was $107,510 in 2020, and employment of software developers is projected to grow 21% from 2020 to 2029, much faster than the average for all occupations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Questions Worth Asking (Self-Elicitation Questions)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-worth-asking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 20:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-worth-asking/</guid>
      <description>Five-Minute Journal Questions Morning I am grateful for… What would make today great? Daily affirmations: I am… Evening What are 3 amazing things that happened today? How could I have made today even better? Morning Questions (5 minutes) What’s one thing I’m grateful for? What’s one thing I’m excited about? What’s one virtue I want to exhibit? What’s one thing I’m avoiding? What’s the one thing I need to do? Evening Questions (5 minutes) What were my biggest wins of the day?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Useful Websites: My Favorite Online Resources</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/most-useful-websites-my-favorite-online-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 19:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/most-useful-websites-my-favorite-online-resources/</guid>
      <description>General / Thinking Untools: https://untools.co/ James Clear: https://jamesclear.com/ Farnam Street: https://fs.blog/ Your Logical Fallacy Is: https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/ Your Bias Is: https://yourbias.is/ Fitness / Health Darebee: https://darebee.com/ Reading / Writing QuillBot: https://quillbot.com/ 12ft Ladder: https://12ft.io/ Open Library: https://openlibrary.org/ Design PDF24 Tools: https://tools.pdf24.org/en/ Unsplash: https://unsplash.com/ The Noun Project: https://thenounproject.com/ Software Development Stack Overflow: https://stackoverflow.com/ O’Reilly: https://learning.oreilly.com/ roadmap.sh: https://roadmap.sh/ cheat.sh: https://cheat.sh/ DevHints.io: https://devhints.io/ Learn X in Y minutes: https://learnxinyminutes.com/ Baeldung (for Java/Spring): https://www.baeldung.com/ What would you add to this list?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Me! 11 Questions I&amp;#8217;d Like You to Answer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mentor-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mentor-me/</guid>
      <description>Say what you will about Tim Ferriss, I’ve always really enjoyed the questions that he asks himself and others.
I also really enjoy LEARNING as much as I can from other people. And so, with that in mind, I’d like to “open source” my search for mentors and invite you, dear reader, to answer at least one of the questions below.
Please comment your answers below this post (that way others can benefit from your knowledge as well!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#ACNAtoo: What you can do to hear, to support, and to respond to abuse survivors</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/acnatoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 06:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/acnatoo/</guid>
      <description>#ACNAtoo is a movement of survivors of ACNA-related abuse &amp;amp; their supporters seeking justice, repentance, healing &amp;amp; a healthier ACNA. This is an overview of the movement including what you can do to hear, to support, and to respond. By Whitney Evans Harrison and Conor Hanson. Why we are here In May 2019, Cherin’s 9-year-old daughter confided in her that she had been repeatedly sexually abused by Mark Rivera, a lay catechist at Christ Our Light Anglican (COLA), the church they attended in Big Rock, Illinois.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Color is My Parachute? The Flower Petal Exercise</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-color-is-my-parachute-the-flower-petal-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 22:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-color-is-my-parachute-the-flower-petal-exercise/</guid>
      <description>I’m working my way through the classic job search guide What Color Is Your Parachute. First, I’ll summarize the 7-part “Flower Petal” exercise—a comprehensive self-assessment geared toward the workplace. Then, I’ll share *my* results from the self-assessment.
Ah, but first, my TL;DR: If you’re looking for work, or going to be looking for work soon, do yourself a huge favor and buy the latest edition of What Color Is Your Parachute.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Haven’t You Torn The Sky Open Yet?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/why-havent-you-torn-the-sky-open-yet-sermon-first-sunday-of-advent-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/why-havent-you-torn-the-sky-open-yet-sermon-first-sunday-of-advent-2020/</guid>
      <description>Sermon preached on Saturday, November 28, 2020 (First Sunday of Advent) via Zoom at Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL.
--- If there are two things I hate, they are waiting and staying awake. I hate waiting.
Ask anyone who knows me. I am absolutely horrible when it comes to delayed gratification. I’ve been known to open new boxes of cereal on the way home from the store.
And I hate staying awake.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&amp;#8217;s Official. I&amp;#8217;m Hitting Pause on My Ph.D. for a Year</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-official-im-hitting-pause-on-my-ph-d-for-a-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 18:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-official-im-hitting-pause-on-my-ph-d-for-a-year/</guid>
      <description>I received word yesterday that the Ph.D. Committee voted to approve my request for “Excused Program Leave” beginning in January 2021 and lasting until January 2022.
At the risk of sounding like Captain Obvious, 2020 has been a particularly difficult year.
Attempting to complete my “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” dissertation has taken a toll on my mental health as I ran into some major research and writing roadblocks right before and during the COVID pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&amp;#8217;m looking for a new role to supplement my part-time work for Anglican Compass</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-looking-for-a-new-role-to-supplement-my-part-time-work-for-anglican-compass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 21:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-looking-for-a-new-role-to-supplement-my-part-time-work-for-anglican-compass/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone! Just a brief update to note that I’m looking for a new role to supplement my part-time work as Managing Editor of Anglican Compass!
I’m pretty flexible at this point, but I want to do something that benefits the church. I think I would make a great Assistant Rector! 🙂
Any advice, opportunities, or connections you can offer would be appreciated!
You can view/share my CV here. And here’s my LinkedIn profile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Josh&#43;? On the use of the sign of the cross (plus sign) in clergy signatures</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/josh-on-the-use-of-the-sign-of-the-cross-plus-sign-in-clergy-signatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 13:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/josh-on-the-use-of-the-sign-of-the-cross-plus-sign-in-clergy-signatures/</guid>
      <description>This is, admittedly, a half-baked opinion. However, I need to get back in the habit of blogging/writing regularly, so here goes.
In my opinion, the use of the sign of the cross in clergy names/signatures—unless it’s done in official ecclesiastical communication or immediately after a blessing or prayer for the recipient—is pretentious. It’s showy. At the very least, it conveys or connotes pretentiousness.
Note that I’m not making a claim about the *people* who use crosses in their signatures, their inner thoughts, or their intentions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&amp;#8217;s Time to Get Some Help</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-to-get-some-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 17:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-to-get-some-help/</guid>
      <description>Due to increased symptoms of depression and anxiety in recent weeks, I’ve decided to try out a combination of counseling and medication.
Sure, I’ve still been able to get out of bed in the morning. And I wasn’t having any serious thoughts about hurting myself. But still, I was feeling hopeless and trapped often enough that I decided it was time to seek out help.
I know, I know. That’s pretty personal for a blog post for the whole internet to read!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer for Trustfulness in Times of Worry and Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-for-trustfulness-in-times-of-worry-and-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 13:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-for-trustfulness-in-times-of-worry-and-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>I needed this prayer this morning, and I plan to return to it often in the days ahead.
Most loving Father, you will us to give thanks for all things, to dread nothing but the loss of you, and to cast all our care on the One who cares for us. Preserve us from faithless fears and worldly anxieties, and grant that no clouds of this mortal life may hide from us the light of that love which is immortal, and which you have manifested unto us in your Son, Jesus Christ our Lord.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Day of 24th Grade!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/first-day-of-24th-grade-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 14:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/first-day-of-24th-grade-2/</guid>
      <description>Not sure how this is going to go, or even why I’m doing this anymore, but here we go! Still praying for either a dissertation break-through or a clear sign that I should quit. I hope to receive or discover one of those before the end of the calendar year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s time for another social media fast!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-for-another-social-media-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 15:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-for-another-social-media-fast/</guid>
      <description>After listening to the Blinkist summary of Cal Newport’s Deep Work (I’ve read the book, this was just for a refresher), I’m convinced that it’s time for another 30-day fast from Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram.
I think I’ll still keep my micro.blog up and running, but between running Anglican Compass and sprinting for some last-ditch clarity on my increasingly frustrating dissertation, I need all the extra bandwidth I can get!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ph.D. Plan (Or the Lack Thereof)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 21:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>For months and months now, I’ve been praying for either (1) a breakthrough on my “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” dissertation or (2) a clear sign that I should quit the Ph.D. Unfortunately, after countless confusing dead ends in my endeavors to put Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer into precise conversation with each other regarding specific passages of the Bible, I’ve now realized that such an approach is not going to work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Shameless Request: Help Me Buy More Books?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 21:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</guid>
      <description>After realizing just how easy it was to lose access to the physical books that I own (now sequestered in my library carrel at Wheaton), on a bit of a whim I created a fundraiser to help my upgrade my Logos Bible Software library to either the Anglican Gold ($216) or Anglican Platinum ($582) libraries.
Upgrading would help me in my preaching, teaching, and writing roles (as a pastor-theologian and as the Managing Editor of AnglicanCompass.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&amp;#8217;m a Female Priest and I Support My Opponents in the Women&amp;#8217;s Ordination Debate</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-a-female-priest-and-i-support-my-opponents-in-the-womens-ordination-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 06:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-a-female-priest-and-i-support-my-opponents-in-the-womens-ordination-debate/</guid>
      <description>There is not unanimous agreement about women’s ordination in the worldwide Anglican Communion. Godly and thoughtful Christians hold opposing convictions about Holy Orders and who is called to ordained ministry. You often see the results of this debate at the Provincial level—a national expression of the Church may or may not ordain women, in accordance with their conviction. But for the Anglican Church in North America this disagreement is internal to the Province, varying from diocese to diocese and bishop to bishop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For the Good of the Order: A Plea for Charity on the Ordination of Women</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/for-the-good-of-the-order-a-plea-for-charity-on-the-ordination-of-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 06:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/for-the-good-of-the-order-a-plea-for-charity-on-the-ordination-of-women/</guid>
      <description>Almost every vocational deacon I know, when asked why he or she has not become a priest, will respond, “I have never felt called to the priesthood.” Some will add emphatically, “not for a minute!”
I am not one of those deacons.
I don’t share this story often, rarely in its fullness, and never in public non-anonymous writing. Be gentle with my soul, O Church. The words which follow are all too raw.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They Say, I Say Writing Templates</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 17:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>SOURCE: They Say / I Say: The Moves that Matter in Academic Writing, 4th edition (affiliate link). Perhaps the most helpful and practical book on academic writing!
Disagreeing Without Being Disagreeable While I understand the impulse to A, my own view is B. While I agree with X that Y, I cannot accept her overall conclusion that Z. While X argues Y, and I argue Z, in a way we’re both right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help! I’m looking for the best Christian resources on the Bible, social justice, racism, Critical Race Theory, and Marxism</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 17:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</guid>
      <description>Help me out. I’m looking for the best, clearest, and most charitable explanations of the following three things:
the biblical and theological reasons for caring about social justice and systemic racism, the unfair ways in which some have used accusations of Critical Race Theory (CRT) and Cultural Marxism to sideline legitimate Christian concerns about social justice and systemic racism, and the legitimate Christian critiques of CRT and Marxism. Now, I know that there are plenty of resources out there that address each of the three items above!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Collect for Juneteenth</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-collect-for-juneteenth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 03:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-collect-for-juneteenth/</guid>
      <description>The following is a “collect” prayer that I composed for Juneteenth in 2020. What’s a “collect” prayer?
The short form of prayer, constructed (with many varieties of detail) from (1) an invocation, (2) a petition, and (3) a pleading of Christ’s name or an ascription of glory to God; and one of the most characteristic items in the W[estern] liturgy.
Source: The Oxford Dictionary of the Christian Church
For more on Juneteenth, see “The Historical Legacy of Juneteenth” (National Museum of African American History and Culture).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who really cares about the Trinity in 2020?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 13:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-in-2020/</guid>
      <description>(To listen to the audio of this sermon as it was preached on June 6, 2020, click here.)
Christians believe that there is one God in three persons—Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.
Or, as my daughter Eva put it recently after seeing a picture in her book, “Father, Son, and Bird.” We’re working on that…
We Christians have been taught that the Trinity is important. No one wants to be a heretic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Books, Movies, and Podcasts about Race for White Christians like Me</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-books-movies-and-podcasts-about-race-for-white-christians-like-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-books-movies-and-podcasts-about-race-for-white-christians-like-me/</guid>
      <description>There are PLENTY of resource recommendations out there for those interested in learning more about racism and anti-racism (just Google “best X (books, movies, podcasts, etc.) on racism,” “antiracist reading list,” etc.).
However, I’m worried that, especially for people who are not used to working their way through lengthy reading lists, getting so many recommendations at once will lead to nothing due to the paradox of choice. I’d much rather recommend a single book that someone will actually read than 100 books they won’t!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“But, What About the Riots and Lawlessness?”</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/but-what-about-the-riots-and-lawlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 21:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/but-what-about-the-riots-and-lawlessness/</guid>
      <description>I commend the entire interview series that Ed Stetzer recently did with Esau McCaulley. Among many highlights, I appreciate McCaulley’s following answer to the question of negotiating the differences between protests and riots. Again, read the whole interview and series, but here’s a key section related to concern about rioting and lawlessness:
[Ed Stetzer] We both agree: Protests are good. Riots are not. Unpack that for us from your context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is the word “systemic” a flashpoint for certain Christians?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/why-is-the-word-systemic-a-flashpoint-for-certain-christians/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 20:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/why-is-the-word-systemic-a-flashpoint-for-certain-christians/</guid>
      <description>Certainly, the Bible has much to say about individual sin and redemption. But (1) focusing on “systemic” issues doesn’t need to negate a focus on “individual” issues. In fact, a focus on “systemic racism” actually exerts a lot of pressure to evaluate people individually, and not on the basis of their race—as long as we keep in mind how those supposedly individual evaluations are often subtly (and nefariously) shaped by systemic issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Fellow ACNA Clergy: On Anti-Racism and a More Diverse and Just Anglicanism</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: As is our policy with all Anglican Compass content, we ask that you please submit a request before republishing content.
Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who recently wrote in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Stir the Pot?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dont-stir-the-pot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dont-stir-the-pot/</guid>
      <description>I’m pondering the “don’t stir the pot” reaction that reliably happens every time we publish something on women’s ordination—most especially anything in favor of women’s ordination—over at Anglican Compass, where I’m the Managing Editor.
(Note: This post is not a subtweet of anyone in particular. It’s just me thinking out loud about a phenomenon that keeps occurring.)
Almost every time we post something about women’s ordination, a controversial issue has been whether or not doing so needlessly “stirs the pot,” as in “causes trouble, unrest, dissent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Altar and the Arena: What Slaves and Martyrs Have to Teach Us About Women’s Ordination</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-altar-and-the-arena-what-slaves-and-martyrs-have-to-teach-us-about-womens-ordination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-altar-and-the-arena-what-slaves-and-martyrs-have-to-teach-us-about-womens-ordination/</guid>
      <description>Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Compass does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.
Over the past several months, readers of Anglican Compass have engaged with many opinions on the topic of women’s ordination. One wonders, given the state of dual integrities within the ACNA and the ever-churning blog debates between our public intellectuals, what is the point of another take on this issue?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balderdash! 12 Suggestions for Overcoming Writer’s Block (From Andrew T. Le Peau’s “Write Better”)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 13:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</guid>
      <description>Writer’s block sucks. I’m currently facing it with regard to my dissertation and I’ve decided to hit pause on research and writing until I regain access to my library carrell at Wheaton.
Thankfully, I’ve come across some helpful advice on overcoming writer’s block in Andrew T. Le Peau’s Writer Better: A Lifelong Editor on Craft, Art, and Spirituality (affiliate link).
The book is filled with helpful and practical advice on writing, rewriting, publishing, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We switched Anglican Compass over from HostGator Shared to Bluehost VPS Hosting</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 15:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</guid>
      <description>As of this morning, it looks like everything for Anglican Compass has been successfully moved over from our HostGator shared hosting to Bluehost VPS hosting.
I’m hoping that this new arrangement works well for us! Although, to be honest, it’s still an open question in my mind whether or not managed WordPress hosting with WPEngine would be a better fit. I just can’t quite tell whether or not it would be worth the extra cost, given our current traffic and budget.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&amp;#8220;They laughed when I became an Anglican, but when I started to pray&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; 27 Anglican Headline Ideas</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</guid>
      <description>I’m reading my way through the new (4th) edition of Robert Bly’s classic The Copywriter’s Handbook. On pages 33–36, Bly offers “38 Model Headlines for Your ‘Swipe File.&amp;rsquo;” Here are some headlines ideas that came to mind, all geared to an Anglican context (due to my work at AnglicanCompass.com).
Why are Anglicans so angry? How do I use the Book of Common Prayer? How can I become an Anglican? What do Anglicans believe?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want a taste of what my dissertation is about? Read these two passages (Dissertation Dispatch, 2020-04-03)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/want-a-taste-of-what-my-dissertation-is-about-read-these-two-passages-dissertation-dispatch-2020-04-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 13:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/want-a-taste-of-what-my-dissertation-is-about-read-these-two-passages-dissertation-dispatch-2020-04-03/</guid>
      <description>What does “religion” mean? Great question! I’m writing my dissertation on Barth, Bonhoeffer, the Bible, and “religion.” However, getting clear on just what Barth and Bonhoeffer meant by “religion” is a huge challenge. It’s what I devoted my entire writing sample to examining, and I plan to devote an entire chapter of my dissertation to the topic.
Neither Barth nor Bonhoeffer used the word “religion” in the way that we’re prone to use the word in everyday speech today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What did Barth and Bonhoeffer think of the Bible? (Dissertation Dispatch, 2020-03-30)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-did-barth-and-bonhoeffer-think-of-the-bible-dissertation-dispatch-2020-03-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 14:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-did-barth-and-bonhoeffer-think-of-the-bible-dissertation-dispatch-2020-03-30/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying to parse out the relevance of Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s engagement with Scripture for making sense of the “Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship.” Specifically, I’m trying to, at the very least, add some biblical content and context to the ongoing debate over the relationship between Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s theological critiques of religion.
As I put it in the “elevator pitch” for my dissertation proposal:
Why does Bonhoeffer in prison, after adopting Barth’s theological critique of religion as idolatrous unbelief…</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible: Back to the Beginning (Dissertation Dispatch, 2020-03-26)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible-back-to-the-beginning-dissertation-dispatch-2020-03-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 14:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible-back-to-the-beginning-dissertation-dispatch-2020-03-26/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps it’s just the global COVID–19 pandemic, but I’ve been really discouraged about my dissertation lately.
My normal reading/writing workflow has ground to a halt because (1) we are temporarily without childcare and (2) my wife, a Family Nurse Practitioner is still working full-time from the office. That leaves me home alone with our 1.5-year-old during the week and, while she is a wonderful child, she’s not really jazzed about dad sitting quietly in a corner getting some reading and writing done during the day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Prayers for Tough Days</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/12-prayers-for-tough-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 21:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/12-prayers-for-tough-days/</guid>
      <description>The “Occasional Prayers” section of the Book of Common Prayer is a goldmine, particularly when the going gets tough.
The following prayers come from the Anglican Church in North America’s 2019 Book of Common Prayer. You can view the text of the 2019 BCP here. And you can download a Word document containing all of the Occasional Prayers here.
58. FOR A PERSON IN TROUBLE OR BEREAVEMENT O merciful Father, you have taught us in your holy Word that you do not willingly afflict or grieve the children of men: Look with pity on the sorrows of your servant N.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Sermon on the Mount (Dissertation Dispatch 2020-02-04)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-sermon-on-the-mount-dissertation-dispatch-2020-02-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 18:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-sermon-on-the-mount-dissertation-dispatch-2020-02-04/</guid>
      <description>I’m still very much in the weeds, taking a closer look at how Bonhoeffer and Barth read the Sermon on the Mount.
Given the importance of the Sermon on Mount for Bonhoeffer’s life and work, I’m persuaded that there’s something important to be found here—something that will hopefully shed some light on the Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship re:their theological critiques of religion.
Additionally, there are at least two other tidbits that have me interested in how Barth and Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help! I&amp;#8217;m looking for examples of &amp;#8220;theological triage,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;doctrinal taxonomy,&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;dogmatic rank&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-looking-for-examples-of-theological-triage-doctrinal-taxonomy-or-dogmatic-rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 16:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-looking-for-examples-of-theological-triage-doctrinal-taxonomy-or-dogmatic-rank/</guid>
      <description>For a research project, I’m looking for examples of the reasoning that goes into what’s been called, among other things
“theological triage,” “doctrinal taxonomy,” or “dogmatic rank.” I’m referring to the process of distinguishing between various levels of importance when it comes to theological statements/positions.
So, for example, the Trinity would usually be considered a “first-order” or “primary” doctrine—a “dogma,” if you will. But a specific view of the end times would usually be considered a “second-order,” “secondary,” or “tertiary” doctrine—AKA “adiaphora.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are the Beatitudes “Renunciations” (Verzichte)?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</guid>
      <description>In Discipleship (DBWE 4), Dietrich Bonhoeffer frames all of the Beatitudes in terms of Jesus’ disciples living in renunciation (Verzicht) and want (Mangel).
Interestingly, for Bonhoeffer, Jesus is only speaking to his disciples in the Beatitudes (he makes this argument on the basis of Luke 6:20ff.). And the disciples’ renunciation and want are caused by Jesus’s call to discipleship.
Jesus sees: his disciples are over there. They have visibly left the people to join him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are the Beatitudes “Good Works”? (Matt. 5:13–16)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/are-the-beatitudes-good-works-matt-51316/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 19:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/are-the-beatitudes-good-works-matt-51316/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I wrote just a bit about interpretive approaches to the Beatitudes in Matthew 5. I’m trying to get a better handle on how Barth and Bonhoeffer treat the Sermon on the Mount, and I’m starting with the Beatitudes.
However, it’s pretty challenging to situate Barth and Bonhoeffer in light of the “standard” approaches to both the Beatitudes and the Sermon on the Mount. A case in point: yesterday, I felt pretty confident that Bonhoeffer does not take the standard “entrance requirements” approach to the Beatitudes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With baby #2 on the way, I&amp;#8217;m looking for work!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/with-baby-2-on-the-way-im-looking-for-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 16:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/with-baby-2-on-the-way-im-looking-for-work/</guid>
      <description>I’m a husband to Rachel and a father to Eva.
I’m also:
An Anglican Priest (serving/volunteering without pay) A Ph.D. Student at Wheaton College (full-time, including a fellowship as a Teaching/Research Assistant) Managing Editor of AnglicanPastor.com (part-time) In May 2020, my full-time residential obligations to Wheaton’s Ph.D. program will come to an end. I’ll still need to finish my dissertation in the following 1-2 years (the sooner, the better!), but I will no longer have to work on campus as a teaching/research assistant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Beatitudes</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 19:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</guid>
      <description>As I said in my previous post, “Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount,” I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.
Of course, when interpreting the Sermon on the Mount, the best place to start is at the beginning! This means beginning with the Beatitudes in Matthew 5:1–12.
The Beatitudes (Matt. 5:1–12) 1 When Jesus saw the crowds, he went up the mountain; and after he sat down, his disciples came to him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 22:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</guid>
      <description>I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.
In order to help situate my discussion of Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s readings, I’m trying to get a better grasp of the various interpretive approaches to the Sermon on the Mount. So far, the most exhaustive Sermon on the Mount “interpretive taxonomy” that I’ve found has been from Grant Osborne’s Matthew (Zondervan Exegetical Commentary on the New Testament; Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2010), 159.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damer’s “Code of Intellectual Conduct”</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/damers-code-of-intellectual-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 15:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/damers-code-of-intellectual-conduct/</guid>
      <description>This code of conduct very much relates to Rapoport’s Rules, Adler’s advice, and Alan Jacobs’s “The Thinking Person’s Checklist.”
SOURCE: T. Edward Damer, Attacking Faulty Reasoning: A Practical Guide to Fallacy-Free Arguments, 6th ed (Australia ; Belmont, CA: Wadsworth/Cengage Learning, 2009), 7–8.
## 1. The Fallibility Principle Each participant in a discussion of a disputed issue should be willing to accept the fact that he or she is fallible, which means that one must acknowledge that one’s own initial view may not be the most defensible position on the question.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking Scripture and Women’s Ordination Seriously: A Response to Blake Johnson and Lee Nelson</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/</guid>
      <description>Editor’s Note: Thank you to the Rev. Dr. Emily McGowin for writing this rejoinder to Fr. Blake Johnson’s and Fr. Lee Nelson’s responses to her original blog post about the in persona Christi argument against women’s ordination. While we invite this conversation (about McGowin’s original blog post) to continue in our comments section and elsewhere—and we plan to publish more about women’s ordination in the future—we will not be adding surrejoinder blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alan Jacobs’s “The Thinking Person’s Checklist”</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/alan-jacobss-the-thinking-persons-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/alan-jacobss-the-thinking-persons-checklist/</guid>
      <description>The following checklist, found on pages 155–56 of Alan Jacobs’s excellent book, How to Think: A Survival Guide for a World at Odds (affiliate link), is a worthy addition to “Rapoport’s Rules” and “Adler’s Advice” (mentioned in my previous post, “Help me come up with ‘rules for conversation’!”).
Emphasis added in **bold**. When faced with provocation to respond to what someone has said, give it five minutes. Take a walk, or weed the garden, or chop some vegetables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me come up with “rules for conversation”!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-come-up-with-rules-for-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 20:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-come-up-with-rules-for-conversation/</guid>
      <description>In my role as Managing Editor for AnglicanPastor.com, I’m realizing the need to develop some “rules for conversation.”
We describe the tone that we’re after as “clarity and charity,” which is an excellent summary. However, to guide our blogposts and comments, I think we need something more detailed and concrete.
With that in mind, “Rapoport’s Rules” and “Adler’s Advice” seem like excellent starting points.
But, if you have any further suggestions, please let me know in the comments!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quit claiming that we mutualists (egalitarians) don&amp;#8217;t take the Bible or tradition seriously.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/quit-claiming-that-we-mutualists-egalitarians-dont-take-the-bible-or-tradition-seriously/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 16:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/quit-claiming-that-we-mutualists-egalitarians-dont-take-the-bible-or-tradition-seriously/</guid>
      <description>In the ongoing debate about women’s ordination (in the Anglican realm and beyond), I keep hearing oversimplified claims from hierarchicalists (or “complementarians,” but that’s not the most helpful term in this debate) that they have the entirety of the Bible and Church tradition on their side.
Therefore, we mutualists (or “egalitarians,” but that’s not the most helpful term in this debate), it is argued, have arrived at our positions for various reasons—perhaps capitulation to liberal cultural trends and hermeneutical methods—but not because we’ve read Scripture or studied the history of the Church very carefully.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No One Knows what &amp;#8220;Positivism of Revelation&amp;#8221; Means!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/no-one-knows-what-positivism-of-revelation-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 02:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/no-one-knows-what-positivism-of-revelation-means/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship, there is perhaps no greater conundrum than the meaning of what Bonhoeffer called Barth’s “Offenbarungspositivismus” (“positivism of revelation” or “revelatory positivism”) in his Letters and Papers from Prison (DBWE 8).
Now, before we proceed, please note that Bonhoeffer meant something very particular by “religion” in his prison letters. For an overview of how Bonhoeffer and Barth differed on the meaning of “religion,” and what that means for how we interpret their theological critiques of religion, please see my essay: “To Be or Not To Be Religious: A Clarification of Karl Barth’s and Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Divergence and Convergence Regarding Religion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&amp;#8217;m quite excited for these Oxford Handbooks!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-quite-excited-for-these-oxford-handbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 16:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-quite-excited-for-these-oxford-handbooks/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve not yet consulted the Oxford Handbook series, you should! The Oxford Handbook of Systematic Theology is especially useful!
I’m very excited because the Oxford Handbook of Dietrich Bonhoeffer and the Oxford Handbook of Karl Barth are both about to be released soon!
I just wish they weren’t so expensive!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My favorite definition of &amp;#8220;theology&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-definition-of-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 21:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-definition-of-theology/</guid>
      <description>This is from Robert Jenson, Systematic Theology, Volume 1, p. 11:
The church has a mission: to see to the speaking of the gospel, whether to the world as message of salvation or to God as appeal and praise. Theology is the reflection internal to the church’s labor on this assignment.
(How) does this definition of “theology” differ from the one you’ve been working with?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth Timeline: A Chronology of Karl Barth&amp;#8217;s Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-timeline-a-chronology-of-karl-barths-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 16:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-timeline-a-chronology-of-karl-barths-life/</guid>
      <description>I really like the timelines of Bonhoeffer’s life that are available in The Cambridge Companion to Dietrich Bonhoeffer and in Bethge’s Dietrich Bonhoeffer: A Biography. (Those last two links are Amazon affiliate links.)
However, I’m having a much harder time finding comparable timelines for the life of Karl Barth. The information is all there, but there’s no comparable table/list of dates in either The Cambridge Companion to Karl Barth or Busch’s Karl Barth: His Life from Letters and Autobiographical Texts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonhoeffer Timeline: A Chronology of Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bonhoeffer-timeline-a-brief-chronology-of-dietrich-bonhoeffers-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 15:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bonhoeffer-timeline-a-brief-chronology-of-dietrich-bonhoeffers-life/</guid>
      <description>The Cambridge Companion to Dietrich Bonhoeffer SOURCE (Amazon affiliate link): John W. de Gruchy, ed., The Cambridge Companion to Dietrich Bonhoeffer (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1999), xxiv–xxvi.
1906, 4 February, Dietrich Bonhoeffer born in Breslau, Germany
1912 Family moves to Berlin, where Karl Bonhoeffer, Dietrich’s father, takes up a position at Berlin University
1913 Dietrich Bonhoeffer begins gymnasium studies
1916 Family moves to the suburb of Grunewald
1918 Walter Bonhoeffer, Dietrich’s brother, dies on the western front</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Dispatch: 2019-11-11</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-11-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 18:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-11-11/</guid>
      <description>I’m narrowing my focus to Genesis 1–3 and the Sermon on the Mount. Originally, my dissertation proposal cast a very wide net. I was going to have the following chapters:
Introduction (5,000 words) Chapter 1: Creation and Fall (Genesis 1–3) (16,000 words) Chapter 2: The Prophets (16,000 words) Chapter 3: The Gospels (16,000 words) Chapter 4: The Epistle to the Romans (16,000 words) Chapter 5: Completing the Biblical Critique of Religion (16,000 words) Summary and Conclusion (5,000 words) However, after doing survey work, and spending most of the previous academic year working on Barth and Bonhoeffer’s reading of Genesis 1–3, I’ve decided to narrow my focus down to Genesis 1–3 and the Sermon on the Mount.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&amp;#8220;True Christianity cannot be a private Christianity&amp;#8221; (Barth)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/true-christianity-cannot-be-a-private-christianity-barth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 18:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/true-christianity-cannot-be-a-private-christianity-barth/</guid>
      <description>![](https://i0.wp.com/joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Karl-Barth-Quote-Green.png?fit=640%2C360&amp;ssl=1)&gt; In short, if I am inhuman, I am also stupid and foolish and godless. The great crisis in which all worship and piety and adoration and prayer and theology constantly finds itself derives of course from the question whether and how far in these things we really have to do with the true and living God who reveals Himself in His Word, and not with an idol. But this question is decided concretely in practice by another one which is inseparable from it—whether and how far in these things we come before God together and not apart from and against one another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&amp;#8217;s a video of my ordination to the Priesthood</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-a-video-of-my-ordination-to-the-priesthood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 22:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-a-video-of-my-ordination-to-the-priesthood/</guid>
      <description>My Bishop, Todd Hunter, preached [an excellent, challenging sermon (“Love Your Enemies, Really?”)](https://friendsofthesavior.org/sermons/love-your-enemies-really-bishop-todd-hunter). It’s definitely worth a listen!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Deacon&amp;#8217;s Last Day</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-deacons-last-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 02:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-deacons-last-day/</guid>
      <description>Lord Jesus, you are the Good Shepherd who cares for his flock: We ask you to bestow upon your Church the gifts of the Holy Spirit in abundance, and to raise up from among us faithful and able persons called to the ministries of Deacon, Priest, and Bishop. Inspire them to spend and be spent for the sake of the Gospel, and make them holy and loving servants and shepherds of the flock for whom you shed your most precious blood.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;m committing myself to as a priest.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-what-im-committing-myself-to-as-a-priest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-what-im-committing-myself-to-as-a-priest/</guid>
      <description>I’m getting ordained to the priesthood this Saturday, November 02. For public/posterity’s sake, I wanted to post some of the main parts of the ordination liturgy (from the ACNA’s 2019 Book of Common Prayer).
The Presentation The Bishop and People sit. The Presenters, standing before the Bishop, present the Ordinand, saying
Reverend Father in God, we present N.N. to be admitted to the Order of Priests.
Bishop: Has he been selected in accordance with the Canons of this Church?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer for Relatives and Friends</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-for-relatives-and-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-for-relatives-and-friends/</guid>
      <description>O Loving Father, we commend to your gracious keeping all who are near and dear to us.
Have mercy upon any who are sick, and comfort those who are in pain, anxiety, or sorrow.
Awaken all who are careless about eternal things.
Bless those who are young and in health, that they may give the days of their strength to you.
Comfort the aged and infirm, that your peace may rest upon them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following Christ as a Hermeneutical Problem?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-christ-as-a-hermeneutical-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-christ-as-a-hermeneutical-problem/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying to puzzle out the meaning of the following paragraph from Bonhoeffer’s Discipleship (DBWE 4).
Fundamentally eliminating simple obedience introduces a principle of scripture foreign to the Gospel.[19] According to it, in order to understand scripture, one first must have a key to interpreting it. But that key would not be the living Christ himself in judgment and grace, and using the key would not be according to the will of the living Holy Spirit alone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two of Bonhoeffer&amp;#8217;s Most Convicting Paragraphs</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-of-bonhoeffers-most-convicting-paragraphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-of-bonhoeffers-most-convicting-paragraphs/</guid>
      <description>The following is from Bonhoeffer’s Discipleship (usually known as “The Cost of Discipleship” in English, although the original title in German was simply Nachfolge).
Bonhoeffer considers how we might respond to Jesus if Jesus were to show up and make the same kinds of concrete commands that he did in the Gospels.
NOTE: I’ve taken two paragraphs in the original and broken them up into smaller chunks to facilitate reading here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&amp;#8220;Why You Never See Your Friends Anymore&amp;#8221; (The Atlantic)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/why-you-never-see-your-friends-anymore-the-atlantic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 16:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/why-you-never-see-your-friends-anymore-the-atlantic/</guid>
      <description>Judith Shulevitz offers up a (depressing) eye-opening analysis of our overbusy lives. There is another way! But community and Sabbath both require sacrifice.
Whereas we once shared the same temporal rhythms—five days on, two days off, federal holidays, thank-God-it’s-Fridays—our weeks are now shaped by the unpredictable dictates of our employers. Nearly a fifth of Americans hold jobs with nonstandard or variable hours. They may work seasonally, on rotating shifts, or in the gig economy driving for Uber or delivering for Postmates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the most important theological terms that every Christian should know?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-the-most-important-theological-terms-that-every-christian-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 14:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-the-most-important-theological-terms-that-every-christian-should-know/</guid>
      <description>Which theological terms would make your shortlist?
Here’s the list of terms found in “Jargon-Busting: A Glossary of Theological Terms,” at the back of Alister E. McGrath’s excellent Christian Theology: An Introduction (25th Anniversary Edition).
adoptionism aggiornamento Alexandrian School allegory Anabaptism analogy of being (analogia entis) analogy of faith (analogia fidei) anthropomorphism Antiochene School anti-Pelagian writings apocalyptic apologetics apophatic apostolic era appropriation Arianism atonement Barthian beatific vision Beatitudes Calvinism Cappadocian fathers Cartesianism catechism catharsis catholic Chalcedonian definition charisma, charismatic Charismatic movement Christology circumincessio conciliarism confession consubstantial consubstantiation contemplation creed Deism dialectical theology Docetism Donatism doxology Ebionitism ecclesiology Enlightenment eschatology Eucharist evangelical exegesis exemplarism fathers fideism filioque Five Ways fourth gospel fundamentalism hermeneutics hesychasm historical Jesus historico-critical method history of religions school homoousios humanism hypostatic union icons ideology incarnation justification by faith, doctrine of kenoticism kerygma liberal Protestantism liberation theology liturgy logos Lutheranism Manicheism modalism monophysitism neo-orthodoxy ontological argument orthodoxy parousia patripassianism patristic Pelagianism perichoresis Pietism postliberalism postmodernism praxis Protestantism Quadriga radical Reformation Reformed Sabellianism sacrament schism scholasticism Scripture principle Socinianism soteriology synoptic gospels synoptic problem theodicy theopaschitism theotokos Thomism transubstantiation Trinity two natures, doctrine of typology Vulgate Zwinglianism </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “Via Media”? Or the “Middle Ground Fallacy”?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-via-media-or-the-middle-ground-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-via-media-or-the-middle-ground-fallacy/</guid>
      <description>At this point, this is just a sketch. But I’m wondering how we Anglican Christians ought to be careful to keep our precious “via media” (“middle way”) mentality and methodology separate from what’s known as the “middle ground” fallacy.
The “Via Media” According to Donald McKim in the Westminster Dictionary of Theological Terms, the “via media” is
(Lat. “the middle way”) Term used to describe the identity of Anglicanism as a middle way between Roman Catholicism and Protestantism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here are all of William Witt&amp;#8217;s essays on Women&amp;#8217;s ordination, in a single PDF (with bookmarks!)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/here-are-all-of-william-witts-essays-on-womens-ordination-in-a-single-pdf-with-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/here-are-all-of-william-witts-essays-on-womens-ordination-in-a-single-pdf-with-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Over on his blog, “Non Sermoni Res,” Dr. William Witt has written several excellent essays on the topic of women’s ordination.
Here’s the guide that Witt put together in order to orient readers to his essays.
What I’ve done is to combine the blog posts into a single PDF, with bookmarks. Here it is:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Women Can Be Saved, Then Women Can Be Priests: A Critique of the &amp;#8220;in persona Christi&amp;#8221; Argument Against Women&amp;#8217;s Ordination</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 05:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</guid>
      <description>Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Pastor does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.
After reading this piece, please see Lee Nelson’s response and Emily McGowin’s rejoinder.
The connection between christology and soteriology A cornerstone of orthodox Christian theology is summed up in the phrase “what is not assumed is not healed”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Outline of Karl Barth&amp;#8217;s Church Dogmatics</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/an-outline-of-karl-barths-church-dogmatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 15:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/an-outline-of-karl-barths-church-dogmatics/</guid>
      <description>![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/BarthTimeline-2-1024x536-1024x536.png)[Karl Barth’s Church Dogmatics Original Publication Dates, courtesy of PostBarthian.com](https://postbarthian.com/2016/04/21/karl-barths-church-dogmatics-original-publication-dates/).If you’re trying to grasp the contours and contents of Karl Barth’s massive *[Church Dogmatics](https://www.logos.com/product/5758/barths-church-dogmatics),* it helps to have an outline! Here’s a helpful PDF version, with subheadings included, from Princeton’s [Center for Barth Studies](http://barth.ptsem.edu). [Barth\_Outline of Church Dogmatics](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Barth_Outline-of-Church-Dogmatics.pdf)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Barth_Outline-of-Church-Dogmatics.pdf)Below is a version that I’ve created from my Logos edition of *Church Dogmatics*. It’s the version found in the Index (CD V/1, 1–13).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Writing Templates</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/helpful-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 14:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/helpful-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>The following templates come from They Say / I Say: The Moves That Matter in Academic Writing.
Introducing What They Say A number of $$$ have recently suggested that $$$. It has become common today to dismiss $$$. In their recent work, Y and Z have offered harsh critiques of Dr. X for $$$. Introducing Standard Views American today tend to believe that $$$ Conventional wisdom has it that $$$ Common sense seems to dictate that $$$ The standard way of thinking about topic X has it that $$$ It is often said that $$$ My whole life I have heard it said that $$$ You would think that $$$ Many people assumed that $$$ Making What They Say Something You Say</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Dispatch: 2019-08-09</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-08-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 15:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-08-09/</guid>
      <description>This summer, I’ve spent most of my reading/writing time working on a paper on Barth’s Römerbrief reading of Romans 10. This paper is for the 2019 Barth Graduate Student Colloquium, and it has taken way longer than I originally anticipated.
Will I get to use this paper in my dissertation? I’m not sure.
At first, I got excited, because, in my work on Genesis 1–3 last school year, I discovered some differences in how Barth and Bonhoeffer handled Genesis 1–3 vis-a-vis the subsequent history of Israel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Guilt of Karl Barth: Strengths and Weaknesses of Barth’s Römerbrief Reading of Romans 9:30–10:21</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-guilt-of-karl-barth-strengths-and-weaknesses-of-barths-romerbrief-reading-of-romans-9301021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 14:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-guilt-of-karl-barth-strengths-and-weaknesses-of-barths-romerbrief-reading-of-romans-9301021/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Here is the paper that I gave at the 2019 Karl Barth Graduate Student Colloquium at the Center for Barth Studies at Princeton Theological Seminary.
INTRODUCTION: “GENTILES” = “WORLD” IS WORSE THAN “ISRAEL” = “CHURCH” On at least one level, Karl Barth’s Römerbrief reading of Romans 9–11 is supersessionist. In general, especially in the second edition, when Paul refers to “Israel” in Romans 9–11, Barth refers to the “Church.”[1] He replaces Israel with the Church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I think Karl Barth missed the (pastoral) point of Romans</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-think-karl-barth-missed-the-pastoral-point-of-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 15:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-think-karl-barth-missed-the-pastoral-point-of-romans/</guid>
      <description>I’m scheduled to give a paper on Karl Barth’s reading of Romans 9:30–10:21 in Der Römerbrief at the 2019 Barth Graduate Student Colloquium at Princeton in August.
Now, of course, it’s a pleasure and a privilege to give a paper at the colloquium. However, in hindsight, I don’t know why I thought giving a paper on chapter 10 of Barth’s Römerbrief was a good idea!
Granted, I don’t have to solve all of the exegetical issues (of which there are many) in Romans 9:30–10:21.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 16:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible/</guid>
      <description>John Webster’s Idea Like so many others, I desperately wish that John Webster were still alive.
After all, my dissertation topic owes much to his essay: “Reading the Bible: The Example of Barth and Bonhoeffer.”
The essay (previously published as ‘“In the Shadow of Biblical Work:” Barth and Bonhoeffer on Reading the Bible,’and then published in Word and Church: Essays in Christian Dogmatics) begins:
Two things at least are clear about the relationship of Barth and Bonhoeffer: that disentangling the history of their relation is of considerable importance for making sense of Bonhoeffer, if not of Barth; and that the disentangling is a rather delicate operation which involves some discriminating interpretation of the writings of two complex theologians.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Dispatch: 2019-07-05</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-07-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 21:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-07-05/</guid>
      <description>I got my dissertation proposal approved in the Spring of 2018. Working title: “Scriptural but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion.”
Barth + Bonhoeffer + Bible + Religion. “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and Bible” is the gap/niche. But that would be too much to tackle comprehensively in a dissertation. So “religion” is designed to be the delimiter—specifically, Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s theological critiques of religion.
Dissertation-wise, I didn’t make as much progress as I would’ve liked to during the 2018–19 school year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desperate Times, Desperate Measures: Writing My Dissertation vs. Funding Abortion</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/desperate-times-desperate-measures-writing-my-dissertation-vs-funding-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 13:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/desperate-times-desperate-measures-writing-my-dissertation-vs-funding-abortion/</guid>
      <description>I’m two years in to my PhD program, and I need to finish writing this dissertation soon, or it’s going to be the death of me!
Don’t get me wrong. I love Wheaton’s program. My supervisor and second reader are fantastic. And I think that this Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible project is worthwhile.
But I’ve got a wife, a kid, a commitment to the Church, and I need to move on with my life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Sermons and Meditations</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dietrich-bonhoeffers-sermons-and-meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 15:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dietrich-bonhoeffers-sermons-and-meditations/</guid>
      <description>SOURCE: Dietrich Bonhoeffer, Indexes and Supplementary Materials, ed. Victoria J. Barnett et al., vol. 17, Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2014), 154–158.
Sermons and Meditations Address on Jeremiah 27–28—(DBWE vol. )9 Address on John 19—9 Address on Luke 12:35ff.—9 Address on Matthew 21:28–31—9 Address on the Decalogue—9 Address on the First Commandment—9 Baptismal Homily on Joshua 24:15—13 Baptism Sermon on 1 John 4:16—11 Baptism Sermon on Ephesians 5:14—11 Bible Reading and Prayer on 1 Corinthians 4:20—13 Biblical Reflection: Morning—14 Catechesis in the Second Theological Examination on the Fifth Petition of the Lord’s Prayer—10 Catechetical Examination on Matthew 8:5–13—9 Catechetical Outline concerning the Second Article of Faith—9 Children’s Address on Psalm 24:7–9 Communion Homily on 1 Corinthians 15:55—15 Confession Homily on Micah 4:9—15 Confirmation—15 Confirmation Question Confirmation Sermon on Mark 9:24 Confirmation Verses Devotional Aids for the Moravian Daily Texts—16 Daily Text Meditation for June 7 and 8, 1944 Daily Text Meditation for Pentecost 1944 Devotions on John 8:31–32—11 Devotions on Luke 4:3–4—11 Devotions on Luke 4:5–8—11 Draft for a Catechism: As You Believe, So You Receive—11 Draft for a Liturgy, Remembrance Sunday—10 Draft for a Liturgy, Reminiscere (Memorial Day)—10 Opening Liturgy Prayer Draft for Worship Service on 2 Corinthians 2:14; 6:10; 6:1—15 Exegesis and Catechetical Lesson on Luke 9:57–62—9 Exegesis and Sermon on James 1:21–25—9 Exposition on Romans 9–11 (Student Notes)—14 Exposition on the First Table of the Ten Words of God—16 Fragment of a Wedding Sermon—13 Funeral Address on Luke 2:29–30—13 Funeral Liturgy and Homily on Proverbs 23:26 for Hans-Friedrich von Kleist-Retzow—16 Guide to Scriptural Meditation—14 Homily for the Children’s Service—10 Homily on Daniel 10:1, 8, 16–19—12 Liturgy for a Seminar Worship Service—12 Liturgy Fragment for Christmas—15 Marriage Sermon on Ruth 1:16–17—13 Meditation and Catechetical Lesson on “Honor”—9 Meditation and Sermon on Luke 9:51–56 for the Theological Examination—9 Meditation on Luke 9:57–62—13 Meditation on Psalm 119—15 Bonhoeffer’s Meditation (Fragment) Two Structural Outlines of Psalm 119 Notes for a Young Man—10 Outline for a Homily for Personal Confession on Proverbs 28:13–14 Outline on Proverbs 3:27–33—14 Recommended Devotions on Jeremiah 16:21 and Ephesians 1:22–23—16 Sermon for Evening Worship Service on 2 Corinthians 12:9—13 Sermon for Evening Worship Service on Proverbs 16:9–13 Sermon for the Lector on Matthew 2:13–23—15 Sermon for the Second Theological Examination on 1 Thessalonians 5:16–18—10 Sermon (Fragment) on Deuteronomy 32:48–52—10 Sermon (Fragment) on Luke 12:49—10 Sermon (Fragment) on Matthew 7:1—10 Sermon (Fragment) on Song of Solomon 8:6b—10 Sermon Meditation on Isaiah 9:6–7—16 Sermon Meditation on Revelation 2:1–7—14 Sermon Meditations—15 Sermon Meditation on John 3:16–21 for the Second Day of Pentecost Sermon Meditation on John 10:11–16 for Misericordias Domini Sunday Sermon Meditation on John 14:23–31 for the First Day of Pentecost Sermon Meditations on John 20:19–31 for Quasimodogeniti Sunday Sermon on 1 Corinthians 2:7–10—13 Sermon on 1 Corinthians 12:27, 26—10 Sermon on 1 Corinthians 13:1–3—13 Sermon on 1 Corinthians 13:4–7—13 Sermon on 1 Corinthians 13:8–12—13 Sermon on 1 Corinthians 13:13—13 Sermon on 1 Corinthians 15:17—10 Pulpit Notes Sermon Sermon on 1 John 2:17—10 Sermon on 1 John 4:16—10, 11 Sermon on 1 Peter 1:7b–9—12 Sermon on 2 Chronicles 20:12—11 Sermon on 2 Corinthians 5:10—13 Sermon on 2 Corinthians 5:20—13 Sermon on 2 Corinthians 12:9—10 Sermon on Colossians 3:1–4—11 Sermon on Genesis 32:25–32; 33:10—11 Sermon on Exodus 32:1–8, 15–16, 18–20, 30–35—12 Sermon on Jeremiah 20:7—13 Sermon on John 8:32—11 Sermon on Judges 6:15–16; 7:2; 8:23—12 Sermon on Luke 1:39–56—14 Sermon on Luke 1:46–55 Sermon on Luke 12:35–40—11 Sermon on Luke 13:1–5—13 Sermon on Luke 16:19–31—11 Sermon on Luke 17:7–10—9 Sermon on Luke 17:33—10 Sermon on Luke 21:28—13 Sermon on Mark 9:23–24—13 Sermon on Matthew 5:8—10 Sermon on Matthew 8:23–27—12 Sermon on Matthew 11:28–30—13 Sermon on Matthew 16:13–18—12 Sermon on Matthew 18:21–35—14 Sermon on Matthew 24:6–14—11 Sermon on Matthew 26:45b–50—14 Sermon on Matthew 28:20—10 Sermon on Philippians 4:7—10 Sermon on Psalm 42—14 Sermon on Psalm 58—14 Sermon on Psalm 62:2—10 Sermon on Psalm 63:3—11 Sermon on Psalm 90—14 Sermon on Psalm 98:1—13 Sermon on Psalm 127:1—9 Sermon on Revelation 2:4–5, 7—12 Sermon on Revelation 3:20—10 Sermon on Revelation 14:6–13—14 Sermon on Romans 5:1–5—15 Sermon on Romans 11:6—10 Sermon on Romans 12:11c—10 Sermon on Romans 12:17–21—15 Sermon on Wisdom 3:3—13 Sermon on Zechariah 3:1–5—14 Supplements to the Monthly Letters from the Confessing Church Council of Brethren in Pomerania to Its Pastors—15 Meditation on Christmas Meditation on Epiphany Theological Reflection on the Lord’s Supper Wedding Sermon from the Prison Cell—8 Wedding Sermon on 1 Thessalonians 5:16–18—14 Wedding Sermon on John 13:34—14 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tree of Religion: Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge in Genesis 2:4–3:24</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-tree-of-religion-karl-barth-and-dietrich-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-in-genesis-24-324/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 15:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-tree-of-religion-karl-barth-and-dietrich-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-in-genesis-24-324/</guid>
      <description>(Here’s a PDF of this paper: STEELE_The Tree of Religion Barth and Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge.)
Introduction The precise meaning of the “tree of the knowledge of good and evil” (=TK) has long vexed interpreters of Genesis 2:4–3:24.[1] While the “tree of life” (=TL) is mentioned and alluded to throughout the Bible, the TK is explicitly mentioned by its full name just twice (Gen. 2:9, 17).[2] Nevertheless, because of the significant role that the TK plays in the narrative, both Dietrich Bonhoeffer and Karl Barth highlight the TK in their theological interpretations of Genesis 1–3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When will Thy Kingdom Come? The Timing and Agency of the Kingdom of God in the Lord&amp;#8217;s Prayer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/when-will-thy-kingdom-come-the-timing-and-agency-of-the-kingdom-of-god-in-the-lords-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 15:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/when-will-thy-kingdom-come-the-timing-and-agency-of-the-kingdom-of-god-in-the-lords-prayer/</guid>
      <description>(Here’s a PDF of this paper: STEELE_When Will Thy Kingdom Come.)
Introduction: “Thy Kingdom [Has/Will] Come”? Just how eschatological is the Lord’s Prayer (=LP; Matt. 6:9–13; Luke 11:2–4), particularly in light of its second petition, “Your kingdom come” (ἐλθέτω ἡ βασιλεία σου, Matt. 6:10a; Luke 11:2d)? In other words, when will God’s kingdom come? Has it already arrived (not eschatological)? Is it in the process of arriving? Or will it arrive at some point in the future (eschatological)?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Into the Far Country</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/into-the-far-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 12:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/into-the-far-country/</guid>
      <description>Jesus Christ has gone into the far country in our stead, to bring us home to God!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only the Suffering God Can Help</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/only-the-suffering-god-can-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/only-the-suffering-god-can-help/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are your &amp;#8220;must-own&amp;#8221; biblical and theological studies reference works?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-your-must-own-biblical-and-theological-studies-reference-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 21:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-your-must-own-biblical-and-theological-studies-reference-works/</guid>
      <description>It just happened again. I had to consult “BDAG,” A Greek–English Lexicon of the New Testament and Other Early Christian Literature (3rd ed.).
I don’t own a copy, so every time I have to consult BDAG I think “I really should buy this.” But for the past decade or so, primarily because of BDAG’s cost ($150 on Logos, $130 used on Amazon, $165 new on Amazon) I’ve held off.
Nevertheless, I’m seeking to build my “must-have” personal reference library to sustain a ministry as a pastor theologian.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me achieve my home gym dream</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-achieve-my-home-gym-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 18:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-achieve-my-home-gym-dream/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying to put together a basic home gym in our basement apartment. Mainly, I’m interested in doing squats for now. Then, I’ll expand to deadlifts and benchpress. Our ceilings are too low for overhead presses, however.
Anyways, I just ordered the Valor Fitness BD-9 squat rack from Amazon.
I still need a decent Olympic bar and Olympic plates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn more about Rublev&amp;#8217;s Trinity icon [video]</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/learn-more-about-rublevs-trinity-icon-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/learn-more-about-rublevs-trinity-icon-video/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always wanted to learn more about Andrei Rublev’s famous icon of the Trinity. If you’re also curious, check out this video.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&amp;#8217;s learn how to be bored again</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-learn-how-to-be-bored-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 17:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-learn-how-to-be-bored-again/</guid>
      <description>From “In Praise of Boredom,” by James K.A. Smith.
But I know at least this: Instagram won’t save us, and tweeted verse will not undo what we’ve done to ourselves. But neither is there any special enchantment to reading in print. So this is not the Luddite’s redoubt, nostalgically canonizing codex or canvas as if history had come to an end in some glorious past. Every medium now reaches us inside the ecology of attention masterminded by Silicon Valley.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theology is exegesis: John Webster on what we can learn from Barth and Bonhoeffer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theology-is-exegesis-john-webster-on-what-we-can-learn-from-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 16:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theology-is-exegesis-john-webster-on-what-we-can-learn-from-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</guid>
      <description>John Webster’s essay, “Reading the Bible: The Example of Barth and Bonhoeffer” (pages 87–110 in Word and Church: Essays in Christian Dogmatics [Edinburgh; New York: T&amp;amp;T Clark, 2001]) is, in large part, the inspiration for my doctoral dissertation.
I’d like to share the three reflections/lessons Webster draws from the biblical work of Barth and Bonhoeffer.
Wrapping up his essay, Webster claims that
Neither Bonhoeffer nor Barth were wissenschaftlich theologians; both were practical or pastoral theologians of the church of Jesus Christ.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Rapoport&amp;#8217;s Rules for Better Conversations and Disagreements</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 17:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</guid>
      <description>I’m reading Walter Sinnott-Armstrong’s excellent book, Think Again: How to Reason and Argue.
In it (on pages 25–26), I came across “Rapoport’s Rules.”
First formulated by mathematical psychologist Anatol Rapoport and discussed by Daniel Dennett (Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking, 31–35), here they are:
1: You should attempt to re-express your target’s position so clearly, vividly, and fairly that your target says, “Thanks, I wish I’d thought of putting it that way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There&amp;#8217;s more than one kind of &amp;#8220;priesthood&amp;#8221; in the New Testament</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theres-more-than-one-kind-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 20:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theres-more-than-one-kind-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>Just came across this article in New Blackfriars, and it looks helpful, especially in the context of Anglican debates about women’s ordination.
Title: “The Four Types of Priesthood in the New Testament: On Avoiding Confusions about What ‘Priesthood’ Means”
Author: Geoffrey Turner
Abstract:
Christian discourse tends to treat the concept of ‘priesthood’ univocally, so that ordained priests are seen to share the priesthood of Christ. But a careful reading of Hebrews shows clearly that the priesthood of Christ is unique to him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women&amp;#8217;s Ordination Debates in Anglicanism: The 2017 ACNA Report and the 2003 AMIA Report</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/womens-ordination-debates-in-anglicanism-the-2017-acna-report-and-the-2003-amia-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/womens-ordination-debates-in-anglicanism-the-2017-acna-report-and-the-2003-amia-report/</guid>
      <description>I became an “egalitarian” in college, before I became an Anglican in seminary.
It’s taken some time for me to get used to the different contours of the women’s ordination debate within Anglicanism. Growing up, the debate was all about particular Bible verses and whether or not women could teach and preach. However, in Anglicanism, although those same questions/arguments are present, I hear much more about whether or not women can administer the sacraments as priests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to Learn More about Women’s Ordination Debates within Anglicanism? Start With These Resources</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you, like me, are coming to Anglicanism from a different tradition.
If that’s the case, then one thing you should know is that Anglican debates about women’s ordination can often be quite different from debates about the same topic in other church contexts.
This is due to Anglicans having different views on, among other things:
ecclesiology (the doctrine of the church), the sacraments, and ordination. For example, in my broadly evangelical/non-denominational/Baptist upbringing, debates about women in ministry centered on whether or not women were allowed to preach and teach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, the Bible, and &amp;#8220;What we ought to do&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-the-bible-and-what-we-ought-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 17:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-the-bible-and-what-we-ought-to-do/</guid>
      <description>Came across this Barth quote in Church Dogmatics II/2 this morning. I really like it, because it’s a good reminder that Barth valued the Bible. His distinction between the Bible as witness to the Word of God and Jesus Christ as the Word of God did not cause him to abandon the Scriptural witness.
It is as well to remind ourselves, at the conclusion of this analysis, that the question: What ought we to do?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth’s Gesamtausgabe (“Complete/Collected Edition”): A List of Works</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-gesamtausgabe-complete-collected-edition-a-list-of-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-gesamtausgabe-complete-collected-edition-a-list-of-works/</guid>
      <description>Note that, as of 2019-01-26, 54 volumes of the Gesamtausgabe have been published.
Unfortunately, only the first 45 of these are available in the Digital Karl Barth Library.
*I’ve marked volumes unavailable in the DKBL with an asterisk.
According to the publisher, TVZ:
Seit 1971 sind im Theologischen Verlag Zürich mehr als 50 Bände der Karl Barth-Gesamtausgabe erschienen. In ihr werden Barths Texte kritisch ediert und so präsentiert, dass sie für die wissenschaftliche Beschäftigung, aber auch für einen grösseren Interessentenkreis lesbar und zugänglich werden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A List of Karl Barth&amp;#8217;s Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</guid>
      <description>To make this list, I’ve used the data available in the Digital Karl Barth Library. I’ve just taken the tables of contents in the sermon volumes of Barth’s collected works and put them all in one place.
The only way to display the dates correctly in Markdown is to write these up as code blocks, as I’ve done below.
Predigten 1913 (GA I.8) 1. und 5. Januar (Neujahr): Prediger 1,9 12.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#8217;s the relationship between biblical and systematic/dogmatic theology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 15:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</guid>
      <description>This is the question we’re considering this week in our doctoral seminar on biblical and theological integration. Two of us are theologians and the other four are bible scholars. Should be interesting!
(Note: we’ll have to save the difference(s) between systematic, historical, and dogmatic theology for another post!)
Here are the articles we were assigned to read for this week:
D.A. Carson, “Systematic Theology and Biblical Theology” in the New Dictionary of Biblical Theology, pp.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spirit, Flesh, Restoration, and Sublimation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 18:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</guid>
      <description>There’s an intriguing passage in Bonhoeffer’s Letters and Papers from Prison where he discusses the relationship between “spirit” and “flesh,” in the context of discussing “restoration” and “sublimation,” in the context of discussing lyrics from certain hymns and songs that were meaningful to him in prison.
Here it is, from a December 19, 1943 (the Fourth Sunday of Advent) letter to Eberhard Bethge:
In recent weeks this line has been running through my head over and over: “Calm your hearts, dear friends; / whatever plagues you, / whatever fails you, / I will restore it all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StickKing to the Slow Carb Diet</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/stickking-to-the-slow-carb-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 02:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/stickking-to-the-slow-carb-diet/</guid>
      <description>Last night, the scale read 192.4. I’d really like it to read 180 or less.
So, in lieu of how effective putting money on the line via StickK has been for my daily writing habit these past two weeks, I’ve decided to put money on the line as motivation to stick to the Slow Carb Diet for a month.
For my writing habit, I’ve committed to writing 500 words toward my dissertation every day for 8 weeks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth and Bonhoeffer on Religion&amp;#8217;s False God(s)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-religions-false-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 19:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-religions-false-gods/</guid>
      <description>In The Epistle to the Romans, Barth writes the following concerning the false image of God at the heart of religion:
What men on this side resurrection name ‘God’ is most characteristically not God. Their ‘God’ does not redeem his creation, but allows free course to the unrighteousness of men; does not declare himself to be God, but is the complete affirmation of the course of the world and of men as it is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth&amp;#8217;s Reversal on the &amp;#8220;Knowledge of Good and Evil&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-reversal-on-the-knowledge-of-good-and-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-reversal-on-the-knowledge-of-good-and-evil/</guid>
      <description>I argue that, although Barth’s interpretation of the Genesis passages changed between The Epistle to the Romans and the Church Dogmatics, his mature readings of Genesis 2–3 still support his overall theological critique of religion as idolatry, the self-justifying positing of false gods.
Specifically, in Romans (240–57, esp. 246–51), Barth interpreted “the knowledge of good and evil” as the divine secret that humans are merely humans.
The prohibition of eating from the tree of knowledge thereby concealed the creator/creature distinction and was meant to enable a direct relationship between God and humans.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I wish these 2 Barth (and Bonhoeffer) books would come out sooner!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-wish-these-2-barth-and-bonhoeffer-books-would-come-out-sooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-wish-these-2-barth-and-bonhoeffer-books-would-come-out-sooner/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
I’m really looking forward to reading these two Barth (and Bonhoeffer) books coming out from Baker in 2019:
Freedom under the Word: Karl Barth’s Theological Exegesis. Edited by Ben Rhodes and Martin Westerholm. Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer: Theologians for a Post-Christian World. By Wolf Krötke. Translated by John P. Burgess. Freedom under the Word (May 2019) According to Baker:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer of Confession</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-of-confession/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 20:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-of-confession/</guid>
      <description>To start off the semester the other day, we prayed this prayer of confession together as a class. The professor didn’t remember where the prayer was from, so I tracked it down online. According to Justin Taylor, it was written by Bob Kauflin.
Holy and righteous God, we confess that like Isaiah, we are a people of unclean lips. But it is not only unclean lips we possess. We are people with unclean hands and unclean hearts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What blogs are you reading?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</guid>
      <description>Right now, I’m using the RSS readers Inoreader and Reeder to subscribe to the following blogs:
Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise. Seth’s Blog Study Hacks – Decoding Patterns of Success – Cal Newport James Clear Barking Up The Wrong Tree – How to be awesome at life. The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds McSweeney’s Internet Tendency Lifehacker – Do everything better What are you reading?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me StickK to my writing habit</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</guid>
      <description>I need to finish this dissertation.
To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.
Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I’ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it’s been a bear to get back on!
So, I’ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonhoeffer&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Definition&amp;#8221; of &amp;#8220;Religion&amp;#8221; in Prison: 15 Facets/Aspects</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bonhoeffers-definition-of-religion-in-prison-15-facets-aspects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 14:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bonhoeffers-definition-of-religion-in-prison-15-facets-aspects/</guid>
      <description>Based upon my own reading of Bonhoeffer’s Letters and Papers from Prison [DBWE 8], here is my attempt at a summary list of the facets/aspects of Bonhoeffer’s view of “religion” in prison.
Religion emphasizes inwardness. [DBWE 8:362, 364, 455–57] Religion emphasizes conscience. [DBWE 8:362] Religion is a temporary phenomenon. [DBWE 8:362, 364] Religion is manipulative and exploitative. [DBWE 8:363, 366, 426–27, 450, 455–57] Religion ignores human strength/knowledge/autonomy and instead focuses on human weakness, ignorance, and boundaries/limits/limitations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Christian Theology: A Draft Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 22:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>As a part of my “pedagogical experience” at Wheaton College this semester, I was required to draft a syllabus for an introduction to Christian theology. Feel free to let me know what you think in the comments.
Note: the length of this syllabus doesn’t necessarily correspond to the difficulty of this course
Contact Information Email: [REDACTED] Phone: [REDACTED] Office Hours (Buswell Library Carrell): T, W, R, 15:00–17:00. Course Description This course is an introduction to the methods of systematic theology and the major topics within biblical revelation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Karl Barth Software Drama Continues: Inaccurate Page Numbers in Logos</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-karl-barth-software-drama-continues-inaccurate-page-numbers-in-logos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 16:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-karl-barth-software-drama-continues-inaccurate-page-numbers-in-logos/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I wrote about how the Scripture search tool in the Digital Karl Barth Library was broken. Thankfully, it appears to have been fixed (although it still has issues). This means I can search Barth’s “Collected Edition” (Gesamtausgabe) if needed.
However, I’m now having some issues with the copy of Barth’s Church Dogmatics I purchased via Logos Bible Software.
Before I complain, let me first say how grateful I am that Logos is MUCH more user-friendly than the Digital Karl Barth Library.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing the Way of the Lord in the Wilderness: Luke 3:1-6</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/preparing-the-way-of-the-lord-in-the-wilderness-luke-31-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 15:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/preparing-the-way-of-the-lord-in-the-wilderness-luke-31-6/</guid>
      <description>I’d like to pray this week’s collect again:
Merciful God, who sent your messengers the prophets to preach repentance and prepare the way for our salvation: Give us grace to heed their warnings and forsake our sins, that we may greet with joy the coming of Jesus Christ our Redeemer; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen.
Introduction It’s been a particularly difficult week here at Church of the Savior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UPDATE: You can now search for Bible citations in the Digital Karl Barth Library again</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/update-you-can-now-search-for-bible-citations-in-the-digital-karl-barth-library-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/update-you-can-now-search-for-bible-citations-in-the-digital-karl-barth-library-again/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote about a problem I found in Alexander Street Press’ Digital Karl Barth Library: the Scripture citation search function no longer worked!
I’m happy to report that, though the DKBL is still far from user-friendly, the Bible search works again!
Now we just need some angel investors and programmers to produce a user-friendly version of the Digital Karl Barth Library! 🙂 Any takers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41482-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 17:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41482-2/</guid>
      <description>Black Friday! Capitalism! Death! Listen to this episode of Stuff You Should Know.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41480-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 17:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41480-2/</guid>
      <description>Go Blue!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41477-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 15:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41477-2/</guid>
      <description>The St Andrews Encyclopaedia of Theology sounds like it will be a marvelous resource! Think the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy, but for theology!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41475-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 19:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41475-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the best Advent/Christmas album I’ve ever listened to. The Oh Hellos Family Christmas Album</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41473-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 15:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41473-2/</guid>
      <description>If the “arc of history” bends toward anything other than randomness and destruction, it does so due to the grace of the Triune God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41471-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 11:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41471-2/</guid>
      <description>Interesting to compare the high holy day of Black Friday to the Christian liturgy. “Take and eat!” might sound similar to “consume!,” but they end up meaning very different things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41469-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41469-2/</guid>
      <description>I’m really interested in using Ryan Holiday’s/Robert Greene’s index card system.
Does anyone else out there use such a notecard system? If so, what do you use to store your index cards? I’m looking for a sturdy box to use for filing cards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a fantastic wooden pencil (Mitsubishi 9850)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</guid>
      <description>Just wanted to give a quick shout-out to this fantastic pencil: the Mitsubishi 9850.
It’s cheap, writes well, erases well, and looks great!
For more on wooden pencils, read this JetPens guide to the best wooden pencils. And, while you’re at it, check out JetPens’ recommendations for the best pencil sharpeners.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41433-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41433-2/</guid>
      <description>This is an aside test.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41431-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41431-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a status test.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;#8217;s gone wrong with the Digital Karl Barth Library?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-gone-wrong-with-the-digital-karl-barth-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 15:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-gone-wrong-with-the-digital-karl-barth-library/</guid>
      <description>As I slowly make progress on my dissertation (“Scriptural but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion”), I’m longing for the day when:
Karl Barth’s Gesamtausgabe (Collected Edition) is finished. They are translated into a critical English edition. They are available within the same database/framework as Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Works in English and German (DBWE and DBW). In the meantime, the Digital Karl Barth Library, provided by Alexander Street Press is the best resource out there for searching the text of Barth’s works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justification and Sanctification</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/justification-and-sanctification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 15:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/justification-and-sanctification/</guid>
      <description>For my “Pedagogical Experience” requirement at Wheaton, I’m helping to teach a masters-level Christian Theology course.
Yesterday, I got to teach a lesson on justification and sanctification. A lot to cover in a 95-minute class session!
If you’re interested in what I covered, here are my slides (in PDF format).
[Justification and Sanctification Slides ](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/19.-Justification-and-Sanctification.pdf)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/19.-Justification-and-Sanctification.pdf)And here is the handout (Word document). [Justification and Sanctification Handout ](https://joshuapsteele.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41412-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 15:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/41412-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a test. Posting from micro.blog iOS app to WordPress.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take Up Your Tongue and Follow Jesus</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/take-up-your-tongue-and-follow-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/take-up-your-tongue-and-follow-jesus/</guid>
      <description>This sermon, on Mark 8:27-38 and James 3:1-12, was originally preached on September 16, 2018 at Christ Redeemer Anglican Church in Milwaukee, WI.
Introduction Would you pray with me?
O God, because without you we are not able to please you—especially in what we say!—mercifully grant that your Holy Spirit may in all things direct and rule our hearts, so that the words of our mouths and the meditations of our hearts might be acceptable in your sight, O Lord, our strength and our redeemer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Theologies: A List (Help Me Update!)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/systematic-theologies-a-list-help-me-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/systematic-theologies-a-list-help-me-update/</guid>
      <description>SYSTEMATIC THEOLOGIES: A LIST I put together the following list, using the 10th edition of John Glynn’s Commentary and Reference Survey (Kegel, 2007) as a starting point.
I’ll be updating this list in the future, but I could use your help. If there’s something that needs included, please let me know in the comments!
Systematic Theologies Barth, Karl. Church Dogmatics, 5 vols. In 14 parts. (T&amp;amp;T Clark, [1932–1967] 1936–1969). Bavinck, Herman.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&amp;#8217;s the Template I Use to Take Notes on Books I Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 19:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</guid>
      <description>Developed from How to Read a Book, by Mortimer J. Adler.
BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA: Author(s):
Editor(s):
Translator(s):
Title and subtitle:
Title and subtitle of any larger work that contains the source:
Pages:
Volume:
Issue:
Edition:
URL and date accessed:
Publisher:
Place:
Date:
INTERPRETATION: Kind of Book (Practical or theoretical?):
Subject Matter:
Problems Attempted to Solve:
Summary (What is the book about as a whole?):
Outline of Source:
Key Terms:
Key Propositions/Arguments (What is being said in detail, and how?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&amp;#8217;m Reading this Fall</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>This upcoming semester, I’ll be taking a seminar on the Doctrine of Creation from my supervisor Marc Cortez. I’ll also be doing my “pedagogical experience” in a Christian Theology course—also with Marc Cortez.
Anyways, in case you’re interested, I thought I’d share what I’ll be reading for each course.
Have you read any of these works? If so, what did you think? What will you be reading this semester?
Doctrine of Creation Colin Gunton, The Triune Creator: A Historical and Systematic Study.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Questions to Ask While Reading Theology</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</guid>
      <description>While reading Beth Felker Jones’ Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically, I came across the following list of extremely helpful questions to ask while reading theology (on page 29).
What are the key Christian teachings being articulated? What is the author’s driving concern or main theme? What counts for the author as authoritative (Scripture, tradition, reason, experience…)? Is the author’s theological method implicit or explicit? How does the author deal with the witness of Scripture?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eva Joy Steele: A Birth Story</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/eva-joy-steele-a-birth-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 15:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/eva-joy-steele-a-birth-story/</guid>
      <description>This is a self-indulgently long story. The gist of it is that my wife, Rachel, was unexpectedly induced due to gestational hypertension at 37 weeks, right before we were supposed to head to Pennsylvania for her sister’s wedding.
After a lengthy induction and labor, our beautiful daughter, Eva Joy Steele, was born at 5:46am on Friday, July 20, 2018.
If that’s all you’d like to know, great! If you’d like to know more about what went down, keep reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Theologians (Should) Do</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-theologians-should-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 14:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-theologians-should-do/</guid>
      <description>Kevin J. Vanhoozer, affectionately known by some as “KJV,” has written one of the best, briefest overviews of what theologians (should) do.
The entire piece is filled with gems like the following:
To become a theologian, you must be willing to bear true witness and call out false witnesses, casting down idols and ideologies. That’s the shadow side of theology, but the best part is speaking light and truth in astonished indications of God’s goodness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Attracts People to Anglicanism? Here&amp;#8217;s My Take</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 21:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</guid>
      <description>Based upon my work over at Rookie Anglican, I was asked by The Telos Collective to write a blog post about the different ways that people are coming into Anglicanism. What’s drawing them in?
You can read my full post over at the Telos Collective blog, but here’s a taste:
Anglican Christianity, precisely because of its weirdness, can remind us that, in the words of Brad Harper and Paul Louis Metzger in Exploring Ecclesiology, “The church is a cultural community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I catalogued a bunch of different takes on Jordan Peterson, before giving my own take.
Since that post, two other pieces about Jordan Peterson have been written that I’d like to share.
“Jordan Peterson, Custodian of the Patriarchy,” by Nellie Bowles (New York Times) Nellie Bowles writes
Mr. Peterson, 55, a University of Toronto psychology professor turned YouTube philosopher turned mystical father figure, has emerged as an influential thought leader.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Four Tendencies: 4 Ways You Can Play to Your Personality Strengths</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 18:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</guid>
      <description>In both my personal and coaching conversations recently, Gretchen Rubin’s personality framework called “The Four Tendencies” has really seemed to resonate with people.
So, I thought I would take a few minutes to share it with you.
Gretchen Rubin Explains the Four Tendencies First, here’s a six-minute video of Gretchen herself explaining the Four Tendencies and their relevance to changing one’s habits.
How do you respond to INNER EXPECTATIONS and OUTER EXPECTATIONS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hate Running? Try Rucking Instead</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 16:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</guid>
      <description>(DISCLAIMER: You are, of course, more than welcome to try rucking, even if you also love running.)
Rucking &amp;gt; Running It took me a long time to “fall in love” with running. It did not take me nearly as long to fall out of love with running!
And yet, even though I’ve long enjoyed doing kettlebell swings and doing the 5×5 weight-lifing workout, I did begin to miss the benefits of cardio training.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&amp;#8217;s the Elevator Pitch for my Dissertation Proposal: &amp;#8220;Scriptural, but Not Religious&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 21:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, I defend the proposal for my dissertation. For now, the dissertation is tentatively titled: “Scriptural, but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion.”
Here’s the “elevator pitch” for the dissertation. Feedback appreciated.
Scriptural, but Not Religious: Barth, Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion My project traces its origins to a single classroom discussion question in the Spring of 2015. The question was this: “In what ways is Bonhoeffer’s understanding of religion similar to, and different from, that of Barth?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Grain of the Gospel: Why Christians Should Care about Food Ethics</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grain-of-the-gospel-why-christians-should-care-about-food-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 06:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grain-of-the-gospel-why-christians-should-care-about-food-ethics/</guid>
      <description>The following is a guest post written by my friend and former college roommate, Zak Weston. Zak’s been working in the area of food ethics, and I asked him to write up a post about why Christians should care about these issues. It’s an area in which I need to make some changes in my own life. He delivered this thought-provoking and challenging piece. I hope you enjoy.
Introduction The three or so decisions you make each day about what to eat are some of the most consequential choices you make in your life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to make of Jordan Peterson? Some takes, then my own.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Read my post, “Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson.”
If I remember correctly, I first heard of and listened to Jordan Peterson on an episode of The Art of Manliness podcast. (Or perhaps it was this episode.)
However, I could be mistaken, because Peterson’s been popping up in conversation all over the place in my circles. Blog posts, podcast episodes, conversations with friends – Peterson has been popping up everywhere, so it seems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do More Better: Tim Challies&amp;#8217; Excellent Little Book on Personal Productivity Could Change Your Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</guid>
      <description>Tim Challies begins his book, Do More Better: A Practical Guide to Productivity with a bold claim: “I believe this book can improve your life.”
However, after reading the book, which is just 120 pages long including endnotes!, I believe that Challies makes good on his claim.
As far as explicitly Christian approaches to personal productivity go, Challies’ Do More Better stands alongside Matt Perman’s What’s Best Next: How the Gospel Transforms the Way You Get Things Done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Please Don&amp;#8217;t Leave Me Alone: On Male Friendships, or the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 18:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you, like me, consider yourself quite the introvert. Maybe you, like me, have a difficult time walking the tightrope between feeling quickly overwhelmed by interpersonal relationships, on the one hand, and feeling incredibly lonely, on the other hand.
Maybe you, like me, feel these problems acutely as a male (although I’m sure that females are having their own relational struggles as our culture increasingly pressures us all to be “alone together,” looking at our screens instead of looking each other in the eye).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Need to Develop a Writing Habit. Do You?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</guid>
      <description>Because good writing = good thinking, I believe that everyone could benefit from developing the habit of regular writing.
However, because I
Am a Ph.D. student about to begin work on his dissertation Edit a blog (Rookie Anglican) Write this personal blog I really need to develop the habit of regular writing.
Up until now, I’ve largely relied upon writing in fits and starts, when the Muse descends, as it were.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting back on the &amp;#8220;Getting Things Done&amp;#8221; Productivity Bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 22:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>Getting Things Done (“GTD” for short) is a wildly popular personal productivity system invented and popularized by David Allen. However, as Nicole Dieker at Lifehacker pointed out in 2017, “You don’t hear a lot of people talk about the Getting Things Done productivity system anymore.”
I think that’s a shame, because it’s a very effective system.
I first tried Getting Things Done after reading “What’s Best Next” by Matt Perman, and then reading “Getting Things Done” by David Allen (in its newly revised 2015 edition) shortly thereafter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Song is a Beautiful Picture of the Theological Journey</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-truth-is-not-a-cave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 21:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-truth-is-not-a-cave/</guid>
      <description>I was recently privileged to see one of my favorite bands, The Oh Hellos, in concert at the House of Blues in downtown Chicago.
I love all of The Oh Hellos’ music, but one song, in particular, has remained poignant to me ever since I first heard it. The song is called “The Truth is a Cave,” and I think it provides a beautiful picture of what I’m calling “the theological journey” – the stages one goes through in one’s knowledge of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Beauty: Phoenix &amp;#038; Grand Canyon Trip 2018</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dangerous-beauty-phoenix-grand-canyon-trip-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 14:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dangerous-beauty-phoenix-grand-canyon-trip-2018/</guid>
      <description>Rachel and I just got back from our very first trip to the Southwest. The main reason for the trip was to visit some good friends of ours, the Smith family, in Phoenix, AZ. Here’s a picture of the group of us together after church at Living Faith Anglican Church in Tempe, AZ, where my friend Peter Smith is the rector.
The trip was a blast. It was great to catch up with the Smiths and to see their new home and church in Arizona.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This One Simple Trick Helps Me Read Faster as a Ph.D. Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 06:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</guid>
      <description>Reading is the closest thing that human beings have to a superpower. We can learn, from other minds, from other times, just by looking at symbols on a screen or a page.
But, I mean, come on. Who has enough time to read? I don’t know about you, but I’ve got a stack of books a mile high that I’d like to work my way through.
Now, there’s a bunch of good advice out there about finding more time to read (see this post from Farnam Street and this post from The Art of Manliness).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christian, Do the Daily Office: 5 Things You Can Learn from Morning and Evening Prayer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christian-daily-office-5-things-can-learn-morning-evening-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christian-daily-office-5-things-can-learn-morning-evening-prayer/</guid>
      <description>The Problem: We All Need to Grow, But We’re Not Sure How Let’s face it: to say the very least, we Christians all have room to grow when it comes to following Jesus. None of us has “arrived.”
There’s always more to learn about who God is, what God has done, and how we can join God’s mission to set the world right again. And, even if we know a bunch about those things in the previous sentence, we surely don’t always live based on that knowledge!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Reasons Why I&amp;#8217;m an Anglican Christian</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 05:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</guid>
      <description>Why am I an Anglican Christian? Here are 3 reasons.
1. Anglicanism as a Refuge from Fundamentalism First, for me, Anglicanism has been a refuge from fundamentalism. Now, to be sure, we do have our own fundamentalists within the Anglican Communion! But, compared to some “ingrown enclaves” I’ve experienced in my Christian upbringing, Anglicanism has been a breath of fresh air. It has been an ecclesiological space for healing as I seek to “not throw the (gospel) baby out with the (fundamentalist) bathwater.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cut the &amp;#8220;Positivity&amp;#8221; Crap: What Frustrates You?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 17:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</guid>
      <description>I’ll keep this short, sweet, and to the point: I’m looking for problems that I can help solve, so I need you to rant at me in the comments.
That’s right, I basically want you to complain to me in the comments section of this post.
What’s causing you frustration, angst, or stress these days? What questions are you struggling to find the answers to? What obstacles are in the way of you achieving your goals?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go to Sleep and Have Some Kids: What the Bible (Psalm 127) Says about Productivity</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 12:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Personal Productivity in Psalm 127 I love Psalm 127. Not because it makes me feel great, necessarily, but because it hits me like a ton of bricks whenever I read it (like I did last night, during evening prayer).
Here’s how the Psalm opens:
Unless the Lord builds the house,
the builders labor in vain.
Unless the Lord watches over the city,
the guards stand watch in vain.
I don’t know about you, but it’s easy for me to think that my success or lack thereof completely depends on me and the intensity of my efforts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Confessions of an Expectant Father</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/3-confessions-expectant-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 12:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/3-confessions-expectant-father/</guid>
      <description>We’re Expecting! In case you haven’t heard the news, my wife Rachel and I are expecting our firstborn child this August! Rachel is currently 16 weeks along, and we won’t find out the gender of the baby (whom I am affectionately calling “Lump”) for another month.
The last few months have been quite busy for us since we found out Rachel is pregnant. She works full-time as a Family Nurse Practitioner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Models: A Helpful Model for Theology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 15:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</guid>
      <description>This idea has been bouncing around in my head for a bit. It’s not fully-formed by any means, but I’d like to get it out there and hear what you think of it.
Here it is: “Mental Models” could be a helpful model for theology.
What is a “mental model”? Definition of mental models Put simply, a “mental model” is a concept used to help explain how the world works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Pray Before You Read and Write: A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 09:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</guid>
      <description>I want to share with you the following prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study, based on Oratio S. Thomae Aquinatis ante studium, which Thomas Aquinas would pray before studying, writing, or preaching.
We prayed it responsively before class (Patristic and Medieval History and Doctrine) with Dr. Piotr Malysz at Beeson Divinity School, and I’ve since turned back to this prayer often!
A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study O God, Creator of all that is, From the treasures of Your wisdom, You have arrayed the universe with marvelous order, And now govern with skill and might.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Questions to Ask When You Study the Bible (Plus a Worksheet!)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 15:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/</guid>
      <description>The Problem: Studying the Bible can Quickly Feel Overwhelming Right? Even with helpful books out there like How to Read the Bible for All Its Worth (that’s an affiliate link, by the way, meaning that I get a small commission at no cost to you if you end up buying the book), there are still so many potential questions to ask of any biblical text when we study it.
How are we supposed to keep questions of authorship, genre, meaning, application, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Books Every Christian Should Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 03:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</guid>
      <description>OK, OK. I get it. Claiming that every Christian should read these 5 books is a bold claim.
But, honestly, I think that these reading recommendations stand up to the scrutiny.
I’ve been wracking my brain trying to come up with just the top 5 books that a busy Christian should read if she wants to learn the essentials about:
Productivity and Time Management Bible Study Theology And, I think I’ve arrived at a pretty good shortlist if I do say so myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An 80/20 Approach to the Christian Life: 2 Reasons Why Christians Should Care About the Pareto Principle</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 12:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to live a more meaningful and purposeful Christian life, but you feel like it’s hard enough just to get everything done on your to-do list each day?
I’m right there with you! That’s why I’ve made “Get Your Act Together (Productivity and Time Management)” the first of my Steps to Find Purpose and Meaning in Life.
Thankfully, I think I’ve found something that can help. I’d like to introduce you to the “Pareto Principle,” also known as “the 80/20 Rule,” the “law of the vital few,” or the “principle of factor sparsity,” if you want to get all technical about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hermeneutical Implications of Scripture&amp;#8217;s Theological Location</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hermeneutical-implications-scriptures-theological-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 15:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hermeneutical-implications-scriptures-theological-location/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION Theological hermeneutics – human understanding and interpretation in light of the identity and acts of the triune God – faces two problematic questions that, I believe, every biblical and/or theological scholar must be prepared to address. First, should the Bible be read in some special sense as divine revelation, or should we read the Bible like any other text? And second, should biblical and theological studies be one discipline, or two?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principles: 10 Imperatives for the Good Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 16:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</guid>
      <description>Why write out a list of principles?
For one thing, it’s my birthday. And, although I’m only in my twenties, I’m feeling a bit reflective.
For another, I’ve just been given a copy of Principles: Life and Work by Ray Dalio (affiliate link).
According to Dalio (ix),
Principles are fundamental truths that serve as the foundations for behavior that gets you what you want out of life. They can be aplied again and again in similar situations to help you achieve your goals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testimony: A Faith Story, In Brief</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/testimony-brief/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 07:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/testimony-brief/</guid>
      <description>The following is an attempt to tell my testimony, the story of my Christian faith, in approximately 500 words. It was challenging to do, but also a helpful exercise! I challenge you to write out your own story in approximately 500 words.
Testimony For as long as I can remember, I have known and followed Jesus Christ as my Lord and Savior. However, there has been a lingering problem in our relationship – on my end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts You Should Listen To</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 15:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts: An Introduction Although podcasts (think “iPod” + “broadcast”) have been around for over a decade, we’re living in a bit of a golden age – or a least a Rennaissance – of the medium. For the uninitiated, here’s a nice video about what podcasts are:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oerm5Q_9u2A
Currently, podcasts are one of my very favorite ways to consume information about a wide variety of topics. Sure, gun to my head, I’ll choose books over podcasts as a way to learn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It is Finished! So, Get to Work! &amp;#8211; A Sermon on the Ascension</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20170613it-is-finished-so-get-to-work-an-ascension-sermon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 01:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20170613it-is-finished-so-get-to-work-an-ascension-sermon/</guid>
      <description>The following is an “It is Finished” sermon preached on Ascension Sunday, 2017. You can listen to the sermon here:
https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/05-28-17JS.mp3
GOODBYES SUCK You know, if there’s one thing I hate, it’s goodbyes. Anyone else here hate goodbyes?
Yeah, and the fact that I hate them so much means I’m not really very good at goodbyes.
Sometimes I get awkward and silent. Sometimes I get awkward and really chatty! Heck, sometimes I get awkward and I make poor choices, like the one time when I was getting ready to say goodbye to my family when they dropped me off at college.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lasting Supper &amp;#8211; Luke 22:14-30</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 19:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/</guid>
      <description>https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/04-13-17JS.mp3
There is something special about last meals, isn’t there?
I’d like to show you a series of photographs. These photographs, except for the last one – which I added, are from a piece called “No Seconds,” and they were put together by Henry Hargreaves.
I don’t want to belabor the artwork with my commentary, so I’ll give you a few seconds to take each slide in.
[![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Slide2-150x150.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/slide2/) [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Slide11-150x150.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/slide11/) [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Slide10-150x150.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/slide10/) [!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is The Well-Equipped Christian Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 23:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had a problem finding a reliable resource for recommendations?
I have.
Certain Google searches are a piece of cake, but the “best resources for ______” ones can be hit-or-miss.
And don’t even get me started on the decision fatigue. As a serial over-thinker, I start to hate myself a little bit after reading through the upteenth list of “5 Best ____s.” It makes it so hard to make a decision!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ahead in God&amp;#8217;s Upside-Down Kingdom: An Appeal for a Consistently Pro-Life Ethic</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-ahead-in-gods-upside-down-kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 16:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-ahead-in-gods-upside-down-kingdom/</guid>
      <description>https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/01-29-17JSGeetingAheadinGodsUpsideDownKingdom.mp3
[MP3: Getting Ahead in God’s Upside-Down Kingdom]
[PDF Sermon Manuscript: Getting Ahead in God’s Upside-Down Kingdom]
Opening Prayer God, our Refuge, I ask that your Holy Spirit would move in our lives, so that we would:
promote your justice embody your steadfast faithful love and humbly obey Your will, even if it costs us our reputations, and even if it costs us our lives.
I ask that this transformation would begin with me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Be or Not To Be Religious: A Clarification of Karl Barth&amp;#8217;s and Dietrich Bonhoeffer&amp;#8217;s Divergence and Convergence Regarding Religion</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/to-be-or-not-to-be-religious-a-clarification-of-karl-barths-and-dietrich-bonhoeffers-divergence-and-convergence-regarding-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 18:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/to-be-or-not-to-be-religious-a-clarification-of-karl-barths-and-dietrich-bonhoeffers-divergence-and-convergence-regarding-religion/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
Christian theologians Karl Barth (1886-1968) and Dietrich Bonhoeffer (1906-1945) inherited a particular understanding of religion. In the broadly post-Kantian milieu, nineteenth-century thinkers such as Friedrich Schleiermacher, Albrecht Ritschl, and Adolf von Harnack defined religion essentially, anthropologically, and subjectively. That is, religion has a particular essence, and is in some manner inalienable from our humanity. The emphasis of this conception is on the experience of the religious subject, instead of the knowledge of religion’s object (let alone its reality).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Disappointing Christmas Homily</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-christmas-homily/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 14:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-christmas-homily/</guid>
      <description>Good morning! And Merry Christmas!
Together, let us pray:
O God, you make us glad by the yearly festival of the birth of your only Son Jesus Christ: Grant that we, who joyfully receive him as our Redeemer, may with sure confidence behold him when he comes to be our Judge; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen.
Almighty God, who wonderfully created us in your own image and yet more wonderfully restored us through your Son Jesus Christ: grant that, as he came to share our humanity, so we may share the life of his divinity; who is alive and reigns with you, in the unity of the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Works on Karl Barth &amp;#038; Dietrich Bonhoeffer. Are There Others?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/works-on-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 20:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/works-on-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</guid>
      <description>ABROMEIT, Hans-Jürgen. Das Geheimnis Christi: Dietrich Bonhoeffers erfahrungsbezogene Christologie. Neukirchener Beiträge zur systemaschen Theologie 8. Neukirchen-Vluyn: Neukirchener Verlag, 1991. BEINTKER, Michael. “Kontingenz und Gegenständlichkeit: Zu Bonhoeffers Barth-Kritik in ‘Akt und Sein.’” In Krisis und Gnade: Gesammelte Studien zu Karl Barth, edited by Stefan Holtmann and Peter Zocher, 29–54. Tübingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2013. BENKTSON, Benkt-Erik. Christus Und Die Religion: Der Religionsbegriff Bei Barth, Bonhoeffer Und Tillich. Arbeiten Zur Theologie, II/9. Stuttgart: Calwer, 1967.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christians and Wealth: An Argument for Downward Mobility</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christians-and-wealth-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 01:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christians-and-wealth-2/</guid>
      <description>Great news! If you only have a minute to read about wealth, here’s my argument in a nutshell:
Outline of My Argument Main Claim: American Christians should reduce their standards of living to what is necessary for human flourishing and give their excess resources beyond this standard to the poor and oppressed. God is the firmest advocate for human flourishing. The pursuit of wealth is spiritually dangerous and crippling. Our culture’s inclinations toward upward financial mobility go against the message of the New Testament and the life of Christ.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following Jesus Beyond the Bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-jesus-beyond-the-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 22:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-jesus-beyond-the-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>(A chapel message in a Christian school.)
There are a few things you should know about me:
I am a student at a Christian seminary. Before that, I went to a Christian college. Before that, I went to a Christian high school, and a Christian middle school. Before that, I was home-schooled, and I grew up in a Christian home. Oh, also: I’m the world’s worst sports fan.
I’m serious. The students in my youth group give me a hard time about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, &amp;#038; The Theological Critique of Religion: My Reading List This Fall</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-the-theological-critique-of-religion-my-reading-list-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 20:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-the-theological-critique-of-religion-my-reading-list-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
This semester — my final one at Beeson Divinity School — I’m doing a directed study with Piotr Malysz on the topic of “Religion” in Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer.
The impetus for this study was a discussion question in Dr. Malysz’s Spring 2015 20th Century History and Doctrine course. On March 24, our third class period on Dietrich Bonhoeffer, our second question for discussion read as follows:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Ridiculously Helpful Markdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 14:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been dragging my heels on learning Markdown for awhile now.
If you don’t know, Markdown is:
lightweight markup language with plain text formatting syntax designed so that it can be converted to HTML and many other formats using a tool by the same name.[8] Markdown is often used to format readme files, for writing messages in online discussion forums, and to create rich text using a plain text editor. [Source: Wikipedia]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Feast of St. James the Apostle: A Homily for Ministers</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-feast-of-st-james-the-apostle-a-homily-for-ministers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 22:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-feast-of-st-james-the-apostle-a-homily-for-ministers/</guid>
      <description>Readings: Psalm 34; Jeremiah 16:14-21; Mark 1:14-20
Like so many other feast days – scheduled, as they are, on the days of the namesakes’ deaths – the feast day of St. James the Apostle is a strong rebuke to our aspirations. To our aspirations as human beings, and especially to our aspirations as ministers of Christ’s Church.
![Saint James the Greater *oil on canvas *92.1 x 74.9 cm *signed b.r.: Rembrandt f.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frustrated with Church? You&amp;#8217;re the Problem!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-youre-the-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-youre-the-problem/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I asked you to join the Church if you, like me, are frustrated with the Church. The strongest critiques of religion come from within, not without, the Christian community. Plus, your frustrations are likely shared by many others within the Church!
However, it’s not enough to point the finger at others from your pew, instead of doing so from the public square. Yes, that’s a good first step, but another one is necessary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frustrated with Church? Join the Club&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-join-the-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 17:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-join-the-club/</guid>
      <description>…and by “club” I of course mean “Church”!
What am I getting at? Am I calling the Church a mere “club”?
No. Although, unfortunately, it often feels that way, doesn’t it?
A club full of hypocrisy, idolatry, indifference, and platitudes. A club full of power-plays, fear-mongering, and Bible-thumping. A club full of saints too afraid to admit that they are sinners. Perhaps you’re sick of this “club,” and you’re ready to leave, if you haven’t left already.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thank God, I Went to Cedarville</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/thank-god-i-went-to-cedarville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 20:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/thank-god-i-went-to-cedarville/</guid>
      <description>As I prepare for my final semester at Beeson Divinity School, it strikes me just how well I was prepared for my seminary education by my undergraduate professors at Cedarville University.
All things considered, my time at CU exposed me to the riches of biblical and theological studies, and it left me hungry for more.
College gave me a love for Christ’s gospel and Christ’s Church – which has only increased since I arrived at Beeson.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Want To Be Remembered?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</guid>
      <description>Do you know what the worst thing about death is?
It’s not the dying itself – its the separation.
That is, we don’t suffer the most from our own deaths (a one-time occurrence), but from suffering the deaths of others (repeatedly). Instead of living relationships, we are left with distant memories.
A sad reality, to be sure.
What if, however, we could use death to our own advantage? I’m convinced this is the truth behind Ecclesiastes 7:2 –</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&amp;#8217;s Take Seth Godin to Church</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</guid>
      <description>I’m not going to lie. My first reaction when I saw the cover of this book? No! Of course you’re not indispensable. What use could this crap possibly be to the Church, or to me – simultaneously a pastor and a pastor-in-training. Then, however, I read the book. And I suggest you do, too!
(Note: affiliate link. I get paid if you make a purchase.)
Seth Godin, bald marketing extraordinaire, is convinced that a paradigm shift has taken place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are you afraid of?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 20:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</guid>
      <description>I’m scared. Are you?
Specifically, as I wrote in my journal this very morning:
I’m scared – I’m scared of wasting my life, I’m scared of not being worth anything outside of the classroom.
Fear drives so many aspects of our lives – from how we dress, to how we raise our children, to how we elect our leaders. And, if we’re honest with ourselves, fear can play a large role in what/whom we worship.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&amp;#8217;m Reading</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 14:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading/</guid>
      <description>Ah, the joys of summer reading.
[![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0493-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0493-2/) Hoping to be able to read German with a dictionary by the end of the summer! [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0492-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0492-2/) Karl Barth’s theological bombshell. [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0494-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0494-2/) I’m trying the Slow-Carb Diet and kettlebell swings. [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0500-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0500-2/) I’ve wanted to get my hands on a copy of the Homilies for some time. [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0495-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0495-2/) Finally getting around to reading this classic! [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0499-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0499-2/) My very first Seth Godin book. [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0496-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0496-2/) What has Barth to do with Plantinga?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kettlebell Swings: Back Balm for the Sedentary [Seminarian]</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 23:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</guid>
      <description>I love books. Books, however, do not like my back.
Can you relate?
Maybe it’s not sitting around reading books all day, but I imagine plenty of you out there suffer from back pain/fatigue.
Let me share a time-saving solution I’ve recently found: two-handed kettlebell swings.
![Our small kettlebell family](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0472-e1464220672909-300x225.jpg)Our small kettlebell family How can these cannonballs with handles help your back?
Well, the kettlebell swing is one of the many exercises out there that activates your posterior chain – the muscles along the back of your body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Groom&amp;#8217;s Big Day</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grooms-big-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 16:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grooms-big-day/</guid>
      <description>[soundcloud url=”https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/256270902″ params=”color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false” width=”100%” height=”166″ iframe=”true” /]
READINGS Ephesians 5:21-33 – Wives and Husbands Psalm 67 – May God Be Gracious to Us and Bless Us Revelation 19:6-10 – The Marriage Supper of the Lamb Matthew 25:1-13 – The Parable of the Ten Virgins HOMILY What makes a great wedding?
Is it the fragrance and color of the flower arrangements? The particular grandeur of the venue?
Is it the number and camaraderie of the guests?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Son of Man, Can Your Bones Live?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/son-of-man-can-your-bones-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 22:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/son-of-man-can-your-bones-live/</guid>
      <description>What would it have been like, on the first Holy Saturday? What would it be like, tonight, if Jesus has been dead for almost 33 hours?
All the hopes and dreams of tonight’s readings – shattered. Blown away by the cold winds of death. Jesus of Nazareth lies in a dark grave, and we, his shell-shocked followers, gather to make some sort of sense of this week’s events – to salvage some sort of hope from this week’s wreckage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Recommendations? Barth&amp;#039;s &amp;#038; Bonhoeffer&amp;#039;s False Gods</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/reading-recommendations-barths-bonhoeffers-false-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 12:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/reading-recommendations-barths-bonhoeffers-false-gods/</guid>
      <description>Hi internet – especially all you Barthians and Bonhoefferians (-ites?) out there.
I’m in the process of compiling a reading list, and I could use your suggestions.
Here’s my goal: to explore the possible relationship between Barth’s critique of the “No-God”(Nich-Gott) and Bonhoeffer’s critique(s) of viewing God as a “stopgap” (Lückenbüßer) or “working hypothesis.”
As far as primary sources go, I plan to focus on the Romans commentary, Garrett Green’s recent re-translation of CD §17, and Letters and Papers from Prison.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Recent Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/three-recent-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 20:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/three-recent-sermons/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a grueling past few weeks at Beeson. Our Spring Break happens to coincide with Holy Week this year, and it can’t come quickly enough!
Part of the hard work has been preparing to preach three sermons for class. However, the opportunity to study and preach God’s Word is a joy that outweighs the burdens of preparation!
I have preached twice in the past month on Psalm 32. First, I delivered a sermon (“The Refreshment of Forgiveness”) designed for the Fourth Sunday in Lent, Year C, for Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sermon: The Challenge of Christmas Light</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sermon-the-challenge-of-christmas-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 15:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sermon-the-challenge-of-christmas-light/</guid>
      <description>There are better preachers out there. So, if you’re short on time, go and listen to them! However, if you’ve got 26 minutes to spare, I offer “The Challenge of Christmas Light” to you, and would love to hear your feedback.
I preached this sermon on December 27, 2015 at St. Peter’s Anglican Church in Mountain Brook, AL, as we celebrated the Feast of St. John the Apostle and Evangelist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvising Church &amp;#038; State: Overaccepting as a Synthesis of Anglican and Anabaptist Approaches</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/improvising-church-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/improvising-church-state/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION: ACCEPTING, BLOCKING, AND STATUS From the church’s perspective, is the state a promising offer, or a threatening one? At the risk of breathtaking oversimplification, Anglicans have tended to adopt the former perspective, leading to accommodation, and Anabaptists the latter, resulting in separation.[1] Following Samuel Wells in his theological appropriation of terms from theatrical improvisation, the Anglican tradition has tended to respond to the promising offers (invitations to respond) of the state by accepting – maintaining the premise(s) of the state’s action(s).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theology in Outline: What Do I Believe?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theology-outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theology-outline/</guid>
      <description>Theology is confusing enough, much more so when you attempt to summarize it all in a single essay! Nevertheless, such was my assignment in seminary in 2015. Here are the results.
“At the centre of Christian faith is the history of Christ. At the centre of the history of Christ is his passion and his death on the cross.” ~ Jürgen Moltmann[1]
Theology in Outline: A[n Attempted] Summary of the Christian Faith We believe that, during the prefecture of Pontius Pilate, God died on a Roman cross.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faithful Faith in a Faithful God: Romans 1.1-17</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/faithful-faith-in-a-faithful-god-romans-1-1-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 08:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/faithful-faith-in-a-faithful-god-romans-1-1-17/</guid>
      <description>I. Introduction: The Prodigal Son, Part 2 What a relief, to get out of that house.
Ordinarily, Jude would have scoffed at his father’s request to purchase farming equipment from the next city – a three-day journey!
But ever since Ethan, that rascal (you might even say that prodigal) brother of his, had returned, Jude could not stand to be in either man’s presence for long.
So he relished the chance to forget about his family tension on this farming errand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Prodigal Son, Part 2: Introduction to Romans</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-prodigal-son-part-2-introduction-to-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 21:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-prodigal-son-part-2-introduction-to-romans/</guid>
      <description>What a relief, to get out of that house.
Ordinarily, Jude would have scoffed at his father’s request to purchase farming equipment from the next city – a three-day journey! But ever since Ethan, that rascal (you might even say that prodigal) brother of his, had returned, Jude could not stand to be in either man’s presence for long.
So he relished the chance to forget about his family tension on this farming errand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: Mark 8.11-21</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-8-11-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-8-11-21/</guid>
      <description>A homily on Mark 8:11-21 (ESV):
The Pharisees came and began to argue with him, seeking from him a sign from heaven to test him. And he sighed deeply in his spirit and said, “Why does this generation seek a sign? Truly, I say to you, no sign will be given to this generation.” And he left them, got into the boat again, and went to the other side.
Now they had forgotten to bring bread, and they had only one loaf with them in the boat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: Mark 1.29-45</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-1-29-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 18:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-1-29-45/</guid>
      <description>A homily on Mark 1:29-45 (ESV):
And immediately he left the synagogue and entered the house of Simon and Andrew, with James and John. Now Simon’s mother-in-law lay ill with a fever, and immediately they told him about her. And he came and took her by the hand and lifted her up, and the fever left her, and she began to serve them.
That evening at sundown they brought to him all who were sick or oppressed by demons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: James 2.1-13</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-james-2-1-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 17:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-james-2-1-13/</guid>
      <description>A homily on James 2.1-13 (ESV):
“My brothers, show no partiality as you hold the faith in our Lord Jesus Christ,the Lord of glory. For if a man wearing a gold ring and fine clothing comes into your assembly, and a poor man in shabby clothing also comes in, and if you pay attention to the one who wears the fine clothing and say, “You sit here in a good place,” while you say to the poor man, “You stand over there,” or, “Sit down at my feet,” have you not then made distinctions among yourselves and become judges with evil thoughts?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus is Not Just &amp;quot;One of Us&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/jesus-is-not-just-one-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 21:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/jesus-is-not-just-one-of-us/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: The audio of the following sermon, preached on July 05, 2015 at St. Peter’s Anglican Church in Mountain Brook, Alabama, can be found here. (I began with a bit of a mic issue. Ignore the garbled first 10 seconds or so!)
—
Introduction The “hometown,” “home court” advantage is a very real occurrence in many areas of life. Familiar fans and supportive surroundings help us humans to perform better at many tasks, from singing to sports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentecost: Songs and Scripture</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pentecost-songs-and-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 15:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pentecost-songs-and-scripture/</guid>
      <description>Listening to the first episode of the excellent new podcast, LectioCast, helped to orient my thoughts toward tomorrow’s readings for Pentecost Sunday. I’ve reproduced the first lesson, psalm, second lesson, and Gospel reading below, but I’d also like to call your attention to three powerful songs.
Song #1: “Dry Bones” by Gungor The first song is “Dry Bones” by Gungor. Read the Ezekiel passage and psalm below, and give it a listen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be human?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-does-it-mean-to-be-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 22:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-does-it-mean-to-be-human/</guid>
      <description>What Does It Mean to Be Human? A clue to the answer lies in the asking of the question, for this act presupposes both a [human] subject and object in a dialectic of self-transcendence.
As Robert Jenson notes, “in asking this question, we somehow take up a vantage outside ourselves to make ourselves our own objects, get beyond ourselves to look back at ourselves.”1 The mystery of human existence is “that I am the subject of the object I am and the object of the subject I am.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disunity in the Church? Absurd!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/disunity-in-the-church-absurd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 09:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/disunity-in-the-church-absurd/</guid>
      <description>Presented at Southeast ETS 2015.
DISUNITY AS ECCLESIOLOGICAL IMPOSSIBILITY:A BARTHIAN ANALOGY
Joshua P. Steele
INTRODUCTION Just as sin is ontological impossibility, disunity is ecclesiological impossibility. The tension between the undeniable reality of sin and Karl Barth’s theological definition of sin as an impossible possibility parallels the tension between the obvious reality of a fractured church1 and the theological definition of the church as the one body of the one Christ. Two excerpts from the Barthian corpus legitimize this connection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hope of the Holy Innocents</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-hope-of-the-holy-innocents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-hope-of-the-holy-innocents/</guid>
      <description>(PDF: [The Hope of the Holy Innocents](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/holy-innocents-matthew-21.pdf)) Today is December 28 (2014) – just the third day since Christmas – a commemoration of what is often called “The Slaughter of the Innocents,” the killing of the baby boys of Bethlehem by King Herod.
The Church’s regard for this day as a feast day is quite early, going back to at least the fifth century. In the fourth century, Chromatius described these babies as the first martyrs of Christ – the first counted worthy to die on Christ’s behalf.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Brokenhearted God</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-brokenhearted-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-brokenhearted-god/</guid>
      <description>Not to take away from the undeniably biblical teaching that God is almighty, but sometimes I think we lose sight of God&amp;rsquo;s love for his image-bearers when we emphasize certain &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; portraits of God at the expense of (instead of alongside of) other &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; portraits found in Scripture. (I put &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; in quotes because perhaps our definitions of strength and weakness therefore need to change!)
It might make some of us uncomfortable to read about God portrayed as a jilted lover or a frustrated mother, but those portraits just might be desperately needed in a time when so many people turn away from God because they can&amp;rsquo;t understand how he can possibly be the good Lord of a world so broken and dying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Uncle, Timothy Steele</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20150424my-uncle-timothy-steele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20150424my-uncle-timothy-steele/</guid>
      <description>(This post is about my late uncle, Timothy Steele. It’s long, and I swear toward the end. Sorry.)
“It is better to go to a funeral than a feast. For death is the destiny of every person, and the living should take this to heart. Sorrow is better than laughter, because sober reflection is good for the heart.” (Ecclesiastes 7:2-3)
Timothy Steele The juxtaposition is staggering. The funeral of the man I most associate with laughter and joy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Give Thanks!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/give-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/give-thanks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not the most thankful person.
However, I am a follower of Jesus, and one of the lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning this semester is that praise, thanksgiving, and gratitude are closely intertwined. Worship should involve the public proclamation of who God is and what He has done — including specific, personal declarations of thanksgiving for God&amp;rsquo;s grace and good gifts.
If, like me, you have a hard time cultivating this worshipful practice of gratitude, then allow me to suggest the following prayers from the Book of Common Prayer to help get us started.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #1, Stones into Bread</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread/</guid>
      <description>Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations isperenniallyinspiring, but particularly poignant during this season of Lent.
What does it mean for Christ to be the Perfect Penitent? And how should this influence our own repentance?
The following series of quotations comes from a lengthy small-print section in CD IV/1, 259-73 (§ 59 The Obedience of the Son of God; 2. The Judge Judged in Our Place). There Barth walks through the three wilderness temptations before masterfully connecting them to Christ&amp;rsquo;s experience in the Garden of Gethsemane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presenting on Karl Barth at 2015 Southeastern ETS</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/presenting-on-barth-at-2015-southeastern-ets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/presenting-on-barth-at-2015-southeastern-ets/</guid>
      <description>I just received the news today that my student paper submission for the 2015 Southeast Regional Meeting of the Evangelical Theological Society has been accepted!
My theme lately has been to write on Karl Barth and the unity of the Church. At last year&amp;rsquo;s Regional ETS (hosted by my seminary, Beeson Divinity School), I presented an edited version of my undergraduate thesis: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof: Atonement, Ecclesiology, and the Unity of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #2, Christendom&amp;#039;s Cost &amp;#8212; Worship Satan</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-2-christendoms-cost-worship-satan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-2-christendoms-cost-worship-satan/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I posted the beginning of Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations. He does a masterful job of explaining how Christ was tempted, not to violate the Law or commit a moral infraction, but to abandon his role as the obedient, Perfect Penitent. Put differently, Barth clarifies that Jesus&amp;rsquo; sinlessness is not a vague moral perfection, but rather obedience and repentance.
Christ&amp;rsquo;s first temptation was to turn stones into bread, thereby using divine power as a &amp;ldquo;technical instrument&amp;rdquo; to save and maintain his own life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #3, The Leap of False Faith</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-3-the-leap-of-false-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-3-the-leap-of-false-faith/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reproducingKarl Barth&amp;rsquo;smagnificent exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations in Church Dogmatics IV/1.
It is a particularly appropriate discussion for this season ofLent, for Jesus was not tempted to break the Law or commit a moral infraction. Instead, he was tempted to abandon his role as the Perfect Penitent. For Barth, if Christ had capitulated to any of the temptations, he would have abandoned God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive mission. Jesus Christ had to persist in penitence in order to be &amp;ldquo;the Judge Judged in Our Place&amp;rdquo; (Barth&amp;rsquo;s most concise description of the atonement proper).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who am I to be a theologian?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-am-i-to-be-a-theologian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-am-i-to-be-a-theologian/</guid>
      <description>For my 20th Century History &amp;amp; Doctrine course at Beeson Divinity School, I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading through Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s Evangelical Theology: An Introduction. If you&amp;rsquo;re involved in the life and ministry of the Church in any respect, I strongly recommend that you buy and read this book!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a particularly challenging portion from the chapter on &amp;ldquo;Wonder,&amp;rdquo; beginning on page 71. I wish the language were gender-inclusive, but Karl&amp;rsquo;s words still ring true:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHITE NOISE, BHOPAL, AND THE HYPERREAL FEAR OF DEATH</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/white-noise-bhopal-and-the-hyperreal-fear-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 08:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/white-noise-bhopal-and-the-hyperreal-fear-of-death/</guid>
      <description>The following essay deals with the theme of the fear of death in White Noise, the novel by Don DeLillo (affiliate link).
It is better to go to a funeral than a feast. For death is the destiny of every person, and the living should take this to heart.[1]
Don DeLillo’s White Noise, “a paradigm of postmodern literature,”[2] yields the kind of cognitive dissonance that makes you wonder whether the author simply missed the mark, or if you are only confused because you suffer from the postmodern condition which DeLillo adroitly analyzes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Sermon: Our Help</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-sermon-our-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 14:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-sermon-our-help/</guid>
      <description>Hey internet: I was recently given the chance to preach at my church, St. Peter’s Anglican, on the Second Sunday of Lent. The sermon audio is now online. If you’ve got 23 minutes to spare, give it a listen!
First, here are the passages:
Psalm 121 Genesis 12:1-4 Romans 4:1-5, 13-17 John 3:1-17 Then, make sure to ignore my two seconds of speech from 16:35-16:37 in the audio, I departed from my notes — which ended at “Nicodemus then fades from the narrative,” (which he does in the passage at hand) — and said that Nicodemus apparently never gets it and never shows up again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 2014 Regional ETS Paper: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 09:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>If you’re interested, here’s the latest version of the Regional ETS paper I will present today at 5:00pm at Beeson Divinity School, room S009.
If you’re able to attend the presentation, that’s great! If not, feel free to give my paper a read and get back to me with any questions, comments, or suggestions. Atonement theology and the unity of the Church are two things about which I am very passionate, and intend to devote further study to these areas in the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ok, Maybe a Bit More on Cedarville&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ok-maybe-a-bit-more-on-cedarville/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 11:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ok-maybe-a-bit-more-on-cedarville/</guid>
      <description>You’ll notice that the previous post on Cedarville ends with a link to the Course Schedule:
“Class Limited to Women” … I know, ludicrous. Especially considering Joy Fagan’s previous track record of making the first class, Scriptural Interpretation of Gender Issues (or SIGI), a truly excellent course by all accounts from former students, male and female.
Equally ludicrous? The textbook choices! Are you ready for what CU students will be reading to form an even-handed perspective of what the Bible has to say on gender?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerning Romans</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/concerning-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 11:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/concerning-romans/</guid>
      <description>Well, judging by my blog stats for the past 48 hours — as compared with the past few months — I’d get many more views on this post if it concerned the chaos at Cedarville University!
However, my schedule and blood pressure won’t allow me to devote any more time to my shameful alma mater at the moment. I’ve got a presentation at the 2014 Southeast Regional Meeting of ETS tomorrow (see my previous post, and come to my presentation at 5:00pm in room S009!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cedarville&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 17:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-2/</guid>
      <description>I wish I could say I was proud of my alma mater…
Despite my Lenten Facebook fast, I was made aware of the following post by my friend Marlena Graves. I thought I’d share it, just in case anyone is considering Cedarville as a choice for college. I’d still strongly recommend you attend another institution, where you can trust the administration. My previous thoughts on these matters still stand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peru 2014!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/peru-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 17:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/peru-2014/</guid>
      <description>I’m happy to announce that Rachel and I will be completing my required Cross Cultural Ministry Practicum for Beeson Divinity School along with our good friends Kyle, Rebekah, and baby Luke DeBoer in Lima, Peru this summer!
Our goal is to assist the Stone families (Dave &amp;amp; Evelyn; Jonathan &amp;amp; Angela) in their various local ministries, including:
Seminario Teológico Bautista (Seminary) Luz del Camino Iglesia (Church) Vida Nueva Centro Prenatal (Pregnancy Center) The goal of Beeson’s required Cross Cultural Ministry Practicum is to “expose students to issues related to cross-cultural ministry through first-hand experience in a cross-cultural ministry setting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Regional ETS Presentation: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 15:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>If you’re in the Birmingham area from March 21-22, 2014, and you’re interested in evangelical theology, please consider attending the Evangelical Theological Society’s Southeastern Regional Meeting at Beeson Divinity School! This year’s theme is “the theological interpretation of Scripture,” and the plenary speaker is Wheaton’s Daniel J. Treier (incidentally, Dr. Treier and I are both alumni of Cedarville…go figure).
Furthermore, if you’re free from 5:00-5:30pm on Friday, March 21, consider swinging by room S009 to hear me present “Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof: Atonement, Ecclesiology, and the Unity of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Translation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-perfect-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 09:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-perfect-translation/</guid>
      <description>Over the break between semesters at Beeson Divinity School, I’m reviewing Bruce Waltke’s The Dance Between God and Humanity: Reading the Bible Today as the People of God and Philip Goodwin’s Translating the English Bible: From Relevance to Deconstruction for Liverpool Hope University’s Theological Book Review.
I’ve just finished the latter, and hope to write my review in the next day or two. However, I’d like to share the following quotes on Deconstructive Literalism and The Perfect Translation, because I find the concepts intriguing as a student of Eugene Nida’s dynamic or functional equivalence (when it comes to both NT Greek and modern Spanish), and a newcomer to relevance theory, which Goodwin uses to provide a way forward in the shadow of the KJV tradition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Epistle to Philemon: Analysis and Application</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-epistle-to-philemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-epistle-to-philemon/</guid>
      <description>As the briefest member of the Pauline corpus, the epistle to Philemon is a letter of recommendation for the sake of reconciliation in which the apostle Paul brings the gospel truth of mutual participation in the body of Christ to bear on an estranged relationship – making a delicate request of his friend Philemon to receive back a certain Onesimus into full fellowship as a brother in Christ.[1] Comprehension of the passage’s contemporaneous Greco-Roman epistolary landscape facilitates a knowledgeable analysis of its constituent parts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Friday Book Recommendation: The Economy of Desire</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/black-friday-book-recommendation-the-economy-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 16:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/black-friday-book-recommendation-the-economy-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>Black Friday proves that the progress of (post)modernity has failed to eradicate the ills of idolatry. Lest we denizens of the “highly-developed” world think that we have left the primitive vestiges of wood, rock, and gold idolatry behind, our shopping patterns (and indeed our shopping identities as consumers) should remind us of our consumerism’s dark side — a lethal one.
As I’ve put in “Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof”:
“Although physical idols may not be as universally common today as they once were, invisible idols are as prevalent as ever, especially within the context of Western materialism, where money, possessions, influence, and power are the modern-day Baal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silence and Violence</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/silence-and-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 18:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/silence-and-violence/</guid>
      <description>[![](http://malcolmguite.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/p1050316silent-cross.jpg?w=500&amp;h=646)](http://malcolmguite.wordpress.com/2013/11/06/silence-a-sonnet-for-remembrance-day-3/)Silent Cross by Margot Krebs Neale “Violence is not human destiny because the God of peace is the beginning and the end of human history…
“Granted, pushing the stone of peace up the steep hill of violence … is hard. It is easier, however, than carrying one’s own cross in the footsteps of the crucified Messiah. This is what Jesus Christ asks Christians to do. Assured of God’s justice and undergirded by God’s presence, they are to break the cycle of violence by refusing to be caught in the automatism of revenge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Holy Trinity: What Is It? (Why) Is It Important?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/holy-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 21:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/holy-trinity/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: The Holy Trinity One God. Three persons. The Holy Trinity.
The orthodox paradox of this Christian confession confounds many, due to its apparent contradictions, abstractions, and absence from Scripture. From Arius to Augustine and beyond, trinitarian debates have raged even among those who agree that God exists, that the Bible is true, and that it is therefore worthwhile to consider what the Bible says because it reveals the existent God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 2: Quare Fremuerunt Gentes? (Why Do the Nations Rage?)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/psalm-2-quare-fremuerunt-gentes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 22:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/psalm-2-quare-fremuerunt-gentes/</guid>
      <description>(Here’s my paper on Psalm 2, submitted to Dr. M. Sydney Park in partial fulfillment of my Biblical Interpretation course here at Beeson Divinity School. Although I don’t consider this the best thing I’ve ever written, I’d love for you to check this piece out and let me know what you think, because no matter the limitations of the assignment, there’s always room for improvement. Plus, I didn’t have space to talk about all the issues whirring around in my head while writing this paper, and your constructive feedback might very well help me take my next intellectual steps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miroslav Volf on Divine Violence</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/volf-on-divine-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 08:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/volf-on-divine-violence/</guid>
      <description>A couple relevant excerpts (given recent posts) from “Violence and Peace,” the final chapter of Miroslav Volf’s Exclusion and Embrace (my emphasis added in bold; paragraph breaks added where noted):
“God will judge, not because God gives people what they deserve, but because some people refuse to receive what no one deserves; if evildoers experience God’s terror, it will not be because they have done evil, but because they have resisted to the end the powerful lure of the open arms of the crucified Messiah.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down With the Pacifists!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/down-with-the-pacifists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 20:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/down-with-the-pacifists/</guid>
      <description>The past week has been a great one for slipshod attacks on pacifism. First, from First Things (Stephen H. Webb) on October 15 —- “John Howard Yoder and the Violent Power of Pacifism” (emphasis added below):
“Nevertheless, pacifists, at least the ones I know, can be very enthusiastic about the rightness of their cause. Since there is no rational justification for pacifism, defenders typically turn their rhetoric against their critics by casting them as stooges of the status quo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scripture: What The Bible Is And Why It Matters</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 13:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-scripture/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION: THE NATURE OF SCRIPTURE As the illocutionary act which testifies to the Son of God1 as the ultimate redemptive and revelatory locution of the the triune God, Scripture is used by the Spirit of God to accomplish the perlocutionary end of redemption of, in, and through the people of God.2 [Ahem, in order to understand my first paragraph, you must first be familiar with the basics of Speech Act Theory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>King Jesus&amp;#039; Kingdom Gospel</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 13:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</guid>
      <description>I highly encourage the following:
1. Read Scot McKnight’s The King Jesus Gospel.
2. Check out Tim Gombis’ insightful series of posts on The Gospel of the Kingdom, pt. 1, 2, and 3.
Gombis hits the nail on the head here:
Over the last several months, I’ve had several conversations about how the Gospels’ language about “the gospel” should shape how Christians conceive of the gospel. Whereas the New Testament mainly envisions a broader announcement of a larger reality, many evangelicals associate “the gospel” with a brief presentation, or information about the mechanics of an individual transaction that can secure divine forgiveness and the establishment of a personal relationship with God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alabama Update</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20130719alabama-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 09:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20130719alabama-update/</guid>
      <description>Rachel and I are in the middle of our second month of calling Birmingham, Alabama “home.”
While we could both do with a little less humidity (!), we’re enjoying ourselves and our surroundings down here in Alabama.
What’s Happening in Birmingham, AL: I don’t start my M.Div. coursework at Beeson Divinity School until late August, but I’ve already started working at Beeson’s Media Center (follow our nascent Twitter account here). It’s an incredibly convenient on-campus job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Requiescas in Pace, Mi Avia</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/requiescas-in-pace-mi-avia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 17:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/requiescas-in-pace-mi-avia/</guid>
      <description>“Depart, O Christian soul, out of this world;
In the Name of God the Father Almighty who created you;
In the Name of Jesus Christ who redeemed you;
In the Name of the Holy Spirit who sanctifies you.
May your rest be this day in peace,
and your dwelling place in the Paradise of God.”</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inductive Bible Study in 7 Steps: &amp;#8220;Scripture, Handle With Care,&amp;#8221; by Amy Chase Ashley</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/inductive-bible-study-7-steps-amy-chase-ashley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/inductive-bible-study-7-steps-amy-chase-ashley/</guid>
      <description>Update (April 2017): I’ve gone back to update/clean-up the formatting in this wonderful June 2013 guest post on the basics of inductive Bible study from my friend **Amy Elizabeth Chase Ashley,** one of the most gifted students of Scripture with whom I’ve been privileged to study. She blogs at . --- Jeremiah 29:11 When I accepted the invitation to speak at my parents’ church, I immediately started thinking about what message I would deliver.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heads up! Guest post on the way.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heads-up-guest-post-on-the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 13:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heads-up-guest-post-on-the-way/</guid>
      <description>Great news! The first ever guest post on this blog is coming soon from my good friend Amy Chase, an incoming student this Fall at Asbury Theological Seminary.
Her post? A sermon titled “Jeremiah 29:11, Scripture: Handle with Care.”
Stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Un)Righteous Anger? &amp;#8211; Yoda, Jonah, Nahum, and Us</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unrighteous-anger-yoda-jonah-nahum-and-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 21:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unrighteous-anger-yoda-jonah-nahum-and-us/</guid>
      <description>(TEXTS: Jonah 3:5-10; 4:1-11; Nahum 1:1-8)
INTRODUCTION A great green theologian of old claimed that anger is based on fear, that it leads to hatred, and results in suffering. And while I do not wish to disregard the wisdom of a long time ago in a galaxy far, far away, I would like to take a closer look at anger as discussed in Scripture, and to consider what makes certain instances of anger righteous or unrighteous, legitimate or illegitimate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Unforgettable Cedarville Experience (pt 2)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience-pt-2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 09:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience-pt-2-2/</guid>
      <description>Since my [previous post](https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/12/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/ &#34;My Unforgettable Cedarville Experience&#34;), quite a few things have happened at my alma mater. Here’s a [Storify overview](https://storify.com/fiatlux125/cedarville-2012-2013/) of my crazy final year at Cedarville University. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Farewell to Cedarville</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-farewell-to-cedarville/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 06:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-farewell-to-cedarville/</guid>
      <description>(Originally posted in The Ventriloquist. Go check out the rest of Issue 10!)
“A Farewell to Cedarville” – Joshua Steele
As what was once a vision for the future has become an agenda for returning to the past, the list of people who no longer fit the Cedarville mold is growing. I contacted former vice president of Student Life, Dr. Carl Ruby; former professor Dr. Michael Pahl; current professors Dr. TC Ham, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honors, Grace, and Generosity</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/honors-grace-and-generosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 22:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/honors-grace-and-generosity/</guid>
      <description>Yahweh and others have been too good to me.
Today I received two awards at Cedarville University’s 49th Annual Academic Honors Day Chapel.
The first: The Oxford University Press Award in Preseminary Bible, given to the graduating senior with the highest cumulative GPA in the preseminary major.
The second: The Daniel Award.
“Established in 2001 by David and Jean Heyd, this endowed award was created to honor their parents, Charles and E.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Building/Burning Bridges</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-buildingburning-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-buildingburning-bridges/</guid>
      <description>DISCLAIMER: there’s a fair bit about the Church that frustrates me.
However, I’d like to address those frustrations in a way that builds bridges, not burns them down. Especially since sin and justice are both relational. It does no good to flee the former for the latter in a way that creates more rifts than it heals.
Therefore, any criticisms I level against my sisters and brothers in Christ, (many of those criticisms coming from outside the walls of the Church), I’d like first to aim them at myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let There Be Light: My Resignation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/let-there-be-light-my-resignation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 16:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/let-there-be-light-my-resignation/</guid>
      <description>**Please read: Let There Be Light – Leadership Transfer**
Until further notice, I hereby rescind my use of the Let There Be Light platform (including blog, Facebook, and Twitter) to protest recent changes at Cedarville University. The LTBL platform will now be exclusively alumni-run, and I encourage everyone interested in developments at the University to follow their posts and make subsequent judgments regarding Cedarville’s identity and vision.
My goal in all of this is to honor my Messiah by following him well and furthering his Kingdom with justice, unity, and true peace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Apology</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-apology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 23:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-apology/</guid>
      <description>To whomever the following concerns:
I’d like to apologize publicly to any persons I may have offended during the past few months of my student activism efforts at Cedarville University.
After all, I recognize that some of my statements/claims about the perceived injustices at my University have seemed quite shocking, especially without further context. So I apologize for the times when I put pithiness before precision and unwittingly ostracized many good people whom I was not intending to criticize at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For shame, Cedarville</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/2320/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 08:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/2320/</guid>
      <description>This is ridiculous and dangerous. For shame, Mr. Scharnberg and Dr. Gredy.
How dare you try and accomplish this (already concerning) return to fundamentalism in an unethical manner! How dare you sacrifice good men and their families on the altar of your own agenda, and then proceed to bathe your actions in lies!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oh Cedarville&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/oh-cedarville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 07:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/oh-cedarville/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been extremely frustrated with someone/thing you love?
That’s been my experience during my final year here at Cedarville University. See, I love this place. And that’s why I can’t stand it sometimes. There are still so many good and godly women and men here, so much potential for God’s Kingdom. And that’s why recent decisions made by Cedarville Admins and Trustees are so heartbreaking. I’ve written about this before (Open Letter).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Interpreting the Bible: Deuteronomy 6:1-15</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/deuteronomy-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 20:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/deuteronomy-6/</guid>
      <description>Deuteronomy 6:1-15 (NRSV) Now this is the commandment—the statutes and the ordinances—that the Lord your God charged me to teach you to observe in the land that you are about to cross into and occupy, 2 so that you and your children and your children’s children may fear the Lord your God all the days of your life, and keep all his decrees and his commandments that I am commanding you, so that your days may be long.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&amp;#8217;re Reading Romans 13 Wrong! Here&amp;#8217;s How to Read It Correctly</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 07:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-13/</guid>
      <description>This study of Romans 13 rests upon a crucial presupposition: without context, words can mean anything and everything, and therefore mean nothing. It is only through the delimiting influence of context that words, phrases, sentences, and paragraphs are endowed with significance.
Although this concept seems simple and justified enough, it is often forgotten within the field of biblical exegesis. Due to influences as simple as our versification of the biblical text and as complex as the historical/theological developments which have dictated how we teach and interpret the Scriptures, many exegetes (wittingly or unwittingly) ignore context when trying to ascertain the meaning of particular biblical texts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter to Cedarville Admins and Trustees</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 21:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/</guid>
      <description>To my sisters and brothers in Christ, entrusted with the arduous task of leading and directing Cedarville University: greetings, grace, and peace.
Allow me to thank you all for your countless hours of service to this institution. I do not want to underestimate your care and concern for this place. In fact, I want to reassure you that I share your passion. Here at Cedarville I have been blessed with the opportunity of meeting, falling in love with, and marrying my wife.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Explanation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/an-explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 13:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/an-explanation/</guid>
      <description>If you haven’t read my previous two blog posts, “Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 1 and pt. 2),” please go do so before reading this post.
Summary: I’ve been blogging in order to raise awareness of Cedarville University’s recent dismissal of Dr. Michael Pahl from his teaching post. Using the University’s statement on Dr. Pahl, I’ve raised some uncomfortable questions that I believe need to be asked in this situation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 2)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 07:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>Read Part One
Further Questions, All Relating to the University Statement on Dr. Pahl’s Dismissal: If Dr. Pahl’s book, The Beginning and the End, was controversial enough to lead to his dismissal, why was the book allowed to be used as a textbook last school year? Shouldn’t we trust the Bible professors’ judgment in their selection of the book as a text? If we should, then was it worth firing Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 1)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 15:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>The Statement: “Dr. Michael Pahl has been relieved of his teaching duties because he is unable to concur fully with each and every position of Cedarville University’s doctrinal statement. This decision was made following a review by the University administration and trustees prompted by Dr. Pahl’s recent book, The Beginning and the End: Rereading Genesis’s Stories and Revelation’s Visions.
Dr. Pahl’s orthodoxy and commitment to the gospel are not in question, nor is his commitment to Scripture’s inspiration, authority and infallibility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacrificing Scripture on the Altars of Our Own Agendas</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sacrificing-scripture-on-the-altars-of-our-own-agendas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 16:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sacrificing-scripture-on-the-altars-of-our-own-agendas/</guid>
      <description>Undoubtedly the title of this blog post could be taken in hundreds of different directions. However, given recent developments close to home, and the Answers in Genesis conference coming to Cedarville University on Sept. 23-24, I’d like to get people thinking about Ken Ham, his organization’s agenda, and how Scripture might very well be getting abused for the sake of Young Earth Creationism.
I say this as someone who used to be a zealous defender of everything that Answers in Genesis stands for.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 3)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 08:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-3/</guid>
      <description>(Read Pt. 1 and Pt. 2 first!)
CREATION AND REDEMPTION: CHRIST AND NEW CREATION Throughout the New Testament, the main use of creation theology is to link creation with redemption, resulting in the praise of the Creator through the Creator-Redeemer, Jesus the Messiah. However, the linked concepts of creation and redemption have a rich OT history. For example, cited impetuses for keeping the Sabbath are Yahweh’s creative work (Exod 20:11) and his redemptive work (Deut 5:15), revealing a close connection between the two actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 2)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 20:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>(Read Pt. 1 First!)
CREATION, COMPLEXITY, AND CHAOS Much of the chaos in the universe can be ascribed to the infiltration of Sin and Death as described in Genesis 3. However, an oft-overlooked facet of biblical creation theology is the appropriate place of complexity and chaos within God’s creation. Even when the effects of the Fall are ignored, God’s temple is by no means a tame environment, nor is humanity the sole venue through which Yahweh receives glory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 1)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 17:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION In many conservative evangelical circles, biblical creation theology has been hijacked and eclipsed by the vitriolic debate between Young Earth Creationism and Neo-Darwinism.[1] It is often difficult to see beyond this morass the beautiful tapestry of creation themes in biblical theology. Waltke summarizes the problem well: “Instead of metaphysical questions that shape culture, questions about dinosaurs, a young earth theory, and such dominate the evangelical landscape. This is unfortunate.”[2] Nevertheless, there is an embarrassment of riches when it comes to Scripture’s use of creation themes, whether the evangelical community gives them appropriate attention or not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Unforgettable Cedarville Experience</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 19:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/</guid>
      <description>(The following is an expanded version of the speech I gave at this year’s CU Scholar Dessert Reception.)
The first thing I ever decided about Cedarville University was that I would not, under any circumstances, attend. Since my administrator’s son, Drew Flamm, worked in admissions at CU, I had been inundated since before I could remember with calls to become a yellow-jacket, and out of sheer stubbornness of heart, I refused.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Vows: My Personal Take on the Traditional Version</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wedding-vows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 20:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wedding-vows/</guid>
      <description>The Traditional Wedding Vows In case you didn’t know, the “traditional” wedding vows – in English, at least – are found in the Book of Common Prayer.
In the 1662 Book of Common Prayer, the marriage vows read as follows:
I M. take thee N. to my wedded wife, to have and to hold,
from this day forward, for better for worſe, for richer for poorer, in ſickneſs and in health, to love and to cheriſh, till death us do part, according to God’s holy ordinance; and thereto I plight thee my troth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Romans, Distilled and Paraphrased</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-distilled-paraphrased/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 14:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-distilled-paraphrased/</guid>
      <description>The following is an attempt, written in 2012, to distill and paraphrase the main argument/message/story/logic of St. Paul’s Epistle to the Romans.
Romans 1:1-17 If you don’t catch anything else from what I’m about to say, remember this:
God is righteous. He is just. He is faithful.
God has proven himself faithful to his promises of restoring the world, working through his faithful Son, the Messiah, to bring about both our faith in and our faithfulness to him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 19:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unity/</guid>
      <description>The more I study the New Testament, I become more convinced that the unity of the Church is of utmost importance to God.
What bothers me is that this has never been taught to me before. All of the things I’ve learned (specifically in my studies on Philippians, Galatians, and now Romans) about the importance of unity for the sake of the Gospel mission and the Kingdom of God have come as somewhat of a shock.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Good News of Christmas</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-good-news-of-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 13:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-good-news-of-christmas/</guid>
      <description>After reading The King Jesus Gospel: The Original Good News Revisited by Scot McKnight, who makes the claim that the gospel is the saving story of Jesus as Messiah, King, and Lord as the completion to the story of Israel, I started to notice some profound gospel messages in the Christmas carols we often sing during this season.
I have found that several of these carols go much deeper (much more biblical) than the personal salvation “gospel” of sin-management that we often preach and sing about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Church and State</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/church_and_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 12:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/church_and_state/</guid>
      <description>(Note: for a more recent piece on the relationship between Church and State, see my essay: “Improvising Church and State.”)
I just read an article by Kevin DeYoung at The Gospel Coalition: “Thinking Theologically About Memorial Day”. Listen to his intro:
This post probably has something to make everyone unhappy. But here goes.
With Memorial Day on Monday (in the U.S.) and, no doubt, a number of patriotic services scheduled for this Sunday, I want to offer a few theses on patriotism and the church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Bible Says About Poverty: The Book of Proverbs</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bible-poverty-proverbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 23:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bible-poverty-proverbs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Poverty and Wealth In contrast to the affluence of mainstream American culture, poverty is a harsh and painful reality. It can be found in abundance in the urban centers of this country, and in countless other places around the globe.
Modern day slavery “more cruel than any beast of prey” (Wright 2005, 136), it traps human beings created in the image of God in a lifestyle of hunger, sickness, anger, and darkness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My High School Graduation Valedictorian Speech was a Poem</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-valediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 21:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-valediction/</guid>
      <description>My Valedictorian Address, a Poem The following is my valedictorian speech, delivered at my high school graduation in 2009. As you’ll see below, the majority of the speech was an original poem. Sure, I’m tempted to be a bit embarrassed by the poem today, but I’m also proud that I went for it. Let me know what you think!
GRADUATION! Such a mix of emotions comes with this simple word…</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From a Grateful Son: A Mother&amp;#8217;s Day Poem</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mothers-day-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 22:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mothers-day-poem/</guid>
      <description>The following is an original Mother’s Day poem of mine, that I wrote for my mom (the best mom ever, of course) back in 2009. It’s called “From a Grateful Son,” and I hope that you enjoy it.
From a Grateful Son – A Poem for My Mother Thank you, Mom, for having me
that day so long ago.
Thank you, then, for holding me
and now for letting go.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
