<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/miscellaneous/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:51:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/miscellaneous/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6 Things I&#39;m Excited About (2024-08-04)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/6-things-im-excited-about-2024-08-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/6-things-im-excited-about-2024-08-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sweater weather&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Losing weight with some help from Zepbound&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Football season (pulling for the Detroit Lions and the University of Michigan Wolverines)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Harbor Freight coming out with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/harborfreight/comments/17mj1sv/from_sema_2023_the_meme_mini_socket_set_is/&#34;&gt;version 2.0 of its “meme tool”&lt;/a&gt; – now with sockets! Hopefully out before the end of the year&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3z6A93Y&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Widening of God’s Mercy: Sexuality Within the Biblical Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Christopher and Richard Hays when it comes out next week&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Learning auto repair by working on my dad’s 1999 Dodge Ram 1500 (next up: replacing the governor pressure solenoid and sensor in the transmission, which will hopefully help with the truck getting stuck in low gear!)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are you excited about these days?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/6-things-im-excited-about-2024-08-04/</guid>
      <description>Sweater weather Losing weight with some help from Zepbound Football season (pulling for the Detroit Lions and the University of Michigan Wolverines) Harbor Freight coming out with version 2.0 of its “meme tool” – now with sockets! Hopefully out before the end of the year Reading The Widening of God’s Mercy: Sexuality Within the Biblical Story by Christopher and Richard Hays when it comes out next week Learning auto repair by working on my dad’s 1999 Dodge Ram 1500 (next up: replacing the governor pressure solenoid and sensor in the transmission, which will hopefully help with the truck getting stuck in low gear!</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Fellow ACNA Clergy: On Anti-Racism and a More Diverse and Just Anglicanism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: As is our policy with &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; Anglican Compass content, we ask that you &lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com/republishing-guidelines/&#34;&gt;please submit a request before republishing content&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://adoc.church/a-letter-concerning-the-death-of-george-floyd-and-so-many-others/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;recently wrote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care. Whether you’re ACNA clergy, a layperson, or a Christian leader outside the ACNA, we invite your consideration of the following and your &lt;a href=&#34;#sign&#34;&gt;signature&lt;/a&gt; in support.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: As is our policy with all Anglican Compass content, we ask that you please submit a request before republishing content.
Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who recently wrote in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care.</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
