<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Church and Theology on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/church-and-theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Church and Theology on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:03:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/church-and-theology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Christianity and Politics: My 2024 Reading List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/christianity-and-politics-my-2024-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/christianity-and-politics-my-2024-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Church and State, particularly the intersection of Christianity and politics, has been on my mind since I first started paying attention during the lead-up to the 2008 USA presidential election. Back then, I was just a high school student, but these themes have stuck with me ever since.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(For those curious, here’s a quick timeline: In 2012, I was studying biblical studies in college. By 2016, I was a seminarian, and in 2020, I was working on my Ph.D. in theology. Now, in 2024, I’m a software engineer! Yet political theology continues to weigh on my mind.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death in His Grave</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/death-in-his-grave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 20:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/death-in-his-grave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Holy Week and Easter coming up, I’ve been thinking about music and artwork that I’ve found particularly poignant when reflection on the crucifixion and resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, I’ve seen many icons of the resurrection (“anastasis,” in Greek) like the one below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But I don’t think I fully appreciated the image until I realized it was Adam and Eve that Christ is helping up out of their graves. He’s trampled down the doors/gates of Hell and is taking an elderly Adam and an elderly Eve by the hand. Rescuing them from the realm of Death, in order to bring them back to eternal life with God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Possibly Unpopular Opinions about Church</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/25-possibly-unpopular-opinions-about-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 13:42:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/25-possibly-unpopular-opinions-about-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following are some of my opinions, held with varying levels of intensity, about church/churches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: These are geared toward Christian churches in the USA. Some would obviously also apply to churches elsewhere. But I haven’t nuanced this entire list for all global church contexts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many churches in the USA are too “busy.” They are trying to do too many different things and should instead refocus on the church’s proper priorities (Word and Sacraments).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logos 10 Bible Software: The Ultimate Theological Learning Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 13:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: If you’re serious about biblical and theological studies, you should invest in Logos 10 Bible Software. &lt;a href=&#34;https://partners.faithlife.com/click.track?CID=431490&amp;amp;AFID=529204&#34;&gt;Do so via my exclusive partner offer for Logos 10 here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I could go back in time and chat with Joshua Steele when he was a Bible &amp;amp; Spanish major in college, there are a few things I’d tell my younger self:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quit laughing at &lt;em&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/em&gt; by Mortimer J. Adler and READ the thing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baba ghanoush is superior to hummus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study computer science sooner rather than later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bite the bullet and INVEST IN A LOGOS BIBLE SOFTWARE LIBRARY.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong. I love physical books as much as anyone, and I own quite a few (hundred)!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Stir the Pot?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dont-stir-the-pot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dont-stir-the-pot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pondering the “don’t stir the pot” reaction that reliably happens every time we publish something on women’s ordination—most especially anything in &lt;em&gt;favor&lt;/em&gt; of women’s ordination—&lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com/&#34;&gt;over at Anglican Compass&lt;/a&gt;, where I’m the Managing Editor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: This post is not a subtweet of anyone in particular. It’s just me thinking out loud about a phenomenon that keeps occurring.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Almost every time we post something about women’s ordination, a controversial issue has been whether or not doing so needlessly “stirs the pot,” as in “causes trouble, unrest, dissent.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help! I&#39;m looking for examples of &#34;theological triage,&#34; &#34;doctrinal taxonomy,&#34; or &#34;dogmatic rank&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/help-im-looking-for-examples-of-theological-triage-doctrinal-taxonomy-or-dogmatic-rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 16:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/help-im-looking-for-examples-of-theological-triage-doctrinal-taxonomy-or-dogmatic-rank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a research project, I’m looking for examples of the reasoning that goes into what’s been called, among other things&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“theological triage,”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“doctrinal taxonomy,” or&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“dogmatic rank.”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m referring to the process of distinguishing between various levels of importance when it comes to theological statements/positions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, for example, the Trinity would usually be considered a “first-order” or “primary” doctrine—a “dogma,” if you will. But a specific view of the end times would usually be considered a “second-order,” “secondary,” or “tertiary” doctrine—AKA “adiaphora.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My favorite definition of &#34;theology&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-favorite-definition-of-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 21:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-favorite-definition-of-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is from Robert Jenson, &lt;em&gt;Systematic Theology&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 1, p. 11:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The church has a mission: to see to the speaking of the gospel, whether to the world as message of salvation or to God as appeal and praise. Theology is the reflection internal to the church’s labor on this assignment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(How) does this definition of “theology” differ from the one you’ve been working with?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;True Christianity cannot be a private Christianity&#34; (Barth)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/true-christianity-cannot-be-a-private-christianity-barth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 18:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/true-christianity-cannot-be-a-private-christianity-barth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;![](https://i0.wp.com/joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Karl-Barth-Quote-Green.png?fit=640%2C360&amp;ssl=1)&lt;/figure&gt;&gt; In short, if I am inhuman, I am also stupid and foolish and godless. The great crisis in which all worship and piety and adoration and prayer and theology constantly finds itself derives of course from the question whether and how far in these things we really have to do with the true and living God who reveals Himself in His Word, and not with an idol. But this question is decided concretely in practice by another one which is inseparable from it—whether and how far in these things we come before God together and not apart from and against one another. True Christianity cannot be a private Christianity, i.e., a rapacious Christianity. Inhumanity at once makes it a counterfeit Christianity.&#xA;&gt; &#xA;&gt; &lt;cite&gt;Barth, Church Dogmatics IV/2, 442.&lt;/cite&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two of Bonhoeffer&#39;s Most Convicting Paragraphs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/two-of-bonhoeffers-most-convicting-paragraphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/two-of-bonhoeffers-most-convicting-paragraphs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is from Bonhoeffer’s &lt;em&gt;Discipleship&lt;/em&gt; (usually known as “The Cost of Discipleship” in English, although the original title in German was simply &lt;em&gt;Nachfolge&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bonhoeffer considers how we might respond to Jesus if Jesus were to show up and make the same kinds of concrete commands that he did in the Gospels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: I’ve taken two paragraphs in the original and broken them up into smaller chunks to facilitate reading here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “Via Media”? Or the “Middle Ground Fallacy”?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-via-media-or-the-middle-ground-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 14:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-via-media-or-the-middle-ground-fallacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At this point, this is just a sketch. But I’m wondering how we Anglican Christians ought to be careful to keep our precious “via media” (“middle way”) mentality and methodology separate from what’s known as the “middle ground” fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-via-media&#34;&gt;The “Via Media”&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Donald McKim in the &lt;em&gt;Westminster Dictionary of Theological Terms&lt;/em&gt;, the “via media” is&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Lat. “the middle way”) Term used to describe the identity of Anglicanism as a middle way between Roman Catholicism and Protestantism. It was coined by John Henry Newman (1801–90) during the Oxford movement (337).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Outline of Karl Barth&#39;s Church Dogmatics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/an-outline-of-karl-barths-church-dogmatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 15:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/an-outline-of-karl-barths-church-dogmatics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/BarthTimeline-2-1024x536-1024x536.png)&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-element-caption&#34;&gt;[Karl Barth’s Church Dogmatics Original Publication Dates, courtesy of PostBarthian.com](https://postbarthian.com/2016/04/21/karl-barths-church-dogmatics-original-publication-dates/).&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;If you’re trying to grasp the contours and contents of Karl Barth’s massive *[Church Dogmatics](https://www.logos.com/product/5758/barths-church-dogmatics),* it helps to have an outline! Here’s a helpful PDF version, with subheadings included, from Princeton’s [Center for Barth Studies](http://barth.ptsem.edu).&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-file aligncenter&#34;&gt;[Barth\_Outline of Church Dogmatics](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Barth_Outline-of-Church-Dogmatics.pdf)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Barth_Outline-of-Church-Dogmatics.pdf)&lt;/div&gt;Below is a version that I’ve created from my Logos edition of *Church Dogmatics*. It’s the version found in the Index (CD V/1, 1–13).&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Want to learn more about Karl Barth, but not quite ready to dive into the &lt;em&gt;Church Dogmatics&lt;/em&gt;? Check out Keith Johnson’s extremely helpful &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/45IDpg5&#34;&gt;The Essential Karl Barth: A Reader and Commentary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; [affiliate link].)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Guilt of Karl Barth: Strengths and Weaknesses of Barth’s Römerbrief Reading of Romans 9:30–10:21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-guilt-of-karl-barth-strengths-and-weaknesses-of-barths-romerbrief-reading-of-romans-9301021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 14:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-guilt-of-karl-barth-strengths-and-weaknesses-of-barths-romerbrief-reading-of-romans-9301021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: Here is the paper that I gave at the 2019 Karl Barth Graduate Student Colloquium at the Center for Barth Studies at Princeton Theological Seminary.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-gentiles--world-is-worse-than-israel--church&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION: “GENTILES” = “WORLD” IS WORSE THAN “ISRAEL” = “CHURCH”&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On at least one level, Karl Barth’s Römerbrief reading of Romans 9–11 is supersessionist. In general, especially in the second edition, when Paul refers to “Israel” in Romans 9–11, Barth refers to the “Church.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#post-41871-footnote-1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; He replaces Israel with the Church. That’s supersessionism, case closed. Right? Well, yes and no. It has become increasingly common to at least mitigate or nuance the charge of supersessionism against Barth’s reading of Romans 9–11. Various scholars have broadly argued that, yes, Barth’s handling of Romans 9–11 at least leaves the door open for at least a certain kind of supersessionism, but, no, he wasn’t being quite as careless with Israel as it might initially seem.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#post-41871-footnote-2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; By and large, I agree with these assessments. Barth should have said more about the actual people and history of Israel, but he wasn’t trying to merely displace Israel with the Church, as if the latter were superior and the former were forgotten. He was trying to bring Israel and the Church together in solidarity, in opposition to the arrogance of the Church.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I think Karl Barth missed the (pastoral) point of Romans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/i-think-karl-barth-missed-the-pastoral-point-of-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 15:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/i-think-karl-barth-missed-the-pastoral-point-of-romans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m scheduled to give a paper on Karl Barth’s reading of Romans 9:30–10:21 in &lt;em&gt;Der Römerbrief&lt;/em&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;2019 Barth Graduate Student Colloquium&lt;/a&gt; at Princeton in August.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, of course, it’s a pleasure and a privilege to give a paper at the colloquium. However, in hindsight, I don’t know why I thought giving a paper on chapter 10 of Barth’s Römerbrief was a good idea!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Granted, I don’t have to solve all of the exegetical issues (of which there are many) in Romans 9:30–10:21. I just have to make some sense of what &lt;em&gt;Barth&lt;/em&gt; thought about the passage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When will Thy Kingdom Come? The Timing and Agency of the Kingdom of God in the Lord&#39;s Prayer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/when-will-thy-kingdom-come-the-timing-and-agency-of-the-kingdom-of-god-in-the-lords-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 15:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/when-will-thy-kingdom-come-the-timing-and-agency-of-the-kingdom-of-god-in-the-lords-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Here’s a PDF of this paper: &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/STEELE_When-Will-Thy-Kingdom-Come.pdf&#34;&gt;STEELE_When Will Thy Kingdom Come&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-thy-kingdom-haswill-come&#34;&gt;Introduction: “Thy Kingdom [Has/Will] Come”?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just how &lt;em&gt;eschatological&lt;/em&gt; is the Lord’s Prayer (=LP; Matt. 6:9–13; Luke 11:2–4), particularly in light of its second petition, “Your kingdom come” (ἐλθέτω ἡ βασιλεία σου, Matt. 6:10a; Luke 11:2d)? In other words, when will God’s kingdom come? Has it already arrived (not eschatological)? Is it in the process of arriving? Or will it arrive at some point in the future (eschatological)? Furthermore, who brings the kingdom about? Humans? God? Or some combination of the two? Settling the question of eschatology involves both the timing and the agency, the &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt;, of the kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Into the Far Country</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/into-the-far-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 12:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/into-the-far-country/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Karl-Barth-Quote-Blue.png&#34; alt=&#34;Karl Barth Quote Blue&#34; title=&#34;Karl Barth Quote Blue.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ has gone into the far country in our stead, to bring us home to God!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are your &#34;must-own&#34; biblical and theological studies reference works?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-are-your-must-own-biblical-and-theological-studies-reference-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 21:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-are-your-must-own-biblical-and-theological-studies-reference-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It just happened again. I had to consult &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.logos.com/product/3878/a-greek-english-lexicon-of-the-new-testament-and-other-early-christian-literature-3rd-ed&#34;&gt;“BDAG,” A Greek–English Lexicon of the New Testament and Other Early Christian Literature (3rd ed.)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t own a copy, so every time I have to consult BDAG I think “I really should buy this.” But for the past decade or so, primarily because of BDAG’s cost ($150 on Logos, $130 used on Amazon, $165 new on Amazon) I’ve held off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I’m seeking to build my “must-have” personal reference library to sustain a ministry as a pastor theologian. So, I think I need to buy BDAG sometime soon. While I’m at it, I might as well get HALOT, the Hebrew and Aramaic Lexicon of the Old Testament… &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.logos.com/product/5228/bdag-halot-bundle&#34;&gt;Logos sells them as a bundle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s more than one kind of &#34;priesthood&#34; in the New Testament</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/theres-more-than-one-kind-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 20:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/theres-more-than-one-kind-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/nbfr.12440&#34;&gt;this article in New Blackfriars&lt;/a&gt;, and it looks helpful, especially in the context of Anglican debates about women’s ordination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Title: “The Four Types of Priesthood in the New Testament: On Avoiding Confusions about What ‘Priesthood’ Means”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Author: Geoffrey Turner&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian discourse tends to treat the concept of ‘priesthood’ univocally, so that ordained priests are seen to share the priesthood of Christ. But a careful reading of Hebrews shows clearly that the priesthood of Christ is unique to him. There are four (even five) types of priest in the New Testament and each of them is distinct and not to be confused.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Ordination Debates in Anglicanism: The 2017 ACNA Report and the 2003 AMIA Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/womens-ordination-debates-in-anglicanism-the-2017-acna-report-and-the-2003-amia-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/womens-ordination-debates-in-anglicanism-the-2017-acna-report-and-the-2003-amia-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I became an “egalitarian” in college, before I became an Anglican in seminary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s taken some time for me to get used to the different contours of the women’s ordination debate within Anglicanism. Growing up, the debate was all about particular Bible verses and whether or not women could teach and preach. However, in Anglicanism, although those same questions/arguments are present, I hear much more about whether or not women can administer the sacraments as priests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the relationship between biblical and systematic/dogmatic theology?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 15:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the question we’re considering this week in our doctoral seminar on biblical and theological integration. Two of us are theologians and the other four are bible scholars. Should be interesting!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: we’ll have to save the difference(s) between systematic, historical, and dogmatic theology for another post!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the articles we were assigned to read for this week:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;D.A. Carson, “Systematic Theology and Biblical Theology” in the New Dictionary of Biblical Theology, pp. 89-104.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;D.A. Carson, “Unity and Diversity in the New Testament: The Possibility of Systematic Theology” in Scripture and Truth, D. A. Carson and J. D. Woodbridge, eds. (Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 1983), pp. 65-95.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;G. Hasel, “The Relationship between Biblical Theology and Systematic Theology” Trinity Journal 5 (1984): 113-27;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I.H. Marshall, “Climbing Ropes, Ellipses and Symphonies: The Relation between Biblical and Systematic Theology” in A Pathway into the Holy Scripture, P.E. Satterthwaite and D.F. Wright, eds. (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1994), 199–219.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;E.A. Martens, “Moving from Scripture to Doctrine” Bulletin for Biblical Research 15.1 (2005): 77-103.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kevin Vanhoozer, “Interpreting Scripture between the Rock of Biblical Studies and the Hard Place of Systematic Theology: The State of the Evangelical (Dis)union” in Richard Lints, ed., Renewing the Evangelical Mission (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2013), 201-25.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other than that, for the rest of the semester, we’re reading at least selections from the following works. The goal is to learn from examples of biblical and theological integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer of Confession</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/a-prayer-of-confession/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 20:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/a-prayer-of-confession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To start off the semester the other day, we prayed this prayer of confession together as a class. The professor didn’t remember where the prayer was from, so &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thegospelcoalition.org/blogs/justin-taylor/a-corporate-confession-of-faith-based-on-the-ten-commandments-and-the-sermon-on-the-mount/&#34;&gt;I tracked it down online. According to Justin Taylor, it was written by Bob Kauflin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy and righteous God, we confess that like Isaiah, we are a people of unclean lips. But it is not only unclean lips we possess. We are people with unclean hands and unclean hearts. We have broken your law times without number, and are guilty of pride, unbelief, self-centeredness and idolatry. Affect our hearts with the severity of our sin and the glory of your righteousness as we now acknowledge our sins in your holy presence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Christian Theology: A Draft Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 22:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a part of my “pedagogical experience” at Wheaton College this semester, I was required to draft a syllabus for an introduction to Christian theology. Feel free to let me know what you think in the comments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: the length of this syllabus doesn’t necessarily correspond to the difficulty of this course&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-information&#34;&gt;Contact Information&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Email: [REDACTED]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Phone: [REDACTED]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Office Hours (Buswell Library Carrell): T, W, R, 15:00–17:00.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course is an introduction to the methods of systematic theology and the major topics within biblical revelation. Special attention is given to the rationale for these Christian doctrines, their systematic interconnections as well as their development within the history of Christian thought, and their contemporary challenges. This class is your opportunity to reinforce why you believe what you believe and to examine how it impacts your life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justification and Sanctification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/justification-and-sanctification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 15:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/justification-and-sanctification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my “Pedagogical Experience” requirement at Wheaton, I’m helping to teach a masters-level Christian Theology course.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I got to teach a lesson on justification and sanctification. A lot to cover in a 95-minute class session!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in what I covered, here are my slides (in PDF format).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-file&#34;&gt;[Justification and Sanctification Slides  ](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/19.-Justification-and-Sanctification.pdf)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/19.-Justification-and-Sanctification.pdf)&lt;/div&gt;And here is the handout (Word document).&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-file&#34;&gt;[Justification and Sanctification Handout  ](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/19.-Justification-and-Sanctification.docx)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/19.-Justification-and-Sanctification.docx)&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Theologies: A List (Help Me Update!)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/systematic-theologies-a-list-help-me-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/systematic-theologies-a-list-help-me-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;systematic-theologies-a-list&#34;&gt;SYSTEMATIC THEOLOGIES: A LIST&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I put together the following list, using the 10th edition of John Glynn’s &lt;em&gt;Commentary and Reference Survey&lt;/em&gt; (Kegel, 2007) as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll be updating this list in the future, but I could use your help. If there’s something that needs included, please let me know in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;systematic-theologies&#34;&gt;Systematic Theologies&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Barth, Karl. Church Dogmatics, 5 vols. In 14 parts. (T&amp;amp;T Clark, [1932–1967] 1936–1969).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bavinck, Herman. Reformed Dogmatics, ed. John Bolt (Baker, 2003-).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Berkhof, Louis. Combined Systematic Theology, 4th ed. (Eerdmans, 1939) and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Berkhof, Louis. Systematic Theology (Eerdmans, 1996).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Berkouwer, G. Studies in Dogmatics, 14 vols. (Eerdmans, 1952-76).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bird, Michael F. Evangelical Theology: A Biblical and Systematic Introduction. (Zondervan, 2013).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bloesch, Donald. Christian Foundations, 7 vols. (IVP, 1992-).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bray, Gerald. God Is Love: A Biblical and Systematic Theology. (Crossway, 2012).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Buswell, James. A Systematic Theology of the Christian Religion, 2 vols. (Zondervan, 1962-63).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calvin, John. Institutes of the Christian Religion, 2 vols. (Westminster John Knox, 1960).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chafer, Lewis. Systematic Theology, 4 vols. (Kregel, 1993). Unabridged.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coakley, Sarah. God, Sexuality, and the Self: An Essay ‘On the Trinity.’ (Cambridge University Press, 2013) Volume 1 of a 4-volume systematic theology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Culver, Robert. Systematic Theology (Christian Focus, 2005).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dulles, Avery. The Craft of Theology (Crossroad, 1992).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Erickson, Millard. Christian Theology, 2d ed. (Baker, 1998).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finger, Thomas. A Contemporary Anabaptist Theology (IVP, 2004).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finger, Thomas. Christian Theology, 2 vols. (Herald, 1985, 1989).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Frame, John. Systematic Theology: An Introduction to Christian Belief. (P&amp;amp;R, 2013).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fries, Heinrich. Fundamental Theology (Catholic University of America, 1996).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garrett, James. Systematic Theology, 1 vols. (Eerdmans, 1990, 1995).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Geisler, Norman. Systematic Theology, 4 vols. (Bethany House, 2002-). Arminian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gerrish, B.A. Christian Faith: Dogmatics in Outline. (Westminster John Knox, 2015).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grenz, Stanley. Theology for the Community of God (Eerdmans, 2000).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grider, J. Kenneth. A Wesleyan-Holiness Theology. (Beacon Hill, 1994).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grudem, Wayne. Systematic Theology (Zondervan, 1994). Calvinistic charismatic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gunton, Colin. The Christian Faith (Blackwell, 2001). Introduction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guthrie, Shirley C., Jr. Christian Doctrine. (WJK, 1994). Revised edition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Henry, Carl. God, Revelation, and Authority, 6 vols. (Word, 1976-83; Crossway, 1999).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hodge, Charles. Systematic Theology, 3 vols. (Hendrickson, 1997).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hodge, Charles. Systematic Theology, abridged 1-vol. ed. (Presbyterian &amp;amp; Reformed, 1997).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Horton, Michael. The Christian Faith. (Zondervan, 2011).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Horton, Stanley, ed. Systematic Theology, rev. ed. (Logion, 1995). Pentecostal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jenson, Robert. Systematic Theology, 2 vols. (Oxford University Press, 1997-99).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kärkkäinen, Veli-Matti. A Constructive Christian Theology for the Pluralistic World, 5 vols. (Eerdmans, 2013-17).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Küng, Hans. Christianity (Continuum, 1995).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lewis, Gordon, and Bruce Demarest. Integrative Theology (Zondervan, 1987-94). Three volumes in one.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;McClendon, James. Systematic Theology, 3 vols. (Abingdon, 2002, 1986-2000). Anabaptist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;McGrath, Alister. Christian Theology, 3d ed. (Blackwell, 2001).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;McKim, Donald. Introducing the Reformed Faith (Westminster John Knox, 2001).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Menzies, William, and Stanley Horton. Bible Doctrines (Logion, 1993). Pentecostal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oden, Thomas. Systematic Theology, 3 vols. (Harper, 1987-92; Prince, 2000). Methodist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olson, Roger. Arminian Theology (IVP, 2006).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olson, Roger. The Mosaic of Christian Belief (IVP, 2002) .&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pannenberg, Wolfhart. Systematic Theology, 3 vols. (Eerdmans, 1991,1994, 1997).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rahner, Karl. Foundations of Christian Faith (Seabury, 1978). Idealist Christology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rahner, Karl. Theological Investigations, 23 vols. (Helicon/Herder and Herder/Seabury/Crossroad, 1961-92).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ratzinger, John. Principles of Catholic Theology (Ignatius, 1987).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rausch, Thomas P. Systematic Theology: A Roman Catholic Approach. (Liturgical Press, 2016).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reymond, Robert. A New Systematic Theology of the Christian Faith (Thomas Nelson, 1998). Reformed introduction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shedd, William. Dogmatic Theology, 3d ed. (Presbyterian &amp;amp; Reformed, 2003).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sonderegger, Katherine. Systematic Theology, 3 vols. (Fortress, 2015-).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strong, Augustus. Systematic Theology (Judson, 1907).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tanner, Kathryn. Jesus, Humanity and the Trinity: A Brief Systematic Theology. (Fortress, 2001).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thiessen, Henry. Lectures in Systematic Theology, rev. ed. (Eerdmans, 1977).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thiselton, Anthony C. Systematic Theology. (Eerdmans, 2015).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tillich, Paul. Systematic Theology, 3 vols. (University of Chicago, 1963).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turretin, Francis. Institutes of Elenctic Theology, 3 vols. (P&amp;amp;R, [1679–85] 1997).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;van der Kooi, Cornelis, and Gijsbert van den Brink. Christian Dogmatics: An Introduction. (Eerdmans, 2017). Translation of 2012 Dutch original.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vos, Geerhardus J. Reformed Dogmatics, 5 vols. (Lexham, 2014-16).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wiley, H. Orton. Christian Theology, 3 vols. (Nazarene Publishing, 1940-43). Arminian perspective.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Williams, Rodman. Renewal Theology (Zondervan, 1992). Three volumes in one, Pentecostal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;handbooks-introductions-and-edited-volumes&#34;&gt;Handbooks, Introductions, and Edited Volumes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Allen, Michael, and Scott R. Swain, eds. Christian Dogmatics: Reformed Theology for the Church Catholic. (Baker Academic, 2016).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beinert, Wolfgang, and Francis Schussler Fiorenza, eds. Handbook of Catholic Theology (Crossroad, 1995).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Berkhof, Louis. Introduction to Systematic Theology (Eerdmans, 1932; Baker, 1979).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enns, Paul. Moody Handbook of Theology (Moody, 1989).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Erickson, Millard. Introducing Christian Doctrine, 2d ed., cd. Arnold Hustad (Baker, 2001). Abridgement of Christian Theology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grudem, Wayne. Bible Doctrine (Zondervan, 1999). Abridgement of Systematic Theology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hanson, Paul. Introduction to Christian Theology (Fortress, 1997).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Horton, Michael. Pilgrim Theology. (Zondervan, 2013). Distillation of Horton’s Christian Faith.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jones, Beth Felker. Practicing Christian Doctrine. (Baker Academic, 2014).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Komanchak, Joseph, Mary Collins, and Dermot Lane, eds. The New Dictionary of Theology (Liturgical, 1987).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Latourelle, Rene, and Rino Fisichella, eds. Dictionary of Fundamental Theology (Crossroad, 1994).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;MacArthur, Biblical Doctrine: A Systematic Summary of Bible Truth. (Crossway, 2017).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;McGrath, Alister. ed. The Christian Theology Reader, 2d cd. (Blackwell, 2001).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;McGrath, Alister. Studies in Doctrine (Zondervan, 1997). Four volumes in one.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Migliore, Daniel. Faith Seeking Understanding. (Eerdmans, 1991, 2004, 2014).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Miller, Ed, and Stanley Grenz, eds. Fortress Introduction to Contemporary Theologies (Fortress, 1998).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Plantinga, Richard J., Thomas R. Thompson, and Matthew D. Lundberg. An Introduction to Christian Theology. (Cambridge University Press, 2010).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ryrie, Charles C. Basic Theology: A Popular Systematic Guide to Understanding Biblical Truth. (Moody, [1986] 1999).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sawyer, James. The Survivor’s Guide to Theology (Zondervan, 2002). Introduction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schussler Fiorenza, Francis, and John Galvin, eds. Systematic Theology, 2 vols. (Fortress, 1991).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stuhlmueller, Carroll, ed. The Collegeville Dictionary of Biblical Theology (Liturgical, 1996).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thorsen, Don. An Exploration of Christian Theology. (Hendrickson, 2008).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-studies&#34;&gt;Special Studies&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brown, Raymond E., Karl Donfried, Joseph Fitzmyer, and John Reumann. Mary in the New Testament (Fortress/Paulist, 1978).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chauvet, Louis-Marie. The Sacraments (Liturgical, 2001).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Collinge, William. The A to Z of Catholicism (Scarecrow, 2001).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Congar, Yves. Diversity and Communion (23rd Community, 1985).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Congdon, David. The God Who Saves: A Dogmatic Sketch. (Cascade, 2016).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;de Lubac, Henri. The Sources of Revelation (Crossroad, 2000).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dulles, Avery. The Assurance of Things Hoped For (Oxford University Press, 1994).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Forlines, Leroy. The Quest for Truth (Randall House, 2001). Non-Wesleyan Arminian position.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grenz, Stanley. Renewing the Center (Baker, 2000).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grenz, Stanley. The Named God and the Question of Being (Westminster John Knox, 2005).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grenz, Stanley. The Social God and the Question of Being (Westminster John Knox, 2001).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kaspar, Walter. The God of Jesus Christ (Crossroad, 1984). Idealist Christology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kaspar, Walter. Theology and Church II (Herder and Herder, 2001).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Küng, Hans. Infallible? 2d ed. (Continuum, 1994).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Livermore, Paul, Donald Bastien, and Thomas Oden. The God of Our Salvation (Light and Life Communications, 1995). Wesleyan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;O’Collins, Gerald. Christology (Oxford University Press, 1995).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Peters, Ted. God: The World’s Future, 2d ed. (Fortress, 2000). Postmodern.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ratzinger, John. In the Beginning (Eerdmans, 1995).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Richard, Lucien. Christ: The Self-Emptying of God (Paulist, 1997). Kenosis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schillebeeckx, Edward. Christ (Crossroad, 1980).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Schillebeeckx, Edward. Church (Crossroad, 1990).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tracy, David. Plurality and Ambiguity (Harper, 1987).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Van Beeck, Frans. God Encountered, 6 vols. (Liturgical, 1993-).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Von Balthasar, Hans Urs. Mysterium Paschale (T &amp;amp; T dark, 1990).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Warfield, Benjamin. Works, 10 vols. (Baker, 1991).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Reading this Fall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-im-reading-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-im-reading-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This upcoming semester, I’ll be taking a seminar on the Doctrine of Creation from my supervisor Marc Cortez. I’ll also be doing my “pedagogical experience” in a Christian Theology course—also with Marc Cortez.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, in case you’re interested, I thought I’d share what I’ll be reading for each course.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you read any of these works? If so, what did you think? What will &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; be reading this semester?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;doctrine-of-creation&#34;&gt;Doctrine of Creation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2OHhIGt&#34;&gt;Colin Gunton, The Triune Creator: A Historical and Systematic Study.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2OJjtmv&#34;&gt;Elizabeth A. Johnson, Ask the Beasts: Darwin and the God of Love.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2OGR0gX&#34;&gt;Catherine Keller, The Face of the Deep: A Theology of Becoming.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2nFuuK2&#34;&gt;Ian A. McFarland, From Nothing: A Theology of Creation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Miwlmx&#34;&gt;Jürgen Moltmann, God in Creation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ODx52y&#34;&gt;Arthur Peacocke, All That Is: A Naturalistic Faith for the Twenty-First Century.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2nLA2T9&#34;&gt;Norman Wirzba, From Nature to Creation: A Christian Vision for Understanding and Loving Our World.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;christian-theology&#34;&gt;Christian Theology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2MAHK0v&#34;&gt;Beth Felker Jones, Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2MoSrUI&#34;&gt;Tom McCall, Forsaken: The Trinity, the Cross, and Why It Matters.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2L1hGXJ&#34;&gt;Timothy C. Tennent (ed.), Theology in the Context of World Christianity: How the Global Church Is Influencing the Way We Think about and Discuss Theology.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2nLh6Ef&#34;&gt;Cornelius Plantinga, Not the Way It’s Supposed to Be: A Breviary of Sin.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: some of the links in this post are &lt;strong&gt;affiliate links&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that, if you click on the link and make a purchase, then, at no extra cost to you, I receive a small commission. I only ever recommend resources that I know will benefit my readers! If you’re interested in these resources, buying them through the affiliate links is a way that you can support my work!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Questions to Ask While Reading Theology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While reading Beth Felker Jones’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2vLkeEo&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I came across the following list of extremely helpful questions to ask while reading theology (on page 29).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What are the key Christian teachings being articulated? What is the author’s driving concern or main theme?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What counts for the author as authoritative (Scripture, tradition, reason, experience…)? Is the author’s theological method implicit or explicit?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How does the author deal with the witness of Scripture?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a. Implicitly? Explicitly?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;b. Does the witness of the Old Testament matter? The New?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;c. What biblical themes are privileged?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;d. What interpretive principles are at work?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How do these claims relate to other doctrines?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How does context (including gender, race, class, culture, and time) shape the theological voice? Is the theologian conscious of this? How does your context shape your evaluation of the piece?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Practice reading charitably. What is the best possible interpretation of how the piece reflects an attempt to be faithful to Jesus Christ?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How do these theological claims relate to the life of faith? Doe you bring other questions from your experience?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If this theological proposal were taken seriously, how would it shape Christian practice? Would it affect our participation in spiritual disciplines? Our understanding of faithful living? Our practice of evangelism? Our life as the church?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add this to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/&#34;&gt;1 simple trick to read faster&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/understand-remember-read-4-questions-ask-reading-book/&#34;&gt;4 questions to ask while reading a book&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/&#34;&gt;3 questions to ask while reading the Bible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Theologians (Should) Do</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-theologians-should-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 14:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-theologians-should-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kevin J. Vanhoozer, affectionately known by some as “KJV,” has written &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.firstthings.com/article/2018/08/letter-to-an-aspiring-theologian&#34;&gt;one of the best, briefest overviews of what theologians (should) do&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The entire piece is filled with gems like the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To become a theologian, you must be willing to bear true witness and call out false witnesses, casting down idols and ideologies. That’s the shadow side of theology, but the best part is speaking light and truth in astonished indications of God’s goodness. I love John Webster’s definition of theology: “that delightful activity in which the Church praises God by ordering its thinking towards the gospel of Christ.” Being a theologian means getting to have not necessarily the last word, but the word about last things, “the end for which God created the world” (to cite the title of a dissertation by Jonathan Edwards). It’s not only a good word but the best of all possible words, namely, that God glorifies humans and all creation, magnifying his own glory and subjecting all things to the Lordship of Christ, so that “God may be all in all” (1 Cor. 15:28). It’s the privilege of the theologian to bear witness to the length, depth, breadth, and width of the cross and Resurrection. Karl Barth is right: “The theologian who has no joy in his work is not a theologian at all.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Attracts People to Anglicanism? Here&#39;s My Take</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 21:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based upon my work over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/&#34;&gt;Rookie Anglican&lt;/a&gt;, I was asked by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teloscollective.com/&#34;&gt;The Telos Collective&lt;/a&gt; to write a blog post about the different ways that people are coming into Anglicanism. What’s drawing them in?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teloscollective.com/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-subversive-cultural-resonance/&#34;&gt;read my full post over at the Telos Collective blog&lt;/a&gt;, but here’s a taste:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anglican Christianity, precisely because of its weirdness, can remind us that, in the words of Brad Harper and Paul Louis Metzger in Exploring Ecclesiology, “The church is a cultural community. It is Christ’s eschatological kingdom community, itself a culture that engages other cultures from Christ’s kingdom vantage point” (p. 207).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/&#34;&gt;I catalogued a bunch of different takes on Jordan Peterson, before giving my own take&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since that post, two other pieces about Jordan Peterson have been written that I’d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;jordan-peterson-custodian-of-the-patriarchy-by-nellie-bowles-new-york-times&#34;&gt;“Jordan Peterson, Custodian of the Patriarchy,” by Nellie Bowles (New York Times)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/18/style/jordan-peterson-12-rules-for-life.html&#34;&gt;Nellie Bowles writes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peterson, 55, a University of Toronto psychology professor turned YouTube philosopher turned mystical father figure, has emerged as an influential thought leader. The messages he delivers range from hoary self-help empowerment talk (clean your room, stand up straight) to the more retrograde and political (a society run as a patriarchy makes sense and stems mostly from men’s competence; the notion of white privilege is a farce). He is the stately looking, pedigreed voice for a group of culture warriors who are working diligently to undermine mainstream and liberal efforts to promote equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to make of Jordan Peterson? Some takes, then my own.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: Read my post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/&#34;&gt;“Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I remember correctly, I first heard of and listened to Jordan Peterson on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2017/08/31/podcast-335-using-power-myths-live-flourishing-life/&#34;&gt;an episode of The Art of Manliness podcast&lt;/a&gt;. (Or perhaps it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/06/12-rules-for-life-jordan-peterson-interview/&#34;&gt;this episode&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;however-i-could-be-mistaken-because-petersons-been-popping-up-in-conversation-all-over-the-place-in-my-circles&#34;&gt;However, I could be mistaken, because Peterson’s been popping up in conversation all over the place in my circles.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blog posts, podcast episodes, conversations with friends – Peterson has been popping up everywhere, so it seems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Song is a Beautiful Picture of the Theological Journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-truth-is-not-a-cave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 21:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-truth-is-not-a-cave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently privileged to see one of my favorite bands, &lt;a href=&#34;http://theohhellos.com/&#34;&gt;The Oh Hellos&lt;/a&gt;, in concert at the House of Blues in downtown Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love all of The Oh Hellos’ music, but one song, in particular, has remained poignant to me ever since I first heard it. The song is called “The Truth is a Cave,” and I think it provides a beautiful picture of what I’m calling “the theological journey” – the stages one goes through in one’s knowledge of God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Models: A Helpful Model for Theology?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 15:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This idea has been bouncing around in my head for a bit. It’s not fully-formed by any means, but I’d like to get it out there and hear what you think of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here it is: “Mental Models” could be a helpful model for theology.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-mental-model&#34;&gt;What is a “mental model”?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition-of-mental-models&#34;&gt;Definition of mental models&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Put simply, a “mental model” is a concept used to help explain how the world works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Pray Before You Read and Write: A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 09:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to share with you the following prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study, based on &lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.preces-latinae.org/thesaurus/Varia/CreatorIneff.html&#34;&gt;Oratio S. Thomae Aquinatis ante studium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, which Thomas Aquinas would pray before studying, writing, or preaching.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We prayed it responsively before class (Patristic and Medieval History and Doctrine) with Dr. Piotr Malysz at Beeson Divinity School, and I’ve since turned back to this prayer often!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study&#34;&gt;A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O God, Creator of all that is, From the treasures of Your wisdom, You have arrayed the universe with marvelous order, And now govern with skill and might. You are the true fount of light and wisdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hermeneutical Implications of Scripture&#39;s Theological Location</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hermeneutical-implications-scriptures-theological-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 15:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hermeneutical-implications-scriptures-theological-location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Theological &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermeneutics&#34;&gt;hermeneutics&lt;/a&gt; – human understanding and interpretation in light of the identity and acts of the triune God – faces two problematic questions that, I believe, every biblical and/or theological scholar must be prepared to address. First, should the Bible be read in some special sense as divine revelation, or should we read the Bible like any other text? And second, should biblical and theological studies be one discipline, or two?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christians and Wealth: An Argument for Downward Mobility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/christians-and-wealth-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 01:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/christians-and-wealth-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! If you only have a minute to read about wealth, here’s my argument in a nutshell:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-my-argument&#34;&gt;Outline of My Argument&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Claim: American Christians should reduce their standards of living to what is necessary for human flourishing and give their excess resources beyond this standard to the poor and oppressed.&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God is the firmest advocate for human flourishing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The pursuit of wealth is spiritually dangerous and crippling.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our culture’s inclinations toward upward financial mobility go against the message of the New Testament and the life of Christ.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God is revealed in Scripture to have a special concern for the poor and the oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians will be held accountable for how they treat the poor and the oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Objections:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This line of reasoning is advocating asceticism and is unbiblical.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians have every right to keep what they have earned and to do what they wish with their excess funds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Because the poor are lazy, Christians should not feel pressured to give, in case their generosity is taken advantage of.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Warrant:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians want to remain true to Scripture and submit to God’s way of life in order to find satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(For more on Christianity, wealth, and poverty, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2011/02/10/20110210proverbs-topical-study-poverty/&#34;&gt;my topical study on what the book of Proverbs has to teach us about poverty&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frustrated with Church? You&#39;re the Problem!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/frustrated-with-church-youre-the-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/frustrated-with-church-youre-the-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I asked you &lt;a href=&#34;http://frustrated&#34;&gt;to join the Church if you, like me, are frustrated with the Church&lt;/a&gt;. The strongest critiques of religion come from within, not without, the Christian community. Plus, your frustrations are likely shared by many others within the Church!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, it’s not enough to point the finger at others from your pew, instead of doing so from the public square. Yes, that’s a good first step, but another one is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frustrated with Church? Join the Club!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/frustrated-with-church-join-the-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 17:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/frustrated-with-church-join-the-club/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;…and by “club” I of course mean “Church”!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What am I getting at? Am I calling the Church a mere “club”?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No. Although, unfortunately, it often feels that way, doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A club full of hypocrisy, idolatry, indifference, and platitudes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A club full of power-plays, fear-mongering, and Bible-thumping.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A club full of saints too afraid to admit that they are sinners.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you’re sick of this “club,” and you’re ready to leave, if you haven’t left already.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Recommendations? Barth&#39;s and Bonhoeffer&#39;s False Gods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reading-recommendations-barths-bonhoeffers-false-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 12:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reading-recommendations-barths-bonhoeffers-false-gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi internet – especially all you Barthians and Bonhoefferians (-ites?) out there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m in the process of compiling a reading list, and I could use your suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s my goal: &lt;strong&gt;to explore the possible relationship between Barth’s critique of the “No-God”&lt;/strong&gt;(Nich-Gott) &lt;strong&gt;and Bonhoeffer’s critique(s) of viewing God as a “stopgap”&lt;/strong&gt; (Lückenbüßer) &lt;strong&gt;or “working hypothesis.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As far as primary sources go, I plan to focus on the &lt;em&gt;Romans&lt;/em&gt; commentary, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/On-Religion-The-Revelation-Sublimation/dp/0567031098&#34;&gt;Garrett Green’s recent re-translation of &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/On-Religion-The-Revelation-Sublimation/dp/0567031098&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;CD&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/On-Religion-The-Revelation-Sublimation/dp/0567031098&#34;&gt; §17&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Letters and Papers from Prison&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvising Church and State: Overaccepting as a Synthesis of Anglican and Anabaptist Approaches</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/improvising-church-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/improvising-church-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-accepting-blocking-and-status&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION: ACCEPTING, BLOCKING, AND STATUS&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the church’s perspective, is the state a promising offer, or a threatening one? At the risk of breathtaking oversimplification, Anglicans have tended to adopt the former perspective, leading to accommodation, and Anabaptists the latter, resulting in separation.&lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Following Samuel Wells in his theological appropriation of terms from theatrical improvisation, the Anglican tradition has tended to respond to the promising &lt;em&gt;offers&lt;/em&gt; (invitations to respond) of the state by &lt;em&gt;accepting&lt;/em&gt; – maintaining the premise(s) of the state’s action(s).&lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; The historical legacy of the Church of England has given Anglicanism, as Anderson notes, an “inheritance of a strong loyalty to the state and a conservatism that has led the church to promote the status quo more often than it agitates for reform.”&lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn3&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; This inheritance from the established Church of England has coincided with a dual tendency to adopt a high &lt;em&gt;status&lt;/em&gt; (a strategy for getting one’s way), in terms of relative privilege and political optimism, and a low status, in terms of frequent subservience in church-state relations.&lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn4&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentecost: Songs and Scripture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pentecost-songs-and-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 15:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pentecost-songs-and-scripture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://homebrewedchristianity.com/2015/05/18/pentecost-the-arrival-of-the-spirit-and-the-lectiocast/&#34;&gt;the first episode&lt;/a&gt; of the excellent new podcast, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jrdkirk.com/2015/05/14/lectiocast-a-lectionary-commentary-podcast/&#34;&gt;LectioCast&lt;/a&gt;, helped to orient my thoughts toward &lt;a href=&#34;http://lectionary.library.vanderbilt.edu/&#34;&gt;tomorrow’s readings&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.christiantoday.com/article/nine.key.things.to.know.about.pentecost/54344.htm&#34;&gt;Pentecost Sunday&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve reproduced the first lesson, psalm, second lesson, and Gospel reading below, but I’d also like to call your attention to three powerful songs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;song-1-dry-bones-by-gungor&#34;&gt;Song #1: “Dry Bones” by Gungor&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first song is “Dry Bones” by Gungor. Read the Ezekiel passage and psalm below, and give it a listen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;422&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ioMRzpmnl7U?feature=oembed&#34; title=&#34;Gungor &#34;Dry Bones&#34; at RELEVANT&#34; width=&#34;750&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;span-classpassage-display-bcvfirst-lesson-ezekiel-371-14-spanspan-classpassage-display-versionnet-biblespan&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;passage-display-bcv&#34;&gt;First Lesson: Ezekiel 37:1-14 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;passage-display-version&#34;&gt;(NET Bible)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;span-classtext-ezek-37-1-iden-net-21399the-valley-of-dry-bonesspan&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ezek-37-1&#34; id=&#34;en-NET-21399&#34;&gt;The Valley of Dry Bones&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34; style=&#34;width: 395px&#34;&gt;![The Vision of the Valley of Dry Bones - Gustave Dore](http://uploads7.wikiart.org/images/gustave-dore/the-vision-of-the-valley-of-dry-bones-1866.jpg!Blog.jpg)&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;The Vision of the Valley of Dry Bones – Gustave Dore&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ezek-37-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;chapternum&#34;&gt;37 &lt;/span&gt;The hand of the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was on me, and he brought me out by the Spirit of the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; and placed me in the midst of the valley, and it was full of bones. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ezek-37-2&#34; id=&#34;en-NET-21400&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;versenum&#34;&gt;2 &lt;/sup&gt;He made me walk all around among them. I realized there were a great many bones in the valley and they were very dry. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ezek-37-3&#34; id=&#34;en-NET-21401&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;versenum&#34;&gt;3 &lt;/sup&gt;He said to me, “Son of man, can these bones live?” I said to him, “Sovereign Lord, you know.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ezek-37-4&#34; id=&#34;en-NET-21402&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;versenum&#34;&gt;4 &lt;/sup&gt;Then he said to me, “Prophesy over these bones, and tell them: ‘Dry bones, hear the word of the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ezek-37-5&#34; id=&#34;en-NET-21403&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;versenum&#34;&gt;5 &lt;/sup&gt;This is what the sovereign &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; says to these bones: Look, I am about to infuse breath into you and you will live. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ezek-37-6&#34; id=&#34;en-NET-21404&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;versenum&#34;&gt;6 &lt;/sup&gt;I will put tendons on you and muscles over you and will cover you with skin; I will put breath in you and you will live. Then you will know that I am the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.’”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be human?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-does-it-mean-to-be-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 22:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-does-it-mean-to-be-human/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-it-mean-to-be-human&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Does It Mean to Be Human?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A clue to the answer lies in the asking of the question, for this act presupposes both a [human] subject and object in a dialectic of self-transcendence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Robert Jenson notes, “in asking this question, we somehow take up a vantage outside ourselves to make ourselves our own objects, get beyond ourselves to look back at ourselves.”&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The mystery of human existence is “that I am the subject of the object I am and the object of the subject I am.”&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disunity in the Church? Absurd!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/disunity-in-the-church-absurd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 09:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/disunity-in-the-church-absurd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Presented at Southeast ETS 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.academia.edu/10252338/DISUNITY_AS_ECCLESIOLOGICAL_IMPOSSIBILITY_A_BARTHIAN_ANALOGY&#34;&gt;DISUNITY AS ECCLESIOLOGICAL IMPOSSIBILITY:A BARTHIAN ANALOGY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joshua P. Steele&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just as sin is ontological impossibility, disunity is ecclesiological impossibility. The tension between the undeniable reality of sin and Karl Barth’s theological definition of sin as an impossible possibility parallels the tension between the obvious reality of a fractured church1 and the theological definition of the church as the one body of the one Christ. Two excerpts from the Barthian corpus legitimize this connection. First, in his prepared remarks to the 1937 Second World Conference on Faith and Order in Edinburgh, Karl Barth maintained that&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #1, Stones into Bread</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Barth&#34;&gt;Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; exegesis of &lt;a href=&#34;http://postbarthian.com/2013/07/17/karl-barth-on-the-temptation-of-jesus-in-the-wilderness/&#34;&gt;Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations&lt;/a&gt; isperenniallyinspiring, but particularly poignant during this season of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lent&#34;&gt;Lent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What does it mean for Christ to be the Perfect Penitent? And how should this influence our own repentance?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://postbarthian.com/2013/07/17/karl-barth-on-the-temptation-of-jesus-in-the-wilderness/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following series of quotations comes from a lengthy small-print section in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_Dogmatics&#34;&gt;CD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foundationrt.org/outlines/Barth_Dogmatics_Volume_IV.pdf&#34;&gt;IV&lt;/a&gt;/1, 259-73 &lt;em&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;font-family:&amp;background-color:rgb(255,255,255);&#34;&gt;§ 59 The Obedience of the Son of God; 2. The Judge Judged in Our Place)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. There Barth walks through the three wilderness temptations before masterfully connecting them to Christ&amp;rsquo;s experience in the Garden of Gethsemane.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #2, Christendom&#39;s Cost — Worship Satan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-2-christendoms-cost-worship-satan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-2-christendoms-cost-worship-satan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread&#34;&gt;Yesterday I posted the beginning of Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations&lt;/a&gt;. He does a masterful job of explaining how Christ was tempted, not to violate the Law or commit a moral infraction, but to abandon his role as the obedient, Perfect Penitent. Put differently, Barth clarifies that Jesus&amp;rsquo; sinlessness is not a vague moral perfection, but rather obedience and repentance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christ&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread&#34;&gt;first temptation was to turn stones into bread&lt;/a&gt;, thereby using divine power as a &amp;ldquo;technical instrument&amp;rdquo; to save and maintain his own life. Today&amp;rsquo;s temptation contains an incisive critique of Christendom&amp;rsquo;s desire for influence, relevance, and power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #3, The Leap of False Faith</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-3-the-leap-of-false-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-3-the-leap-of-false-faith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reproducing&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Barth&#34;&gt;Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;magnificent exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_Dogmatics&#34;&gt;Church Dogmatics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; IV/1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a particularly appropriate discussion for this season of&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lent&#34;&gt;Lent&lt;/a&gt;, for Jesus was not tempted to break the Law or commit a moral infraction. Instead, he was tempted to abandon his role as the Perfect Penitent. For Barth, if Christ had capitulated to any of the temptations, he would have abandoned God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive mission. Jesus Christ had to persist in penitence in order to be &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=BAzwi9GQHtoC&amp;amp;pg=PA211&amp;amp;lpg=PA211&amp;amp;dq=judge+judged+in+our+place&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=6QQm6gLbOc&amp;amp;sig=T82UORb7xuRT8l8I__5370Dilk0&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=SRrtVOTuJK3ksATGrIDoDw&amp;amp;ved=0CCYQ6AEwAQ#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=judge%20judged%20in%20our%20place&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;the Judge Judged in Our Place&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; (Barth&amp;rsquo;s most concise description of the atonement proper).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHITE NOISE, BHOPAL, AND THE HYPERREAL FEAR OF DEATH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/white-noise-bhopal-and-the-hyperreal-fear-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 08:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/white-noise-bhopal-and-the-hyperreal-fear-of-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following essay deals with the theme of the fear of death in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2EgL3pA&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;White Noise&lt;/em&gt;, the novel by Don DeLillo&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is better to go to a funeral than a feast. For death is the destiny of every person, and the living should take this to heart.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don DeLillo’s &lt;em&gt;White Noise&lt;/em&gt;, “a paradigm of postmodern literature,”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; yields the kind of cognitive dissonance that makes you wonder whether the author simply missed the mark, or if you are only confused because you suffer from the postmodern condition which DeLillo adroitly analyzes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 2014 Regional ETS Paper: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 09:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, here’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/steele-southeast-ets-2014-paper-final-presesntation-edit.pdf&#34;&gt;the latest version of the Regional ETS paper&lt;/a&gt; I will present today at 5:00pm at Beeson Divinity School, room S009.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re able to attend the presentation, that’s great! If not, feel free to give &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/steele-southeast-ets-2014-paper-final-presesntation-edit.pdf&#34;&gt;my paper&lt;/a&gt; a read and get back to me with any questions, comments, or suggestions. Atonement theology and the unity of the Church are two things about which I am very passionate, and intend to devote further study to these areas in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Regional ETS Presentation: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 15:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.beesondivinity.com/assets/1346/11_cs070900557.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;If you’re in the Birmingham area from March 21-22, 2014, and you’re interested in evangelical theology, please consider attending the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.beesondivinity.com/ets&#34;&gt;Evangelical Theological Society’s Southeastern Regional Meeting at Beeson Divinity School&lt;/a&gt;! This year’s theme is “the theological interpretation of Scripture,” and the plenary speaker is Wheaton’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wheaton.edu/Academics/Faculty/T/Daniel-Treier&#34;&gt;Daniel J. Treier&lt;/a&gt; (incidentally, Dr. Treier and I are both alumni of Cedarville…go figure).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, if you’re free from 5:00-5:30pm on Friday, March 21, consider swinging by room S009 to hear me present &lt;strong&gt;“Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof: Atonement, Ecclesiology, and the Unity of God.”&lt;/strong&gt; The atonement and the unity of the Church are topics that I’m passionate about, and I’m extremely grateful for the opportunity to give my first ever conference paper. Here’s the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silence and Violence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/silence-and-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 18:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/silence-and-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://malcolmguite.wordpress.com/2013/11/06/silence-a-sonnet-for-remembrance-day-3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://malcolmguite.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/p1050316silent-cross.jpg?w=500&amp;amp;h=646&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Violence is not human destiny because the God of peace is the beginning and the end of human history…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Granted, pushing the stone of peace up the steep hill of violence … is hard. It is easier, however, than carrying one’s own cross in the footsteps of the crucified Messiah. This is what Jesus Christ asks Christians to do. Assured of God’s justice and undergirded by God’s presence, they are to break the cycle of violence by refusing to be caught in the automatism of revenge.”&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Exclusion-Embrace-Theological-Exploration-Reconciliation/dp/0687002826&#34;&gt;Volf, E&amp;amp;E, 306&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Holy Trinity: What Is It? (Why) Is It Important?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/holy-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 21:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/holy-trinity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-the-holy-trinity&#34;&gt;Introduction: The Holy Trinity&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt;One God. Three persons. The Holy Trinity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt;The orthodox paradox of this Christian confession confounds many, due to its apparent contradictions, abstractions, and absence from Scripture. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt;From Arius to Augustine and beyond, trinitarian debates have raged even among those who agree that God exists, that the Bible is true, and that it is therefore worthwhile to consider what the Bible says because it reveals the existent God. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miroslav Volf on Divine Violence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/volf-on-divine-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 08:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/volf-on-divine-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple relevant excerpts (given recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2013/10/22/down-with-the-pacifists/&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;) from “Violence and Peace,” the final chapter of Miroslav Volf’s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Exclusion-Embrace-Theological-Exploration-Reconciliation/dp/0687002826&#34;&gt;Exclusion and Embrace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (my emphasis added in &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt;; paragraph breaks added where noted):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“God will judge, not because God gives people what they deserve, but &lt;strong&gt;because some people refuse to receive what no one deserves; if evildoers experience God’s terror, it will not be because they have done evil, but because they have resisted to the end the powerful lure of the open arms of the crucified Messiah&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down With the Pacifists!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/down-with-the-pacifists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 20:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/down-with-the-pacifists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week has been a great one for slipshod attacks on pacifism. First, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firstthings.com/&#34;&gt;First Things&lt;/a&gt; (Stephen H. Webb) on October 15 —- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firstthings.com/onthesquare/2013/10/john-howard-yoder-and-the-violent-power-of-pacifism&#34;&gt;“John Howard Yoder and the Violent Power of Pacifism”&lt;/a&gt; (emphasis added below):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Nevertheless, pacifists, at least the ones I know, can be very enthusiastic about the rightness of their cause. Since &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;there is no rational justification for pacifism&lt;/span&gt;, defenders typically turn their rhetoric against their critics by casting them as stooges of the status quo. Since pacifists are against all forms of violence, anyone who disagrees with them must be in favor of violence. What this ploy misses is obvious. In a fallen world, not only is violence pervasive but it is also a toxin that, when legitimately used, can cure as well as kill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>King Jesus&#39; Kingdom Gospel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 13:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I highly encourage the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Read Scot McKnight’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-King-Jesus-Gospel-Revisited/dp/031049298X&#34;&gt;The King Jesus Gospel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. Check out Tim Gombis’ insightful series of posts on &lt;a href=&#34;http://timgombis.com/2013/09/16/the-gospel-of-the-kingdom/&#34;&gt;The Gospel of the Kingdom&lt;/a&gt;, pt. &lt;a href=&#34;http://timgombis.com/2013/09/16/the-gospel-of-the-kingdom/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://timgombis.com/2013/09/17/the-gospel-of-the-kingdom-pt-2/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://timgombis.com/2013/09/18/the-gospel-of-the-kingdom-pt-3/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gombis hits the nail on the head here:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the last several months, I’ve had several conversations about how the Gospels’ language about “the gospel” should shape how Christians conceive of the gospel. Whereas the New Testament mainly envisions a broader announcement of a larger reality, many evangelicals associate “the gospel” with a brief presentation, or information about the mechanics of an individual transaction that can secure divine forgiveness and the establishment of a personal relationship with God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Reading Romans 13 Wrong! Here&#39;s How to Read It Correctly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/romans-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 07:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/romans-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study of Romans 13 rests upon a crucial presupposition: without context, words can mean anything and everything, and therefore mean nothing. It is only through the delimiting influence of context that words, phrases, sentences, and paragraphs are endowed with significance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although this concept seems simple and justified enough, it is often forgotten within the field of biblical exegesis. Due to influences as simple as our versification of the biblical text and as complex as the historical/theological developments which have dictated how we teach and interpret the Scriptures, many exegetes (wittingly or unwittingly) ignore context when trying to ascertain the meaning of particular biblical texts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 3)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/creation-and-doxology-pt-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 08:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/creation-and-doxology-pt-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/17/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/&#34; title=&#34;Creation and Doxology (pt. 1)&#34;&gt;Pt. 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/17/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/&#34; title=&#34;Creation and Doxology (pt. 2)&#34;&gt;Pt. 2 &lt;/a&gt;first!)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation-and-redemption-christ-and-new-creation&#34;&gt;CREATION AND REDEMPTION: CHRIST AND NEW CREATION&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div&gt;Throughout the New Testament, the main use of creation theology is to link creation with redemption, resulting in the praise of the Creator through the Creator-Redeemer, Jesus the Messiah. However, the linked concepts of creation and redemption have a rich OT history. For example, cited impetuses for keeping the Sabbath are Yahweh’s creative work (Exod 20:11) and his redemptive work (Deut 5:15), revealing a close connection between the two actions.[\[1\]](/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn1) The logic behind this correlation is one of continued creation: Yahweh is personally invested in the success of his creative purposes, the functionality of his temple.[\[2\]](/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn2) Sin and Death will not have the final word. The Creator will redeem by creating anew through his Son.&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The New Testament unites creation and redemption in the person of Jesus the Messiah. Evidence abounds, but consider three poignant examples. In John 1:1-18, Jesus is spoken of as the agent of creation (1:3) and the redemptive agent of grace and truth (1:17).&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn3&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; In Colossians 1:15-20, Jesus is the “image of God, the firstborn over all creation (1:15),” illustrating his role as the eternal nexus between Creator and creation.&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn4&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt; Furthermore, Christ is spoken of, again, as both the agent of creation (1:16) and reconciliatory redemption (1:19-20).&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn5&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; Finally, in Heb 1:1-4, the author of Hebrews takes special care to link the Son’s creative work with his redemptive work through a verbal parallel: through the Son, the universe and redemptive cleansing are both &lt;em&gt;made&lt;/em&gt; (poievw).&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn6&#34;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 20:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/17/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/&#34; title=&#34;Creation and Doxology (pt. 1)&#34;&gt;(Read Pt. 1 First!)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation-complexity-and-chaos&#34;&gt;CREATION, COMPLEXITY, AND CHAOS&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much of the chaos in the universe can be ascribed to the infiltration of Sin and Death as described in Genesis 3. However, an oft-overlooked facet of biblical creation theology is the appropriate place of complexity and chaos within God’s creation. Even when the effects of the Fall are ignored, God’s temple is by no means a tame environment, nor is humanity the sole venue through which Yahweh receives glory. This facet is a crucial one, for it reorients a proper view of worship in an untamed temple, necessitating humility in the worship of the Creator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 17:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In many conservative evangelical circles, biblical creation theology has been hijacked and eclipsed by the vitriolic debate between Young Earth Creationism and Neo-Darwinism.&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; It is often difficult to see beyond this morass the beautiful tapestry of creation themes in biblical theology. Waltke summarizes the problem well: “Instead of metaphysical questions that shape culture, questions about dinosaurs, a young earth theory, and such dominate the evangelical landscape. This is unfortunate.”&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Nevertheless, there is an embarrassment of riches when it comes to Scripture’s use of creation themes, whether the evangelical community gives them appropriate attention or not. Unfortunately, a comprehensive analysis of biblical creation theology, a field fertile enough to provide lifetimes of work and study, far exceeds the purview of this essay.&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn3&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; However, a brief analysis of the motifs of creation as temple, chaos, and redemption will show that the overarching use of creation theology in Scripture is to bring about the praise of the Creator. Biblical creation theology, properly understood, leads to doxology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 19:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The more I study the New Testament, I become more convinced that the unity of the Church is of utmost importance to God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What bothers me is that this has never been taught to me before. All of the things I’ve learned (specifically in my studies on Philippians, Galatians, and now Romans) about the importance of unity for the sake of the Gospel mission and the Kingdom of God have come as somewhat of a shock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Good News of Christmas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-good-news-of-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 13:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-good-news-of-christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031049298X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=faithinirelan-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399373&amp;amp;creativeASIN=031049298X&#34;&gt;The King Jesus Gospel: The Original Good News Revisited&lt;/a&gt; by Scot McKnight, who makes the claim that the gospel is the saving story of Jesus as Messiah, King, and Lord as the completion to the story of Israel, I started to notice some profound gospel messages in the Christmas carols we often sing during this season.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have found that several of these carols go much deeper (much more biblical) than the personal salvation “gospel” of sin-management that we often preach and sing about. What’s tragic is that, even though these carols are quite possibly the best-known Christian songs, their familiarity (and the fact that we only break them out for 1/12th of the year), makes it quite easy to ignore their substance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Church and State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/church_and_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 12:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/church_and_state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Note: for a more recent piece on the relationship between Church and State, see my essay: “&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2015/12/08/improvising-church-state/&#34;&gt;Improvising Church and State&lt;/a&gt;.”)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I just read an article by Kevin DeYoung at The Gospel Coalition: &lt;a href=&#34;http://thegospelcoalition.org/blogs/kevindeyoung/2011/05/26/thinking-theologically-about-memorial-day/?comments#comments&#34;&gt;“Thinking Theologically About Memorial Day”&lt;/a&gt;. Listen to his intro:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post probably has something to make everyone unhappy. But here goes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Memorial Day on Monday (in the U.S.) and, no doubt, a number of patriotic services scheduled for this Sunday, I want to offer a few theses on patriotism and the church. Each of these points could be substantially expanded and beg more detailed defense and explanation, but since this is a blog and not a term paper, I’ll try to keep this under 1500 words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
