<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>anglican on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/anglican/</link>
    <description>Recent content in anglican on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 21:02:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/anglican/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Attracts People to Anglicanism? Here&#39;s My Take</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 21:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</guid>
      <description>Based upon my work over at Rookie Anglican, I was asked by The Telos Collective to write a blog post about the different ways that people are coming into Anglicanism. What&amp;rsquo;s drawing them in?
You can read my full post over at the Telos Collective blog, but here&amp;rsquo;s a taste:
Anglican Christianity, precisely because of its weirdness, can remind us that, in the words of Brad Harper and Paul Louis Metzger in Exploring Ecclesiology, “The church is a cultural community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Reasons Why I&#39;m an Anglican Christian</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 05:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</guid>
      <description>Why am I an Anglican Christian? Here are 3 reasons.
1. Anglicanism as a Refuge from Fundamentalism First, for me, Anglicanism has been a refuge from fundamentalism. Now, to be sure, we do have our own fundamentalists within the Anglican Communion! But, compared to some &amp;ldquo;ingrown enclaves&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced in my Christian upbringing, Anglicanism has been a breath of fresh air. It has been an ecclesiological space for healing as I seek to &amp;quot; not throw the (gospel) baby out with the (fundamentalist) bathwater.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
