<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Theology on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theology on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <image>
      <title>Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <url>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</url>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 10:12:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/theology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>No Kings</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/no-kings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 10:00:12 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/no-kings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No kings, save One, the King of Kings,&lt;br&gt;
whose kingdom peace and justice brings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No kings, but He who blessed the poor,&lt;br&gt;
and binds their wounds forevermore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No kings, except the Crucified,&lt;br&gt;
who, on a tyrant&amp;rsquo;s cross, died &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No kings! &amp;ndash; to save the last, the least,&lt;br&gt;
and bring them to His wedding feast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No kings, save One, who wore a crown&lt;br&gt;
of bitter thorns upon His brow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No kings, but He who rose to save,&lt;br&gt;
to lift the outcasts from their grave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No kings, save One, the King of Kings,<br>
whose kingdom peace and justice brings.</p>
<p>No kings, but He who blessed the poor,<br>
and binds their wounds forevermore.</p>
<p>No kings, except the Crucified,<br>
who, on a tyrant&rsquo;s cross, died &ndash;</p>
<p>No kings! &ndash; to save the last, the least,<br>
and bring them to His wedding feast.</p>
<p>No kings, save One, who wore a crown<br>
of bitter thorns upon His brow.</p>
<p>No kings, but He who rose to save,<br>
to lift the outcasts from their grave.</p>
<p>No kings, except the Refugee,<br>
who came to set the captives free.</p>
<p>No kings, no tyrants, on their thrones,<br>
they&rsquo;ll be cast down by One alone &ndash;</p>
<p>No kings! &ndash; whose kingdom is not of this age,<br>
whose war is not by violence waged.</p>
<p>No kings, but He who&rsquo;ll come again<br>
to right the bloodstained wrongs of men.</p>
<p>So, kings, so, despots, bend the knee!<br>
Fear Him who sets your prisoners free.</p>
<p>No, kings, One saves! His freedom rings!<br>
No kings, save One, the King of Kings.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bible Is Clear about the Poor, Oppressed, and Marginalized</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-bible-is-clear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 14:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-bible-is-clear/</guid>
      <description>The Bible is clear about the poor, the oppressed, and the marginalized.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em>&ldquo;The Bible is clear&hellip;&rdquo;</em><br>
<em>&ldquo;The Bible says&hellip;&rdquo;</em><br>
<em>&ldquo;The Bible is for/against&hellip;&rdquo;</em></p></blockquote><p>How often—especially within American evangelicalism—do these phrases become rhetorical battering rams for partisan talking points?</p>
<p>Let’s be honest: <em>the Bible is not a monolith.</em> It is a library of ancient, inspired texts written across centuries, cultures, and genres. &ldquo;What the Bible says&rdquo; on any given topic often depends heavily on who’s reading, how they&rsquo;re reading, and what they bring to the text.</p>
<p>And yet—amidst the diversity of voices and genres—there is a steady and unmistakable chorus that rises from Scripture, if you&rsquo;re willing to hear it: <strong>God sides with the poor, the oppressed, and the marginalized.</strong></p>
<p>This is not peripheral. It’s not a minor subplot. It’s a core theme, echoed by the Torah, the prophets, Jesus, and the early church.</p>
<p>If we read the Bible &ldquo;from below&rdquo;—from the perspective of the least, the last, and the lost—we encounter a God who delivers slaves from Egypt, warns kings against injustice, and identifies himself with the hungry, the sick, and the imprisoned.</p>
<p>Consider just a small sampling:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>“You must not mistreat or oppress foreigners in any way. Remember, you yourselves were once foreigners in the land of Egypt. You must not exploit a widow or an orphan&hellip;”</strong><br>
<em>Exodus 22:21–24</em></p></blockquote><blockquote><p><strong>“Don’t rob the poor just because you can, or exploit the needy in court. For the Lord is their defender. He will ruin anyone who ruins them.”</strong><br>
<em>Proverbs 22:22–23</em></p></blockquote><blockquote><p><strong>“He has shown you, O mortal, what is good. And what does the Lord require of you? To act justly and to love mercy and to walk humbly with your God.”</strong><br>
<em>Micah 6:8</em></p></blockquote><blockquote><p><strong>“He has brought down the powerful from their thrones and lifted up the lowly; he has filled the hungry with good things, and sent the rich away empty.”</strong><br>
<em>Luke 1:52–53 (Mary&rsquo;s Magnificat)</em></p></blockquote><blockquote><p><strong>“The Spirit of the Lord is upon me&hellip; He has sent me to proclaim release to the captives&hellip; to let the oppressed go free.”</strong><br>
<em>Luke 4:18–19 (Jesus quoting Isaiah)</em></p></blockquote><blockquote><p><strong>“Blessed are you who are poor, for yours is the kingdom of God.”</strong><br>
<em>Luke 6:20–21</em></p></blockquote><p>This isn’t &ldquo;liberal theology.&rdquo; It’s just <em>Bible.</em></p>
<p>So the next time someone claims “the Bible is clear,” it’s worth asking: <em>Clear about what?</em> Because when it comes to God&rsquo;s concern for the vulnerable, the Bible speaks with thunderous clarity.</p>
<p>And if your version of Christianity conveniently forgets the poor—or worse, vilifies them—then it&rsquo;s not Jesus you&rsquo;re following. It&rsquo;s an idol dressed in Scripture’s clothing.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>For Further Reflection:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>When you think of God&rsquo;s priorities, do they align with the voices Scripture consistently lifts up?</li>
<li>How might your politics, theology, or way of life change if you centered the poor and marginalized the way Jesus did?</li>
<li>Where do you see the Spirit at work today—still bringing good news to the poor and setting the oppressed free?</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonhoeffer on Stupidity</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/bonhoeffer-on-stupidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 15:16:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/bonhoeffer-on-stupidity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his &amp;ldquo;Letters and Papers from Prison,&amp;rdquo; Dietrich Bonhoeffer made some remarkably insightful observations about the nature of stupidity and its dangers to society. These reflections, perhaps more relevant today than ever, deserve our careful attention. Here they are in full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-stupidity-dbwe-843-44&#34;&gt;On Stupidity (DBWE 8:43-44)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stupidity is a more dangerous enemy of the good than malice. One may protest against evil; it can be exposed and, if need be, prevented by use of force. Evil always carries within itself the germ of its own subversion in that it leaves behind in human beings at least a sense of unease. Against stupidity we are defenseless. Neither protests nor the use of force accomplish anything here; reasons fall on deaf ears; facts that contradict one’s prejudgment simply need not be believed—in such moments the stupid person even becomes critical—and when facts are irrefutable they are just pushed aside as inconsequential, as incidental. In all this the stupid person, in contrast to the malicious one, is utterly self-satisfied and, being easily irritated, becomes dangerous by going on the attack. For that reason, greater caution is called for when dealing with a stupid person than with a malicious one. Never again will we try to persuade the stupid person with reasons, for it is senseless and dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In his &ldquo;Letters and Papers from Prison,&rdquo; Dietrich Bonhoeffer made some remarkably insightful observations about the nature of stupidity and its dangers to society. These reflections, perhaps more relevant today than ever, deserve our careful attention. Here they are in full.</p>
<h2 id="on-stupidity-dbwe-843-44">On Stupidity (DBWE 8:43-44)</h2>
<blockquote><p>Stupidity is a more dangerous enemy of the good than malice. One may protest against evil; it can be exposed and, if need be, prevented by use of force. Evil always carries within itself the germ of its own subversion in that it leaves behind in human beings at least a sense of unease. Against stupidity we are defenseless. Neither protests nor the use of force accomplish anything here; reasons fall on deaf ears; facts that contradict one’s prejudgment simply need not be believed—in such moments the stupid person even becomes critical—and when facts are irrefutable they are just pushed aside as inconsequential, as incidental. In all this the stupid person, in contrast to the malicious one, is utterly self-satisfied and, being easily irritated, becomes dangerous by going on the attack. For that reason, greater caution is called for when dealing with a stupid person than with a malicious one. Never again will we try to persuade the stupid person with reasons, for it is senseless and dangerous.</p>
<p>If we want to know how to get the better of stupidity, we must seek to understand its nature. This much is certain, that it is in essence not an intellectual defect but a human one. There are human beings who are of remarkably agile intellect yet stupid, and others who are intellectually quite dull yet anything but stupid. We discover this to our surprise in particular situations. The impression one gains is not so much that stupidity is a congenital defect but that, under certain circumstances, people are made stupid or that they allow this to happen to them. We note further that people who have isolated themselves from others or who live in solitude manifest this defect less frequently than individuals or groups of people inclined or condemned to sociability. And so it would seem that stupidity is perhaps less a psychological than a sociological problem. It is a particular form of the impact of historical circumstances on human beings, a psychological concomitant of certain external conditions. Upon closer observation, it becomes apparent that every strong upsurge of power in the public sphere, be it of a political or a religious nature, infects a large part of humankind with stupidity. It would even seem that this is virtually a sociological-psychological law. The power of the one needs the stupidity of (page 44 begins) the other. The process at work here is not that particular human capacities, for instance, the intellect, suddenly atrophy or fail. Instead, it seems that under the overwhelming impact of rising power, humans are deprived of their inner independence and, more or less consciously, give up establishing an autonomous position toward the emerging circumstances. The fact that the stupid person is often stubborn must not blind us to the fact that he is not independent. In conversation with him, one virtually feels that one is dealing not at all with him as a person, but with slogans, catchwords, and the like that have taken possession of him. He is under a spell, blinded, misused, and abused in his very being. Having thus become a mindless tool, the stupid person will also be capable of any evil and at the same time incapable of seeing that it is evil. This is where the danger of diabolical misuse lurks, for it is this that can once and for all destroy human beings.</p>
<p>Yet at this very point it becomes quite clear that only an act of liberation, not instruction, can overcome stupidity. Here we must come to terms with the fact that in most cases a genuine internal liberation becomes possible only when external liberation has preceded it. Until then we must abandon all attempts to convince the stupid person. This state of affairs explains why in such circumstances our attempts to know what “the people” really think are in vain and why, under these circumstances, this question is so irrelevant for the person who is thinking and acting responsibly. The word of the Bible that the fear of God is the beginning of wisdom declares that the internal liberation of human beings to live the responsible life before God is the only genuine way to overcome stupidity.</p>
<p>But these thoughts about stupidity also offer consolation in that they utterly forbid us to consider the majority of people to be stupid in every circumstance. It really will depend on whether those in power expect more from peoples’ stupidity than from their inner independence and wisdom.</p></blockquote><p>Full citation: Dietrich Bonhoeffer, Letters and Papers from Prison, ed. Christian Gremmels et al., trans. Isabel Best et al., vol. 8 of Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2010), 43–44.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logos 10 Bible Software: The Ultimate Theological Learning Tool</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 13:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: If you’re serious about biblical and theological studies, you should invest in Logos 10 Bible Software. &lt;a href=&#34;https://partners.faithlife.com/click.track?CID=431490&amp;amp;AFID=529204&#34;&gt;Do so via my exclusive partner offer for Logos 10 here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could go back in time and chat with Joshua Steele when he was a Bible &amp;amp; Spanish major in college, there are a few things I’d tell my younger self:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quit laughing at &lt;em&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/em&gt; by Mortimer J. Adler and READ the thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baba ghanoush is superior to hummus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Study computer science sooner rather than later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bite the bullet and INVEST IN A LOGOS BIBLE SOFTWARE LIBRARY.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong. I love physical books as much as anyone, and I own quite a few (hundred)!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>TL;DR: If you’re serious about biblical and theological studies, you should invest in Logos 10 Bible Software. <a href="https://partners.faithlife.com/click.track?CID=431490&amp;AFID=529204">Do so via my exclusive partner offer for Logos 10 here!</a></strong></p>
<hr>
<p>If I could go back in time and chat with Joshua Steele when he was a Bible &amp; Spanish major in college, there are a few things I’d tell my younger self:</p>
<ol>
<li>Quit laughing at <em>How to Read a Book</em> by Mortimer J. Adler and READ the thing.</li>
<li>Baba ghanoush is superior to hummus.</li>
<li>Study computer science sooner rather than later.</li>
<li>Bite the bullet and INVEST IN A LOGOS BIBLE SOFTWARE LIBRARY.</li>
</ol>
<p>Don’t get me wrong. I love physical books as much as anyone, and I own quite a few (hundred)!</p>
<p>Nevertheless, when I finally became a Logos Bible Software customer in 2018 as a Ph.D. Student, Anglican Deacon, and Anglican website editor, it took my studies to the next level. I purchased a Logos 8 Anglican Silver package, <a href="https://www.logos.com/product/5758/barths-church-dogmatics">Karl Barth’s Church Dogmatics (31 Vols.)</a>, and <a href="https://www.logos.com/product/152651/dietrich-bonhoeffer-works-german-english">Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works: German-English (34 Vols.)</a>, and I haven’t looked back since!</p>
<p>(NOTE: If you’re interested in the best FREE Bible and theology resources out there, then you NEED to check out <a href="https://bibleproject.com/">The Bible Project</a>, <a href="https://netbible.org/bible/Matthew+1#">The NET Bible</a>, and <a href="https://www.saet.ac.uk/index.php/articles">The St. Andrews Encyclopaedia of Theology</a>!)</p>
<h2 id="logos-10-worth-the-cost">Logos 10: Worth the Cost?</h2>
<p>Has it been a pricey investment over the years? To be sure.</p>
<p>However, even if I just consider the amount of <strong>time saved</strong> (1) looking things up and (2) citing works (which Logos handles AUTOMATICALLY when you copy and paste quotes!!!), I’ve come out on top</p>
<p>This is not to mention the breadth and depth that Logos Bible Software has added to my essays, sermons, emails (I used to receive a lot of Anglicanism-related questions!), and blog posts.</p>
<p>Now that Logos 10 is out, I can heartily continue to recommend Logos Bible Software. If you haven’t done so already, I strongly encourage you to consider buying (or upgrading to) Logos 10! (<a href="https://partners.faithlife.com/click.track?CID=431490&amp;AFID=529204">Again, you can do so via my exclusive partner link here!</a>)</p>
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mfoaX1zkhuU?feature=oembed" title="Logos 10 Is Here" width="750"></iframe></div></figure>
<h2 id="top-3-features-of-logos-10">Top 3 Features of Logos 10</h2>
<p>Real quick, here are my 3 favorite things about Logos 10 (compared to Logos 8 and 9).</p>
<h3 id="1-its-faster">1. It’s FASTER</h3>
<p>Right out of the box, you can tell that they’ve tweaked things under the hood to make Logos 10 run faster (noticeably faster on my 2016 MacBook Pro) than previous versions.</p>
<p>Especially when you’ve got a large library (I’ve got 3,975 items in my Logos library right now) and you’re using multiple resources at a time, running Logos Bible Software is computationally expensive. So I’m glad that the Logos team have made behind-the-scene improvements to the software that have yielded a noticeably superior user experience on my end!</p>
<h3 id="2-with-print-library-catalog-you-can-add-and-search-your-print-books">2. With Print Library Catalog, you can add and search your PRINT BOOKS</h3>
<p>The new <a href="https://www.logos.com/features/print-library-catalog">Print Library Catalog feature</a> is a game-changer, especially if you, like me, have quite a few physical biblical and theological books laying around!</p>
<p>If you add those physical books to your Logos Print Library Catalog, then, as long as Logos has digital versions of those books, you can use the power of Logos search to help you find things in your physical books!</p>
<p>This means that Logos Bible Software can now help you take better advantage of the physical books you already own! Genius.</p>
<h3 id="3-church-history-themes">3. Church History Themes</h3>
<p>As a student of historical theology, I’m a bit biased here, but I think that most Christians these days have a woefully inadequate understanding of Church history!</p>
<p>Granted, not everyone needs to become Church history experts! But all Christians should know at least the broad contours and the major themes from Church history. Let’s learn the most we can from saints who have gone before us!</p>
<p>Logos 10 makes a big step forward here with the new <a href="https://www.logos.com/features/church-history">Church History Themes</a> feature. It’s a fantastic way to get up to speed on some of the most important movements and topics from the history of Christianity.</p>
<h3 id="4-bonus-auto-translation">4. (Bonus) Auto Translation!</h3>
<p>OK, we’re into the weeds a bit here, because I realize that not everyone will be interested in this. But, as someone who (attempted) a Ph.D. on two German-speaking theologians, let me just tell you that I REALLY wish this feature had been introduced earlier!</p>
<p>Logos 10’s new <a href="https://www.logos.com/features/auto-translation">Auto Translation feature</a> makes it easier than ever to engage with works written in, say, Latin, French, or German right from Logos. I really hope that this kind of AI-assisted translation continues to improve, because there are so many works out there originally written in other languages. Plenty of these haven’t been translated into English yet. And, even when they have (looking at you, Barth’s Church Dogmatics), there’s really no replacement for engaging with a work in its original language.</p>
<h2 id="other-helpful-logos-10-bible-software-reviews">Other Helpful Logos 10 Bible Software Reviews</h2>
<p>I’ve only scratched the surface of the new and improved features of Logos 10. I’ll say it again, I strongly recommend that you <a href="https://partners.faithlife.com/click.track?CID=431490&amp;AFID=529204">invest in a Logos 10 Bible Software library</a>!</p>
<p>And don’t just take my word for it! Here are some other reviews of Logos 10 Bible Software that you should take a look at as you consider whether or not to purchase/upgrade:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://overviewbible.com/logos-bible-software-review/">Logos Bible Software 10 review: Do you REALLY need it?</a> (OverviewBible)</li>
<li><a href="https://biblebuyingguide.com/logos-10-bible-software-review/">Logos 10 Bible Software Review</a> (BibleBuyingGuide)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zN6USy9hc4I">10 Noteworthy New Logos 10 Features in Under 10 Minutes</a> (Chris J. Wilson, YouTube)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.propreacher.com/logos-10-review/">Logos 10 Review: The Best Bible App?</a> (ProPreacher)</li>
<li><a href="https://churchtechtoday.com/top-3-new-features-in-logos-10-bible-software-review/">Top 3 New Features in Logos 10 Bible Software</a> (ChurchTechToday)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help! I’m looking for the best Christian resources on the Bible, social justice, racism, Critical Race Theory, and Marxism</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 17:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Help me out. I’m looking for the best, clearest, and most charitable explanations of the following three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the biblical and theological reasons for caring about social justice and systemic racism,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the unfair ways in which some have used accusations of Critical Race Theory (CRT) and Cultural Marxism to sideline legitimate Christian concerns about social justice and systemic racism, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the legitimate Christian critiques of CRT and Marxism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that there are plenty of resources out there that address each of the three items above!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Help me out. I’m looking for the best, clearest, and most charitable explanations of the following three things:</p>
<ol>
<li>the biblical and theological reasons for caring about social justice and systemic racism,</li>
<li>the unfair ways in which some have used accusations of Critical Race Theory (CRT) and Cultural Marxism to sideline legitimate Christian concerns about social justice and systemic racism, and</li>
<li>the legitimate Christian critiques of CRT and Marxism.</li>
</ol>
<p>Now, I <em>know</em> that there are plenty of resources out there that address each of the three items above!</p>
<p>I’m specifically looking for the resources that are the <em>easiest to understand</em> for someone who has little (or no) biblical, theological, or philosophical training. I’m thinking something that you could easily share with friends and relatives who have legitimate questions.</p>
<p>I’m also specifically looking for resources that address 2 or 3 of the items above, not just 1.</p>
<p>Do such resources already exist?</p>
<p>If not, should we start a Kickstarter to create a “Crash Course”-style YouTube video that addresses all three points above??</p>
<h2 id="my-current-shortlist-of-helpful-resources">My current shortlist of helpful resources</h2>
<p>To provide some grist for the mill, the following resources don’t address all three of my points above, but they <em>are</em> really good and they’re on my current short list of recommended resources for family and friends:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AGUwcs9qJXY">Phil Vischer’s video on “Race in America”</a> (he’s the creator of VeggieTales and the voice of Bob the Tomato)</li>
<li><a href="https://ntwrightpage.com/2020/06/14/undermining-racism-complete-text/">N.T. Wright’s talk on “Undermining Racism”</a> (scroll to the bottom for a video of the talk)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/kelly.hamren.7/posts/10156935647256923">Kelly Hamren’s “Reflections from a Christian scholar on Social Justice, Critical Race Theory, Marxism, and Biblical Ethics”</a> (Facebook essay)</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s more than one kind of &#34;priesthood&#34; in the New Testament</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/theres-more-than-one-kind-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 20:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/theres-more-than-one-kind-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/nbfr.12440&#34;&gt;this article in New Blackfriars&lt;/a&gt;, and it looks helpful, especially in the context of Anglican debates about women’s ordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Title: “The Four Types of Priesthood in the New Testament: On Avoiding Confusions about What ‘Priesthood’ Means”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Geoffrey Turner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Christian discourse tends to treat the concept of ‘priesthood’ univocally, so that ordained priests are seen to share the priesthood of Christ. But a careful reading of Hebrews shows clearly that the priesthood of Christ is unique to him. There are four (even five) types of priest in the New Testament and each of them is distinct and not to be confused.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just came across <a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/nbfr.12440">this article in New Blackfriars</a>, and it looks helpful, especially in the context of Anglican debates about women’s ordination.</p>
<p>Title: “The Four Types of Priesthood in the New Testament: On Avoiding Confusions about What ‘Priesthood’ Means”</p>
<p>Author: Geoffrey Turner</p>
<p>Abstract:</p>
<blockquote><p>Christian discourse tends to treat the concept of ‘priesthood’ univocally, so that ordained priests are seen to share the priesthood of Christ. But a careful reading of Hebrews shows clearly that the priesthood of Christ is unique to him. There are four (even five) types of priest in the New Testament and each of them is distinct and not to be confused.</p></blockquote><h2 id="types-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament">Types of Priesthood in the New Testament</h2>
<ol>
<li>Aaronic, sacrificing priest (like Zechariah, Luke 1:5)</li>
<li>The risen Christ</li>
<li>Priesthood of all believers</li>
<li>Ordained presbyters/elders</li>
<li>Passing mention of pagan priests (Acts 14:13)</li>
</ol>
<p>Concluding paragraph:</p>
<blockquote><p>The point of this paper, however, is not to try to change our naming of the ordained; our practice has centuries of tradition behind it. The purpose is to ensure that we do not muddle these distinctive types of priesthood. And the recent practice of calling our ordained priests ‘ministerial priests’ is a recognition that their priesthood is distinct from that of Jesus Christ and distinct from that of the baptised. There is no basis in the NT for supposing that that presbyters share the high priesthood of Christ as it is described in Hebrews. On the contrary, that high priesthood has only two members: Melchizedek and Jesus, and only one of those is a historical person. Deciding who may become a presbyter/ministerial priest and on what basis must be decided on its own terms and not by merging it with some other form of priesthood. Muddling these is particularly unhelpful when discussing whether women can be ordained as presbyters/ministerial priests.</p></blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the relationship between biblical and systematic/dogmatic theology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 15:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the question we’re considering this week in our doctoral seminar on biblical and theological integration. Two of us are theologians and the other four are bible scholars. Should be interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: we’ll have to save the difference(s) between systematic, historical, and dogmatic theology for another post!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the articles we were assigned to read for this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D.A. Carson, “Systematic Theology and Biblical Theology” in the New Dictionary of Biblical Theology, pp. 89-104.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D.A. Carson, “Unity and Diversity in the New Testament: The Possibility of Systematic Theology” in Scripture and Truth, D. A. Carson and J. D. Woodbridge, eds. (Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 1983), pp. 65-95.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;G. Hasel, “The Relationship between Biblical Theology and Systematic Theology” Trinity Journal 5 (1984): 113-27;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I.H. Marshall, “Climbing Ropes, Ellipses and Symphonies: The Relation between Biblical and Systematic Theology” in A Pathway into the Holy Scripture, P.E. Satterthwaite and D.F. Wright, eds. (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1994), 199–219.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E.A. Martens, “Moving from Scripture to Doctrine” Bulletin for Biblical Research 15.1 (2005): 77-103.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin Vanhoozer, “Interpreting Scripture between the Rock of Biblical Studies and the Hard Place of Systematic Theology: The State of the Evangelical (Dis)union” in Richard Lints, ed., Renewing the Evangelical Mission (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2013), 201-25.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, for the rest of the semester, we’re reading at least selections from the following works. The goal is to learn from examples of biblical and theological integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the question we’re considering this week in our doctoral seminar on biblical and theological integration. Two of us are theologians and the other four are bible scholars. Should be interesting!</p>
<p><em>(Note: we’ll have to save the difference(s) between systematic, historical, and dogmatic theology for another post!)</em></p>
<p>Here are the articles we were assigned to read for this week:</p>
<ol>
<li>D.A. Carson, “Systematic Theology and Biblical Theology” in the New Dictionary of Biblical Theology, pp. 89-104.</li>
<li>D.A. Carson, “Unity and Diversity in the New Testament: The Possibility of Systematic Theology” in Scripture and Truth, D. A. Carson and J. D. Woodbridge, eds. (Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 1983), pp. 65-95.</li>
<li>G. Hasel, “The Relationship between Biblical Theology and Systematic Theology” Trinity Journal 5 (1984): 113-27;</li>
<li>I.H. Marshall, “Climbing Ropes, Ellipses and Symphonies: The Relation between Biblical and Systematic Theology” in A Pathway into the Holy Scripture, P.E. Satterthwaite and D.F. Wright, eds. (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1994), 199–219.</li>
<li>E.A. Martens, “Moving from Scripture to Doctrine” Bulletin for Biblical Research 15.1 (2005): 77-103.</li>
<li>Kevin Vanhoozer, “Interpreting Scripture between the Rock of Biblical Studies and the Hard Place of Systematic Theology: The State of the Evangelical (Dis)union” in Richard Lints, ed., Renewing the Evangelical Mission (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2013), 201-25.</li>
</ol>
<p>Other than that, for the rest of the semester, we’re reading at least selections from the following works. The goal is to learn from examples of biblical and theological integration.</p>
<ul>
<li>Richard Bauckham, Monotheism &amp; Christology in the New Testament (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1998).</li>
<li>Walter Brueggemann, Theology of the Old Testament: Testimony, Dispute, Advocacy (Minneapolis: Augsburg Fortress, 1997).</li>
<li>Graham A. Cole, The God who became Human: A biblical theology of incarnation (NSBT; Downers Grove: IVP, 1995).</li>
<li>C. John Collins, The God of Miracles: An Exegetical Examination of God’s Action in the World (Wheaton: Crossway, 2000).</li>
<li>Wesley Hill, Paul and the Trinity: Persons, Relations, and the Pauline Letters (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2015).</li>
<li>R. W. L. Moberly, The Bible, Theology, and Faith: A Study of Abraham and Jesus (Cambridge: Cambridge Univ. Press, 2000).</li>
<li>Oliver O’Donovan, The Desire of the Nations: Rediscovering the Roots of Political Theology (Cambridge: Cambridge Univ. Press, 1996).</li>
<li>Francis Watson, Texts and Truth: Redefining Biblical Theology (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1997).</li>
<li>Steven N. Williams, The Election of Grace: A Riddle without a Resolution? (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2015).</li>
</ul>
<p>What’s the best thing you’ve ever read that combines biblical and theological study?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Christian Theology: A Draft Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 22:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a part of my “pedagogical experience” at Wheaton College this semester, I was required to draft a syllabus for an introduction to Christian theology. Feel free to let me know what you think in the comments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: the length of this syllabus doesn’t necessarily correspond to the difficulty of this course&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-information&#34;&gt;Contact Information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email: [REDACTED]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone: [REDACTED]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office Hours (Buswell Library Carrell): T, W, R, 15:00–17:00.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is an introduction to the methods of systematic theology and the major topics within biblical revelation. Special attention is given to the rationale for these Christian doctrines, their systematic interconnections as well as their development within the history of Christian thought, and their contemporary challenges. This class is your opportunity to reinforce why you believe what you believe and to examine how it impacts your life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>As a part of my “pedagogical experience” at Wheaton College this semester, I was required to draft a syllabus for an introduction to Christian theology. Feel free to let me know what you think in the comments.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>Note: the length of this syllabus doesn’t necessarily correspond to the difficulty of this course</p>
<h1 id="contact-information">Contact Information</h1>
<ul>
<li>Email: [REDACTED]</li>
<li>Phone: [REDACTED]</li>
<li>Office Hours (Buswell Library Carrell): T, W, R, 15:00–17:00.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h1 id="course-description">Course Description</h1>
<p>This course is an introduction to the methods of systematic theology and the major topics within biblical revelation. Special attention is given to the rationale for these Christian doctrines, their systematic interconnections as well as their development within the history of Christian thought, and their contemporary challenges. This class is your opportunity to reinforce why you believe what you believe and to examine how it impacts your life.</p>
<ul>
<li>~15-20 students, graduate, non-theology majors; assuming that this is the first and last systematic theology course you’ll take (but not the last time you’ll do theology, hopefully!).</li>
<li>Meets twice a week (T/R) for 110 minutes (80 mins of content, 20 minutes of breaks, 10 minutes of intro and conclusion). We’ll be modeling each class session after the “Pomodoro Technique,” in which you do focused work for 20 mins and then reward yourself with a short break. Here’s the rough outline:
<ul>
<li>5 min: opening prayer, introduction</li>
<li>20 min content</li>
<li>5 min break</li>
<li>20 min content</li>
<li>10 min break</li>
<li>20 min content</li>
<li>5 min break</li>
<li>20 min content</li>
<li>5 min: conclusion, final questions</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="course-goals">Course Goals</h1>
<p>The student who successfully completes the course will achieve the following goals:</p>
<h2 id="directly-assessed">Directly Assessed</h2>
<ol>
<li>(Foundational Knowledge) Understand key concepts, themes, terms, debates, and thinkers within Christian theology.</li>
<li>(Application; Human Dimension) Know how to read and engage with theological proposals both critically and charitably.</li>
<li>(Application) Know how to craft a theological argument and explain theological concepts.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="indirectly-assessed">Indirectly Assessed</h2>
<ol>
<li>(Integration) Relate Christian theology to other disciplines and the Christian life.</li>
<li>(Caring; Human Dimension) Grow in wisdom, in the knowledge and love of God.</li>
<li>(Learning How to Learn) Know how to keep on learning about Christian theology after this course is over.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h1 id="textbooks">Textbooks</h1>
<p>Total cost: ~$75.</p>
<h2 id="jenson-robert-a-theology-in-outline-can-these-bones-live-oxford-university-press-2016">Jenson, Robert. <em>A Theology in Outline: Can These Bones Live?</em> (Oxford University Press, 2016).</h2>
<ul>
<li>152 pages.</li>
<li>ISBN: 978-0190214593</li>
<li>~$25 on Amazon.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="kibbe-michael-from-topic-to-thesis-a-guide-to-theological-research-ivp-academic-2016">Kibbe, Michael. <em>From Topic to Thesis: A Guide to Theological Research.</em> (IVP Academic, 2016).</h2>
<ul>
<li>153 pages.</li>
<li>ISBN: 978-0830851317</li>
<li>˜$10 on Amazon.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mcgrath-alister-e-theology-the-basics-4th-ed-blackwell-2017">McGrath, Alister E. <em>Theology: The Basics.</em> 4th ed. (Blackwell, 2017).</h2>
<ul>
<li>296 pages.</li>
<li>ISBN: 978-1119158080</li>
<li>~$20 on Amazon.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mcgrath-alister-e-theology-the-basic-readings-3rd-ed-blackwell-2018">McGrath, Alister E. <em>Theology: The Basic Readings.</em> 3rd ed. (Blackwell, 2018).</h2>
<ul>
<li>280 pages.</li>
<li>ISBN: 978-1119158158</li>
<li>~$20 on Amazon.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h1 id="course-requirements">Course Requirements</h1>
<h2 id="participation--assigned-reading--20">Participation &amp; Assigned Reading – 20%</h2>
<p>Participation will be based on class discussions, which will require students to come to class prepared by having read thoughtfully the assigned readings.</p>
<p>Students will be expected to read all of the required texts in their entirety as indicated on the course schedule. This reading needs to be complete <strong>prior to</strong> the designated class session and students will be graded based on their ability to participate actively in the discussions relative to those readings.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that additional articles may be assigned during the course.</p>
<h2 id="reading-quizzes--20">Reading Quizzes – 20%</h2>
<p>Once a week (the first class session of the week), students will take a brief reading quiz on the main points of the assigned reading (usually from McGrath’s <em>Theology: The Basics</em>) for that day.</p>
<h2 id="reading-presentations--20">Reading Presentations – 20%</h2>
<p>Once a week (the second class session of the week), students will give brief presentations on the assigned primary source readings from McGrath’s <em>Theology: The Basic Readings.</em></p>
<p>In each presentation, the student will have 2 minutes to:<br>
– read a <strong>one-sentence summary</strong> of the passage that they’ve written<br>
– <strong>praise</strong> one aspect/point of the reading<br>
– <strong>critique</strong> one aspect/point of the reading.</p>
<p>The rest of the class will then spend ˜5 minutes responding to each presentation, before moving on to the next presentation.</p>
<p>Each student will give 3-4 presentations over the course of the semester. The schedule for reading presentations will be assigned by the professor at the beginning of the course.</p>
<p><em>Don’t like public speaking?</em> That’s OK. I encourage you to manuscript your presentation and read it.</p>
<h2 id="one-minute-papers--10">One-Minute Papers – 10%</h2>
<p>Over the course of the semester (5 times), students will be given a few minutes in class to write out their answer to a reflection question, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>What was the muddies/least clear idea you encountered in class this week?</li>
<li>What was the most important idea you encountered in class this week?</li>
<li>What important questions remain unanswered for you?</li>
</ul>
<p>These brief papers will be left with or emailed to the professor, and will be graded on a pass/fail basis for each paper (i.e., if you do all 5, you’ll get full credit, if you do 4/5, you’ll get 80% credit).</p>
<h2 id="final-paper--30">Final Paper – 30%</h2>
<p>Over the course of the semester, students will work on a 3,000 word essay on a theological topic of their choice (within the broad range of theological topics covered in Jenson and McGrath).</p>
<p>I expect you to incorporate at least two sources in addition to the assigned readings in this class.</p>
<p>Overall, this project will be worth 30% of the final grade. However, it will be completed in stages. Students will:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Pick a topic</strong> and let the professor know by the fourth class session (end of week 2).</li>
<li><strong>Submit a 1-2 page outline, abstract, and bibliography (5% of final grade)</strong> by the tenth class session (end of week 5). Let me know what additional sources you’re thinking about using.</li>
<li>Receive a graded outline/abstract with feedback by the twelfth class session (end of week 6).</li>
<li><strong>Submit a 3,000 word final paper (15% of final grade)</strong> by the twentieth class session (end of week 10).</li>
<li>Receive a graded final paper with feedback by the twenty-fourth class session (end of week 12).</li>
<li><strong>Submit a 3,000 word revised final paper (10% of final grade)</strong> by the thirtieth class session (end of week 15, end of term). You’ll be expected to give me a <strong>one paragraph summary of how you’ve improved the paper</strong>.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h1 id="grading">Grading</h1>
<ul>
<li>A: 94-100</li>
<li>A-: 90-93.9</li>
<li>B+: &gt;87</li>
<li>B: &gt;84</li>
<li>B-: &gt;80</li>
<li>C+: &gt;77</li>
<li>C: &gt;74</li>
<li>C-: &gt;70</li>
<li>D+: &gt;67</li>
<li>D: &gt;64</li>
<li>D-: &gt;60</li>
<li>F: &lt;60</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h1 id="course-policies">Course Policies</h1>
<ol>
<li>Students are expected to arrive in class on time, stay for the duration of class, and actively engage in the discussion of material under consideration.</li>
<li>Students should submit assignments on the dates indicated by the course schedule.</li>
<li>Students with special needs or disabilities should speak to the professor <em>early</em> in the semester to facilitate adequate and suitable arrangements to meet the relevant needs.</li>
<li>For academic discourse, spoken and written, the faculty expects students to use <strong>gender inclusive language for human beings</strong></li>
<li>Students will be expected to attend every class session except in the case of sickness or when an absence has been arranged with the professor. Missing more than 20% of the class hours will result in a grade reduction.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h1 id="class-schedule">Class Schedule</h1>
<h2 id="section-one-the-nature-of-theology-and-an-example-of-theology">SECTION ONE: THE NATURE OF THEOLOGY AND AN EXAMPLE OF THEOLOGY</h2>
<h3 id="week-1-what-is-theology-how-do-we-do-it">Week 1: What is theology? How do we do it?</h3>
<h4 id="1-what-is-theology">(1) What is theology?</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>McGrath, <em>Basics</em>, Preface – Getting Started</li>
<li>McGrath, <em>Readings</em>, How to Use this Book – Apostles’ Creed</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li>Submit an <strong>introductory survey</strong> (emailed to students before the beginning of term).
<ul>
<li>What’s your denominational/church background, if any?</li>
<li>What theological education, if any, have you received before?</li>
<li>What’s one theological question you really hope that we address in this course?</li>
<li>What’s a theological debate that you’re particularly interested in and/or confused by?</li>
<li>Do you have any favorite Christian theologians, pastors, or authors?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="2-how-do-we-do-theology">(2) How do we do theology?</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>Kibbe, Introduction (11) – Conclusion (91) (Appendices are optional, but will be helpful for your paper.)</li>
<li>Vanhoozer, “Letter to an Aspiring Theologian”: <a href="https://www.firstthings.com/article/2018/08/letter-to-an-aspiring-theologian">https://www.firstthings.com/article/2018/08/letter-to-an-aspiring-theologian</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>One-minute paper</strong> (in class)</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-2-theology-in-outline">Week 2: Theology in Outline</h3>
<h4 id="3-theology-israel-jesus-and-the-triune-god">(3) Theology, Israel, Jesus, and the Triune God</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jenson, introduction and chapters 1–4</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="4-the-image-of-god-sin-salvation-and-church">(4) The Image of God, Sin, Salvation, and Church</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>Jenson, 5–9</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pick a topic for your final paper.</strong> The following topics are open game:
<ul>
<li>Israel</li>
<li>Jesus</li>
<li>Resurrection</li>
<li>Trinity</li>
<li>Creation</li>
<li>Image of God</li>
<li>Sin</li>
<li>Salvation</li>
<li>Church</li>
<li>Faith</li>
<li>Spirit</li>
<li>Sacraments</li>
<li>Heaven</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="section-two-the-basics-of-theology">SECTION TWO: THE BASICS OF THEOLOGY</h2>
<h3 id="week-3-faith-i-believe">Week 3: Faith (“I believe…”)</h3>
<h4 id="5-faith-the-basics">(5) Faith: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 1</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li>Submit your <strong>special topics requests/suggestions</strong> for the final two weeks of class (emailed to students during the first week of class).
<ul>
<li>We have two “buffer weeks” built into the end of this course.</li>
<li>I’d like to devote them to in-depth analysis and debate of at least one topic.</li>
<li>Submit your requests/suggestions through the link included in the email.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="6-faith-readings">(6) Faith: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 1</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Vote on the submitted topic requests/suggestions</strong> for the final two weeks of class.</li>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Augustine</li>
<li>Vincent</li>
<li>Calvin</li>
<li>Barth</li>
<li>Brunner</li>
<li>Tillich</li>
<li>Lewis</li>
<li>JP2</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>One-minute paper</strong> (in class)</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-4-god-in-god-the-father-almighty">Week 4: God (“In God, the Father Almighty”)</h3>
<h4 id="7-god-the-basics">(7) God: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 2</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="8-god-readings">(8) God: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 2</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Athenagoras</li>
<li>Aquinas</li>
<li>Moltmann</li>
<li>von Balthasar</li>
<li>Johnson</li>
<li>Coakley</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-5-creation-creator-of-heaven-and-earth">Week 5: Creation (“Creator of heaven and earth”)</h3>
<h4 id="9-creation-the-basics">(9) Creation: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 3</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="10-creation-readings">(10) Creation: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 3</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Submit the Outline &amp; Abstract for your Final Paper.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Mirandola</li>
<li>Edwards</li>
<li>Paley</li>
<li>Newman</li>
<li>Chesterton</li>
<li>Sayers</li>
<li>Polkinghorne</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>One-minute paper</strong> (in class)</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-6-jesus-i-believe-in-jesus-christ-gods-only-son-our-lord">Week 6: Jesus (“I believe in Jesus Christ, God’s only Son, our Lord…”)</h3>
<h4 id="11-jesus-the-basics">(11) Jesus: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 4</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="12-jesus-readings">(12) Jesus: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 4</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Athanasius</li>
<li>Leo</li>
<li>Kähler</li>
<li>Tyrrell</li>
<li>Farrer</li>
<li>Hooker</li>
<li>Wright</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-7-salvation">Week 7: Salvation</h3>
<h4 id="13-salvation-the-basics">(13) Salvation: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 5</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="14-salvation-readings">(14) Salvation: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 5</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Rufinus</li>
<li>Maximus</li>
<li>Anselm</li>
<li>Schleiermacher</li>
<li>Lonergan</li>
<li>Gunton</li>
<li>Ruether</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Mid-Term Reflection</strong> (in class; questions taken from Fink, <em>Creating Significant Learning Experiences</em>, 134):
<ul>
<li>What <em>key ideas or information</em> have you learned about the subject or the course?</li>
<li>What have you learned about <em>how to use or apply</em> the content of the course?</li>
<li>What parts of your knowledge, thinking, or actions have you been able to <em>integrate</em> or connect within or external to this learning experience?</li>
<li>What have you learned about the <em>human dimension</em> of this subject? That is, how have <em>you</em> changed in some important way, and have you changed in your ability to interact with <em>others</em>?</li>
<li>Have any of your interests, feelings, or <em>values</em> changed as a result of this learning experience?</li>
<li>What have you learned about <em>how to learn</em>?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-8-spirit-i-believe-in-the-holy-spirit">Week 8: Spirit (“I believe in the Holy Spirit”)</h3>
<h4 id="15-holy-spirit-the-basics">(15) Holy Spirit: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 6</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="16-holy-spirit-readings">(16) Holy Spirit: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 6</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Ambrose</li>
<li>John of Damascus</li>
<li>Formula of Concord</li>
<li>Gore</li>
<li>Swete</li>
<li>Webster</li>
<li>Meyendorff</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-9-trinity">Week 9: Trinity</h3>
<h4 id="17-trinity-the-basics">(17) Trinity: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 7</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="18-trinity-readings">(18) Trinity: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 7</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Irenaeus</li>
<li>Eleventh Council</li>
<li>Richard</li>
<li>Rahner</li>
<li>Macquarrie</li>
<li>Jenson</li>
<li>LaCugna</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>One-minute paper</strong> (in class)</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-10-church-the-holy-catholic-church">Week 10: Church (“…the holy Catholic Church”)</h3>
<h4 id="19-church-the-basics">(19) Church: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 8</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="20-church-readings">(20) Church: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 8</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Submit your Final Paper.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Luther</li>
<li>Newbigin</li>
<li>Vatican II</li>
<li>Dragas</li>
<li>Hauerwas</li>
<li>Boff</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-11-sacraments">Week 11: Sacraments</h3>
<h4 id="21-sacraments-the-basics">(21) Sacraments: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 9</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="22-sacraments-readings">(22) Sacraments: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 9</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Cyril</li>
<li>Zwingli</li>
<li>Trent</li>
<li>WCC</li>
<li>Williams</li>
<li>Benedict</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>One-minute paper</strong> (in class)</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-12-heaven">Week 12: Heaven</h3>
<h4 id="23-heaven-the-basics">(23) Heaven: The Basics</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Basics</em>, 10</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Quiz</strong></li>
</ul>
<h4 id="24-heaven-readings">(24) Heaven: Readings</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Readings</em>, 10</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reading Presentations</strong> (Summary; 1 Positive; 1 Critique):
<ul>
<li>Cyprian</li>
<li>Methodius</li>
<li>Abelard</li>
<li>Wesley</li>
<li>Catechism</li>
<li>Pannenberg</li>
<li>Tanner</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="section-three-doing-theology-ourselves">SECTION THREE: DOING THEOLOGY OURSELVES</h2>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-13-special-topic-1-tbd">Week 13: SPECIAL TOPIC #1, TBD</h3>
<h4 id="25">(25)</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>TBD</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li>TBD</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="26">(26)</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>TBD</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li>TBD</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-14-special-topic-2-tbd">Week 14: SPECIAL TOPIC #2, TBD</h3>
<h4 id="27">(27)</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>TBD</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li>TBD</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="28">(28)</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>TBD</li>
</ul>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li>TBD</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="week-15-where-do-we-go-from-here">Week 15: Where do we go from here?</h3>
<h4 id="29-how-to-become-a-better-theologian-on-your-own">(29) How to become a better theologian “on your own”</h4>
<p>Reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>Re-read Vanhoozer’s “Letter to an Aspiring Theologian”</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="30-how-to-become-a-better-theologian-inwith-the-church">(30) How to become a better theologian in/with the Church</h4>
<p>Assignment:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Submit your Revised Final paper.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Final Reflection</strong> (in class):
<ul>
<li>What <em>key ideas or information</em> have you learned about the subject or the course?</li>
<li>What have you learned about <em>how to use or apply</em> the content of the course?</li>
<li>What parts of your knowledge, thinking, or actions have you been able to <em>integrate</em> or connect within or external to this learning experience?</li>
<li>What have you learned about the <em>human dimension</em> of this subject? That is, how have <em>you</em> changed in some important way, and have you changed in your ability to interact with <em>others</em>?</li>
<li>Have any of your interests, feelings, or <em>values</em> changed as a result of this learning experience?</li>
<li>What have you learned about <em>how to learn</em>?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h1 id="recommended-further-reading">Recommended Further Reading</h1>
<p>The following books would make excellent “next steps” after this course, and/or “first steps” in researching for your final paper.</p>
<ul>
<li>Erickson, Millard. Christian Theology, 3d ed. (Baker, 2013).</li>
<li>Gunton, Colin, ed. The Cambridge Companion to Christian Doctrine. (Cambridge University Press, 1997).</li>
<li>Jenson, Robert. Story and Promise: A Brief Theology of the Gospel about Jesus. (Fortress, 1973).</li>
<li>McGrath, Alister. Christian Theology: An Introduction, 6th ed. (Blackwell, 2016).</li>
<li>McGrath, Alister, ed. The Christian Theology Reader, 5th ed. (Blackwell, 2016).</li>
<li>Oden, Thomas. Classic Christianity: A Systematic Theology. (HarperOne, 2009).</li>
<li>van der Kooi, Cornelis, and Gijsbert van den Brink. Christian Dogmatics: An Introduction. (Eerdmans, 2017).</li>
<li>Webster, John, Kathryn Tanner, and Iain Torrance, eds. The Oxford Handbook of Systematic Theology. (Oxford University Press, 2007).</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h1 id="rationale-for-textbooks">Rationale for Textbooks</h1>
<p>These days, we’re spoiled for choice when it comes to theology textbooks. I don’t claim to have chosen the very best textbooks, but here are some of my reasons for choosing the texts I did, as well as my reasons for <em>not</em> choosing 5 books that almost made the cut.</p>
<h2 id="why-i-chose-our-texts">Why I Chose Our Texts</h2>
<h3 id="jenson-a-theology-in-outline">Jenson, <em>A Theology in Outline</em></h3>
<p>I wanted us to read a brief book that (1) showcased a theologian <em>doing</em> theology, and not merely surveying theology and (2) gave a taste for how the various aspects of Christian doctrine hang together. Jenson’s book, comprised of lectures he gave to undergraduate students at Princeton at the end of his career, fit the bill nicely. It will give us a taste of what Christian theology can look like as a whole before we dive into its parts. I also hope that it provides enough grist for the mill early in the semester so that you can choose topics that you’re interested in for your papers.</p>
<h3 id="kibbe-from-topic-to-thesis">Kibbe, <em>From Topic to Thesis</em></h3>
<p>Speaking of papers, Kibbe’s book is an excellent primer for theological research and writing. Because people come into this course from different academic backgrounds, some kind of introduction to what research and writing should look like in theology is necessary. I know of no better bang for the buck (and for the page) than this recent book from Kibbe.</p>
<h3 id="mcgrath-theology-the-basics--theology-the-basic-readings">McGrath, <em>Theology: The Basics</em> &amp; <em>Theology: The Basic Readings</em></h3>
<p>I’ll admit that it was difficult to choose between these two shorter books and McGrath’s longer offerings, <em>Christian Theology: An Introduction</em> and <em>The Christian Theology Reader.</em></p>
<p>All of McGrath’s textbooks are excellent in that they expose the reader to the main contours of Christian theology and how those contours have developed over the history of the Church. Furthermore, McGrath teaches you how to engage with primary texts, and gives you guided practice in doing so. Finally, these textbooks have stood the test of time, going through multiple revisions that have incorporated classroom feedback from around the world.</p>
<p>In the end, I went with the shorter options because I’d like us to have time to engage with the works quite thoroughly, instead of feeling like we have to struggle to keep up with the longer books.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, I’ll be drawing from McGrath’s longer books frequently in my lectures, and I highly recommend them to you for after this course if this semester successfully whets your appetite for Christian theology!</p>
<h2 id="the-top-5-that-almost-made-the-cut">The “Top 5” that Almost Made the Cut</h2>
<p>(Note: these are in alphabetical order, not ranked.)</p>
<h3 id="erickson-christian-theology">Erickson, <em>Christian Theology</em></h3>
<p>Erickson’s work is a classic and would be well worth your time and money to purchase and use as a reference after this course. However, it’s almost 1200 pages long. While that allows him to address many topics that aren’t covered in McGrath’s shorter books, I felt it was too long of a text to require for this semester.</p>
<h3 id="grudem-systematic-theology">Grudem, <em>Systematic Theology</em></h3>
<p>Grudem’s is perhaps the best-known systematic theology in evangelical circles. It has many merits, especially the extent to which it integrates biblical material at every turn (the subtitle is, appropriately, “An Introduction to Biblical Doctrine”). However, it’s just over 1200 pages long—too long, in my opinion, for a one semester survey.</p>
<h3 id="felker-jones-practicing-christian-doctrine">Felker Jones, <em>Practicing Christian Doctrine</em></h3>
<p>This work isn’t a classic, yet! I do suspect, however, that it will gain in popularity because, coming in at under 250 pages, it’s a fantastic introduction to Christian doctrine and the importance of both “thinking and living theologically” (from the book’s subtitle). However, while the book has more of an emphasis on living theologically than McGrath does, it contains less guidance and practice of engaging with primary sources. No single book can do everything, of course, but the associated reader was a big reason why I chose McGrath over Felker Jones.</p>
<h3 id="oden-classic-christianity">Oden, <em>Classic Christianity</em></h3>
<p>This book is a wonderful resource for finding out what the consensus teaching of the Church, emphasis on the early Church, has been on the various main topics of Christian theology—“classic consensual ecumenical teaching,” as Oden puts it. It reads almost like a systematically-categorized catalogue of quotations from the early Church. I think it deserves a place on your bookshelf alongside another more “standard” systematic theology like Erickson or van der Kooi and van den Brink. However, at just over 900 pages, it’s too long to work well as a main text for this course.</p>
<h3 id="van-der-kooi--van-den-brink-christian-dogmatics">Van der Kooi &amp; van den Brink, <em>Christian Dogmatics</em></h3>
<p>This is another resource that isn’t a classic yet, at least not in the USA, because it’s only been available in English translation since 2017. However, it’s already a classic work in Dutch since it came out in the Netherlands in 2012. Just like Erickson and Grudem above, this is a pedagogically useful and comprehensive systematic theology. However, just like Erickson and Grudem, at 800 pages, this book is also too long to serve as our main text.</p>
<p>Furthermore, while Erickson and Grudem approach things from a particularly Baptist perspective, van der Kooi and van den Brink approach things from a particularly Dutch Reformed perspective. Nothing against these perspectives, of course, but (1) I don’t hold them and (2) I think McGrath (as well as Felker Jones, Oden, and others) does a better job of exposing us to as broad/mainstream an exposition of Christian theology as possible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Models: A Helpful Model for Theology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 15:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This idea has been bouncing around in my head for a bit. It’s not fully-formed by any means, but I’d like to get it out there and hear what you think of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here it is: “Mental Models” could be a helpful model for theology.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-mental-model&#34;&gt;What is a “mental model”?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition-of-mental-models&#34;&gt;Definition of mental models&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, a “mental model” is a concept used to help explain how the world works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This idea has been bouncing around in my head for a bit. It’s not fully-formed by any means, but I’d like to get it out there and hear what you think of it.</p>
<p><strong>Here it is: “Mental Models” could be a helpful model for theology.</strong></p>
<h1 id="what-is-a-mental-model">What is a “mental model”?</h1>
<h2 id="definition-of-mental-models">Definition of mental models</h2>
<p>Put simply, a “mental model” is a concept used to help explain how the world works.</p>
<p>According to Wikipedia:</p>
<blockquote><p>A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mental_model"><strong>mental model</strong></a> is an explanation of someone’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thought" title="Thought">thought</a> process about how something works in the real world. It is a representation of the surrounding world, the relationships between its various parts and a person’s intuitive perception about his or her own acts and their consequences. Mental models can help shape <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behaviour" title="Behaviour">behaviour</a> and set an approach to solving problems (similar to a personal <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm" title="Algorithm">algorithm</a>) and doing tasks.</p></blockquote><p>Here’s a helpful video from <a href="https://www.fs.blog/mental-models/">Farnam Street</a> explaining mental models (and giving an idea of how they’re usually appropriated these days for decision making and personal development):</p>
<iframe allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/177585900?dnt=1&app_id=122963" title="Farnam Street: Mental Models" width="750"></iframe>
<h2 id="examples-of-mental-models">Examples of mental models</h2>
<p>For example, <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/">the 80/20 Principle</a> (20% of causes lead to 80% of effects) and the <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/prioritize-life-5-minutes-introduction-eisenhower-decision-matrix/">Eisenhower Decision Matrix</a> (organizing things by importance and urgency to prioritize decisions) could both be considered mental models.</p>
<p>Another famous mental model is <a href="https://www.fs.blog/2017/05/mental-model-occams-razor/">Occam’s Razor</a>, the idea that the simplest hypothesis is preferable.</p>
<p>One of my personal favorite mental models is <a href="https://www.fs.blog/2017/04/mental-model-hanlons-razor/">Hanlon’s Razor</a>, the idea that one should “never attribute to malice that which can be adequately explained by neglect.”</p>
<h2 id="mental-models-are-trueuseful-but-also-limited">*Mental models are TRUE/USEFUL, but also LIMITED*</h2>
<p>This is, perhaps, the most important thing about mental models.</p>
<p>On the one hand, a mental model needs to be true and useful. It needs to accurately describe at least one thing about how the world works.</p>
<p>However, on the other hand, a mental model is LIMITED. No single model can accurately account for the way the entire world works!</p>
<p>So, instead of clinging to one mental model and acting like it’s somehow comprehensive, you’re much better off developing a “toolbox” or a “latticework” (to borrow Charlie Munger’s phrase) of mental models.</p>
<h1 id="examples-of-theological-mental-models">Examples of theological mental models</h1>
<p>Theology is filled with statements and theories that, I think, work a lot like mental models. They are designed to accurately describe some aspect of theological reality. And yet, they are also limited. No single model/statement can account for everything about the person and work of the Triune God.</p>
<p>For one thing, many of the <a href="http://amzn.to/2F1gkgu">central themes of biblical theology</a> [affiliate link] could be considered analogous to mental models.</p>
<ul>
<li>Covenants</li>
<li>Divine Commands</li>
<li>Atonement</li>
<li>Servant of the Lord</li>
<li>Day of the Lord</li>
<li>People of God</li>
<li>History of Redemption</li>
</ul>
<p>Atonement theories also tend to work much like mental models:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ransom_theory_of_atonement">Ransom Theory</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christus_Victor">Christus Victor</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satisfaction_theory_of_atonement">Satisfaction Theory</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moral_influence_theory_of_atonement">Moral Influence Theory</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Also, consider the following Trinitarian theological mental models:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://zondervanacademic.com/blog/common-places-pro-nicene-theology-inseparable-operations/">Inseparable Operations</a>: how the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit relate to each other</li>
<li>“<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Rahner#Economic_and_immanent_Trinity">Rahner’s Rule</a>“: “the economic Trinity is the immanent Trinity, and the immanent Trinity is the economic Trinity”</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="4-reasons-why-mental-models-might-be-useful-for-theology">4 Reasons why mental models might be useful for theology</h1>
<p><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Again, here’s my idea: Mental models could provide a helpful model for theology. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Why? </span></p>
<h2 id="1-mental-models-could-help-keep-theologians-humble">1. Mental Models could help keep theologians humble</h2>
<p>Remember, mental models are true, but also limited. Such is also the case, I would argue, when it comes to theological claims.</p>
<p>When we make a claim about who God is or what God has done, we are, in effect, proposing a theological Mental Model.</p>
<p>If the model is worthwhile, then it will be true. And we can test its truthfulness on the basis of Scripture (and tradition, reason, and experience – in that order of significance).</p>
<p>However, no matter how worthwhile the model is, it will always be limited! It will never FULLY suffice to PERFECTLY describe the Truth with a capital T.</p>
<p>Therefore, we should remain humble both when (1) proposing or (2) critiquing theological Mental Models.</p>
<h2 id="2-mental-models-could-help-keep-theologians-creative">2. Mental models could help keep theologians creative.</h2>
<p>Because no single model can account for everything about the person and work of the Triune God, there is always more work to be done!</p>
<p>New models need to be proposed. Old models need to be critiqued, refined, and distilled.</p>
<p>This is why the theological conversation continues. We don’t just “arrive” at a list of correct theological positions. Instead, we delve deeper into the mysteries of God.</p>
<h2 id="3-mental-models-could-help-introduce-theology-to-others">3. Mental models could help introduce theology to others.</h2>
<p>Let’s be honest, theology can be quite confusing. One could easily wonder what all the theological fuss is about. Theologians have been arguing with each other for thousands of years. Why haven’t we figured everything out yet?</p>
<p>Thinking of and presenting theology in terms of a latticework of theological models might be a helpful way forward, because it helps to make it clear why the theological enterprise is ongoing. It could also help people to evaluate and adopt various theological statements/positions on their own.</p>
<h2 id="4-mental-models-could-help-us-talk-about-the-history-of-theology-and-the-church">4. Mental models could help us talk about the history of theology and the Church.</h2>
<p>This is, perhaps, a corollary of the previous point. The history of theology and the Church can be quite confusing. How are we supposed to keep track of all the different figures and theological statements?</p>
<p>Thinking of theology in terms of mental models might help to clarify the discussion a bit. This is already done in many areas of theology, especially when it comes to learning the different “theories” of the atonement.</p>
<p>I think, however, that there’s room to expand the use of theological models throughout all of the different doctrines and figures in the history of theology. For example, when teaching someone about Martin Luther, we could emphasize an important “model” that Luther “discovered” – <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_two_kinds_of_righteousness">the distinction between passive and active righteousness</a>.</p>
<p>I realize that this is already being done, but perhaps there’s room to make “theological mental models” (or “theological models”) more of a thoroughgoing model/framework for theology as a whole.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="what-do-you-think-are-mental-models-as-useful-for-theology-as-i-think-they-are">What do you think? Are mental models as useful for theology as I think they are?</h1>
<h2 id="let-me-know-in-the-comments-below">Let me know in the comments below!</h2>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
