<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Racism on Joshua P. Steele</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/racism/</link><description>Recent content in Racism on Joshua P. Steele</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 17:01:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/racism/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Help! I’m looking for the best Christian resources on the Bible, social justice, racism, Critical Race Theory, and Marxism</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 17:01:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</guid><description>&lt;p>Help me out. I’m looking for the best, clearest, and most charitable explanations of the following three things:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>the biblical and theological reasons for caring about social justice and systemic racism,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the unfair ways in which some have used accusations of Critical Race Theory (CRT) and Cultural Marxism to sideline legitimate Christian concerns about social justice and systemic racism, and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the legitimate Christian critiques of CRT and Marxism.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Now, I &lt;em>know&lt;/em> that there are plenty of resources out there that address each of the three items above!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who really cares about the Trinity in 2020?</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 13:02:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-in-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>(&lt;a href="https://friendsofthesavior.org/sermons/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-josh-steele/">To listen to the audio of this sermon as it was preached on June 6, 2020, click here.&lt;/a>)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Christians believe that there is one God in three persons—Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or, as my daughter Eva put it recently after seeing a picture in her book, “Father, Son, and Bird.” We’re working on that…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We Christians have been taught that the Trinity is important. No one wants to be a heretic. Trinity, good. Modalism, bad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top 3 Books, Movies, and Podcasts about Race for White Christians like Me</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-books-movies-and-podcasts-about-race-for-white-christians-like-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:02:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-books-movies-and-podcasts-about-race-for-white-christians-like-me/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are PLENTY of resource recommendations out there for those interested in learning more about racism and anti-racism (just Google “best X (books, movies, podcasts, etc.) on racism,” “antiracist reading list,” etc.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, I’m worried that, especially for people who are not used to working their way through lengthy reading lists, getting so many recommendations at once will lead to nothing due to the paradox of choice. I’d much rather recommend a single book that someone will actually read than 100 books they won’t!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Letter to Fellow ACNA Clergy: On Anti-Racism and a More Diverse and Just Anglicanism</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>NOTE&lt;/strong>: As is our policy with &lt;em>all&lt;/em> Anglican Compass content, we ask that you &lt;a href="https://anglicancompass.com/republishing-guidelines/">please submit a request before republishing content&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://adoc.church/a-letter-concerning-the-death-of-george-floyd-and-so-many-others/">&lt;em>recently wrote&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &lt;em>in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care. Whether you’re ACNA clergy, a layperson, or a Christian leader outside the ACNA, we invite your consideration of the following and your &lt;a href="#sign">signature&lt;/a> in support.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>