<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>bible-and-scripture on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/bible-and-scripture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bible-and-scripture on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/bible-and-scripture/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Brokenhearted God</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-brokenhearted-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-brokenhearted-god/</guid>
      <description>Not to take away from the undeniably biblical teaching that God is almighty, but sometimes I think we lose sight of God&amp;rsquo;s love for his image-bearers when we emphasize certain &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; portraits of God at the expense of (instead of alongside of) other &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; portraits found in Scripture. (I put &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; in quotes because perhaps our definitions of strength and weakness therefore need to change!)
It might make some of us uncomfortable to read about God portrayed as a jilted lover or a frustrated mother, but those portraits just might be desperately needed in a time when so many people turn away from God because they can&amp;rsquo;t understand how he can possibly be the good Lord of a world so broken and dying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Translation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-perfect-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 09:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-perfect-translation/</guid>
      <description>Over the break between semesters at Beeson Divinity School, I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing Bruce Waltke&amp;rsquo;s The Dance Between God and Humanity: Reading the Bible Today as the People of God and Philip Goodwin&amp;rsquo;s Translating the English Bible: From Relevance to Deconstruction for Liverpool Hope University&amp;rsquo;s Theological Book Review.
I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished the latter, and hope to write my review in the next day or two. However, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share the following quotes on Deconstructive Literalism and The Perfect Translation, because I find the concepts intriguing as a student of Eugene Nida&amp;rsquo;s dynamic or functional equivalence (when it comes to both NT Greek and modern Spanish), and a newcomer to relevance theory, which Goodwin uses to provide a way forward in the shadow of the KJV tradition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 2: Quare Fremuerunt Gentes? (Why Do the Nations Rage?)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/psalm-2-quare-fremuerunt-gentes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 22:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/psalm-2-quare-fremuerunt-gentes/</guid>
      <description>(Here&amp;rsquo;s my paper on Psalm 2, submitted to Dr. M. Sydney Park in partial fulfillment of my Biblical Interpretation course here at Beeson Divinity School. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t consider this the best thing I&amp;rsquo;ve ever written, I&amp;rsquo;d love for you to check this piece out and let me know what you think, because no matter the limitations of the assignment, there&amp;rsquo;s always room for improvement. Plus, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have space to talk about all the issues whirring around in my head while writing this paper, and your constructive feedback might very well help me take my next intellectual steps.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
