<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Prayer on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/prayer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prayer on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 23:15:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/prayer/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prayers for the Sick</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayers-for-the-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 23:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayers-for-the-sick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(The following prayers come from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcponline.org/PastoralOffices/ministration_to_the_sick.html&#34;&gt;the 1979 Book of Common Prayer&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prayers-for-the-sick&#34;&gt;Prayers for the Sick&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-a-sick-person&#34;&gt;For a Sick Person&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O Father of mercies and God of all comfort, our only help in time of need: We humbly beseech thee to behold, visit, and relieve thy sick servant &lt;em&gt;N.&lt;/em&gt; for whom our prayers are desired. Look upon &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; with the eyes of thy mercy; comfort &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; with a sense of thy goodness; preserve &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; from the temptations of the enemy; and give &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; patience under &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; affliction. In thy good time, restore &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; to health, and enable &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; to lead the residue of &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; life in thy fear, and to thy glory; and grant that finally he may dwell with thee in life everlasting; through Jesus Christ our Lord. &lt;em&gt;Amen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(The following prayers come from <a href="https://www.bcponline.org/PastoralOffices/ministration_to_the_sick.html">the 1979 Book of Common Prayer</a>.)</p>
<h2 id="prayers-for-the-sick">Prayers for the Sick</h2>
<h3 id="for-a-sick-person">For a Sick Person</h3>
<p>O Father of mercies and God of all comfort, our only help in time of need: We humbly beseech thee to behold, visit, and relieve thy sick servant <em>N.</em> for whom our prayers are desired. Look upon <em>him</em> with the eyes of thy mercy; comfort <em>him</em> with a sense of thy goodness; preserve <em>him</em> from the temptations of the enemy; and give <em>him</em> patience under <em>his</em> affliction. In thy good time, restore <em>him</em> to health, and enable <em>him</em> to lead the residue of <em>his</em> life in thy fear, and to thy glory; and grant that finally he may dwell with thee in life everlasting; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="for-recovery-from-sickness">For Recovery from Sickness</h3>
<p>O God, the strength of the weak and the comfort of sufferers: Mercifully accept our prayers, and grant to your servant <em>N.</em> the help of your power, that <em>his</em> sickness may be turned into health, and our sorrow into joy; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<p>or this</p>
<p>O God of heavenly powers, by the might of your command you drive away from our bodies all sickness and all infirmity: Be present in your goodness with your servant <em>N.</em>, that <em>his</em> weakness may be banished and <em>his</em> strength restored; and that, <em>his</em> health being renewed, <em>he</em> may bless your holy Name; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="for-a-sick-child">For a Sick Child</h3>
<p>Heavenly Father, watch with us over your child <em>N.</em>, and grant that <em>he</em> may be restored to that perfect health which it is yours alone to give; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<p>or this</p>
<p>Lord Jesus Christ, Good Shepherd of the sheep, you gather the lambs in your arms and carry them in your bosom: We commend to your loving care this child <em>N.</em> Relieve <em>his</em> pain, guard <em>him</em> from all danger, restore to <em>him</em> your gifts of gladness and strength, and raise <em>him</em> up to a life of service to you. Hear us, we pray, for you dear Name’s sake. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="before-an-operation">Before an Operation</h3>
<p>Almighty God our heavenly Father, graciously comfort your servant <em>N.</em> in <em>his</em> suffering, and bless the means made use of for his cure. Fill <em>his</em> heart with confidence that, though at times <em>he</em> may be afraid, <em>he</em> yet may put <em>his</em> trust in you; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<p>or this</p>
<p>Strengthen your servant <em>N.</em>, O God, to do what <em>he</em> has to do and bear what <em>he</em> has to bear; that, accepting your healing gifts through the skill of surgeons and nurses, <em>he</em> may be restored to usefulness in your world with a thankful heart; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="for-strength-and-confidence">For Strength and Confidence</h3>
<p>Heavenly Father, giver of life and health: Comfort and relieve your sick servant <em>N.</em>, and give your power of healing to those who minister to <em>his</em> needs, that <em>he</em> may be strengthened in <em>his</em> weakness and have confidence in your loving care; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="for-the-sanctification-of-illness">For the Sanctification of Illness</h3>
<p>Sanctify, O Lord, the sickness of your servant <em>N.</em>, that the sense of <em>his</em> weakness may add strength to <em>his</em> faith and seriousness to <em>his</em> repentance; and grant that <em>he</em> may live with you in everlasting life; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="for-health-of-body-and-soul">For Health of Body and Soul</h3>
<p>May God the Father bless you, God the Son heal you, God the Holy Spirit give you strength. May God the holy and undivided Trinity guard your body, save your soul, and bring you safely to his heavenly country; where he lives and reigns for ever and ever. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="for-doctors-and-nurses">For Doctors and Nurses</h3>
<p>Sanctify, O Lord, those whom you have called to the study and practice of the arts of healing, and to the prevention of disease and pain. Strengthen them by your life-giving Spirit, that by their ministries the health of the community may be promoted and your creation glorified; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="thanksgiving-for-a-beginning-of-recovery">Thanksgiving for a Beginning of Recovery</h3>
<p>O Lord, your compassions never fail and your mercies are new every morning: We give you thanks for giving our brother (sister) <em>N.</em> both relief from pain and hope of health renewed. Continue in <em>him</em>, we pray, the good work you have begun; that <em>he</em>, daily increasing in bodily strength, and rejoicing in your goodness, may so order <em>his</em> life and conduct that</p>
<p><em>he</em> may always think and do those things that please you; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h2 id="prayers-for-use-by-a-sick-person">Prayers for use by a Sick Person</h2>
<h3 id="for-trust-in-god">For Trust in God</h3>
<p>O God, the source of all health: So fill my heart with faith in your love, that with calm expectancy I may make room for your power to possess me, and gracefully accept your healing; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="in-pain">In Pain</h3>
<p>Lord Jesus Christ, by your patience in suffering you hallowed earthly pain and gave us the example of obedience to your Father’s will: Be near me in my time of weakness and pain; sustain me by your grace, that my strength and courage may not fail; heal me according to your will; and help me always to believe that what happens to me here is of little account if you hold me in eternal life, my Lord and my God. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="for-sleep">For Sleep</h3>
<p>O heavenly Father, you give your children sleep for the refreshing of soul and body: Grant me this gift, I pray; keep me in that perfect peace which you have promised to those whose minds are fixed on you; and give me such a sense of your presence, that in the hours of silence I may enjoy the blessed assurance of your love; through Jesus Christ our Lord. <em>Amen.</em></p>
<h3 id="in-the-morning">In the Morning</h3>
<p>This is another day, O Lord. I know not what it will bring forth, but make me ready, Lord, for whatever it may be. If I am to stand up, help me to stand bravely. If I am to sit still, help me to sit quietly. If I am to lie low, help me to do it patiently. And if I am to do nothing, let me do it gallantly. Make these words more than words, and give me the Spirit of Jesus. <em>Amen.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer for Trustfulness in Times of Worry and Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-for-trustfulness-in-times-of-worry-and-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 13:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-for-trustfulness-in-times-of-worry-and-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed this prayer this morning, and I plan to return to it often in the days ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most loving Father, you will us to give thanks for all things, to dread nothing but the loss of you, and to cast all our care on the One who cares for us. Preserve us from faithless fears and worldly anxieties, and grant that no clouds of this mortal life may hide from us the light of that love which is immortal, and which you have manifested unto us in your Son, Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I needed this prayer this morning, and I plan to return to it often in the days ahead.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Most loving Father, you will us to give thanks for all things, to dread nothing but the loss of you, and to cast all our care on the One who cares for us. Preserve us from faithless fears and worldly anxieties, and grant that no clouds of this mortal life may hide from us the light of that love which is immortal, and which you have manifested unto us in your Son, Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Occasional Prayer #80, Book of Common Prayer 2019. From <a href="https://www.dailyoffice2019.com/?setting_psalter=30&amp;setting_reading_cycle=1&amp;setting_reading_length=full&amp;setting_reading_audio=on&amp;setting_canticle_rotation=1979&amp;setting_theme=theme-dark&amp;setting_lectionary=mass-readings&amp;setting_confession=short&amp;setting_absolution=priest&amp;setting_morning_prayer_invitatory=invitatory_jubilate_on_feasts&amp;setting_reading_headings=off&amp;setting_language_style=traditional&amp;setting_national_holidays=all&amp;setting_suffrages=rotating&amp;setting_collects=rotating&amp;setting_pandemic_prayers=pandemic_yes&amp;setting_mp_great_litany=mp_litany_everyday&amp;setting_ep_great_litany=ep_litany_off&amp;setting_general_thanksgiving=on&amp;setting_chrysostom=on&amp;setting_grace=rotating&amp;setting_o_antiphons=literal">Morning Prayer this morning.)</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Collect for Juneteenth</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-collect-for-juneteenth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 03:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-collect-for-juneteenth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a “collect” prayer that I composed for Juneteenth in 2020. What’s a “collect” prayer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short form of prayer, constructed (with many varieties of detail) from (1) an invocation, (2) a petition, and (3) a pleading of Christ’s name or an ascription of glory to God; and one of the most characteristic items in the W[estern] liturgy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3xqwpK0&#34;&gt;The Oxford Dictionary of the Christian Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on Juneteenth, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://nmaahc.si.edu/explore/stories/historical-legacy-juneteenth&#34;&gt;“The Historical Legacy of Juneteenth” (National Museum of African American History and Culture)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The following is a “collect” prayer that I composed for Juneteenth in 2020. What’s a “collect” prayer?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The short form of prayer, constructed (with many varieties of detail) from (1) an invocation, (2) a petition, and (3) a pleading of Christ’s name or an ascription of glory to God; and one of the most characteristic items in the W[estern] liturgy.</p>
<p><cite>Source: <a href="https://amzn.to/3xqwpK0">The Oxford Dictionary of the Christian Church</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>For more on Juneteenth, see <a href="https://nmaahc.si.edu/explore/stories/historical-legacy-juneteenth">“The Historical Legacy of Juneteenth” (National Museum of African American History and Culture)</a>.</p>
<p>Here’s the prayer. Please feel free to use and share!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Almighty God, you rescued your people from slavery in Egypt, and throughout the ages you have never failed to hear the cries of the captives; We remember before you our sisters and brothers in Galveston, Texas who on this day received the glad tidings of their emancipation; Forgive us for the many grave sins that delayed that liberating word; Anoint us with your Spirit to bring good news to the poor, to proclaim release to the captives and recovery of sight to the blind, to let the oppressed go free, and to proclaim the year of your favor; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you, in the unity of the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever. Amen.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
