<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:24:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/technology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Online Scams: A Simple Guide for Non-Tech-Savvy Internet Users</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Online scams can touch anyone’s life. They don’t discriminate based on how tech-savvy you are or how often you use the internet. We’ve all heard stories—maybe from a friend, a family member, or even in the news—of someone getting tricked online, often with distressing consequences. It serves as a stark reminder of the darker side of our digital world.
This is why it’s crucial for every one of us to understand online scams—how they operate, how to identify them, and most importantly, how to avoid becoming a victim.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anything: Software Engineering Questions from a Coding Bootcamp Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 14:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</guid>
      <description>I’m posting my answers to these software engineering questions here, just in case anyone else finds them helpful! (Also, it gives me another link to share when I get asked these kinds of questions.)
How did you become interested in software engineering? I wrote a bit about my coding bootcamp journey in a previous post.
Part of my interest in software engineering is/was related to the particular path my journey took.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
