<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Acna on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/acna/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Acna on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 19:50:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/acna/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Resigning from Ordained Ministry in the Anglican Church in North America</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 19:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a considerable period of discernment, coupled with my growing disaffection with the Anglican Church in North America, I sense God calling me to step away from ordained ministry in the ACNA and instead to focus on my family and my career as a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also coincides with plans to move closer to family in NW Ohio (where there is not much of an ACNA presence to speak of) and to then pursue church involvement outside of the ACNA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a considerable period of discernment, coupled with my growing disaffection with the Anglican Church in North America, I sense God calling me to step away from ordained ministry in the ACNA and instead to focus on my family and my career as a software engineer.</p>
<p>This also coincides with plans to move closer to family in NW Ohio (where there is not much of an ACNA presence to speak of) and to then pursue church involvement outside of the ACNA.</p>
<p>Therefore, in accordance with Title III, Canon 6, Section 4 of the ACNA Canons (“Concerning Voluntary Resignation from the Ordained Ministry of this Church”), I have tendered my voluntary resignation from the ordained ministry of the Anglican Church in North America, effective on 2023-11-01.</p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
  <img src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/Joshua-Steele-ACNA-Resignation_2023-11-07.jpg" alt="A letter from Todd Hunter, Bishop Ordinary of The Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others, approving Joshua Steele's request to resign from ministerial duties in the ACNA.">
  <figcaption>A letter from Todd Hunter, Bishop Ordinary of The Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others, approving Joshua Steele's request to resign from ministerial duties in the ACNA.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As of 2023-11-07, my bishop and diocese have confirmed that I am a Presbyter in good standing, not under discipline as defined in Title IV of the ACNA Canons, and that my resignation is not occasioned by misconduct or irregularity, but is voluntary and for causes which do not affect my moral character.</p>
<p>My resignation has therefore been accepted. This means that I am released from the obligations of the Ministerial office. I relinquish the right to exercise the gifts and spiritual authority as a Minister of God’s Word and Sacraments in the Anglican Church in North America.</p>
<p>Lastly, I’d like to clarify that the ACNA Canons differentiate between (A) resigning from the ordained ministry of the ACNA and (B) renouncing one’s Holy Orders as such.</p>
<p>While I currently have no plans to pursue ordained ministry within another Christian denomination or jurisdiction, I am solely (A) resigning from the ordained ministry in the ACNA, not (B) renouncing my Holy Orders. This distinction leaves the door ajar for potential ordained ministry elsewhere, should the Lord call me back to such in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
