<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Romans on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/romans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Romans on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 15:21:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/romans/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Dispatch: 2019-08-09</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-08-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 15:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dissertation-dispatch-2019-08-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This summer, I’ve spent most of my reading/writing time working on a paper on Barth’s Römerbrief reading of Romans 10. This paper is for the 2019 Barth Graduate Student Colloquium, and it has taken &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; longer than I originally anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I get to use this paper in my dissertation? I’m not sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I got excited, because, in my work on Genesis 1–3 last school year, I discovered some differences in how Barth and Bonhoeffer handled Genesis 1–3 vis-a-vis the subsequent history of Israel. Namely, while &lt;em&gt;Barth&lt;/em&gt; takes care to work his way from Eden to the Church only after moving through the history of Israel and Jesus, &lt;em&gt;Bonhoeffer&lt;/em&gt; jumps right from Eden to the Church via Christ. This difference in what I’m provisionally calling “Christological immediacy”—which is perhaps a confessional one that parallels some of the exegetical differences between Calvin and Luther—has me wondering whether Barth and Bonhoeffer differed in important ways on Israel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Guilt of Karl Barth: Strengths and Weaknesses of Barth’s Römerbrief Reading of Romans 9:30–10:21</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-guilt-of-karl-barth-strengths-and-weaknesses-of-barths-romerbrief-reading-of-romans-9301021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 14:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-guilt-of-karl-barth-strengths-and-weaknesses-of-barths-romerbrief-reading-of-romans-9301021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: Here is the paper that I gave at the 2019 Karl Barth Graduate Student Colloquium at the Center for Barth Studies at Princeton Theological Seminary.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-gentiles--world-is-worse-than-israel--church&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION: “GENTILES” = “WORLD” IS WORSE THAN “ISRAEL” = “CHURCH”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On at least one level, Karl Barth’s Römerbrief reading of Romans 9–11 is supersessionist. In general, especially in the second edition, when Paul refers to “Israel” in Romans 9–11, Barth refers to the “Church.”&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#post-41871-footnote-1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; He replaces Israel with the Church. That’s supersessionism, case closed. Right? Well, yes and no. It has become increasingly common to at least mitigate or nuance the charge of supersessionism against Barth’s reading of Romans 9–11. Various scholars have broadly argued that, yes, Barth’s handling of Romans 9–11 at least leaves the door open for at least a certain kind of supersessionism, but, no, he wasn’t being quite as careless with Israel as it might initially seem.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#post-41871-footnote-2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; By and large, I agree with these assessments. Barth should have said more about the actual people and history of Israel, but he wasn’t trying to merely displace Israel with the Church, as if the latter were superior and the former were forgotten. He was trying to bring Israel and the Church together in solidarity, in opposition to the arrogance of the Church.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I think Karl Barth missed the (pastoral) point of Romans</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-think-karl-barth-missed-the-pastoral-point-of-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 15:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-think-karl-barth-missed-the-pastoral-point-of-romans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m scheduled to give a paper on Karl Barth’s reading of Romans 9:30–10:21 in &lt;em&gt;Der Römerbrief&lt;/em&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;2019 Barth Graduate Student Colloquium&lt;/a&gt; at Princeton in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, of course, it’s a pleasure and a privilege to give a paper at the colloquium. However, in hindsight, I don’t know why I thought giving a paper on chapter 10 of Barth’s Römerbrief was a good idea!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, I don’t have to solve all of the exegetical issues (of which there are many) in Romans 9:30–10:21. I just have to make some sense of what &lt;em&gt;Barth&lt;/em&gt; thought about the passage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
