<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>theology on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in theology on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 15:18:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/theology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the relationship between biblical and systematic/dogmatic theology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 15:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</guid>
      <description>This is the question we&amp;rsquo;re considering this week in our doctoral seminar on biblical and theological integration. Two of us are theologians and the other four are bible scholars. Should be interesting!
(Note: we&amp;rsquo;ll have to save the difference(s) between systematic, historical, and dogmatic theology for another post!)
Here are the articles we were assigned to read for this week:
D.A. Carson, “Systematic Theology and Biblical Theology” in the New Dictionary of Biblical Theology, pp.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Christian Theology: A Draft Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 22:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>As a part of my &amp;ldquo;pedagogical experience&amp;rdquo; at Wheaton College this semester, I was required to draft a syllabus for an introduction to Christian theology. Feel free to let me know what you think in the comments.
Note: the length of this syllabus doesn’t necessarily correspond to the difficulty of this course
Contact Information Email: [REDACTED] Phone: [REDACTED] Office Hours (Buswell Library Carrell): T, W, R, 15:00–17:00. Course Description This course is an introduction to the methods of systematic theology and the major topics within biblical revelation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Models: A Helpful Model for Theology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 15:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</guid>
      <description>This idea has been bouncing around in my head for a bit. It&amp;rsquo;s not fully-formed by any means, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to get it out there and hear what you think of it.
Here it is: &amp;ldquo;Mental Models&amp;rdquo; could be a helpful model for theology.
What is a &amp;ldquo;mental model&amp;rdquo;? Definition of mental models Put simply, a &amp;ldquo;mental model&amp;rdquo; is a concept used to help explain how the world works.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
