<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 16:09:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/tools/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Help, I&#39;m Addicted to Mini Toolkits: The EDC Tool Struggle Is Real</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/help-im-addicted-to-mini-toolkits-the-edc-tool-struggle-is-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 16:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/help-im-addicted-to-mini-toolkits-the-edc-tool-struggle-is-real/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what it is about mini toolkits, but I love them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, scratch that. I know why. It’s the same reason I love buying tools and books, more generally: the illusion of control. I like how having tools (and a great personal library) makes me feel like I’m ready for whatever life throws at me (ha!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s why I liked carrying around a pocketknife as a kid, and it’s why I’m into EDC (everyday carry) and tools as an adult.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don’t know what it is about mini toolkits, but I love them.</p>
<p>Actually, scratch that. I know why. It’s the same reason I love buying tools and books, more generally: the illusion of control. I like how having tools (and a great personal library) makes me feel like I’m ready for whatever life throws at me (ha!).</p>
<p>It’s why I liked carrying around a pocketknife as a kid, and it’s why I’m into EDC (everyday carry) and tools as an adult.</p>
<p>OK, but what about these “mini toolkits”?</p>
<p>It all started when I got the <a href="https://amzn.to/3XVS6fv">Sunex Tools 44-Piece 1/4″ Drive Mini Dual Flex Head Ratchet with Socket &amp; Bit Set (9732)</a>. I love the extra SAE/Metric flexibility from the spline sockets. And it’s got basically every bit I’ve needed.</p>
<p>Those spline sockets in the Sunex are actually why I ended up returning <a href="https://amzn.to/3XM6KG2">the extremely popular Wera Tool-Check Plus kit</a> after giving it a try. Sure, it’s definitely sexier and machined a bit better than the Sunex, but the Sunex sockets saved me at least once when the Wera failed me, so I really couldn’t justify keeping the (fairly expensive) Wera kit around.</p>
<p>Sure, I wish the Sunex kit had a better case, and could fit in my pocket, if needed…</p>
<p>So, enter what <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/harborfreight/">the r/HarborFreight subreddit</a> calls the “Meme Tool”: the <a href="https://www.harborfreight.com/locking-flex-head-ratchet-and-bit-set-35-piece-58074.html">ICON Locking Flex Head Ratchet and Bit Set, 35-Piece</a>. She’s a beauty. I love that the ratchet is a *locking* flex head. The extension can be used in multiple configurations to get at just about any fastener. And, again, basically every bit I’ve ever needed.</p>
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tyvhq65iJ8s?feature=oembed" title="ICON Locking Flex Head Ratchet And Bit Set, 35 Pc by Harbor Freight tools! NTDT!" width="750"></iframe></div></figure>What’s more, it’s got a no-hassle lifetime warranty, so if I happen to break something, I can go to the nearest Harbor Freight and get a new kit!
<p>I carry the Harbor Freight “Meme Tool” kit around with me most places, in addition to the Harbor Freight Leatherman Wave knockoff, the <a href="https://www.harborfreight.com/20-in-1-multi-tool-59617.html">GORDON 20-in-1 Multi-Tool</a>.</p>
<p>The only thing the Harbor Freight meme tool is missing is *sockets*! This is the one thing the Sunex kit wins-out on. I wish there were a way to combine the nice case, better ratchet, and useful extension from the HF Icon kit with he sockets of the Sunex kit.</p>
<p>Turns out, I’m not the only one who feels this way! Someone over at r/HarborFreight has <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/harborfreight/comments/1dhj1o8/i_present_to_you_hooligans_v2_the_icant/">designed a print-it-yourself case that can hold the original items from the Icon set plus sockets (they call it the ICAN’T, lol).</a></p>
<p>The only reason I haven’t bought <a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/jaahwnsstuff/?etsrc=sdt">one of those modified ICAN’T cases from the absolute genius on Etsy</a> is that, last year at the SEMA 2023 conference, Harbor Freight unveiled a new “Meme Tool + Sockets” and said that it would come out sometime in 2024!</p>
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5pr4fG5NzCo?start=585&feature=oembed" title="Unveiling all the NEW Harbor Freight Tools At SEMA 2023!" width="750"></iframe></div><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Start at 9:45 to see the Meme Tool w/Sockets</figcaption></figure>So, here we are. It’s mid-September and I’m checking r/HarborFreight and the Harbor Freight website daily to see if the new Meme Tool w/Sockets is out yet.
<p>And, while I wait for Harbor Freight to come through, I can’t help but notice other ratchet, bit, and socket combinations out there (like <a href="https://amzn.to/4d8MDWV">this one from P.I.T.</a>, or <a href="https://amzn.to/4epaaUC">this one from Bosch</a>)!</p>
<p>Yes, I probably have a problem. But does anyone else out there have the same problem? Have you found a mini toolkit that you absolutely love? What about other EDC tools? Please let me know in the comments below!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Improvement Roadmap and Roadblocks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home-improvement-roadmap-and-roadblocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 16:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home-improvement-roadmap-and-roadblocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We bought our first house in late 2023 and, since moving-in in January 2024, I’ve been chipping away at home improvement projects. Since I’m a software engineer and spend my day in front of a screen, I enjoy working with tools as a change of pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, some upcoming projects will clearly outstrip my capabilities and I plan to hire professionals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Replace roof and gutters&lt;br&gt;
– Replace furnace and central air conditioning&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We bought our first house in late 2023 and, since moving-in in January 2024, I’ve been chipping away at home improvement projects. Since I’m a software engineer and spend my day in front of a screen, I enjoy working with tools as a change of pace.</p>
<p>Now, some upcoming projects will clearly outstrip my capabilities and I plan to hire professionals:</p>
<p>– Replace roof and gutters<br>
– Replace furnace and central air conditioning</p>
<p>Other projects are probably beyond my capabilities, and I will most likely hire professionals. But, I still spend a fair bit of time thinking about doing them myself:</p>
<p>– Get/build a shed<br>
– Trim and/or take down tall oak trees (they’re quite tall and we’re in a residential neighborhood…if we lived out in the country, I’d totally try to do this myself!)<br>
– Install a handrail with columns on basement stairway (to prevent falling-off the stairs into the basement)</p>
<p>Other things I plan to do myself:</p>
<p>– Install water-powered backup sump pump (in progress!)<br>
– Clean gutters (which have really old and difficult-to-remove sheet metal “leaf guards” on them)<br>
– Fix oddly-wired light switches in bedrooms<br>
– Power-wash house, driveway, and sidewalk<br>
– Re-caulk exterior of house (ugh, really not looking forward to this…lots of scraping old caulk required!)<br>
– Install a new duct and register in main, finished basement room<br>
– Install new PVC drain pipes for kitchen sink and garbage disposal<br>
– Build my own garage workbench</p>
<p>I’ve got a bunch of hand and power tools already, but I’m running into a roadblock when it comes to obtaining and moving larger objects: I don’t have a truck!</p>
<p>This is currently preventing me from doing things like:</p>
<p>– Getting plywood and 2x4s for my workbench<br>
– Getting an extension ladder for cleaning out my gutters, trimming tree branches, etc.<br>
– Purchasing a used refrigerator for our garage<br>
– Purchasing a used table saw for our garage</p>
<p>Instead, we’ve got a 2007 Honda Civic sedan and a 2019 Kia Sedona minivan. Neither of which have roof bars or a towing hookup.</p>
<p>I’m debating installing a roof rack on one or both cars. I’m also considering purchasing a towing hookup for the minivan and getting a trailer from Harbor Freight.</p>
<p>Otherwise, I’m on the lookout for a good deal on a used truck!</p>
<p>Given the truck roadblock, I’m also trying to figure out the best order to tackle these projects in.</p>
<p>I think it makes sense to start with getting a shed, since that would clear out more space in my garage for a work bench.</p>
<p>After that, though, I’m not sure. But “figure out a way to be able to transport large things” is definitely floating around at the top of the mental list.</p>
<p>Any thoughts on how best to tackle some of these home improvement projects? Am I making too big of a deal about not having a truck, and should I just suck it up and either rent one or buy one? Let me know!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
