<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity-and-time-management on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/productivity-and-time-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity-and-time-management on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 19:41:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/productivity-and-time-management/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s the Template I Use to Take Notes on Books I Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 19:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</guid>
      <description>Developed from How to Read a Book, by Mortimer J. Adler.
BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA: Author(s):
Editor(s):
Translator(s):
Title and subtitle:
Title and subtitle of any larger work that contains the source:
Pages:
Volume:
Issue:
Edition:
URL and date accessed:
Publisher:
Place:
Date:
INTERPRETATION: Kind of Book (Practical or theoretical?):
Subject Matter:
Problems Attempted to Solve:
Summary (What is the book about as a whole?):
Outline of Source:
Key Terms:
Key Propositions/Arguments (What is being said in detail, and how?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Four Tendencies: 4 Ways You Can Play to Your Personality Strengths</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 18:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</guid>
      <description>In both my personal and coaching conversations recently, Gretchen Rubin&amp;rsquo;s personality framework called &amp;ldquo;The Four Tendencies&amp;rdquo; has really seemed to resonate with people.
So, I thought I would take a few minutes to share it with you.
Gretchen Rubin Explains the Four Tendencies First, here&amp;rsquo;s a six-minute video of Gretchen herself explaining the Four Tendencies and their relevance to changing one&amp;rsquo;s habits.
How do you respond to INNER EXPECTATIONS and OUTER EXPECTATIONS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hate Running? Try Rucking Instead</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 16:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</guid>
      <description>(DISCLAIMER: You are, of course, more than welcome to try rucking, even if you also love running.)
Rucking &amp;gt; Running It took me a long time to &amp;ldquo;fall in love&amp;rdquo; with running. It did not take me nearly as long to fall out of love with running!
And yet, even though I&amp;rsquo;ve long enjoyed doing kettlebell swings and doing the 5x5 weight-lifing workout, I did begin to miss the benefits of cardio training.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do More Better: Tim Challies&#39; Excellent Little Book on Personal Productivity Could Change Your Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</guid>
      <description>Tim Challies begins his book, Do More Better: A Practical Guide to Productivity with a bold claim: &amp;ldquo;I believe this book can improve your life.&amp;rdquo;
However, after reading the book, which is just 120 pages long including endnotes!, I believe that Challies makes good on his claim.
As far as explicitly Christian approaches to personal productivity go, Challies’ Do More Better stands alongside Matt Perman’s What’s Best Next: How the Gospel Transforms the Way You Get Things Done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting back on the &#34;Getting Things Done&#34; Productivity Bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 22:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>Getting Things Done (&amp;ldquo;GTD&amp;rdquo; for short) is a wildly popular personal productivity system invented and popularized by David Allen. However, as Nicole Dieker at Lifehacker pointed out in 2017, &amp;ldquo;You don’t hear a lot of people talk about the Getting Things Done productivity system anymore.&amp;rdquo;
I think that&amp;rsquo;s a shame, because it&amp;rsquo;s a very effective system.
I first tried Getting Things Done after reading &amp;quot; What&amp;rsquo;s Best Nex t&amp;quot; by Matt Perman, and then reading &amp;quot; Getting Things Done&amp;quot; by David Allen (in its newly revised 2015 edition) shortly thereafter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go to Sleep and Have Some Kids: What the Bible (Psalm 127) Says about Productivity</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 12:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Personal Productivity in Psalm 127 I love Psalm 127. Not because it makes me feel great, necessarily, but because it hits me like a ton of bricks whenever I read it (like I did last night, during evening prayer).
Here&amp;rsquo;s how the Psalm opens:
Unless the Lord builds the house,the builders labor in vain.Unless the Lord watches over the city,the guards stand watch in vain.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy for me to think that my success or lack thereof completely depends on me and the intensity of my efforts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Pray Before You Read and Write: A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 09:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</guid>
      <description>I want to share with you the following prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study, based on Oratio S. Thomae Aquinatis ante studium, which Thomas Aquinas would pray before studying, writing, or preaching.
We prayed it responsively before class (Patristic and Medieval History and Doctrine) with Dr. Piotr Malysz at Beeson Divinity School, and I’ve since turned back to this prayer often!
A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study O God, Creator of all that is, From the treasures of Your wisdom, You have arrayed the universe with marvelous order, And now govern with skill and might.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Books Every Christian Should Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 03:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</guid>
      <description>OK, OK. I get it. Claiming that every Christian should read these 5 books is a bold claim.
But, honestly, I think that these reading recommendations stand up to the scrutiny.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been wracking my brain trying to come up with just the top 5 books that a busy Christian should read if she wants to learn the essentials about:
Productivity and Time Management Bible Study Theology And, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve arrived at a pretty good shortlist if I do say so myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An 80/20 Approach to the Christian Life: 2 Reasons Why Christians Should Care About the Pareto Principle</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 12:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to live a more meaningful and purposeful Christian life, but you feel like it&amp;rsquo;s hard enough just to get everything done on your to-do list each day?
I&amp;rsquo;m right there with you! That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve made &amp;quot; Get Your Act Together (Productivity and Time Management)&amp;quot; the first of my Steps to Find Purpose and Meaning in Life.
Thankfully, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve found something that can help. I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce you to the &amp;quot; Pareto Principle,&amp;quot; also known as &amp;quot; the 80/20 Rule,&amp;quot; the &amp;ldquo;law of the vital few,&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;principle of factor sparsity,&amp;rdquo; if you want to get all technical about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principles: 10 Imperatives for the Good Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 16:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</guid>
      <description>Why write out a list of principles?
For one thing, it&amp;rsquo;s my birthday. And, although I&amp;rsquo;m only in my twenties, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a bit reflective.
For another, I&amp;rsquo;ve just been given a copy of Principles: Life and Work by Ray Dalio (affiliate link).
According to Dalio (ix),
Principles are fundamental truths that serve as the foundations for behavior that gets you what you want out of life. They can be aplied again and again in similar situations to help you achieve your goals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts You Should Listen To</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 15:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts: An Introduction Although podcasts (think &amp;ldquo;iPod&amp;rdquo; + &amp;ldquo;broadcast&amp;rdquo;) have been around for over a decade, we&amp;rsquo;re living in a bit of a golden age - or a least a Rennaissance - of the medium. For the uninitiated, here&amp;rsquo;s a nice video about what podcasts are:
Currently, podcasts are one of my very favorite ways to consume information about a wide variety of topics. Sure, gun to my head, I&amp;rsquo;ll choose books over podcasts as a way to learn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is The Well-Equipped Christian Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 23:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had a problem finding a reliable resource for recommendations?
I have.
Certain Google searches are a piece of cake, but the &amp;ldquo;best resources for ______&amp;rdquo; ones can be hit-or-miss.
And don&amp;rsquo;t even get me started on the decision fatigue. As a serial over-thinker, I start to hate myself a little bit after reading through the upteenth list of &amp;ldquo;5 Best ____s.&amp;rdquo; It makes it so hard to make a decision!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Ridiculously Helpful Markdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 14:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been dragging my heels on learning Markdown for awhile now.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know, Markdown is:
lightweight markup language with plain text formatting syntax designed so that it can be converted to HTML and many other formats using a tool by the same name.[8] Markdown is often used to format readme files, for writing messages in online discussion forums, and to create rich text using a plain text editor. [Source: Wikipedia]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Want To Be Remembered?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</guid>
      <description>Do you know what the worst thing about death is?
It&amp;rsquo;s not the dying itself - its the separation.
That is, we don&amp;rsquo;t suffer the most from our own deaths (a one-time occurrence), but from suffering the deaths of others (repeatedly). Instead of living relationships, we are left with distant memories.
A sad reality, to be sure.
What if, however, we could use death to our own advantage? I&amp;rsquo;m convinced this is the truth behind Ecclesiastes 7:2 -</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Take Seth Godin to Church</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not going to lie. My first reaction when I saw the cover of this book? No! Of course you&amp;rsquo;re not indispensable. What use could this crap possibly be to the Church, or to me - simultaneously a pastor and a pastor-in-training. Then, however, I read the book. And I suggest you do, too!
(Note: affiliate link. I get paid if you make a purchase.) Seth Godin, bald marketing extraordinaire, is convinced that a paradigm shift has taken place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are you afraid of?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 20:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m scared. Are you?
Specifically, as I wrote in my journal this very morning:
I&amp;rsquo;m scared - I&amp;rsquo;m scared of wasting my life, I&amp;rsquo;m scared of not being worth anything outside of the classroom.
Fear drives so many aspects of our lives - from how we dress, to how we raise our children, to how we elect our leaders. And, if we&amp;rsquo;re honest with ourselves, fear can play a large role in what/whom we worship.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kettlebell Swings: Back Balm for the Sedentary [Seminarian]</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 23:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</guid>
      <description>I love books. Books, however, do not like my back.
Can you relate?
Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not sitting around reading books all day, but I imagine plenty of you out there suffer from back pain/fatigue.
Let me share a time-saving solution I&amp;rsquo;ve recently found: two-handed kettlebell swings.
How can these cannonballs with handles help your back?
Well, the kettlebell swing is one of the many exercises out there that activates your posterior chain - the muscles along the back of your body.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
