<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Christian Life on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/the-christian-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Christian Life on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:03:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/the-christian-life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Christianity and Politics: My 2024 Reading List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/christianity-and-politics-my-2024-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/christianity-and-politics-my-2024-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Church and State, particularly the intersection of Christianity and politics, has been on my mind since I first started paying attention during the lead-up to the 2008 USA presidential election. Back then, I was just a high school student, but these themes have stuck with me ever since.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(For those curious, here’s a quick timeline: In 2012, I was studying biblical studies in college. By 2016, I was a seminarian, and in 2020, I was working on my Ph.D. in theology. Now, in 2024, I’m a software engineer! Yet political theology continues to weigh on my mind.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prayers for the Sick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/prayers-for-the-sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 23:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/prayers-for-the-sick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(The following prayers come from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcponline.org/PastoralOffices/ministration_to_the_sick.html&#34;&gt;the 1979 Book of Common Prayer&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-rank-math-toc-block&#34; id=&#34;rank-math-toc&#34;&gt;## Contents&#xA;&lt;nav&gt;- [Prayers for the Sick](#prayers-for-the-sick)&#xA;    - [For a Sick Person](#for-a-sick-person)&#xA;    - [For Recovery from Sickness](#for-recovery-from-sickness)&#xA;    - [For a Sick Child](#for-a-sick-child)&#xA;    - [Before an Operation](#before-an-operation)&#xA;    - [For Strength and Confidence](#for-strength-and-confidence)&#xA;    - [For the Sanctification of Illness](#for-the-sanctification-of-illness)&#xA;    - [For Health of Body and Soul](#for-health-of-body-and-soul)&#xA;    - [For Doctors and Nurses](#for-doctors-and-nurses)&#xA;    - [Thanksgiving for a Beginning of Recovery](#thanksgiving-for-a-beginning-of-recovery)&#xA;- [Prayers for use by a Sick Person](#prayers-for-use-by-a-sick-person)&#xA;    - [For Trust in God](#for-trust-in-god)&#xA;    - [In Pain](#in-pain)&#xA;    - [For Sleep](#for-sleep)&#xA;    - [In the Morning](#in-the-morning)&#xA;&lt;/nav&gt;&lt;/div&gt;---&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prayers-for-the-sick&#34;&gt;Prayers for the Sick&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-a-sick-person&#34;&gt;For a Sick Person&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O Father of mercies and God of all comfort, our only help in time of need: We humbly beseech thee to behold, visit, and relieve thy sick servant &lt;em&gt;N.&lt;/em&gt; for whom our prayers are desired. Look upon &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; with the eyes of thy mercy; comfort &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; with a sense of thy goodness; preserve &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; from the temptations of the enemy; and give &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; patience under &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; affliction. In thy good time, restore &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; to health, and enable &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; to lead the residue of &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; life in thy fear, and to thy glory; and grant that finally he may dwell with thee in life everlasting; through Jesus Christ our Lord. &lt;em&gt;Amen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logos 10 Bible Software: The Ultimate Theological Learning Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 13:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: If you’re serious about biblical and theological studies, you should invest in Logos 10 Bible Software. &lt;a href=&#34;https://partners.faithlife.com/click.track?CID=431490&amp;amp;AFID=529204&#34;&gt;Do so via my exclusive partner offer for Logos 10 here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I could go back in time and chat with Joshua Steele when he was a Bible &amp;amp; Spanish major in college, there are a few things I’d tell my younger self:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quit laughing at &lt;em&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/em&gt; by Mortimer J. Adler and READ the thing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baba ghanoush is superior to hummus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study computer science sooner rather than later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bite the bullet and INVEST IN A LOGOS BIBLE SOFTWARE LIBRARY.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong. I love physical books as much as anyone, and I own quite a few (hundred)!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help! I’m looking for the best Christian resources on the Bible, social justice, racism, Critical Race Theory, and Marxism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 17:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Help me out. I’m looking for the best, clearest, and most charitable explanations of the following three things:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the biblical and theological reasons for caring about social justice and systemic racism,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the unfair ways in which some have used accusations of Critical Race Theory (CRT) and Cultural Marxism to sideline legitimate Christian concerns about social justice and systemic racism, and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the legitimate Christian critiques of CRT and Marxism.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that there are plenty of resources out there that address each of the three items above!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Collect for Juneteenth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/a-collect-for-juneteenth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 03:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/a-collect-for-juneteenth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a “collect” prayer that I composed for Juneteenth in 2020. What’s a “collect” prayer?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The short form of prayer, constructed (with many varieties of detail) from (1) an invocation, (2) a petition, and (3) a pleading of Christ’s name or an ascription of glory to God; and one of the most characteristic items in the W[estern] liturgy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3xqwpK0&#34;&gt;The Oxford Dictionary of the Christian Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more on Juneteenth, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://nmaahc.si.edu/explore/stories/historical-legacy-juneteenth&#34;&gt;“The Historical Legacy of Juneteenth” (National Museum of African American History and Culture)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Books, Movies, and Podcasts about Race for White Christians like Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-3-books-movies-and-podcasts-about-race-for-white-christians-like-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-3-books-movies-and-podcasts-about-race-for-white-christians-like-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are PLENTY of resource recommendations out there for those interested in learning more about racism and anti-racism (just Google “best X (books, movies, podcasts, etc.) on racism,” “antiracist reading list,” etc.).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I’m worried that, especially for people who are not used to working their way through lengthy reading lists, getting so many recommendations at once will lead to nothing due to the paradox of choice. I’d much rather recommend a single book that someone will actually read than 100 books they won’t!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“But, What About the Riots and Lawlessness?”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/but-what-about-the-riots-and-lawlessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 21:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/but-what-about-the-riots-and-lawlessness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I commend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.christianitytoday.com/edstetzer/2020/june/race-in-america-interview-with-esau-mccaulley-part-one.html&#34;&gt;the entire interview series that Ed Stetzer recently did with Esau McCaulley&lt;/a&gt;. Among many highlights, I appreciate McCaulley’s following answer to the question of negotiating the differences between protests and riots. Again, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.christianitytoday.com/edstetzer/2020/june/racism-in-america-interview-with-esau-mccaulley-part-four.html&#34;&gt;read the whole interview&lt;/a&gt; and series, but here’s a key section related to concern about rioting and lawlessness:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Ed Stetzer] We both agree: Protests are good. Riots are not. Unpack that for us from your context.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Esau: There is a cycle of what happens. There’s a racial incident. African Americans protest. Some of those protests from people inside and outside the community turn violent. People say, “Hey, look at this. Why aren’t the Christians who are speaking out against the racial injustice equally strong speaking about the riots?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is the word “systemic” a flashpoint for certain Christians?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/why-is-the-word-systemic-a-flashpoint-for-certain-christians/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 20:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/why-is-the-word-systemic-a-flashpoint-for-certain-christians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Certainly, the Bible has much to say about &lt;em&gt;individual&lt;/em&gt; sin and redemption. But (1) focusing on “systemic” issues doesn’t need to negate a focus on “individual” issues. In fact, a focus on “systemic racism” actually exerts a lot of pressure to evaluate people individually, and not on the basis of their race—as long as we keep in mind how those supposedly individual evaluations are often subtly (and nefariously) shaped by systemic issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Prayers for Tough Days</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/12-prayers-for-tough-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 21:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/12-prayers-for-tough-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The “Occasional Prayers” section of the Book of Common Prayer is a goldmine, particularly when the going gets tough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following prayers come from &lt;a href=&#34;http://bcp2019.anglicanchurch.net/&#34;&gt;the Anglican Church in North America’s 2019 Book of Common Prayer&lt;/a&gt;. You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://bcp2019.anglicanchurch.net/index.php/downloads/&#34;&gt;view the text of the 2019 BCP here&lt;/a&gt;. And you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/56-Occasional-Prayers.docx&#34;&gt;download a Word document containing all of the Occasional Prayers here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;58-for-a-person-in-trouble-or-bereavement&#34;&gt;58. FOR A PERSON IN TROUBLE OR BEREAVEMENT&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O merciful Father, you have taught us in your holy Word that you do not willingly afflict or grieve the children of men: Look with pity on the sorrows of your servant &lt;em&gt;N&lt;/em&gt;. Remember &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt;, O Lord, in mercy; nourish &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; soul with patience; comfort &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; with a sense of your goodness; lift up your countenance upon &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt;; and give &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; peace; through Jesus Christ our Lord.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damer’s “Code of Intellectual Conduct”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/damers-code-of-intellectual-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 15:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/damers-code-of-intellectual-conduct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This code of conduct very much relates to &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/help-me-come-up-with-rules-for-conversation/&#34;&gt;Rapoport’s Rules, Adler’s advice&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/alan-jacobss-the-thinking-persons-checklist/&#34;&gt;Alan Jacobs’s “The Thinking Person’s Checklist.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOURCE: T. Edward Damer, &lt;em&gt;Attacking Faulty Reasoning: A Practical Guide to Fallacy-Free Arguments&lt;/em&gt;, 6th ed (Australia ; Belmont, CA: Wadsworth/Cengage Learning, 2009), 7–8.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-embed-amazon-kindle wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-amazon&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-embed__wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;550&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?preview=inline&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;ref_=k4w_oembed_V9rDc1WZVbDCiH&amp;asin=1133049982&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&#34; style=&#34;max-width:100%&#34; title=&#34;Attacking Faulty Reasoning&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;750&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;## 1. The Fallibility Principle &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each participant in a discussion of a disputed issue should be willing to accept the fact that he or she is &lt;strong&gt;fallible&lt;/strong&gt;, which means that &lt;strong&gt;one must acknowledge that one’s own initial view may not be the most defensible position on the question&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alan Jacobs’s “The Thinking Person’s Checklist”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/alan-jacobss-the-thinking-persons-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/alan-jacobss-the-thinking-persons-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following checklist, found on pages 155–56 of Alan Jacobs’s excellent book, &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/33TtBRv&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Think: A Survival Guide for a World at Odds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link), is a worthy addition to “Rapoport’s Rules” and “Adler’s Advice” (mentioned in my previous post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/help-me-come-up-with-rules-for-conversation/&#34;&gt;“Help me come up with ‘rules for conversation’!”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-embed-amazon-kindle wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-amazon&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-embed__wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;550&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://read.amazon.com/kp/card?preview=inline&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;ref_=k4w_oembed_Eii2WAqN2ej4WE&amp;asin=0451499603&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&#34; style=&#34;max-width:100%&#34; title=&#34;How to Think: A Survival Guide for a World at Odds&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;750&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;Emphasis added in **bold**.&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When faced with provocation to respond to what someone has said, give it five minutes&lt;/strong&gt;. Take a walk, or weed the garden, or chop some vegetables. Get your body involved: your body knows the rhythms to live by, and if your mind falls into your body’s rhythm, you’ll have a better chance of thinking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value learning over debating&lt;/strong&gt;. Don’t “talk for victory.”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As best you can, online and off, &lt;strong&gt;avoid the people who fan flames&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remember that &lt;strong&gt;you don’t have to respond to what everyone else is responding to in order to signal your virtue and right-mindedness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have to respond to what everyone else is responding to&lt;/strong&gt; in order to signal your virtue and right-mindedness, or else lose your status in your community, then you should realize that &lt;strong&gt;it’s not a community but rather an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lewissociety.org/innerring/&#34;&gt;Inner Ring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gravitate&lt;/strong&gt; as best you can, in every way you can, &lt;strong&gt;toward people who seem to value genuine community and can handle disagreement with equanimity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seek out the best and fairest-minded of people whose views you disagree with.&lt;/strong&gt; Listen to them for a time without responding. Whatever they say, &lt;em&gt;think it over&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Patiently, and as honestly as you can, &lt;strong&gt;assess your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/repugnance&#34;&gt;repugnances&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sometimes &lt;strong&gt;the “ick factor”&lt;/strong&gt; is telling; sometimes it’s a distraction from what matters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beware of &lt;strong&gt;metaphors&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;myths&lt;/strong&gt; that do too much heavy cognitive lifting; notice what your &lt;strong&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terministic_screen&#34;&gt;terministic screens&lt;/a&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt; [See pages 90–91] are directing your attention to-and what they’re directing your attention &lt;em&gt;away from&lt;/em&gt;; look closely for hidden metaphors and beware the power of myth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Try to &lt;strong&gt;describe others’ positions in the language that &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; use, without indulging in in-other-wordsing.&lt;/strong&gt; [See pg. 106: “We see it every day. Someone points at an argument—a blog post, say, or an op-ed column—and someone else replies, ‘In other words, you’re saying … ‘ And inevitably the argument, when put &lt;em&gt;in other words&lt;/em&gt;, is revealed to be vacuous or wicked.]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be &lt;strong&gt;brave&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me come up with “rules for conversation”!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/help-me-come-up-with-rules-for-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 20:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/help-me-come-up-with-rules-for-conversation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my role as Managing Editor for AnglicanPastor.com, I’m realizing the need to develop some “rules for conversation.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We describe the tone that we’re after as “clarity and charity,” which is an excellent summary. However, to guide our blogposts and comments, I think we need something more detailed and concrete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, “Rapoport’s Rules” and “Adler’s Advice” seem like excellent starting points.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But, if you have any further suggestions, please let me know in the comments!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two of Bonhoeffer&#39;s Most Convicting Paragraphs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/two-of-bonhoeffers-most-convicting-paragraphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/two-of-bonhoeffers-most-convicting-paragraphs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is from Bonhoeffer’s &lt;em&gt;Discipleship&lt;/em&gt; (usually known as “The Cost of Discipleship” in English, although the original title in German was simply &lt;em&gt;Nachfolge&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bonhoeffer considers how we might respond to Jesus if Jesus were to show up and make the same kinds of concrete commands that he did in the Gospels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: I’ve taken two paragraphs in the original and broken them up into smaller chunks to facilitate reading here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s learn how to be bored again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lets-learn-how-to-be-bored-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 17:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lets-learn-how-to-be-bored-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://imagejournal.org/article/in-praise-of-boredom/&#34;&gt;“In Praise of Boredom,” by James K.A. Smith&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But I know at least this: Instagram won’t save us, and tweeted verse will not undo what we’ve done to ourselves. But neither is there any special enchantment to reading in print. So this is not the Luddite’s redoubt, nostalgically canonizing codex or canvas as if history had come to an end in some glorious past. Every medium now reaches us inside the ecology of attention masterminded by Silicon Valley. We take pictures of our books and coffee, for heaven’s sake. The point isn’t platform but desire: what do we want when we pick up our phones? We don’t need better media, or to romanticize old media. We need to change what we want.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Rapoport&#39;s Rules for Better Conversations and Disagreements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 17:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading Walter Sinnott-Armstrong’s excellent book, &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2BNTlTq&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Think Again: How to Reason and Argue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In it (on pages 25–26), I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Rapoport%27s_Rules&#34;&gt;“Rapoport’s Rules.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First formulated by mathematical psychologist Anatol Rapoport and discussed by Daniel Dennett (&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2NmrH4m&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 31–35), here they are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1: You should attempt to re-express your target’s position so clearly, vividly, and fairly that your target says, “Thanks, I wish I’d thought of putting it that way.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer of Confession</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/a-prayer-of-confession/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 20:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/a-prayer-of-confession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To start off the semester the other day, we prayed this prayer of confession together as a class. The professor didn’t remember where the prayer was from, so &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thegospelcoalition.org/blogs/justin-taylor/a-corporate-confession-of-faith-based-on-the-ten-commandments-and-the-sermon-on-the-mount/&#34;&gt;I tracked it down online. According to Justin Taylor, it was written by Bob Kauflin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy and righteous God, we confess that like Isaiah, we are a people of unclean lips. But it is not only unclean lips we possess. We are people with unclean hands and unclean hearts. We have broken your law times without number, and are guilty of pride, unbelief, self-centeredness and idolatry. Affect our hearts with the severity of our sin and the glory of your righteousness as we now acknowledge our sins in your holy presence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Attracts People to Anglicanism? Here&#39;s My Take</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 21:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based upon my work over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/&#34;&gt;Rookie Anglican&lt;/a&gt;, I was asked by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teloscollective.com/&#34;&gt;The Telos Collective&lt;/a&gt; to write a blog post about the different ways that people are coming into Anglicanism. What’s drawing them in?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teloscollective.com/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-subversive-cultural-resonance/&#34;&gt;read my full post over at the Telos Collective blog&lt;/a&gt;, but here’s a taste:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anglican Christianity, precisely because of its weirdness, can remind us that, in the words of Brad Harper and Paul Louis Metzger in Exploring Ecclesiology, “The church is a cultural community. It is Christ’s eschatological kingdom community, itself a culture that engages other cultures from Christ’s kingdom vantage point” (p. 207).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/&#34;&gt;I catalogued a bunch of different takes on Jordan Peterson, before giving my own take&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since that post, two other pieces about Jordan Peterson have been written that I’d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;jordan-peterson-custodian-of-the-patriarchy-by-nellie-bowles-new-york-times&#34;&gt;“Jordan Peterson, Custodian of the Patriarchy,” by Nellie Bowles (New York Times)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/18/style/jordan-peterson-12-rules-for-life.html&#34;&gt;Nellie Bowles writes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peterson, 55, a University of Toronto psychology professor turned YouTube philosopher turned mystical father figure, has emerged as an influential thought leader. The messages he delivers range from hoary self-help empowerment talk (clean your room, stand up straight) to the more retrograde and political (a society run as a patriarchy makes sense and stems mostly from men’s competence; the notion of white privilege is a farce). He is the stately looking, pedigreed voice for a group of culture warriors who are working diligently to undermine mainstream and liberal efforts to promote equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Grain of the Gospel: Why Christians Should Care about Food Ethics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-grain-of-the-gospel-why-christians-should-care-about-food-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 06:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-grain-of-the-gospel-why-christians-should-care-about-food-ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following is a guest post written by my friend and former college roommate, &lt;strong&gt;Zak Weston&lt;/strong&gt;. Zak’s been working in the area of food ethics, and I asked him to write up a post about why Christians should care about these issues. It’s an area in which I need to make some changes in my own life. He delivered this thought-provoking and challenging piece. I hope you enjoy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;span-stylefont-weight-400introductionspan&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;The three or so decisions you make each day about what to eat are some of the most consequential choices you make in your life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to make of Jordan Peterson? Some takes, then my own.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: Read my post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/&#34;&gt;“Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I remember correctly, I first heard of and listened to Jordan Peterson on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2017/08/31/podcast-335-using-power-myths-live-flourishing-life/&#34;&gt;an episode of The Art of Manliness podcast&lt;/a&gt;. (Or perhaps it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/06/12-rules-for-life-jordan-peterson-interview/&#34;&gt;this episode&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;however-i-could-be-mistaken-because-petersons-been-popping-up-in-conversation-all-over-the-place-in-my-circles&#34;&gt;However, I could be mistaken, because Peterson’s been popping up in conversation all over the place in my circles.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blog posts, podcast episodes, conversations with friends – Peterson has been popping up everywhere, so it seems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Please Don&#39;t Leave Me Alone: On Male Friendships, or the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 18:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe you, like me, consider yourself quite the introvert. Maybe you, like me, have a difficult time walking the tightrope between feeling quickly overwhelmed by interpersonal relationships, on the one hand, and feeling incredibly lonely, on the other hand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe you, like me, feel these problems acutely as a male (although I’m sure that females are having their own relational struggles as our culture increasingly pressures us all to be “alone together,” looking at our screens instead of looking each other in the eye).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christian, Do the Daily Office: 5 Things You Can Learn from Morning and Evening Prayer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/christian-daily-office-5-things-can-learn-morning-evening-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/christian-daily-office-5-things-can-learn-morning-evening-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-problem-we-all-need-to-grow-but-were-not-sure-how&#34;&gt;The Problem: We All Need to Grow, But We’re Not Sure How&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;lets-face-it-to-say-the-very-least-we-christians-all-have-room-to-grow-when-it-comes-to-following-jesus&#34;&gt;Let’s face it: to say the very least, we Christians all have room to grow when it comes to following Jesus.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;None of us has “arrived.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s always more to learn about who God is, what God has done, and how we can join God’s mission to set the world right again. And, even if we know a bunch about those things in the previous sentence, we surely don’t always live based on that knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Reasons Why I&#39;m an Anglican Christian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 05:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/RA-Logo-Black-Transparent-Background-200x167.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why am I an Anglican Christian? Here are 3 reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-anglicanism-as-a-refuge-from-fundamentalism&#34;&gt;1. Anglicanism as a Refuge from Fundamentalism&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, for me, Anglicanism has been a refuge from fundamentalism. Now, to be sure, we do have our own fundamentalists within the Anglican Communion! But, compared to some “ingrown enclaves” I’ve experienced in my Christian upbringing, Anglicanism has been a breath of fresh air. It has been an ecclesiological space for healing as I seek to “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patheos.com/blogs/rogereolson/2012/08/on-not-throwing-the-baby-out-with-the-bathwater-a-message-for-abused-ex-fundamentalists/&#34;&gt;not throw the (gospel) baby out with the (fundamentalist) bathwater&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cut the &#34;Positivity&#34; Crap: What Frustrates You?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 17:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep this short, sweet, and to the point: &lt;strong&gt;I’m looking for problems that I can help solve, so I need you to rant at me in the comments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s right, I basically want you to complain to me in the comments section of this post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What’s causing you frustration, angst, or stress these days?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What questions are you struggling to find the answers to?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What obstacles are in the way of you achieving your goals?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s MY problem/frustration: &lt;strong&gt;I don’t know what problems are causing YOU the most friction!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christians and Wealth: An Argument for Downward Mobility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/christians-and-wealth-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 01:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/christians-and-wealth-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! If you only have a minute to read about wealth, here’s my argument in a nutshell:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-my-argument&#34;&gt;Outline of My Argument&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Claim: American Christians should reduce their standards of living to what is necessary for human flourishing and give their excess resources beyond this standard to the poor and oppressed.&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God is the firmest advocate for human flourishing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The pursuit of wealth is spiritually dangerous and crippling.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our culture’s inclinations toward upward financial mobility go against the message of the New Testament and the life of Christ.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God is revealed in Scripture to have a special concern for the poor and the oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians will be held accountable for how they treat the poor and the oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Objections:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This line of reasoning is advocating asceticism and is unbiblical.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians have every right to keep what they have earned and to do what they wish with their excess funds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Because the poor are lazy, Christians should not feel pressured to give, in case their generosity is taken advantage of.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Warrant:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians want to remain true to Scripture and submit to God’s way of life in order to find satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(For more on Christianity, wealth, and poverty, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2011/02/10/20110210proverbs-topical-study-poverty/&#34;&gt;my topical study on what the book of Proverbs has to teach us about poverty&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Give Thanks!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/give-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/give-thanks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not the most thankful person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I am a follower of Jesus, and one of the lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning this semester is that &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;praise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thanksgiving&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, and &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gratitude&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt; are closely intertwined. Worship should involve the public proclamation of who God is and what He has done — including specific, personal declarations of thanksgiving for God&amp;rsquo;s grace and good gifts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If, like me, you have a hard time cultivating this worshipful practice of gratitude, then allow me to suggest the following prayers from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bcponline.org/&#34;&gt;Book of Common Prayer&lt;/a&gt; to help get us started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 2014 Regional ETS Paper: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 09:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, here’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/steele-southeast-ets-2014-paper-final-presesntation-edit.pdf&#34;&gt;the latest version of the Regional ETS paper&lt;/a&gt; I will present today at 5:00pm at Beeson Divinity School, room S009.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re able to attend the presentation, that’s great! If not, feel free to give &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/steele-southeast-ets-2014-paper-final-presesntation-edit.pdf&#34;&gt;my paper&lt;/a&gt; a read and get back to me with any questions, comments, or suggestions. Atonement theology and the unity of the Church are two things about which I am very passionate, and intend to devote further study to these areas in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Regional ETS Presentation: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 15:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.beesondivinity.com/assets/1346/11_cs070900557.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;If you’re in the Birmingham area from March 21-22, 2014, and you’re interested in evangelical theology, please consider attending the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.beesondivinity.com/ets&#34;&gt;Evangelical Theological Society’s Southeastern Regional Meeting at Beeson Divinity School&lt;/a&gt;! This year’s theme is “the theological interpretation of Scripture,” and the plenary speaker is Wheaton’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wheaton.edu/Academics/Faculty/T/Daniel-Treier&#34;&gt;Daniel J. Treier&lt;/a&gt; (incidentally, Dr. Treier and I are both alumni of Cedarville…go figure).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, if you’re free from 5:00-5:30pm on Friday, March 21, consider swinging by room S009 to hear me present &lt;strong&gt;“Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof: Atonement, Ecclesiology, and the Unity of God.”&lt;/strong&gt; The atonement and the unity of the Church are topics that I’m passionate about, and I’m extremely grateful for the opportunity to give my first ever conference paper. Here’s the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Epistle to Philemon: Analysis and Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-epistle-to-philemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-epistle-to-philemon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt;As the briefest member of the Pauline corpus, the epistle to Philemon is a letter of recommendation for the sake of reconciliation in which the apostle Paul brings the gospel truth of mutual participation in the body of Christ to bear on an estranged relationship – making a delicate request of his friend Philemon to receive back a certain Onesimus into full fellowship as a brother in Christ.&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Users/Joshua/Google%20Drive/Beeson/1%20Fall%202013/Biblical%20Interp/Papers/JoshuaSteeleEpistle.docx#_ftn1&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Friday Book Recommendation: The Economy of Desire</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/black-friday-book-recommendation-the-economy-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 16:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/black-friday-book-recommendation-the-economy-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Black Friday proves that the progress of (post)modernity has failed to eradicate the ills of idolatry. Lest we denizens of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_Human_Development_Index&#34;&gt;“highly-developed” world &lt;/a&gt;think that we have left the primitive vestiges of wood, rock, and gold idolatry behind, our shopping patterns (and indeed our shopping identities as consumers) should remind us of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/blogs-trending-25153350&#34;&gt;our consumerism’s dark side&lt;/a&gt; — a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blackfridaydeathcount.com/&#34;&gt;lethal one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I’ve put in &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/&#34;&gt;“Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof”:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Although physical idols may not be as universally common today as they once were, invisible idols are as prevalent as ever, especially within the context of Western materialism, where money, possessions, influence, and power are the modern-day &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baal&#34;&gt;Baal&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silence and Violence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/silence-and-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 18:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/silence-and-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://malcolmguite.wordpress.com/2013/11/06/silence-a-sonnet-for-remembrance-day-3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://malcolmguite.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/p1050316silent-cross.jpg?w=500&amp;amp;h=646&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Violence is not human destiny because the God of peace is the beginning and the end of human history…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Granted, pushing the stone of peace up the steep hill of violence … is hard. It is easier, however, than carrying one’s own cross in the footsteps of the crucified Messiah. This is what Jesus Christ asks Christians to do. Assured of God’s justice and undergirded by God’s presence, they are to break the cycle of violence by refusing to be caught in the automatism of revenge.”&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Exclusion-Embrace-Theological-Exploration-Reconciliation/dp/0687002826&#34;&gt;Volf, E&amp;amp;E, 306&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down With the Pacifists!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/down-with-the-pacifists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 20:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/down-with-the-pacifists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week has been a great one for slipshod attacks on pacifism. First, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firstthings.com/&#34;&gt;First Things&lt;/a&gt; (Stephen H. Webb) on October 15 —- &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.firstthings.com/onthesquare/2013/10/john-howard-yoder-and-the-violent-power-of-pacifism&#34;&gt;“John Howard Yoder and the Violent Power of Pacifism”&lt;/a&gt; (emphasis added below):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Nevertheless, pacifists, at least the ones I know, can be very enthusiastic about the rightness of their cause. Since &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;there is no rational justification for pacifism&lt;/span&gt;, defenders typically turn their rhetoric against their critics by casting them as stooges of the status quo. Since pacifists are against all forms of violence, anyone who disagrees with them must be in favor of violence. What this ploy misses is obvious. In a fallen world, not only is violence pervasive but it is also a toxin that, when legitimately used, can cure as well as kill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scripture: What The Bible Is And Why It Matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/on-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 13:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/on-scripture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-stylecolor-000000introduction-the-nature-of-scripturespan&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION: THE NATURE OF SCRIPTURE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt;As the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Illocutionary_act&#34;&gt;illocutionary act&lt;/a&gt; which testifies to the Son of God&lt;a href=&#34;#sdfootnote1sym&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as the ultimate redemptive and revelatory &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Locutionary_act&#34;&gt;locution&lt;/a&gt; of the the triune God, Scripture is used by the Spirit of God to accomplish the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perlocutionary_act&#34;&gt;perlocutionary end&lt;/a&gt; of redemption &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;through&lt;/em&gt; the people of God.&lt;a href=&#34;#sdfootnote2sym&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Ahem, in order to understand my first paragraph, you must first be familiar with the basics of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speech_act&#34;&gt;Speech Act Theory&lt;/a&gt;. If you’ve never heard of it before, click that link, and then come back here. It will be worth it, I promise!]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>King Jesus&#39; Kingdom Gospel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 13:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I highly encourage the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Read Scot McKnight’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-King-Jesus-Gospel-Revisited/dp/031049298X&#34;&gt;The King Jesus Gospel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. Check out Tim Gombis’ insightful series of posts on &lt;a href=&#34;http://timgombis.com/2013/09/16/the-gospel-of-the-kingdom/&#34;&gt;The Gospel of the Kingdom&lt;/a&gt;, pt. &lt;a href=&#34;http://timgombis.com/2013/09/16/the-gospel-of-the-kingdom/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://timgombis.com/2013/09/17/the-gospel-of-the-kingdom-pt-2/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://timgombis.com/2013/09/18/the-gospel-of-the-kingdom-pt-3/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gombis hits the nail on the head here:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the last several months, I’ve had several conversations about how the Gospels’ language about “the gospel” should shape how Christians conceive of the gospel. Whereas the New Testament mainly envisions a broader announcement of a larger reality, many evangelicals associate “the gospel” with a brief presentation, or information about the mechanics of an individual transaction that can secure divine forgiveness and the establishment of a personal relationship with God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inductive Bible Study in 7 Steps: &#34;Scripture, Handle With Care,&#34; by Amy Chase Ashley</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/inductive-bible-study-7-steps-amy-chase-ashley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/inductive-bible-study-7-steps-amy-chase-ashley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;address&gt;Update (April 2017): I’ve gone back to update/clean-up the formatting in this wonderful June 2013 guest post on the basics of inductive Bible study from my friend **Amy Elizabeth Chase Ashley,** one of the most gifted students of Scripture with whom I’ve been privileged to study. She blogs at &lt;https://amyechase.wordpress.com/&gt;. &lt;/address&gt;---&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;jeremiah-2911&#34;&gt;Jeremiah 29:11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I accepted the invitation to speak at my parents’ church, I immediately started thinking about what message I would deliver. I decided to give a message on something that is very important to me after my four years at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cedarville.edu/&#34;&gt;Cedarville&lt;/a&gt; and something I am very passionate about. I hope it will be &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;engaging&lt;/span&gt;; I hope it will &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;make you think&lt;/span&gt;; and I hope it will &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;bring glory to God&lt;/span&gt;. If I can accomplish those three things, I will be satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Interpreting the Bible: Deuteronomy 6:1-15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/deuteronomy-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 20:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/deuteronomy-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;deuteronomy-61-15-nrsv&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy 6:1-15 (NRSV)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Deut-6-1&#34;&gt;Now this is the commandment—the statutes and the ordinances—that the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God charged me to teach you to observe in the land that you are about to cross into and occupy, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Deut-6-2&#34; id=&#34;en-NRSV-5089&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;versenum&#34;&gt;2 &lt;/sup&gt;so that you and your children and your children’s children may fear the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God all the days of your life, and keep all his decrees and his commandments that I am commanding you, so that your days may be long. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Deut-6-3&#34; id=&#34;en-NRSV-5090&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;versenum&#34;&gt;3 &lt;/sup&gt;Hear therefore, O Israel, and observe them diligently, so that it may go well with you, and so that you may multiply greatly in a land flowing with milk and honey, as the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the God of your ancestors, has promised you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Reading Romans 13 Wrong! Here&#39;s How to Read It Correctly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/romans-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 07:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/romans-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study of Romans 13 rests upon a crucial presupposition: without context, words can mean anything and everything, and therefore mean nothing. It is only through the delimiting influence of context that words, phrases, sentences, and paragraphs are endowed with significance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although this concept seems simple and justified enough, it is often forgotten within the field of biblical exegesis. Due to influences as simple as our versification of the biblical text and as complex as the historical/theological developments which have dictated how we teach and interpret the Scriptures, many exegetes (wittingly or unwittingly) ignore context when trying to ascertain the meaning of particular biblical texts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Romans, Distilled and Paraphrased</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/romans-distilled-paraphrased/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 14:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/romans-distilled-paraphrased/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following is an attempt, written in 2012, to distill and paraphrase the main argument/message/story/logic of St. Paul’s Epistle to the Romans.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;romans-11-17&#34;&gt;Romans 1:1-17&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you don’t catch anything else from what I’m about to say, remember this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God is righteous. He is just. He is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God has proven himself faithful to his promises of restoring the world, working through his faithful Son, the Messiah, to bring about both our faith in and our faithfulness to him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 19:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The more I study the New Testament, I become more convinced that the unity of the Church is of utmost importance to God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What bothers me is that this has never been taught to me before. All of the things I’ve learned (specifically in my studies on Philippians, Galatians, and now Romans) about the importance of unity for the sake of the Gospel mission and the Kingdom of God have come as somewhat of a shock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Good News of Christmas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-good-news-of-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 13:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-good-news-of-christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031049298X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=faithinirelan-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399373&amp;amp;creativeASIN=031049298X&#34;&gt;The King Jesus Gospel: The Original Good News Revisited&lt;/a&gt; by Scot McKnight, who makes the claim that the gospel is the saving story of Jesus as Messiah, King, and Lord as the completion to the story of Israel, I started to notice some profound gospel messages in the Christmas carols we often sing during this season.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have found that several of these carols go much deeper (much more biblical) than the personal salvation “gospel” of sin-management that we often preach and sing about. What’s tragic is that, even though these carols are quite possibly the best-known Christian songs, their familiarity (and the fact that we only break them out for 1/12th of the year), makes it quite easy to ignore their substance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Church and State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/church_and_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 12:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/church_and_state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Note: for a more recent piece on the relationship between Church and State, see my essay: “&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2015/12/08/improvising-church-state/&#34;&gt;Improvising Church and State&lt;/a&gt;.”)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I just read an article by Kevin DeYoung at The Gospel Coalition: &lt;a href=&#34;http://thegospelcoalition.org/blogs/kevindeyoung/2011/05/26/thinking-theologically-about-memorial-day/?comments#comments&#34;&gt;“Thinking Theologically About Memorial Day”&lt;/a&gt;. Listen to his intro:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post probably has something to make everyone unhappy. But here goes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Memorial Day on Monday (in the U.S.) and, no doubt, a number of patriotic services scheduled for this Sunday, I want to offer a few theses on patriotism and the church. Each of these points could be substantially expanded and beg more detailed defense and explanation, but since this is a blog and not a term paper, I’ll try to keep this under 1500 words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Bible Says About Poverty: The Book of Proverbs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bible-poverty-proverbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 23:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bible-poverty-proverbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-poverty-and-wealth&#34;&gt;Introduction: Poverty and Wealth&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In contrast to the affluence of mainstream American culture, poverty is a harsh and painful reality. It can be found in abundance in the urban centers of this country, and in countless other places around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern day slavery “more cruel than any beast of prey” (Wright 2005, 136), it traps human beings created in the image of God in a lifestyle of hunger, sickness, anger, and darkness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
