<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Engineering on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/software-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Engineering on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 12:50:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/software-engineering/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discover Learn X in Y Minutes: An Invaluable Resource for Programmers</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/discover-learn-x-in-y-minutes-an-invaluable-resource-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 12:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/discover-learn-x-in-y-minutes-an-invaluable-resource-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a programmer or someone aspiring to be one, you’re always on the lookout for valuable resources to help you learn new languages and tools. Today, I’m excited to introduce you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://learnxinyminutes.com/&#34;&gt;learnxinyminutes.com&lt;/a&gt;, a must-visit website for anyone interested in coding. This site offers concise, code-focused tutorials for dozens of programming languages and essential tools, making it a perfect learning companion for beginners and experienced coders alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-and-efficient-learning&#34;&gt;Quick and Efficient Learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn X in Y Minutes understands that time is precious, which is why it provides:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Linux: Top Commands Every New Computer Programmer Should Learn</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mastering-linux-top-commands-every-new-computer-programmer-should-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 17:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mastering-linux-top-commands-every-new-computer-programmer-should-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you new to the world of computer programming? If so, learning &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; commands is an essential step in your journey. Linux is a powerful and versatile operating system used by developers across various fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we’ll cover the most important Linux commands that every new computer programmer should learn to level up their skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Want to learn even more about Linux? Check out &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3mRKdY5&#34;&gt;Linux Pocket Guide: Essential Commands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3ZSntpL&#34;&gt;The Linux Command Line: A Complete Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anything: Software Engineering Questions from a Coding Bootcamp Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 14:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m posting my answers to these software engineering questions here, just in case anyone else finds them helpful! (Also, it gives me another link to share when I get asked these kinds of questions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-you-become-interested-in-software-engineering&#34;&gt;How did you become interested in software engineering?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a bit about &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/&#34;&gt;my coding bootcamp journey&lt;/a&gt; in a previous post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my interest in software engineering is/was related to the particular path my journey took. That is, while studying Bible/religion/theology, I always knew that “bi-vocational ministry” (ministering in a church setting while also making money from another profession) was on the table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
