<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Anglican Compass on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/anglican-compass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anglican Compass on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 08:40:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/anglican-compass/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a Female Priest and I Support My Opponents in the Women&#39;s Ordination Debate</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/im-a-female-priest-and-i-support-my-opponents-in-the-womens-ordination-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 06:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/im-a-female-priest-and-i-support-my-opponents-in-the-womens-ordination-debate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is not unanimous agreement about women’s ordination in the worldwide Anglican Communion. Godly and thoughtful Christians hold opposing convictions about Holy Orders and who is called to ordained ministry. You often see the results of this debate at the Provincial level—a national expression of the Church may or may not ordain women, in accordance with their conviction. But for the Anglican Church in North America this disagreement is internal to the Province, varying from diocese to diocese and bishop to bishop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is not unanimous agreement about women’s ordination in the worldwide Anglican Communion. Godly and thoughtful Christians hold opposing convictions about Holy Orders and who is called to ordained ministry. You often see the results of this debate at the Provincial level—a national expression of the Church may or may not ordain women, in accordance with their conviction. But for the Anglican Church in North America this disagreement is internal to the Province, varying from diocese to diocese and bishop to bishop.</p>
<p>This makes the ACNA a complicated place to be ordained, especially as a woman. However, I also believe that this diversity of conviction and practice is a strength of our denomination.</p>
<h2 id="unity-in-diversity">Unity in Diversity</h2>
<p>Since the inception of the ACNA, the College of Bishops has embraced a “dual integrities” approach to the ordination of women.</p>
<ul>
<li>Some bishops ordain women as priests and commission them as church planters.</li>
<li>Some bishops only ordain women as deacons.</li>
<li>Some bishops do not ordain women but will license a woman to serve in a particular church that requests it.</li>
<li>Some bishops do not receive women in Holy Orders at all.</li>
</ul>
<p>The specifics of which ACNA dioceses do/don’t ordain women can be found <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QG0EDrpgGnfPf668T5qsnUcczUA_g6b3HjgbPC-aiTg/edit#gid=0">here</a>.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://anglicanchurch.net/about/#1582571780228-6ce9e506-048c">stated on the ACNA website</a>:</p>
<p>“<strong>Q. What is the ACNA’s position on women’s ordination?</strong></p>
<p>“A. At the inception of the Anglican Church in North America, the lead Bishops unanimously agreed to work together for the good of the Kingdom. As part of this consensus, it was understood that there were differing understandings regarding the ordination of women to Holy Orders, but there existed a mutual love and respect for one another and a desire to move forward for the good of the Church. This commitment was deeply embedded in the Constitution and Canons overwhelmingly adopted by the Inaugural Assembly (2009).</p>
<p>“In respect of the two integrities concerning Holy Orders, three matters were specifically agreed in Constitution and Canons:</p>
<ol>
<li>The Province shall make no canon abridging the authority of any member dioceses, clusters or networks (whether regional or affinity-based) and those dioceses banded together as jurisdictions with respect to its practice regarding the ordination of women to the diaconate or presbyterate (Constitution, Article VIII)</li>
<li>Except as hereinafter provided, the norms for ordination shall be determined by the Bishops having jurisdiction. (Title III Canon 1.4)</li>
<li>To be a suitable candidate for the episcopate (bishops), a person must: Be a male Presbyter at least 35 years old. (Title III Canon 8.3.7)”</li>
</ol>
<p>In other words, our bishops have agreed to disagree, honoring a diversity of convictions about ministry and mission. This is a model of Christian charity for all of us, a unity that does not demand unanimous agreement on every issue.</p>
<p>When my husband and I were first exploring the Anglican tradition, this unity in diversity attracted us. We were weary of the perpetual divisions characterized by theological hairsplitting and defensiveness. It seemed that, in an effort to defend doctrinal purity, many Protestant churches kept getting smaller and smaller by separating from those who disagreed with them on this or that issue.</p>
<p>Anglicanism, on the other hand, describes a willingness to hold together a lot of diversity within the bounds of Christian orthodoxy. Some Anglicans around the world are extremely charismatic; others more evangelical; others more sacramental. Some are very Reformed in their theology, others more Arminian. This felt like a breath of fresh air to us, and an opportunity to acknowledge that the Church—the global, historic body of Christ—is actually quite large and diverse. The Church includes people who disagree with me, and I am grateful to share Table fellowship with them.</p>
<p>Unity does not have to mean absolute unanimity on secondary issues and practices. I realize that some would consider women’s ordination a primary issue. But since the bishops in the ACNA have agreed to allow differences of opinion on this issue within the Province, it remains a secondary issue in practice.</p>
<h2 id="this-is-not-to-say-that-anything-goes">This is not to say that “anything goes”</h2>
<p>As canon theologian Esau McCaulley <a href="https://esaumccaulley.com/2020/01/26/come-let-us-read-together-a-hopefully-warm-invitation-to-think-the-best-of-each-other-in-the-womens-ordination-discussion/?fbclid=IwAR2Aafb_9UCW8j0W-F-DTzH-p2BvWfmszuPIQp0Yx6zLgjklU8u7cGFzkcs">noted</a>, there are certainly boundaries around what constitutes “tolerable” disagreement in the Church. This is precisely why the historic ecumenical creeds came into being, and this is why our bishops gather to have difficult conversations about questions of orthodoxy today. Therefore we can follow their example by practicing gracious respect for conscience within those parameters.</p>
<h2 id="bearing-with-one-another-in-love">Bearing with one another in love</h2>
<p>The dual integrities model gives us an opportunity to practice this graciousness. It provides the opportunity to “walk…with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another in love, eager to maintain the unity of the Spirit in the bond of peace” as the apostle Paul encourages us to do (Eph. 4:1–3).</p>
<p>I recently saw this happen at a diocesan gathering where members of a task-force who represented a variety of perspectives on women’s ordination presented together on ways all of our churches can encourage and strengthen the ministry of women in their midst. In addition to a unified presentation, they shared stories of how they had personally grown in respect for each other and become true friends through the process, despite their differences of opinion. As I heard them speak, I felt grateful to be part of a church that creates space for this kind of connection to happen.</p>
<p>This practice of “bearing with one another” is not only good for the Church. It is also good for the world. We live in a society that is characterized by polarization and ultimatums. “If you don’t agree with me,” we are told, “you can’t have fellowship with me.” Often this goes much further: “If you don’t agree with me, you don’t deserve to exist.” In light of this, Christians who can live peaceably together—even with significant disagreements—can be a powerful apologetic to the broader culture.</p>
<h2 id="laying-down-our-lives">Laying down our lives</h2>
<p>I don’t mean to imply that this is easy to do. With significant disagreement often comes significant pain. I know women who experience real discouragement and frustration, ranging from challenges finding a job (or even a discernment committee) to the inability to exercise their ordained ministry in their diocese. I also know men and women who feel uncomfortable bringing their children to Communion when a woman is celebrating the Eucharist.</p>
<p>And of course, the disagreement does not cleanly fall along gendered lines, or even diocesan or parish lines. The dual integrity approach is not exactly comfortable for anyone. However, my own faith has been strengthened as I’ve witnessed people on both sides steward these challenges with humility and grace.</p>
<p>And for those of us in Holy Orders, this personal discomfort can connect us even more deeply to the meaning of our vows. We promise to “share in the humility and service of our Lord Jesus Christ” who “humbled himself, becoming obedient even to death on a Cross.”</p>
<p>During their ordination service, ordinands traditionally lie prostrate—in the shape of a Cross—before the Bishop. This gesture has layers of meaning and is sometimes exchanged for kneeling (which—full disclosure—I had to do as I was ordained while eight months pregnant!). But the significance is the same: those in Holy Orders make vows of servanthood and self-sacrifice. And in the ACNA, we all get to practice humility and self-sacrifice when it comes to our disagreements over women’s ordination.</p>
<p>Would it be easier if we all agreed? Absolutely. Is agreement a worthy goal to work toward? Sure. But until then—if that day ever comes—there is also great value in learning to live together with differences. Some of my dearest friends are people who love Jesus, preach the gospel, and disagree with my ordination. They have made me a better Christian; and, I hope, a more thoughtful, sensitive priest. Our togetherness is complex, but it is a gift nonetheless.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For the Good of the Order: A Plea for Charity on the Ordination of Women</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/for-the-good-of-the-order-a-plea-for-charity-on-the-ordination-of-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 06:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/for-the-good-of-the-order-a-plea-for-charity-on-the-ordination-of-women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost every vocational deacon I know, when asked why he or she has not become a priest, will respond, “I have never felt called to the priesthood.” Some will add emphatically, “not for a minute!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not one of those deacons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t share this story often, rarely in its fullness, and never in public non-anonymous writing. Be gentle with my soul, O Church. The words which follow are all too raw.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Almost every vocational deacon I know, when asked why he or she has not become a priest, will respond, “I have never felt called to the priesthood.” Some will add emphatically, “not for a minute!”</p>
<p>I am not one of those deacons.</p>
<p>I don’t share this story often, rarely in its fullness, and never in public non-anonymous writing. Be gentle with my soul, O Church. The words which follow are all too raw.</p>
<h2 id="baby-steps">Baby steps.</h2>
<p>I first felt called to the priesthood before I claimed the word “priest.” It was a fleeting moment in the middle school mind, and easily abandoned. Children try on shoes, and my wandering attention during a dull class did take a bit of a look at the shoes labeled “minister” but set them aside as having too much to do with funerals. As a college freshman, it was the word “priest” that came and caught me in a lonely hallway, one afternoon. I presented it to friends as a joke, before it settled in on me during the weeks that followed as a very serious reality.</p>
<p>I read everything I could get my hands on. I was not yet confirmed as an Anglican, let alone having a theology of the priesthood, even less as a woman. I read the autobiographies of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philadelphia_Eleven">the Philadelphia Eleven (the eleven women ordained to the priesthood irregularly and as an act of defiance in 1974)</a>, and anything else on women priests I could get my hands on. I kept a journal, and I prayed. I took all the right steps, and when the rector of my church “back home” asked me out of the blue what I felt God was leading me to do with my life, I swallowed hard and told him what was on my heart. His response was, “Well the first thing we need to do is get you confirmed.” And yes, I was confirmed, by the Episcopal Bishop of Iowa, and my bishop back home in East Tennessee was very receptive to considering a young woman with a liberal undergraduate background in religion for discernment for ordination.</p>
<p>I look back on that sometimes and think of what could have been. If I had kept my mouth shut, nodded at all the right affirmations, and kept my feet on the path that had been neatly placed before me. It would have been an easy thing to just keep moving forward, to find myself twenty years later as a priest in the Episcopal Church.</p>
<p>Instead of following the path before me, I veered from it. At a friend’s suggestion, I chose a seminary unsanctioned by the bishop of East Tennessee. I had a baby during my first year of seminary and began to question my priorities. I felt pigeon-holed into forms of ministry I never envisioned. In the end, I walked away from the ordination process entirely for a couple of years.</p>
<h2 id="vocations-dont-leave-us-alone">Vocations don’t leave us alone.</h2>
<p>Eventually, presented with a strong model of the vocational diaconate in my parish (by then in the Diocese of Pittsburgh) I again swallowed hard and shared my sense of vocation with the woman who would become my “mother in the diaconate.” I knew as soon as I did, it would again be out of my hands. This time, I submitted to the process; I let it unfold as it willed. I was ordained a deacon in June of 2004.</p>
<p>I would like to say that since then my call to the priesthood has gone away, but it has not. Most of the time, it lies dormant, but it has its triggers. Some have been intentionally put in my path by well-intended priests, occasionally even those in authority over me. Some I have simply had to stumble upon by chance, or in a more self-indulgent moment have sought out and examined anew.</p>
<h2 id="so-why-am-i-not-a-priest-in-a-diocese-which-would-happily-ordain-a-woman-priest">So why am I not a priest in a diocese which would happily ordain a woman priest?</h2>
<p>In short, the cost is just too high. I simply do not have the right to pursue my individual sense of calling at the cost of the unity of the Church.</p>
<p>Those who might consider themselves my cheerleaders, encouragers who accept the priestly ordination of women have as much as exhorted me, from time to time, that the place of women within the church was hard won, and perhaps I am betraying the sacrifices of others to step away from the path they have blazed. Yet they have blazed that path in rebellion, all the while taking vows of submission to authority and to the Tradition of the Church. Somehow, in the span of my lifetime, we have come, unwittingly, to rest significant aspects of our theology of Holy Orders, as they relate to women, on a secular idea of equal rights. To be clear, no one has a right to ordination, whether a man or a woman; ordination is quite the opposite, a setting aside of one’s personal rights for the sake of the whole Church. We follow a Lord who did not consider his own equality with God a thing to be grasped, but humbled himself to death on a Cross. And yet, we are conditioned to grasp and cling to our rights. It is the modern, Western way.</p>
<p>In practical terms, as a woman deacon I can go anywhere (or close to it) from women clergy gatherings to fellowship with bishops whose conscience would never allow them to ordain a woman. I can serve among Anglo-Catholics (the branch of the Church which holds my heart) but also among the Evangelicals, whom I hold dear. The whole Church is my people.</p>
<p>This is essential to me. In this mobile society, we should know now more than ever that our clergy are ordained for the whole Church, and it is the whole Church that bears responsibility for the actions of a few. Each diocese is responsible not only to its neighbors, but to our ecumenical partners and also to those whom we set apart as ordained leaders, as well. Many of our women priests, when transitioning from one diocese to another find themselves orphaned in a diocese that does not ordain women priests. Many of our “traditionalist” clergy are as easily orphaned when transitioning to a diocese that joyfully ordains women priests. The two so-called extremes are not as different from one another as they may seem.</p>
<p>But Christ did not establish a divided Church. We were made for more than this.</p>
<h2 id="women-priests-many-of-whom-are-my-friends-i-honor-your-ministry">Women priests, many of whom are my friends, I honor your ministry.</h2>
<p>I see the pain you’ve experienced and the sacrifices you’ve made. Yet I cannot see a way in which there can be a priesthood that emerges from an act of rebellion and division, as took place with the Philadelphia Eleven, that can be good or healthy for the whole Church. I do not see a women’s priesthood in Anglicanism today that is focused on unity over rights, on ordination as self-emptying rather than claiming our equality.</p>
<p>Perhaps it is a failure of imagination on my part, but I do not see a path forward, on our current trajectory, for ordaining women to the priesthood that does not sacrifice our unity for the sake of our individual sense of vocation. Any viable and unified path will require deep sacrifice, and it will be women in leadership who will be required to make those sacrifices. We will all lay our vocations on the altar.</p>
<p>I do not believe the church has been kind to women priests. Many are simply trying to love Jesus and serve him the best way they know how. Yet the Church has systematically abandoned them to their ministries with no assurance of their place within the whole Church, shuttled them out of the public eye as if they represented a momentary indiscretion, and even subjected them to verbal abuse in our public discourse. This is not the tradition we inherited. It is not who we are to be in Christ. The early Church was a haven for women in part because of the intentionality of the Church’s empowerment of those whom secular society disenfranchised, quite notably women. Jesus himself surrounded himself with women. Paul called them fellow workers and greeted them prominently in his letters. Whether or not they were ordained to the priesthood, the early Church’s women were empowered for ministry. While some served as hospitality co-ordinators and nursery workers (or some ancient equivalents thereof), others served as missionaries, evangelists and martyrs, and yes, deacons. The modern Church has failed, in some places quite miserably, in this task of empowering women to serve in ways that fulfill our less traditionally feminine gifts and vocations.</p>
<h2 id="those-who-oppose-the-ordination-of-women-i-hope-you-will-understand-the-sacrifice-required-specifically-of-women-to-lay-our-vocations-on-the-altar-knowing-that-it-cannot-be-expected-to-be-received-by-the-whole-church">Those who oppose the ordination of women, I hope you will understand the sacrifice required, specifically of women, to lay our vocations on the altar knowing that it cannot be expected to be received by the whole Church.</h2>
<p>This is a uniquely feminine sacrifice, to be called and never empowered, to be shuttled off to birthing and raising babies (and being told that the painful and messy “miracle of life” should be enough for us), and to the ministry of hospitality and children’s ministry in some branches of the Church, when our gifts and our calling are to proclaim the gospel and make our Lord known in the breaking of bread. The women of the Church are often the walking wounded, caught in the crossfire of other Christians’ battles. Unless you look at women’s ministries through the lens of sacrifice, you will never truly see.</p>
<p>There are some, I understand, who are vocal in our Church’s public discourse, whose social media personae seem to be that of card carrying misogynists, but I know firsthand that they are no majority voice. In fact, rarely have I felt as empowered in my diaconal vocation nor as valued as a woman than I have when in the company of my friends from Forward in Faith, the REC, and dioceses that do not ordain women (some not even ordaining women deacons). Our conversations are often open and honest, affectionate and theological. We value one another. It grieves me that the tone for the whole church is not being set by these individual bishops and faithful believers.</p>
<p>In my own journal, I recorded a quote from Archbishop Beach shortly after his election to serve as our archbishop. When asked what he thought about the Church’s women priests he replied, “For the people on the other side of that issue, for me I feel we need to honor them and respect them and treat them royally” (personal journal, July 6, 2014). Many in the Church have done just that. Nonetheless, when the official statements come down—the sort which carefully balances itself not to offend either side nor to make progress in either direction—we continually fail to acknowledge that our women priests are sisters in Christ, our women deacons are caught in a perpetual crossfire, and our dioceses which do not ordain women at all are often missing any visible and healthy vision of women in ministry other than the stereotypically feminine roles. Many of us are just not cut from that cloth.</p>
<h2 id="vocational-deacons-my-own-heart-this-does-not-diminish-the-wild-abandon-of-joy-i-have-for-our-order">Vocational deacons, my own heart, this does not diminish the wild abandon of joy I have for our order.</h2>
<p>My love for the order defines my diaconate, and I see your own sacrifices and self-emptying defining yours. Each of us has had to lay lives upon Christ’s altar and acknowledge that it is not about us. Even our own vocation is not ours. It is about our Lord and his Church and the profound beauty of his creation, of which we are part.</p>
<p>I have been blessed to work with deacons (men and women) from coast to coast, in Evangelical and Anglo-Catholic dioceses. I have never encountered one who would not lay down their life for the unity of the Church and the gospel of our Lord. Every single deacon has a complex call to walk in an in-between world, fully in orders and yet limited, under authority, even at times wholly defined by what deacons can’t do. Every single deacon has a vocation of sacrifice. This small story is simply a portion of mine.</p>
<p>In short, it is from the diaconate, this foundational order, that I find the most encouragement for the future. While women’s ordination to the priesthood has, quite frankly, gutted the modern diaconate in the global north, the order has continued to hold fast, examine its heart, and increasingly take up its historical identity in connection with the deacons who have gone before. What is perhaps overlooked here is that the diaconate continues to need encouragement and development, despite being somewhat outside the fray.</p>
<h2 id="i-do-not-share-this-story-to-gain-your-sympathy">I do not share this story to gain your sympathy.</h2>
<p>I would rather not share it at all, most especially not in a church that sees every mention of the ordination of women as an opportunity to demonize one another and fragment further along party lines. I would rather hoard it to myself, and not risk becoming the next target of ecclesiastical angst and ire. I do share it, however, in order to remind the whole Church what is truly at stake here. I share this story because I see the Church as the only institution on earth which is literally called to hand-feed its members from baptism to the last moments of life, and I see that the Church of the Internet Age has traded that call for a culture that devours one another instead.</p>
<p>Our gifts and our identities are received from God; we do not make them ourselves. We have a responsibility to one another to hold those offerings gently and to lift one another up, to be merciful to one another, to sacrifice our own wills for the sake of the gospel. This is the diaconal identity, the self-humbling ministry of Christ, and it is therefore the foundation of all our Holy Orders. It is also the only way we have to move forward.</p>
<p>St. Paul struggled with such painful factions and divisions in Corinth, and wrote to the church in Philippi on the value of placing our Christian identity, as a community, ahead of our individual goals, however well-intended: “So if there is any encouragement in Christ, any comfort from love, any participation in the Spirit, any affection and sympathy, complete my joy by being of the same mind, having the same love, being in full accord and of one mind. Do nothing from selfish ambition or conceit, but in humility count others more significant than yourselves. Let each of you look not only to his own interests, but also to the interests of others” (Phil. 2:1–4, ESV).</p>
<p>What follows this passage is the great “Christ hymn” in which we are reminded that our Lord himself did not consider his rightful nature of the godhead as a prize to be grasped, but emptied himself to the point of death on a Cross.</p>
<p>There is no healthy priesthood that is sourced in an act of rebellion. It does not matter that the rebellion took place a generation ago. Neither does healthy discernment depend on our individual ambitions and personal liberties. Holy Orders must come as an act of radical obedience. There is no fulfillment of a diaconal vow that comes at the cost of the universal Church, for which we are to be servants.</p>
<h2 id="i-am-humbled-and-gratified-daily-that-our-lord-saw-fit-to-make-me-a-deacon-and-has-mostly-given-me-the-grace-to-be-satisfied-in-this-gift-which-he-has-given-me">I am humbled and gratified daily that our Lord saw fit to make me a deacon and has (mostly) given me the grace to be satisfied in this gift which he has given me.</h2>
<p>I am hopeful that we may someday be able to set aside our conceits and agendas and truly seek God’s will as one Body. I am convinced that my continued experience of a call to the priesthood is part of the Lord’s call to me to set aside what I may think even of my own self and let him fashion me instead after his own likeness. That is, after all, every Christian’s hope, sacrifice, and joy. I am also convinced that our Lord’s call to all of us is to a unity that loves one another, even as Christ has loved us, even to death on a Cross, no matter which side of our divisions we claim as our own.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Fellow ACNA Clergy: On Anti-Racism and a More Diverse and Just Anglicanism</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: As is our policy with &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; Anglican Compass content, we ask that you &lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com/republishing-guidelines/&#34;&gt;please submit a request before republishing content&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://adoc.church/a-letter-concerning-the-death-of-george-floyd-and-so-many-others/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;recently wrote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care. Whether you’re ACNA clergy, a layperson, or a Christian leader outside the ACNA, we invite your consideration of the following and your &lt;a href=&#34;#sign&#34;&gt;signature&lt;/a&gt; in support.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>NOTE</strong>: As is our policy with <em>all</em> Anglican Compass content, we ask that you <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/republishing-guidelines/">please submit a request before republishing content</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who</em> <a href="https://adoc.church/a-letter-concerning-the-death-of-george-floyd-and-so-many-others/"><em>recently wrote</em></a> <em>in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care. Whether you’re ACNA clergy, a layperson, or a Christian leader outside the ACNA, we invite your consideration of the following and your <a href="#sign">signature</a> in support.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="our-context">Our Context</h2>
<p>Our province, The Anglican Church in North America (ACNA), was born as part of a global movement that features diverse leadership and reflects the churches and people of global Anglicanism. It is a manifestation of the universal power and eschatological <em>telos</em> of the Gospel of Jesus: “from every nation, from all tribes and peoples and languages, standing before the throne and before the Lamb” (Rev. 7:9).</p>
<p>Currently, the American population is about 38% non-white. By many projections, over the next 20 years, it will be increasingly composed of ethnic minorities. Our province, however, is far from representative of this emerging reality. The mission on our doorstep is clear: to reach North America, in all of its ethnic diversity, “with the transforming love of Jesus Christ.” We have the opportunity to proclaim the Gospel “to the whole creation” (Mark 16:15) and to be Jesus’ witnesses “to the ends of the earth” (Acts 1:8). We are called to reflect the ethnic diversity of the global movement of which we are a part, as well as the diverse locales in which we are present.</p>
<p>In order to more fully embody our Gospel witness, we must support, encourage, and empower the leadership of brothers and sisters of color in the ACNA to create more hospitable and welcoming spaces for people of color. This includes Black, Latino/a, Native, Asian, and other people groups. We must listen and respond to these voices in our midst and collectively seek to understand and address the historic and ongoing ways in which people of color continue to struggle under various expressions of injustice.</p>
<p>We see and grieve the racism and discrimination that exists and has a deep cultural and structural influence in our society, in our communities, and in our churches. The recent tragedies of Ahmaud Arbery, Breonna Taylor, and George Floyd are simply the latest in a long line of harrowing examples of these deeply embedded systemic realities. We see and grieve that our brothers and sisters of color, including many in our own dioceses and parishes, have been and continue to be profoundly affected by these realities.</p>
<p>Against this backdrop, we offer the following confessions and make the following commitments.</p>
<h2 id="confessions">Confessions</h2>
<p>We confess that we have failed to see, understand, and address the expressions of racism, both personal and systemic, that plague our society, communities, and churches.</p>
<p>We confess our slowness to listen to the dismay and discouragement of our brothers and sisters of color, especially those in our own province, and have neglected to cultivate hospitable spaces for them to flourish.</p>
<p>We confess that our ignorance, complacency, and silence have undermined our fidelity to the Great Commandment to love God and love our neighbor (Matt. 22:36-40), which fundamentally calls us into disciplines of anti-racism.</p>
<h2 id="commitments">Commitments</h2>
<p>We commit to listening to, learning from, and supporting leaders of color in their witness to our province.</p>
<p>We commit to partnering with these friends, and with organizations like</p>
<ul>
<li>the<a href="https://anglicanmultiethnic.org/"> Anglican Multiethnic Network (AMEN)</a>,</li>
<li><a href="https://www.caminemos-juntos.com/">Caminemos Juntos</a>,</li>
<li><a href="http://www.ammic.ca/">Asian &amp; Multicultural Ministries in Canada</a>, and</li>
<li>the<a href="http://etnn.org/"> Every Tribe and Nation Network</a></li>
</ul>
<p>that are working to promote, support, and invest in a more diverse and just Anglicanism.</p>
<p>And, in all of our different capacities and platforms, in our churches and in the world, we commit ourselves to investing in the work of anti-racism—in our catechesis, discipleship, preaching, ministry, advocacy, and reform.</p>
<p><em>(Editor’s note: You should also check out <a href="https://www.anglicanjusticeandmercy.org/home">the work being done by The Matthew 25 Initiative</a>.)</em></p>
<h2 id="the-road-ahead">The Road Ahead</h2>
<p>We are encouraged by the leaders, including the Archbishop, who have spoken out about the recent injustices, and we know that there are places within the province where there is movement toward realizing this vision of a multi-ethnic church, one that is unhindered by racism in all its forms, that can reach the entirety of North America.</p>
<p>However, there is significant work yet to be done. We hope that others will join us in our intentional commitment to partnering with leaders of color and the provincial organizations listed above in order to cultivate a diverse and just Anglicanism in North America.</p>
<p>We are a group of clergy committed to the ACNA and its mission. <a href="#sign">If you would like either to join us in these confessions and commitments or signal your affirmation of such work, we invite you to add your name to this letter.</a></p>
<p>Our ultimate goal, however, is not just signatures, but a collective public commitment towards diversity and justice for the sake of the gospel and our Kingdom witness.</p>
<p><em>Almighty God, you created us in your own image: Grant us grace to contend fearlessly against evil and to make no peace with oppression; and help us to use our freedom rightly in the establishment of justice in our communities and among the nations, to the glory of your holy Name; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and for ever. Amen.</em></p>
<p>Sincerely in Christ,</p>
<h2 id="authors">Authors</h2>
<p>Rev. Ryan Boettcher<br>
<em>Associate Clergy,</em> <a href="https://www.rezaustin.com/"><em>Resurrection Anglican South Austin</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Dr. Shawn McCain<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.rezaustin.com/"><em>Resurrection Anglican South Austin</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Seth Richardson<br>
<a href="https://www.teloscollective.com/"><em>The Telos Collective</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Dr. J.R. Rozko<br>
<em>National Director,</em> <a href="https://www.missioalliance.org/"><em>Missio Alliance</em></a> <em>&amp; Co-Lead Pastor,</em> <a href="http://www.firstchurchcanton.com/"><em>First Church of the Resurrection</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Ben Sternke<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.thetableindy.org/"><em>The Table Indianapolis</em></a> <em>&amp; Co-Founder,</em> <a href="https://gravityleadership.com/"><em>Gravity Leadership</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Matt Tebbe<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.thetableindy.org/"><em>The Table Indianapolis</em> </a><em>&amp; Co-Founder,</em> <a href="https://gravityleadership.com/"><em>Gravity Leadership</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Erik Willits<br>
<em>Host of</em> <a href="https://www.teloscollective.com/podcast/"><em>The Intersection Podcast</em></a> <em>Special Projects,</em> <a href="https://www.c4so.org/"><em>Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</em></a></p>
<h2 id="initial-signatories-click-here-or-scroll-down-to-sign">Initial Signatories (<a href="#sign">Click Here or Scroll Down to Sign</a>)</h2>
<p>Rev. Canon Dr. Dan Alger<br>
<em>Provincial Canon for Church Planting,</em> <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/index.php/main/Staff_Directory/"><em>Anglican Church in North America</em></a><br>
<em>Director,</em> <a href="https://www.always-forward.com/"><em>Always Forward Church Planting Initiative</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Gary Ball<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="http://www.redeemerasheville.com/"><em>Redeemer Asheville</em></a><em>, NC</em></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Taylor Bodoh<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.incarnationtallahassee.org/"><em>Incarnation, Tallahassee</em></a><br>
<em>Canon for Church Planting,</em> <a href="http://www.gulfatlanticdiocese.org/"><em>Gulf Atlantic Diocese</em></a><br>
<em>Leader in the</em> <a href="https://anglicanmultiethnic.org/"><em>Anglican Multiethnic Network (AMEN)</em></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Seth Cain<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://villageanglican.church/">The Village Anglican, Greenville</a></em><br>
</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Dan Claire<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://rezchurch.org/">The Church of the Resurrection, Washington, D.C.</a></em></span></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Greg Goebel<br>
<em>Editor-in-chief,</em> <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/"><em>Anglican Compass</em></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. David Martin Hanke<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://restorationarlington.org/">Restoration Anglican, Arlington</a></em><br>
</span></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Alan Hawkins<br>
<em>Chief Operating Officer,</em> <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/index.php/main/Staff_Directory/"><em>Anglican Church in North America</em></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Thomas Hinson<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://adventdc.org/">Advent Anglican, Washington, D.C.</a></em></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Hannah King<br>
<em>Associate Rector, <a href="https://villageanglican.church/">The Village Anglican, Greenville</a></em></span></p>
<p>Rev. Michael King<br>
<em>Associate Rector, <a href="https://villageanglican.church/">The Village Anglican, Greenville</a></em></p>
<p>Very Rev. Canon Dr. Kris McDaniel<br>
<em>Senior Pastor,</em> <a href="https://atltrinity.org/"><em>Trinity Anglican, Atlanta</em></a> <em>Canon for Church Development (Planting and Adoptions),</em> <a href="https://www.c4so.org/our-team/"><em>Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Dr. Emily McGowin<br>
<em>Associate Lecturer of Theology,</em> <a href="https://www.wheaton.edu/academics/faculty/emily-mcgowin/"><em>Wheaton College</em></a><br>
<em>Canon,</em> <a href="https://www.c4so.org/our-team/"><em>The Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Ron McGowin<br>
<em>Interim Rector,</em> <a href="http://www.holycross-anglican.org/"><em>Holy Cross Anglican Church, Lake Villa, IL</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Lee Nelson<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.christchurchwaco.org/"><em>Christ Church, Waco</em></a></p>
<p>Very Rev. Rob Patterson<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://redeemeranglican.com/">Redeemer Anglican, Santa Cruz</a> Regional Dean, Northern California, <a href="https://www.c4so.org/">Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</a></em></p>
<p>Rev. Marty Reardon<br>
<em>Westside Worship Pastor,</em> <a href="https://westside.atltrinity.org/"><em>Trinity Anglican, Atlanta</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Erik Rogers<br>
<em>Assisting Clergy, <a href="https://www.rezaustin.com/">Resurrection Anglican South Austin</a></em></p>
<p>Rev. Canon David Roseberry<br>
<em>Publisher,</em> <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/"><em>Anglican Compass</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Joshua Steele<br>
<em>Managing Editor,</em> <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/"><em>Anglican Compass</em></a></p>
<p>Very Rev. Cliff Warner<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://christchurchofaustin.org/"><em>Christ Church, Austin</em></a></p>
<p>Christine Warner<br>
<em>Director,</em><a href="https://www.anglicanjusticeandmercy.org/"> <em>Matthew 25 Initiative</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Tish Harrison Warren<br>
<em>Author,</em> <a href="https://amzn.to/2TTk7CT"><em>Liturgy of the Ordinary</em></a><br>
<em>Writer-in-Residence,</em> <a href="https://www.ascensionpittsburgh.org/our-leadership/"><em>Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Dr. Jonathan Warren Pagán<br>
<em>Associate Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.ascensionpittsburgh.org/our-leadership/"><em>Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Janna Ziegler<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://resurrectionla.org/"><em>Church of the Resurrection, Los Angeles</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Jon Ziegler<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://resurrectionla.org/"><em>Church of the Resurrection, Los Angeles</em></a></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="sign-the-letter">Sign the Letter</h2>
<p><em>If you’re ACNA clergy, please use the first form. We’d also love for laypeople and Christian leaders outside of the ACNA to indicate their support. If you’re <strong>not ACNA clergy</strong>, please use the <strong>second</strong> form (scroll down).</em></p>
<p><em>(<strong>NOTE</strong>: Don’t worry if you don’t see your name appear below right away. There might be a bit of a lag. No need to submit twice.)</em></p>
<p>[emailpetition id=”2″]</p>
<h3 id="all-other-supporters">All Other Supporters</h3>
<p>[emailpetition id=”3″]</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="signatures">Signatures</h2>
<h3 id="acna-clergy">ACNA Clergy</h3>
<div class="wp-block-file">[ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter\_2022-08-15](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter_2022-08-15.csv)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter_2022-08-15.csv)</div>\[signaturelist id=”2″\]
<h3 id="all-other-supporters-1">All Other Supporters</h3>
<div class="wp-block-file">[Not-ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter-Here\_2022-08-15](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Not-ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter-Here_2022-08-15.csv)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Not-ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter-Here_2022-08-15.csv)</div>\[signaturelist id=”3″\]]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Stir the Pot?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/dont-stir-the-pot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/dont-stir-the-pot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pondering the &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t stir the pot&amp;rdquo; reaction that reliably happens every time we publish something on women&amp;rsquo;s ordination—most especially anything in &lt;em&gt;favor&lt;/em&gt; of women&amp;rsquo;s ordination—&lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com/&#34;&gt;over at Anglican Compass&lt;/a&gt;, where I&amp;rsquo;m the Managing Editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: This post is not a subtweet of anyone in particular. It&amp;rsquo;s just me thinking out loud about a phenomenon that keeps occurring.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every time we post something about women&amp;rsquo;s ordination, a controversial issue has been whether or not doing so needlessly &amp;ldquo;stirs the pot,&amp;rdquo; as in &amp;ldquo;causes trouble, unrest, dissent.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m pondering the &ldquo;don&rsquo;t stir the pot&rdquo; reaction that reliably happens every time we publish something on women&rsquo;s ordination—most especially anything in <em>favor</em> of women&rsquo;s ordination—<a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">over at Anglican Compass</a>, where I&rsquo;m the Managing Editor.</p>
<p><em>(Note: This post is not a subtweet of anyone in particular. It&rsquo;s just me thinking out loud about a phenomenon that keeps occurring.)</em></p>
<p>Almost every time we post something about women&rsquo;s ordination, a controversial issue has been whether or not doing so needlessly &ldquo;stirs the pot,&rdquo; as in &ldquo;causes trouble, unrest, dissent.&rdquo;</p>
<p>On the one hand, some argue that this issue has already been debated to death. From this perspective, continuing to post about women&rsquo;s ordination simply exacerbates a condition that would be better off left alone—<a href="https://anglicancompass.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/">the “dual integrities” diocesan-level division on women&rsquo;s ordination that currently characterizes the ACNA.</a>. On the other hand, however, others argue that, since this issue is not settled, it&rsquo;s perfectly appropriate to blog about this.</p>
<p>The issue, then, is whether or not women&rsquo;s ordination is worth talking about, at least among Anglicans in public.</p>
<p>My own personal view is that it <em>is</em> worth talking about the Anglican debate over women&rsquo;s ordination in public. Though I concede that needless provocation (“stirring the pot”) is vicious, I still maintain that there is an important difference between <em>causing</em> or <em>exacerbating</em> a division and <em>describing</em> one.</p>
<p>For example, it would be vicious to take pot shots across the divide and try to get everyone to think either that (1) all egalitarians/mutualists completely ignore Scripture and tradition and choose to follow cultural trends instead, or that (2) all complementarians/hierarchicalists/patriarchalists hate women and want to keep them out of positions of power and influence. This would be <em>stirring the pot</em> and exacerbating our divisions.</p>
<p>However, I think it is an importantly different endeavor to try to help people on both sides of the debate see where the others stand. To remind the egalitarians that it&rsquo;s unfair to say that all complementarians hate women. To remind the complementarians that it&rsquo;s unfair to say that all egalitarians prioritize cultural trends over Scripture and tradition.</p>
<p>Some might object that giving both sides of the debate airtime means that we&rsquo;ve abandoned the truth in one direction or the other. But given that this is an important and ongoing division within the ACNA, between conservative and orthodox Christians, this seems like necessary work. It strikes me as unduly tribalistic to either pretend like the other side doesn&rsquo;t exist, or to condemn anyone who would listen to arguments from the other side as a dangerous traitor.</p>
<p>Furthermore, some might object that this work has already been done. By and large, I would agree. But just because almost every facet of the debate has already been covered in various settings—books, articles, etc.—doesn&rsquo;t mean that we don&rsquo;t have room to grow in understanding of our differences. There may be nothing new under the sun, and yet we still keep writing and talking about other things. Why not women&rsquo;s ordination as well?</p>
<p>On the issue of women&rsquo;s ordination, we obviously disagree with one another—both within the ACNA and within the Anglican Communion. And yet I&rsquo;m not quite sure that we fully understand one another. From my limited perspective, it&rsquo;s worth &ldquo;stirring the pot&rdquo; until we at least reach full, respectful understanding—even if we never reach full agreement on this side of eternity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Altar and the Arena: What Slaves and Martyrs Have to Teach Us About Women’s Ordination</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-altar-and-the-arena-what-slaves-and-martyrs-have-to-teach-us-about-womens-ordination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-altar-and-the-arena-what-slaves-and-martyrs-have-to-teach-us-about-womens-ordination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Compass does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past several months, readers of Anglican Compass have engaged with many opinions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/tag/womens-ordination/&#34;&gt;the topic of women’s ordination&lt;/a&gt;. One wonders, given the state of dual integrities within the ACNA and the ever-churning blog debates between our public intellectuals, what is the point of another take on this issue?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Compass does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>Over the past several months, readers of Anglican Compass have engaged with many opinions on <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/tag/womens-ordination/">the topic of women’s ordination</a>. One wonders, given the state of dual integrities within the ACNA and the ever-churning blog debates between our public intellectuals, what is the point of another take on this issue?</p>
<p>But stay with me, friends. At the risk of debate fatigue, I want to stir these waters once more because after reading these pieces, I believe we are missing several key points in the conversation. In fact, I believe we need to engage in a fundamentally different conversation—one that centers the debate in its proper theological home: baptism and the Person of Christ.</p>
<p>Proponents of the male-only priesthood have argued that a literal reading of scripture shows women clearly cannot have priestly authority in the church. They also propound that women’s orders would go against a natural order of male headship, established by God in creation, and perhaps even reflected within God’s trinitarian being. But these arguments redirect the issue away from its true theological foundation and veer into less than orthodox weeds. These are not christological positions and they don’t say much about our identity in Jesus Christ through baptism.</p>
<p>In what follows, I want to discuss how Anglicans have misused both baptism and the literal interpretation of scripture to uphold hierarchical social orders, a pattern of thought that closely mirrors ancient Gnostic exegesis, of which male headship is a prime example.</p>
<p>To counter that, I want to explore the biblical relationship between baptism and priesthood, as outlined in the book of Hebrews. Because Christ is two natures, his priesthood—his mediation—is his person, which has a direct bearing on how we conceive of our own priesthood. We see this clearly evidenced in the martyrdoms of Ignatius of Antioch and Blandina of Lyons, a woman who, as she dies, is depicted <em>in persona Christi</em>.</p>
<p>In their eagerness to support their understanding of tradition, Anglicans have sometimes compromised the Kingdom with cultural values, veering away from a biblical theology of human ordination and missing the reality of baptism. If we are to have a good faith conversation around these issues, this must be addressed. So come, let’s wade in the waters one more time.</p>
<h2 id="claiming-baptism-against-the-bishop">Claiming Baptism Against the Bishop</h2>
<p>In 1723, Edmund Gibson, the Bishop of London and ecclesial authority over England’s colonies, was faced with a crisis. What happens when slaves want to be baptized and taught the faith? The slaveholders, he knew, were adamantly against baptism or education of any kind, fearing it would lead to the slaves’ agitation against their social position. In fact, they were so desperate to prevent this that slaves who learned to read or who taught others to do so were brutally punished and killed.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, a group of slaves came together and wrote an urgent <a href="http://www.encyclopediavirginia.org/_Letter_from_Virginia_Slaves_to_Bishop_Edmund_Gibson_August_4_September_8_1723">entreaty</a> to the Bishop of London:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We your humble and poor parishioners do beg Sir your aid and assistance in this one thing which lies as I do understand in your lordship’s brest which is that your honor will by the help of our suffering lord King George…release us out of this curel bondege and this we beg for Jesus Christ’s sake who has commanded us to seek first the kingdom of God and all things shall be added unto us. And here it is to be noted that one brother is a slave to another and one sister to another…and we are commanded to keep holy the sabbath day and we do hardly know when it comes for our task masters are as hard with us as the Egyptians were with the Children of Israel, God be merciful to us.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Several things are at play here. First, in an act of cultural rebellion, they learned to read scripture and, more importantly, to read themselves into it theologically. They saw themselves in the enslaved children of Israel and understood that scripture laid out their freedom on the basis of baptism.</p>
<p>Second, they understood that the act of baptism made them parishioners of the church, members of a body which fundamentally changed their previous social relations. The cry of the slaves was that they were under the Bishop’s care and both he and they worshiped the same Lord Jesus Christ. It is a cry of hope and a desire to live in a new relationship of belonging in Christ, to throw off the oppression of evil. One could almost read this as a colonial-era Philemon, if Onesimus had penned the letter instead of Paul.</p>
<p>In that era, Christians could not own other Christians as slaves. Slaves therefore were always defined as idolators, heathens, fundamentally ‘other’. So when these slaves wrote to him <em>as Christians</em>, Bp. Gibson had a pastoral crisis on his hands. It isn’t known whether the Bishop saw this letter, although it was found at Lambeth Palace. But we do have his response in a <a href="http://catalog.princeton.edu/catalog/7190370#view">letter</a> circulated to plantation owners where he argues, based on 1 Cor. 7:20, that baptism in no way changes social relationships, but rather will make slaves better slaves because that’s what the New Testament commands—literally (Col. 3:22-23).</p>
<p>The Bishop, torn between his desire to uphold social order and his duty to increase the flock, took hold of his literal reading of St. Paul and attempted a classic Anglican <em>via media</em>: baptism would save the soul of the slave, but leave their body in its pre-established position in the social hierarchy. They would be “saved” in faith, but remain property in body. Slavery, the Bishop and his contemporaries (theologians like Cotton Mather and Jonathan Edwards) argued, is a cosmic structure, natural and God-ordained (<em>Divided by Faith,</em> Emerson and Smith, pg. 22-26). Salvation was open to all because all were made in God’s image, but it would in no way violate that “natural” created order.</p>
<p>Which of these, do you think, was a better reader of scripture? The one who showed us Christ. The slaves interpreted their lives according to the scriptures, reading after the model of Peter and Paul. God’s word was for them, <em>pro nobis</em>, a Christological reading practice. They read scripture against their culture, against the “natural state of things” and their “place” within it and by doing so understood the logic of baptism. They saw that it was creation anew, that the Old Adam passes away as we are born of Christ, not returning to Eden, but discovering the New Jerusalem, as something neither gnostic nor dualist, but with a claim on real social relations and a claim on those with whom they were baptized: the Bishop, priests, and even their Christian slave owners. They knew that they should be free because they were free together in Christ.</p>
<h2 id="male-headship-as-gnostic-anthropology">Male Headship as Gnostic Anthropology</h2>
<p>What we saw in Bp. Gibson’s response is sadly not a historical outlier. Christianity’s social imagination has often been hijacked to support less than biblical mythologies, especially in how it imagines bodies arranged within hierarchies of power.</p>
<p>As we look back at Bp. Gibson’s verdict, we can see the Gnostic worldview hardly concealed. Gnosticism taught that there were three human essences, each in a role of hierarchy over the next. Of these, it was only the top tier, the ‘spiritual’ humans, who were truly saved. Their redemption narrative grounded this belief in a pre-fall hierarchy of essences and they worked toward a return to that state by ordering and controlling humanity in the present. In Bp. Gibson’s response to the plantation owners, he inhabited this worldview (slavery is a cosmic structure), even while attempting a literal reading and application of the scriptures. Instead of preaching Christ crucified, he unwittingly inhabited Gnostic myth by differentiating African slave essence from European Christian essence and keeping them hierarchically aligned.</p>
<p>In our contemporary moment, I see this same interpretive tendency within the discourse on gender roles. Certain theologians have promoted a concept of male headship that reduces the complex notion of ‘head’ in the ancient world (see Lucy Peppiatt’s <em>Rediscovering Scripture’s Vision for Women</em>) to an authority/submission structure (a meaning taken from ancient military culture, not found in the New Testament). This concept is then grounded univocally in both the Trinity and creation, establishing a hierarchy of essentialized roles between the Father and the Son, and locating this structure for social order in a pre-creation, pre-fall world. Men and women are described as possessing “gifts” or “charisms” that correlate to an essential masculinity or femininity, existing always in a hierarchical relation. Salvation in this worldview means not just putting on Christ, but also putting on your essence as a male or female and accepting your place within the hierarchy God established before the fall.</p>
<p>The end result of this is that the worldview of male headship misappropriates the story of salvation to elevate a particular kind of male essence—one that sees itself as a universal principle, requiring the submission of other essences, whether those be non-white, female, or even land.</p>
<p>Perhaps it would better be named a principality or power.</p>
<p>St. Irenaeus of Lyons refuted this kind of gnostic thinking when he criticized the myth of hierarchies by showing how God’s whole economy of Creation and Redemption centered on the flesh of Christ, who is God’s Image and the true Human Being.</p>
<p>Christ, he reminded the Christians of his day, is the beginning, middle, and goal of creation. In creation, the <em>adam</em> was a type of the one to come, Jesus Christ (Rom. 5:14). Salvation’s goal is not Christ returning us to a pre-fall state, whatever idyllic mythology we project back onto the garden. Salvation is eschatological, the end and the goal, that has appeared in Jesus Christ in the present. We tend to think of salvation as moving from Adam to Christ, who restores what Adam was.</p>
<p>No.</p>
<p>St. Irenaeus, St. Paul, and the Gospel of John all have it differently: Humanity is re-founded, <em>re-created in Christ</em>. The old (Adam) is passing away, the new (Christ) has come (Col. 1:15-20). To read the Genesis narrative as a description of male/female hierarchy in nature and role is to read it through the lense of our own cultural assumptions. In other words, if we’re not reading Genesis christologically, we’re likely to be reading it Gnostically. You need to know the end, Christ, to understand the beginning, the <em>adam</em>.</p>
<p>It is the person of Christ that stands against any gnostic mythology, any dualism, as the sole essence of creation.</p>
<h2 id="the-difference-baptism-makesin-christ-out-of-adam">The Difference Baptism Makes—In Christ, Out of <em>adam</em></h2>
<p>Not only do we fall into Gnostic mythology, but we also miss something fundamental about the incarnation itself if we think first of nature and look to Christ second. His person is <em>two</em> natures, uncreated and created.</p>
<p>He is the God-human.</p>
<p>I say human here purposely. In the New Testament the Greek word <em>‘anthropos’</em> is used of Christ, not the male ‘<em>arsen</em>’ which pairs with <em>‘gune/thelys’</em> female, which can signal gender or wife. This is important because in Christ’s <em>anthropos</em> there is no <em>arsen/thelys</em> (Gal. 3:28). The enmity between male/female in Adam has been reconciled in Christ, which is why Paul says in 2 Cor. 5 that we do not regard anyone according to the flesh, <em>not even Christ</em>. Christ shows us what it means to be human eschatologically, from the completion of creation back into history. Humanity isn’t going back to Eden. And that’s a good thing.</p>
<p>So, then, if we insist that Christians must conform to the pattern of some “natural” state—i.e., the roles of headship/submission—in order to to be fully human, what we’re really doing is rebirthing them into the Old Adam and interposing another mediator between ourselves and Christ. We’re choosing a baptism not into Christ, but into a social order of death.</p>
<p>There is only one head, one source for Christians: the divine-<em>anthropos</em> Jesus Christ. When, as St. Paul says, we were baptized into Christ’s death, our former source in the <em>adam</em> (male/female) of death was ended—thanks be to God—and our new life is only and exclusively the life of the divine-<em>anthropos</em>, Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>To state it bluntly, asserting an Adamic male headship is to adhere to Gnostic mythology and to insist on the continuation of male/female as idealized identities based in headship is to get Christ’s work precisely backwards, leaving unreconciled something Christ has fundamentally put to death by his death. He doesn’t perfect the Adamic archetype. He brings it to death and raises himself as the new eschatological Human Being. He has, by the blood of his cross, put to death all divisions caused by the fall, whether male/female, master/slave, Jew/Gentile, and has raised instead the Human Being, who is known and justified by faith. Because Christ is two natures, our baptism into him transfers us out of what we are by nature into what he is in his person: infinite God united to flesh, a new mode of being.</p>
<h2 id="a-new-priesthoodhebrews-and-the-priesthood-of-christ">A New Priesthood—Hebrews and the Priesthood of Christ</h2>
<p>With the acknowledgment of a new mode of being human, we must also ask some fundamental questions about the priesthood itself. Christ’s priesthood, Hebrews tells us, is of the order of Melchizedek. Why then has the church often implemented a version of the Levitical priesthood, when Christ’s priesthood is of a completely different order?</p>
<p>The Levitical priesthood was a caste, males of a specific tribe set apart for Israel’s rituals, whereas the priesthood of Melchizedek was not based on any natural qualities that would group him within a holy caste. “No father, no mother, no genealogy” (Heb 7:3). He is a priest of God not because of his nature, but because of God’s calling.</p>
<p>That is Christ’s priesthood also, not according to any natural qualities (male, female, Jew, Gentile), but by the will of God. This is the priesthood Christ shares with us through baptism and his personal calling, one in which we belong not by nature but by faith in him who called us. Priesthood under the new covenant has also been re-founded, re-created in Christ. Just as there is now one Human Being (<em>anthropos</em>), Jesus Christ, so also there is now only one priest, one mediator, and his priesthood is based in his Person, not in the natural qualities of his divinity or his humanity (although it does not exclude them). It arbitrarily privileges certain human particulars to say the priesthood after Christ is a caste of Christian males, whether ethnically Jewish or Gentile. More seriously, it disregards the reality of the new covenant and mars the priesthood with supersessionism.</p>
<p>If we imagine that Christ’s body, composed of the baptized, must still uphold the regulations of the old covenant, have we really understood baptism in the first place? Or is there an aspect of our Adamic identity we want to preserve from the death of baptism, a toe or heel of maleness kept out of the water, through which we try to be justified by nature? The very thing we withhold from the death of baptism is that which will cause us to stumble, a place where death is still at work.</p>
<p>If we are justified to be priests by our maleness, then we might as well bring back the lambs for slaughter. St. Paul said as much about circumcision. Why is this any different?</p>
<h2 id="she-is-the-form-of-christ">“She is the Form of Christ”</h2>
<p>So what does it mean to be <em>in persona Christi</em>–<em>as</em>–<em>anthropos</em>? What is the Human Being and how do we, as the body of Christ, embody that through baptism?</p>
<p>It is Pilate, ironically, who lifts the curtain for us as he presents the robed and thorn-crowned Jesus to the crowd.“Look at the Human Being,” he declares, or in the Greek “ ἰδοὺ ὁ ἄνθρωπος” (John 19:5). Here is the <em>anthropos</em>, a martyr, in passion and death—which in Christ is life. This is the Imago Dei, the goal into which the male/female <em>adam</em> is called to be recreated.</p>
<p>Christ is the Human Being in the Holy of Holies of his Temple—his body—from which streams of living water flow and of which the church, the new humanity, is born.</p>
<p>It is in the lives of the martyrs that we can see the revealed <em>anthropos</em> most clearly. In his <em>Ecclesial Histories</em>, Eusebius chronicles the story of Blandina, a slave girl from Lyons, France, who is brought to the arena for torture and death. Eusebius recounts the testimonies of several martyrs, but it is that of Blandina that strengthens everyone.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Blandina, through whom Christ showed that things which appear mean and obscure and despicable to men are with God of great glory … [She]was filled with such power as to be delivered and raised above those who were torturing her by turns from morning till evening in every manner, so that they acknowledged that they were conquered, and could do nothing more to her. And they were astonished at her endurance, as her entire body was mangled and broken; and they testified that one of these forms of torture was sufficient to destroy life, not to speak of so many and so great sufferings.</p>
<p>But the blessed woman, like a noble athlete, renewed her strength in her confession; and her comfort and recreation and relief from the pain of her sufferings was in exclaiming, ‘I am a Christian, and there is nothing vile done by us.’ … [Then she] was suspended on a stake, and exposed to be devoured by the wild beasts who should attack her. <em>And because she appeared as if hanging on a cross, and because of her earnest prayers</em>, she inspired the combatants with great zeal. For they looked on her in her conflict, and beheld with their outward eyes, <em>in the form of their sister, him who was crucified for them</em>, that he might persuade those who believe in him, that every one who suffers for the glory of Christ has fellowship always with the living God.” (emphasis mine).</p></blockquote>
<p>Blandina was a slave. Not only that, she was a female slave, the lowest position in the cultural hierarchy. Her social status bordered on the non-human. And yet, as Eusebius recounts it, truly this woman was <em>in persona Christi</em>.</p>
<p>Her baptized body transgresses every boundary the hierarchy has erected. She is <em>in persona Christi</em> because Christ shares his life with her and co-suffers with her, “not on the basis of a legal requirement concerning bodily descent, but by the power of an indestructible life” (Heb. 7:16). His indestructible life is her life, her cross is his cross, his communion is the communion she offers by the testimony of her body and blood, which is also the Church’s seed.</p>
<p>Have we grasped the truly sacramental nature of martyrdom, of being the <em>anthropos</em>? Ignatius of Antioch described his imminent death as becoming “the pure bread” of Christ, explaining that he would become the eucharist as the lions ground his body to pieces. “When I shall have arrived [at martyrdom],” Ignatius wrote, “ I will be the Human Being.” Are we able to embrace testimony like that? Like Blandina’s? Or have we lost a vision of the eucharist as a martyric event in which all the baptized share?</p>
<p>If instead our sacramental worldview reduces <em>in persona Christi</em> to necessitating “the male form of Christ,” we are utilizing a docetic form of <em>persona</em>: he seems like Christ, approximates Christ’s form only in maleness. This use of <em>persona</em> is more pagan than its meaning rooted in trinitarian and christological discourse. To be in the person of Christ, to understand the <em>anthropos</em>, look instead to the martyrs. Look to the bodies broken, the blood spilled, the life in death.</p>
<p>It is not Adam (or Eve) at the altar or hanging before the wild animals in the arena. It is Christ the Human Being in the body of Ignatius, in the blood of Blandina.</p>
<p>If women are <em>in persona Christi</em> in the arena, they are <em>in persona Christi</em> at the altar.</p>
<h2 id="what-he-cannot-by-nature-have">“What He Cannot By Nature Have”</h2>
<p>So where does this leave us, then? In the 1662 Book of Common Prayer, the preface to Holy Baptism says:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Forasmuch as all men are conceived and born in sin, and that our Savior Christ saith, none can enter into the kingdom of God, except he be regenerate and born anew of Water and of the Holy Ghost: I beseech you to call upon God the Father, through our Lord Jesus Christ, that of his bounteous mercy he will grant to <em>this Child</em> that thing which by nature <em>he</em> cannot have; that <em>he</em> may be baptized with Water and the Holy Ghost, and received into Christ’s holy Church, and be made a lively member of the same.”</p></blockquote>
<p>That thing which by nature he cannot have.</p>
<p>We cannot have the life of Christ, much less be priests in Christ’s church, by nature. Stipulating a certain nature to qualify for the priesthood is anti-baptismal. Our calling to be priests exists always within our primary calling to martyrdom, to be the Human Being. As many as have put on Christ in baptism, who are thus becoming the eschatological <em>anthropos</em>, they also can be called to ordination.</p>
<p>Any disagreement among Christians is an opportunity to discern the mind of Christ (Phil 4:1-5). As the debate on ordination continues in our communion, I hope that we will not be satisfied with anything less than the whole Christ. Sadly, Anglicans have a history of adapting to cultural hierarchies, whether that be slavery, gnostic mythologies of gender, or even subordinating the Trinity to a cultural idol of social order. A literal reading of Scripture won’t save us from that theological misdirection.</p>
<p>For that, we need a christological reasoning that re-centers this debate in the life and death of Jesus Christ, the God-human, and the priesthood of his body and blood.</p>
<p>If you are baptized into Christ, you are a new creation and are justified by faith to be a priest following Christ’s priesthood. To quote <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/">Dr. McGowin’s first piece on Anglican Compass</a>, “by becoming one with Christ in our baptism, all become partakers of his Royal Priesthood.” Because both men and women are called to be Christ’s witnesses, to be the <em>anthropos</em>, they are both called to be <em>in persona Christi</em>, to embody the life of martyrdom, whether in the arena or at the altar.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We switched Anglican Compass over from HostGator Shared to Bluehost VPS Hosting</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 15:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As of this morning, it looks like everything for &lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com/&#34;&gt;Anglican Compass&lt;/a&gt; has been successfully moved over from our HostGator shared hosting to Bluehost VPS hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping that this new arrangement works well for us! Although, to be honest, it’s still an open question in my mind whether or not managed WordPress hosting with WPEngine would be a better fit. I just can’t quite tell whether or not it would be worth the extra cost, given our current traffic and budget.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As of this morning, it looks like everything for <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">Anglican Compass</a> has been successfully moved over from our HostGator shared hosting to Bluehost VPS hosting.</p>
<p>I’m hoping that this new arrangement works well for us! Although, to be honest, it’s still an open question in my mind whether or not managed WordPress hosting with WPEngine would be a better fit. I just can’t quite tell whether or not it would be worth the extra cost, given our current traffic and budget.</p>
<p>What I would <em>really</em> love is for someone to sit down with me and give me a consultation on whether or not we’ve got things set up well for the following 3 websites on Bluehost:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">https://anglicancompass.com/</a> (this is our most important website right now, it gets the most traffic)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.leaderworks.org/">http://www.leaderworks.org/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://theevergreenproject.org/">https://theevergreenproject.org/</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Until now, I’ve only been involved with the backend of <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">Anglican Compass</a>, so I’m not really sure of the ins and outs of how the other 2 websites are set up on the backend. But these three projects are going to be associated going forward, and I’d like to make sure that we’re set up for future success as our numbers increase!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking Scripture and Women’s Ordination Seriously: A Response to Blake Johnson and Lee Nelson</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: Thank you to the Rev. Dr. Emily McGowin for writing this rejoinder to &lt;a href=&#34;http://theopolisinstitute.com/sacramental-representation-and-the-created-order/&#34;&gt;Fr. Blake Johnson’s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/&#34;&gt;Fr. Lee Nelson’s&lt;/a&gt; responses to &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/&#34;&gt;her original blog post&lt;/a&gt; about the&lt;/em&gt; in persona Christi &lt;em&gt;argument against women’s ordination. While we invite this conversation (about McGowin’s original blog post) to continue in our comments section and elsewhere—and we plan to publish more about women’s ordination in the future—we will not be adding surrejoinder blog posts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Editor’s Note: Thank you to the Rev. Dr. Emily McGowin for writing this rejoinder to <a href="http://theopolisinstitute.com/sacramental-representation-and-the-created-order/">Fr. Blake Johnson’s</a> and <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/">Fr. Lee Nelson’s</a> responses to <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/">her original blog post</a> about the</em> in persona Christi <em>argument against women’s ordination. While we invite this conversation (about McGowin’s original blog post) to continue in our comments section and elsewhere—and we plan to publish more about women’s ordination in the future—we will not be adding surrejoinder blog posts.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>I am grateful to <a href="http://theopolisinstitute.com/sacramental-representation-and-the-created-order/">Fr. Blake Johnson</a> and <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/">Fr. Lee Nelson</a> for their responses to my previous blog post, <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/">“If Women Can Be Saved, Then Women Can Be Priests.”</a></p>
<p>I begin with a point of clarification: My piece was intentionally narrow. I offered a critique of the <em>in persona Christi</em> argument against women’s ordination to the priesthood. I was not offering a full argument for women’s ordination. It seems some confusion has resulted from those who assume I was doing the latter rather than the former.</p>
<p>With that in mind, I am glad to see Johnson and Nelson have broadened the discussion on this subject. They help to demonstrate that the conclusion one draws regarding women in the priesthood depends not only upon the christological issue I raised initially, but also a variety of other weighty matters, including biblical interpretation, how one draws upon the sources of the tradition, and more.</p>
<h2 id="beginning-with-scripture">Beginning with Scripture</h2>
<p>While both authors raise a variety of issues worthy of engagement, I want to begin with biblical interpretation (something Nelson faults me for not doing enough of). Since both Johnson and Nelson root their arguments in a particular reading of Genesis 2, I’ll focus my attention there. In what follows, I am drawing, in part, upon conversations with my Wheaton College colleague, <a href="http://www.wheaton.edu/academics/faculty/aubrey-buster/">Dr. Aubrey Buster</a>.</p>
<h3 id="genesis-2">Genesis 2</h3>
<h4 id="first-in-genesis-22122-the-hebrew-word-tsela-does-not-mean-rib-as-nelson-suggests">First, in Genesis 2:21–22, the Hebrew word <em>tsela’</em> does not mean “rib” as Nelson suggests.</h4>
<p>It is translated “rib” by some Bible translations today, but that translation is not demonstrative of the best scholarship on the subject.</p>
<p>According to <a href="http://www.logos.com/product/5226/hebrew-and-aramaic-lexicon-of-the-old-testament"><em>HALOT</em></a>, the current standard Hebrew lexicon, there is no other occurrence in the Hebrew Bible where <em>tsela’</em> means “rib”. In every other case, it is translated “side” (see p. 1030). The Septuagint translates the Hebrew with the Greek word <em>pleura</em>, which also means “side.” Even in cognate languages where it is used for animal or human anatomy, it refers to the side of the chest.</p>
<h4 id="why-is-this-important">Why is this important?</h4>
<p>Because the scriptures say Eve is constructed out of Adam’s <em>side.</em> Eve is derivative in the sense of being taken from Adam (like Adam was taken from the earth), but decidedly <em>not</em> derivative in the sense of subordinate to Adam; she is his <em>side,</em> one half of a whole. The theological point of Genesis 2 is not to emphasize the <em>hierarchical</em> <em>difference</em> between Adam and Eve, whether in terms of ontology, function, or roles, but their <em>similarity</em>. Put simply, Adam and Eve are made of the same stuff. Eve is not an alien creature. She is Adam’s side—his own flesh and bone—which Dr. John Walton calls Adam’s “ontological equal” (see <em><a href="http://amzn.to/2NXWq9N">The Lost World of Adam and Eve</a></em>, p. 110).</p>
<p>Interpreters of Genesis note that chapters 1 and 2 appear to be intentionally subversive of the creation stories and cosmologies of the nations surrounding the people of Israel. The same holds true in the creation of woman. It was quite common in the cultures of the ANE to view women as creatures of inferior ontology in comparison to men. (Not just the ANE, of course, but in Greek thought, too, where the supposed inferior ontology of women becomes more institutionalized.) The biblical narrative is, in Walton’s words, “operating in the same room of discourse” as the ANE, but “Genesis has rearranged all the furniture”. The author is offering a subversive, countercultural perspective: one that affirms the full humanity and God-ordained status of women side-by-side with men.</p>
<h4 id="second-a-close-reading-of-the-text-shows-that-the-task-for-which-eve-is-created-is-the-same-task-for-which-the-man-is-created">Second, a close reading of the text shows that the task for which Eve is created is the <em>same</em> task for which the man is created.</h4>
<p>Johnson rightly notes that God gives to the man a task, namely to “keep and to guard” the garden (v. 15), which parallels the temple service of the Levites (see Num. 3:8-9). And it is in the context of <em>this task</em> that God says it is not good for him to be alone (v. 18).</p>
<p>That is to say, is it not good for Adam to do his keeping and guarding work alone. Instead, he must have an <em>ezer kenegdo</em> (v. 18): an “ally (one who aids someone in accomplishing a task) of the same kind.” What is this ally-ship for, but for the task for which the man was created? Eve will be the one who helps him in accomplishing the task given him by God.</p>
<p>Others have written about the significance of <em>ezer</em> in Gen. 2:18, so I won’t duplicate their work here. I’ll simply point out that the word <em>ezer</em> occurs 21 times in the Bible: it is used twice to describe the woman in Gen. 2, sixteen times to describe God, and three times to describe an army aiding in battle.</p>
<p>For example,</p>
<ul>
<li>in Exod. 18:4: “…the name of the other, Eliezer (for he said, “The God of my father was my <em>help</em>, and delivered me from the sword of Pharaoh”).</li>
<li>In Deut. 33:26: “There is none like God, O Jeshurun, who rides through the heavens to your <em>help</em>, through the skies in his majesty.”</li>
<li>And Ps. 33:20: “Our soul waits for the Lord; he is our <em>help</em> and our shield.”</li>
</ul>
<p>The word <em>ezer</em> is never used to refer to aid in procreation and there is certainly never any sense of subordination in its usage (especially since it is used so often to speak of God himself!). In most contexts, <em>ezer</em> is referring to something related to the military, hence the translation of “ally” offered above.</p>
<p>Furthermore, in Gen. 2 there is no reference in the creation of woman to her function as “life-giver,” or any procreative purposes whatsoever until after the fall (Gen. 3:20). The only task that is given the man and the woman in the passage regarding the purposes for which they are created is the mandate to keep and to guard the garden, and to obey the command of the Lord (Gen. 2:15-17).</p>
<p>(Now, the creation narrative of Gen. 1 does indeed contain a reference to procreation. In that context, though, man and woman are created simultaneously in the image of God and blessed <em>as a pair</em>, just as the animals are blessed, to “be fruitful and multiply” [Gen. 1:28]. Fruitfulness and reproduction are not unique to humankind, but part of the plant and animal world in which they exist. What the text emphasizes, rather, is the dominion that God grants to the humans [“subdue it” in v. 28]. Furthermore, there is no sense in Gen. 1 that fruitfulness and multiplication are functions given to women exclusively; it is something the human couple <em>shares</em>.)</p>
<h4 id="finally-in-contrast-to-nelsons-translation-adam-is-certainly-not-tasked-with-serving-as-a-gardener">Finally, in contrast to Nelson’s translation, Adam is certainly not tasked with serving as a “gardener.”</h4>
<p>As Johnson points out, because of its parallel to Num. 3:8 and other references to the temple, what’s being spoken of here is keeping and guarding the <em>the place where God’s presence dwells</em>.</p>
<p>This is priestly language describing a priestly vocation. And, once again, it is something Adam is not meant to do alone. It is precisely the work of preserving sacred space that Adam is unable to accomplish without Eve. In the vocation of tending to the place where God’s presence dwells, Eve is Adam’s “ally of the same kind” (<em>ezer kenegdo).</em></p>
<h4 id="now-in-fairness-to-johnson-and-nelson-they-are-not-doing-a-strictly-grammatical-and-historical-reading-of-gen-2">Now, in fairness to Johnson and Nelson, they are not doing a strictly grammatical and historical reading of Gen. 2.</h4>
<p>Instead, they are employing a typological reading, one clearly inspired, in my estimation, by <a href="http://www.usccb.org/issues-and-action/marriage-and-family/natural-family-planning/catholic-teaching/theology-of-the-body.cfm">Pope John Paul II’s “Theology of the Body</a>.”</p>
<p>To be clear, I have no problem with typological readings of Scripture in general. But, I do have a problem when a typological reading imposes something that is alien to, or directly at odds with, the most natural and straightforward interpretation of the sacred text.</p>
<p>And this, I believe, is one of those instances. Those of us committed to the authority of Scripture must, at the very least, allow Scripture to speak for itself before assigning to it typological meanings that go beyond the intent of the original author.</p>
<h4 id="before-moving-on-and-along-the-same-lines-i-want-to-offer-a-word-of-caution-to-those-inclined-to-agree-with-nelsons-interpretation-of-gen-2-and-the-theology-of-the-body-as-a-whole">Before moving on, and along the same lines, I want to offer a word of caution to those inclined to agree with Nelson’s interpretation of Gen. 2 and the “Theology of the Body” as a whole.</h4>
<p>The notion that, as Nelson says, “sexual difference serves to show the relation between God and creation,” with men imaging God (father, gardener, giver) and women imaging creation (life-giver, mother, receiver) has deep conceptual resonance with the <em>pagan</em> cosmology of the Ancient Near East.</p>
<p>In fact, it is this kind of Canaanite cosmology, which closely linked human sexuality and the deity, that the creation narratives of Genesis 1-2 are expressly denying.</p>
<p>In their desire to find a unified essentialist theology of gender in the scriptures, I fear many are extrapolating the analogies of Christ and the church, Yahweh and Israel, husband and wife, in ways that are deeply harmful—both for our theology proper and our theological anthropology.</p>
<p>I therefore encourage my sisters and brothers to think more critically about these kinds of claims and to consider carefully whether their conclusions are, indeed, in continuity with the scriptures and the great tradition of the Christian church.</p>
<h3 id="there-are-many-more-points-of-interpretive-disagreement-i-could-cite-between-nelsons-and-johnsons-responses-but-i-find-myself-constrained-by-time-and-space">There are many more points of interpretive disagreement I could cite between Nelson’s and Johnson’s responses, but I find myself constrained by time and space.</h3>
<p>Regarding the conclusions we draw from the Pauline corpus, like 1 Tim. 2:11-16, 1 Cor. 11:1-16; and 1 Cor. 14:34-35, I’ll simply say this: Nelson demonstrates precisely the kind of argumentation that Johnson rightly warns against—treating these texts simply as “knockdown verse[s]” against women’s ordination to the priesthood, rather than engaging carefully with St. Paul’s reasoning in its immediate and canonical context.</p>
<p>For instance, what does Paul mean about forbidding women to teach men (1 Tim. 2:12) when he assumes elsewhere that they will, in fact, do so? And, when they do, Paul says they should do so with their heads covered (1 Cor. 11:2-16) and in good order (1 Cor. 14:1-33)?</p>
<p>Whatever we are to make of this, it is by no means simple and straightforward. We should not insult our interlocutors by suggesting that it is.</p>
<h2 id="i-want-to-be-very-clear-about-my-position-i-do-not-support-the-ordination-of-women-to-the-priesthood-despite-the-bible-i-support-it-because-of-the-bible">I want to be very clear about my position: I do not support the ordination of women to the priesthood <em>despite</em> the Bible; I support it <em>because</em> of the Bible.</h2>
<p>And I am by no means alone in this. I encourage those who argue against women’s ordination to the priesthood to engage the works of a great many respected and orthodox biblical scholars whose research on this subject directly refutes many, if not all, of the interpretive points Nelson and Johnson raise:</p>
<ul>
<li>Craig Keener (the new president of the Evangelical Theological Society),</li>
<li>Scot McKnight,</li>
<li>Ben Witherington III,</li>
<li>Nijay Gupta,</li>
<li>Cynthia Long Westfall,</li>
<li>Lucy Peppiatt,</li>
<li>N.T. Wright,</li>
<li>Gordon Fee,</li>
<li>Richard Bauckham,</li>
<li>I. Howard Marshall,</li>
<li>and Anthony Thiselton, among many others.</li>
</ul>
<p>In my view, Scripture does not, in fact, define narrowly what men and women are ontologically, nor does it demarcate women’s and men’s functions based solely on their gender. Such notions have to be read into the text.</p>
<p>Instead, the scriptures provide an overarching vision for women and men as different, distinct, and mutually submissive partners in the Kingdom of God. This was God’s intention from the beginning and it is a partnership restored in the reign of God inaugurated by Jesus Christ. And this new creation is something the church gets to embody as an outpost of the Kingdom within this fallen world until our Lord returns.</p>
<h2 id="other-questionsissues">Other Questions/Issues</h2>
<p>As I said at the beginning, the interpretation of Scripture is not the only area within which we must adjudicate the question of women’s ordination to the priesthood.</p>
<p>For the sake of clarity, I think it will be helpful to acknowledge some of the many questions raised by Johnson’s and Nelson’s responses:</p>
<h3 id="on-the-subject-of-scripture-and-its-interpretation">On the subject of Scripture and its interpretation:</h3>
<ul>
<li>What does the narrative of Scripture have to say about the meaning of being created male and female? Does Scripture indeed teach discrete roles or functions in the world and Christ’s church based on gender?</li>
<li>Does the canon speak with one voice on the subject of women and women’s “roles”? Or is there discernible development/movement within the canon?</li>
<li>More specifically, is the New Covenant best understood as continuous or discontinuous with the Old Covenant in regard to ecclesial leadership; namely, the priesthood?</li>
<li>How are we to interpret the passages in the letters of St. Paul, which seem to restrict women in some instances (1 Tim. 2:11-15; 1 Cor. 11:1-16; 1 Cor. 14:34-35), while freeing them and assuming their leadership in other instances (1 Cor. 12:1-31; 1 Cor. 14:1-33; Gal. 3:28; Rom. 16:1-16; Phil. 4:2-3)? What is the best way to interpret these passages so as to make sense of all of the evidence in the canon?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="on-the-subject-of-the-tradition">On the subject of the tradition:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Does the great tradition of Christianity speak with one voice on the subject of women in leadership, particularly, sacramental leadership? If not, what do we make of dissenting voices or practices within the tradition?</li>
<li>What do we make of <a href="http://www.palgrave.com/gp/book/9783030111106">recent findings</a> that suggest that significantly more expanded roles for women were operative in the earliest days of the church? Does this have any impact on our perspective on and interpretation of the tradition?</li>
<li>Does tradition need to be interpreted within its own contexts? Or are the voices of the tradition permitted to speak without regard to their own social and cultural norms (particularly in regard to their views of women)?</li>
<li>Along similar lines, are the conclusions of the early church fathers regarding women and women’s roles normative for Christians today? If so, why? And how so?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="on-the-subject-of-the-anglican-communions-relationship-to-other-catholic-bodies">On the subject of the Anglican Communion’s relationship to other catholic bodies:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Are Anglicans mainly Protestant or mainly Catholic, or something else entirely? And what impact does that have on our theological method and church practice?</li>
<li>Are the traditions of the Roman Catholic Church and Orthodox Church on the matter of women in the priesthood normative for the Anglican Communion?</li>
<li>More specifically, are the teachings of Pope John Paul II, particularly his “Theology of the Body,” which are often brought to bear on this issue, to be understood as normative for Anglicans today?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="on-the-subject-of-theological-method">On the subject of theological method:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Are arguments from natural law, upon which much of the “Theology of the Body” is based, appropriate within the Anglican theological tradition?</li>
<li>Is our conception of natural law context-free? Or, are our notions of what is “natural” in some way shaped by our social and cultural context—not to mention our fallenness and the fallenness of our world?</li>
<li>Should our biblical exegesis be constrained by the perspective of the church fathers? Or, is there room for <em>ecclesia semper reformanda</em> (“the church always being reformed”) within Anglican theological method?</li>
<li>Does the apparent work of the Holy Spirit in setting apart and empowering women for priestly ministry today—not just in the West, but in regions all over the world—have something to contribute to the discussion? Certainly, experience alone cannot be normative within the Anglican tradition, but can it be permitted a seat at the theological “table”?</li>
</ul>
<p>I could go on, but I’ll stop here.</p>
<h2 id="the-point-is-this-johnson-nelson-and-i-disagree-on-the-matter-of-womens-ordination-to-the-priesthood-not-because-i-do-not-take-the-authority-of-scripture-seriously-i-most-certainly-do-but-because-we-have-different-answers-to-a-number-of-vitally-important-questions">The point is this: Johnson, Nelson, and I disagree on the matter of women’s ordination to the priesthood, not because I do not take the authority of Scripture seriously (I most certainly do), but because we have different answers to a number of vitally important questions.</h2>
<p>For instance, I do not accept the premise that Nelson’s version of gender essentialism is taught by Scripture, nor do I find the church fathers teaching the same.</p>
<p>As I tell my students, every text has to be interpreted. Whether we’re talking about the tradition or the scriptures, “nature” or the church fathers, all these “texts” must be interpreted. And since the Anglican tradition does not have a Magisterium like the Roman Catholic Church’s, which can declare an issue definitively settled for all time (i.e., <a href="http://w2.vatican.va/content/john-paul-ii/en/apost_letters/1994/documents/hf_jp-ii_apl_19940522_ordinatio-sacerdotalis.html">John Paul II’s apostolic letter, <em>Ordinatio Sacerdotalis</em></a>), Anglicans must engage in the hard work of interpretation ever mindful of the fact that people of goodwill are going to disagree.</p>
<p>Moreover, this list of questions also makes clear that, because of the interplay of so many weighty matters (i.e., biblical exegesis and hermeneutics, historical and systematic theology, liturgical and sacramental theology, biology, sociology, and culture), the question of gender and its implications is probably one of the most complicated and challenging subjects facing the church today. This conversation is going to continue—as it should. And I hope we can continue to do so with humility and charity befitting sisters and brothers in Christ.</p>
<p>In some ways, it would be easier if we still lived in a time when <a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-the-argument-from-tradition-is-not-the-traditional-argument/">women were assumed to be physically, intellectually, emotionally, and spiritually inferior to men. Then, the argument would be moot, as it was for many years of the church’s history</a>. Obviously, inferior persons should not serve as priests in Christ’s church.</p>
<p>But we now know with certainty that women are <em>not</em> inherently inferior to men. Though essentially distinct in important ways—ways we are just beginning to understand—church leaders, biblical scholars, and theologians must consider carefully what these distinctions <em>mean.</em></p>
<p>Despite claims to the contrary, the meaning of gender difference is not, in fact, clear and obvious, and neither is the question of what impact that meaning should have on the structure of Christ’s body, the church.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>(Want to learn more about women’s ordination debates within Anglicanism? <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/">Start with these resources</a>.)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Women Can Be Saved, Then Women Can Be Priests: A Critique of the &#39;in persona Christi&#39; Argument Against Women&#39;s Ordination</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 05:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Pastor does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After reading this piece, please see &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/&#34;&gt;Lee Nelson’s response&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/&#34;&gt;Emily McGowin’s rejoinder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-connection-between-christology-and-soteriology&#34;&gt;The connection between christology and soteriology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cornerstone of orthodox Christian theology is summed up in the phrase “what is not assumed is not healed”. The phrase is echoed by many early church fathers, but it is credited to St. Gregory of Nazianzus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Pastor does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.</em></p>
<p><em>After reading this piece, please see <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/">Lee Nelson’s response</a> and <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/">Emily McGowin’s rejoinder</a>.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-connection-between-christology-and-soteriology">The connection between christology and soteriology</h2>
<p>A cornerstone of orthodox Christian theology is summed up in the phrase “what is not assumed is not healed”. The phrase is echoed by many early church fathers, but it is credited to St. Gregory of Nazianzus.</p>
<p>I teach this principle to undergraduates in my theology classes every semester when we are discussing the development of classical christology (the doctrine of Christ). And my students usually grasp the significance of this principle quite easily.</p>
<p>As the early church fathers sought to make sense of the revelation of God in Jesus Christ, they recognized that if Christ were not fully human—human in every way as we are, yet without sin—then Christ could not redeem humanity.</p>
<p>Thus, Jesus Christ had to have:</p>
<ul>
<li>a real human body,</li>
<li>a real human mind,</li>
<li>real human emotions, and</li>
<li>a real human soul.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the words of St. Gregory of Nazianzus:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“For that which he has not assumed he has not healed; but that which is united to his Godhead is also saved. If only half Adam fell, then that which Christ assumes and saves may be half also; but if the whole of his nature fell, it must be united to the whole nature of him that was begotten, and so be saved as a whole” (Epistle 101, 32).</p></blockquote>
<p>In this way, christology and soteriology (the doctrine of salvation) are intimately connected. To rescue us from the dominion of Sin, Evil, and Death, the Word, the Second Person of the Trinity, had to become like us.</p>
<p>As the divine Word, he could descend into the darkest depths of human sin and suffering without being overcome by them. And, as the Word-made-flesh, he could ascend to the heights of heaven following his resurrection—and bring us, now reconciled and united with God, along with him.</p>
<h2 id="implications">Implications</h2>
<p>If “what is not assumed is not healed” is a crucial, non-negotiable aspect of orthodox Christianity, then we do well to consider carefully its implications.</p>
<p>For example, if the flesh that the Word assumed in Jesus Christ was ethnically Jewish, does that mean Jesus cannot save Gentiles?</p>
<p>The church has consistently answered: No, of course not. In the logic of “what is not assumed is not healed,” what matters in the incarnation is Jesus’ <em>humanness</em>, not his Jewishness.</p>
<p>(To be clear, Jesus’ Jewishness is crucial to his person and work. Without recognizing that Jesus was a first-century Jew, and all the religious, social, and cultural implications that entails, one cannot fully understand Jesus and what he has done on our behalf. But what I’m exploring here is the logic at work in orthodox reasoning about christology and soteriology.)</p>
<p>Indeed, it is precisely in the particularities of Jesus Christ’s person that he can save all people. The particularity of the incarnation is the pathway to the universality of salvation. “[H]e had to be made like them, fully human in every way, in order that he might become a merciful and faithful high priest in service to God, and that he might make atonement for the sins of the people” and “not only for ours but also for the sins of the whole world” (Heb. 2:17; 1 Jn. 2:2).</p>
<p>As Beth Felker Jones says in her book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Practicing-Christian-Doctrine-Introduction-Theologically/dp/0801049334/ref=as_li_ss_tl?keywords=Practicing+Christian+Doctrine&amp;pd_rd_i=0801049334&amp;pd_rd_r=01c428a0-07cc-4048-8894-9d6ce2c96457&amp;pd_rd_w=P9xKu&amp;pd_rd_wg=KXfEi&amp;pf_rd_p=39e7c2a0-69e1-4a3f-8d8f-4c4ee1aefdb5&amp;pf_rd_r=66AKMKQNSQTGPJWF63JS&amp;psc=1&amp;qid=1569494218&amp;s=gateway&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=anglicanpasto-20&amp;linkId=6d704c46c306131181f6420e60ccefbf&amp;language=en_US"><em>Practicing Christian Doctrine</em></a>, “Jesus does not come among us as a generic human being; he comes as we do, with particulars.” The truth is, there is no such thing as a generic human being. So, in order to be human, the Word had to become a particular human being, with ethnicity, culture, language, sex, gender, and more.</p>
<p>What, then, of Jesus’ maleness? Can a male Christ save women?</p>
<p>Yes, orthodox theologians reply. Yes, of course he can.</p>
<p>Why? Because in assuming the flesh and blood, soul and spirit, of a particular human being, the Word has assumed the flesh and blood, soul and spirit of <em>all</em> human beings—including women.</p>
<p>(It is worth observing that, according to orthodox Christian teaching, the human nature of Jesus Christ was formed in the womb of the Virgin Mary, without the contribution of male “flesh” whatsoever. The Word-made-flesh receives his human flesh from a woman. I am grateful to my colleague, Rev. Dr. Amy Peeler, for bringing this to my attention.)</p>
<p>Again, what matters for salvation is Jesus’ <em>humanness</em>, not Jesus’ maleness.</p>
<h2 id="now-what-does-all-this-have-to-do-with-womens-ordination">Now, what does all this have to do with women’s ordination?</h2>
<p>Quite a lot, actually.</p>
<p>Many arguments are proffered against women’s ordination, some biblical, some theological, some historical, some even biological and psychological. Of course, there is far more to the arguments for and against women’s ordination than this short piece is able to address.</p>
<p>For now, due to space constraints, I choose to focus on one argument against women’s ordination that I find particularly theologically problematic: The assertion that women cannot represent Christ in the celebration of the Eucharist; the claim that women cannot act <em>in persona Christi</em> (“in the person of Christ”).</p>
<p>The argument, in short, goes something like this: Because women have female bodies and Jesus Christ has a male body, women cannot serve as a sacramental sign of Christ in the Eucharist.</p>
<p>To be more specific, women cannot act <em>in persona Christi</em> because their female bodies do not correspond to the body of the male Christ. In this view, female priests are not just <em>not allowed</em>; female priests are <em>false signifiers</em>. In their female persons, female priests lie, as it were, about the male person of Jesus Christ, who is presiding sacramentally at the altar.</p>
<p>And, as a result, women must not represent Christ at the Eucharistic feast.</p>
<p>Today, very often, though not always, this perspective is linked to a form gender essentialism gleaned from Pope John Paul II’s “<a href="http://amzn.to/2lXRIO3">theology of the body</a>” and his recent popularizer, <a href="http://amzn.to/2mV9kdy">Christopher West</a>.</p>
<p>In the theology of the body, male and female are seen as ontologically distinct, two parts of the one whole of the <em>imago Dei.</em> This “natural” gender division then serves as the foundation for structured gender roles.</p>
<p>When it comes to the function of the priesthood, then, the male sacramentally represents Christ while the female sacramentally represents the Church. Within this perspective, to have a woman priest is to usurp and upend a fundamental ontological reality of the world God has made.</p>
<p>But this brings us back to our christological and soteriological principle: “what is not assumed is not healed”. If women qua women are fundamentally incapable—and, according to some Christians, even <em>ontologically</em> incapable—of representing the male Jesus Christ in their female persons, then that calls into question whether their female persons can be redeemed by the male Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>But, of course, we know that isn’t the case.</p>
<p>All human beings—Jew and Greek, male and female, slave and free—are saved through the Incarnation of the Word (the life, death, resurrection and ascension of Jesus Christ).</p>
<p>The particularities of Jesus’ person—a poor, Jewish, male, unmarried, 30-something adult living in first-century, Roman-occupied Israel—are the means by which <em>all</em> human persons are redeemed. And, by becoming one with Christ in our baptism, all become partakers of his Royal Priesthood.</p>
<p>If that’s the case, then all persons are potentially capable of serving as sacramental signs of their Savior.</p>
<h2 id="responding-to-an-objection-arent-redemption-and-sacramental-representation-different">Responding to an objection: Aren’t redemption and sacramental representation different?</h2>
<p>But, some might object: “Jesus, though male, can redeem women. But women can’t sacramentally represent Jesus because redemption and sacramental representation are two different things.”</p>
<p>I would respond: On what basis does the concept of sacramental representation rest?</p>
<p>Many things could be addressed on this front, but I’ll specify only a few.</p>
<h3 id="first-the-idea-of-sacramentality-is-rooted-in-part-in-the-analogy-of-being">First, the idea of sacramentality is rooted, in part, in the analogy of being.</h3>
<p>An analogy does not require a pure one-to-one correspondence—indeed, in Christian theology it specifies the opposite. Between creature and Creator there are similarities, but never such that the dissimilarities are not always greater. Thus, all analogies between God and human beings are inadequate. They are able to speak some real truth, but always fall short in the end.</p>
<p>Similarly, the sacramental representation of the priest will always fall short of pure representation because it is based on analogy.</p>
<h3 id="second-sacramental-representation-means-the-priest-functions-not-as-christ-but-as-an-icon-of-christ">Second, sacramental representation means the priest functions not <em>as Christ</em>, but as an <em>icon</em> of Christ.</h3>
<p>As William Witt has argued, priests are jars of clay, pointing away from him- or herself and pointing to Christ the High Priest, particularly as they share in his suffering (2 Cor. 4:5-10).</p>
<p>What is central is not physical similarity to the male body of Christ, but the priest’s participation in the pattern of Christ, the Suffering Servant. Insofar as the priest demonstrates this participation, the priest serves as a sacramental representation.</p>
<h3 id="finally-if-the-sacramental-validity-of-the-priesthood-is-based-in-significant-part-upon-the-sexed-and-gendered-body-of-the-priest-that-is-a-male-body-to-match-the-male-christ-then-we-find-ourselves-in-a-bit-of-a-bind">Finally, if the sacramental validity of the priesthood is based in significant part upon the sexed and gendered body of the priest (that is, a male body to match the male Christ), then we find ourselves in a bit of a bind.</h3>
<p>As Sarah Coakley (among others) has shown, in the course of the Eucharistic service, the priest not only acts <em>in persona Christi</em>, but also <em>in persona Ecclesiae</em>, which, in the imagery of Eph. 5:22, is gendered female.</p>
<p>If a woman cannot act <em>in persona Christi</em> because her female body does not match the male body of Christ, then how will a man act <em>in persona Ecclesiae</em> when his male body does not match the female Church?</p>
<p>The answer, of course, is that they can; because the priestly body functions sacramentally, or analogically.</p>
<h3 id="no-matter-which-priestly-body-is-the-subject-of-scrutiny-all-bodies-inevitably-fall-short-of-a-pure-one-to-one-correspondence-between-the-sexed-and-gendered-body-of-human-beings-and-the-bride-and-bridegroom-they-are-meant-to-represent">No matter which priestly body is the subject of scrutiny, all bodies inevitably fall short of a pure one-to-one correspondence between the sexed and gendered body of human beings and the Bride and Bridegroom they are meant to represent.</h3>
<p>And that brings us back to the principle of analogy. No human body exactly, literally, univocally corresponds to our Great High Priest, Jesus Christ. But, they do not have to. They need only serve as analogues, which is, in fact, core to what sacrament means in the first place.</p>
<p>Let us return then to Gregory’s great insight, “what is not assumed is not healed,” and put my overall point as plainly as possible:</p>
<h2 id="conclusion-if-christ-in-his-male-body-saves-women-through-their-shared-humanity-then-women-through-their-shared-humanity-with-christ-can-represent-christ-at-the-altar">Conclusion: If Christ in his male body saves women through their shared humanity, then women, through their shared humanity with Christ, can represent Christ at the altar.</h2>
<p>If they cannot—if, in their female bodies, women are incapable of serving as sacramental signs of the male Savior, Jesus Christ—then women’s salvation is in jeopardy, as is the salvation of all who differ from Christ in their embodied particulars.</p>
<p>The good news of “what is not assumed is not healed” is that this jeopardy is decidedly <em>not</em> the case. The Word-made-flesh has made provision in his life, death, resurrection, and ascension for the salvation of all humankind. As Gregory of Nazianzus insisted: “[God] has assumed humanity for our salvation … that by one and the same person, who was perfect man and also God, the entire humanity fallen through sin might be created anew” (Epistle 101, 34).</p>
<p>Do women demonstrate bodily differences from the God-man, Jesus Christ? Yes, of course they do.</p>
<p>But it is by virtue of those very distinctions that women offer a powerful sacramental sign of our Great High Priest and the new creation he has inaugurated in his body. And we who feast at Eucharistic tables presided over by women priests get to see glimpses of this new creation every Sunday.</p>
<h2 id="postscript-further-reading">Postscript: Further Reading</h2>
<p>The argument offered here is inspired, in part, by the following resources. I recommend them to you for further reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>Thomas F. Torrance, <a href="http://amzn.to/2mVXCiM"><em>Royal Priesthood: A Theology of Ordained Ministry</em></a>, 2nd Edition (London: T &amp; T Clark, 2003).</li>
<li>Sarah Coakley, “<a href="http://www.anglicantheologicalreview.org/read/issue/13/">The Woman at the Altar: Cosmological Disturbance or Gender Subversion?</a>” <em>Anglican Theological Review</em>, 86.1 (2004): 75-93.</li>
<li>William G. Witt, “Concerning Women’s Ordination: Women’s Ordination and the Priesthood of Christ”, accessed September 12, 2019: <a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-and-the-priesthood-of-christ/">http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-and-the-priesthood-of-christ/</a>.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/adam_jones/27713547834">Featured image by Adam Jones via Flickr</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/">Want to learn more about women’s ordination debates within Anglicanism? Check out these resources.</a></p>
<p><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/write-for-anglican-pastor/">Want to write for Anglican Pastor? Check out our writing guidelines.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to Learn More about Women’s Ordination Debates within Anglicanism? Start With These Resources</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe you, like me, are coming to Anglicanism from a different tradition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that’s the case, then one thing you should know is that Anglican debates about women’s ordination can often be quite different from debates about the same topic in other church contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is due to Anglicans having different views on, among other things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ecclesiology (the doctrine of the church),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the sacraments, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in my broadly evangelical/non-denominational/Baptist upbringing, debates about women in ministry centered on whether or not women were allowed to preach and teach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maybe you, like me, are coming to Anglicanism from a different tradition.</p>
<p>If that’s the case, then one thing you should know is that Anglican debates about women’s ordination can often be quite different from debates about the same topic in other church contexts.</p>
<p>This is due to Anglicans having different views on, among other things:</p>
<ul>
<li>ecclesiology (the doctrine of the church),</li>
<li>the sacraments, and</li>
<li>ordination.</li>
</ul>
<p>For example, in my broadly evangelical/non-denominational/Baptist upbringing, debates about women in ministry centered on whether or not women were allowed to preach and teach.</p>
<p>In Anglican circles, although you can still find debates about preaching/teaching, I’ve found that people place much more focus on whether or not women can administer the sacraments as priests.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in learning more about the contours of Anglican debates on women’s ordination, I recommend that you start out by reading the <strong>2017 ACNA Holy Orders Task Force Report</strong>. It is an especially useful document for those coming from a USA evangelical background into Anglicanism.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-acna-holy-orders-task-force-report-2017">The ACNA Holy Orders Task Force Report (2017)</h2>
<p><em>Here’s an excerpt from <a href="http://anglicanchurch.net/?/main/page/1448">the official ACNA announcement of the report</a>, quoted from the ACNA website.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>In 2012 the College of Bishops appointed a Task Force on Holy Orders to provide the College with a scholarly and informed study on Holy Orders and, specifically, women in Holy Orders (the enabling resolution is reprinted in what follows). The Task Force, led by Bishop David Hicks, consisted of people representing differing perspectives and practices. They have met for the past 5 years and during that time have periodically released progress reports. This past January Bishop Hicks presented a report on the last phase of the process to the College, and we are now releasing the whole report to the Province.</p></blockquote>
<p>You can download a PDF of the entire report by <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce.pdf">clicking here</a>.</p>
<p>The report is quite long (318 pages). So, I’ve broken it up into shorter PDFS.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-1_The-Task-Force-and-its-Process.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 1_The Task Force and its Process.pdf">Section I: The Task Force and its Process</a> (pp. 1–11)</li>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-2_A-Unified-Approach-to-Scripture.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 2_A Unified Approach to Scripture.pdf">Section II: A Unified Approach to Scripture</a> (pp. 12–17)</li>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-3_Principles-of-Anglican-Ecclesiology.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 3_Principles of Anglican Ecclesiology.pdf">Section III: Principles of Anglican Ecclesiology</a> (pp. 18–256)</li>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-4_Arguments-For-and-Against.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 4_Arguments For and Against.pdf">Section IV: The Arguments For and Against [Women’s Ordination]</a> (pp. 257–311)</li>
<li>NOTE: The “evangelical” portion of this section relies heavily upon <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/AMIA_2003_Womens-Ordination-Report.pdf" title="AMIA_2003_Women's Ordination Report.pdf">this 2003 AMIA Report on Women’s Ordination</a>. In fact, when it comes to the exegesis of specific biblical texts, the ACNA report simply quotes from the AMIA report. See pages 269–74 of the ACNA Report and pages 37–105 of the AMIA Report.</li>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-5_Analysis-and-Conclusion.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 5_Analysis and Conclusion.pdf">Section V: Analysis and Conclusions</a> (pp. 312–18).</li>
</ul>
<p>As you can tell from the list above, <strong>if you’d like to read the arguments for and against women’s ordination, check out <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-4_Arguments-For-and-Against.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 4_Arguments For and Against.pdf">section 4</a> on pages 257 to 311</strong>. You’ll also need to consult <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/AMIA_2003_Womens-Ordination-Report.pdf" title="AMIA_2003_Women's Ordination Report.pdf">this 2003 AMIA Report on Women’s Ordination</a>.</p>
<p>I <em>highly</em> recommend that you at least <strong>take the time to read Section 5, because it includes a final summary of the task force’s findings, including their recommendations to the College of Bishops</strong>.</p>
<p>Speaking of which, the College of Bishops issued a statement on the ordination of women on September 7, 2017.</p>
<h2 id="a-statement-from-the-acna-college-of-bishops-on-the-ordination-of-women">A Statement from the ACNA College of Bishops on the Ordination of Women</h2>
<p><em>Click <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/?/main/page/1519">here</a> to see the original version of this on the ACNA website, which includes an introduction from Archbishop Foley Beach.</em></p>
<p>In the preamble to the statement, the Bishops say the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In an act of mutual submission at the foundation of the Anglican Church in North America, it was agreed that each Diocese and Jurisdiction has the freedom, responsibility, and authority to study Holy Scripture and the Apostolic Tradition of the Church, and to seek the mind of Christ in determining its own convictions and practices concerning the ordination of women to the diaconate and the priesthood. It was also unanimously agreed that women will not be consecrated as bishops in the Anglican Church in North America. These positions are established within our Constitution and Canons and, because we are a conciliar Church, would require the action of both Provincial Council and Provincial Assembly to be changed.</p></blockquote>
<p>Then, they proceed to the statement itself:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Having gratefully received and thoroughly considered the five-year study by the Theological Task Force on Holy Orders, we acknowledge that there are differing principles of ecclesiology and hermeneutics that are acceptable within Anglicanism that may lead to divergent conclusions regarding women’s ordination to the priesthood. However, we also acknowledge that this practice is a recent innovation to Apostolic Tradition and Catholic Order. We agree that there is insufficient scriptural warrant to accept women’s ordination to the priesthood as standard practice throughout the Province. However, we continue to acknowledge that individual dioceses have constitutional authority to ordain women to the priesthood.</p></blockquote>
<p>Finally, the Bishops state their commitments moving forward:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As a College of Bishops, we confess that our Province has failed to affirm adequately the ministry of all Christians as the basic agents of the work of the Gospel. We have not effectively discipled and equipped all Christians, male and especially female, lay and ordained, to fulfill their callings and ministries in the work of God’s kingdom. We repent of this and commit to work earnestly toward a far greater release of the whole Church to her God-given mission.</p>
<p>Having met in Conclave to pray, worship, study, talk, and listen well to one another, we commit to move forward in unity to carry on the good witness and work that God has given us to do in North America (Ephesians 4:1-6; John 17). We invite and urge all members of the Province to engage with us in this endeavor to grow in understanding the mission and ministry of all God’s people.</p></blockquote>
<p>This statement was adopted unanimously by the ACNA College of Bishops in September 2017. It describes the current state of the issue in the ACNA.</p>
<h2 id="whats-the-acnas-position-on-womens-ordination">What’s The ACNA’s Position on Women’s Ordination?</h2>
<p>This question is included on the <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/index.php/main/faq/">ACNA’s FAQ page</a>. Here’s the answer:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>At the inception of the Anglican Church in North America, the lead Bishops unanimously agreed to work together for the good of the Kingdom. As part of this consensus, it was understood that there were differing understandings regarding the ordination of women to Holy Orders, but there existed a mutual love and respect for one another and a desire to move forward for the good of the Church. This commitment was deeply embedded in the Constitution and Canons overwhelmingly adopted by the Inaugural Assembly (2009).</p>
<p>In respect of the two integrities concerning Holy Orders, three matters were specifically agreed in Constitution and Canons:</p>
<p>(1) The Province shall make no canon abridging the authority of any member dioceses, clusters or networks (whether regional or affinity-based) and those dioceses banded together as jurisdictions with respect to its practice regarding the ordination of women to the diaconate or presbyterate (Constitution, Article VIII)<br>
(2) Except as hereinafter provided, the norms for ordination shall be determined by the Bishops having jurisdiction. (Title III Canon 1.4)<br>
(3) To be a suitable candidate for the episcopate (bishop), a person must: Be a male Presbyter at least 35 years old. (Title III Canon 8.3.7)</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="which-acna-dioceses-dodont-ordain-women">Which ACNA Dioceses Do/Don’t Ordain Women?</h2>
<p>To put some numbers to this debate, <a href="http://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QG0EDrpgGnfPf668T5qsnUcczUA_g6b3HjgbPC-aiTg/edit?usp=sharing">I’ve produced the following chart</a>. <a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/acna/Congregational_Report_to_Provincial_Council_2018.pdf">The congregation/membership/attendance data comes from this 2018 report.</a> Please let me know if you spot any errors!</p>
<p>Click the image below to view the most recent version of the spreadsheet on Google Sheets.</p>
<p><a href="http://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QG0EDrpgGnfPf668T5qsnUcczUA_g6b3HjgbPC-aiTg/edit?usp=sharing"><img loading="lazy" src="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Screen-Shot-2020-01-14-at-11.33.22-AM.png" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="bibliography-for-further-study">Bibliography for Further Study</h2>
<p>If you’d like to do some more reading and research on this topic, then the Task Force Report has a very helpful <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Bibliography-for-Further-Study.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Bibliography for Further Study.pdf">annotated Bibliography for Further Study</a> (pp. 300–11 of the Task Force Report).</p>
<p>Click the link above to download the PDF of just the bibliography. Otherwise, I’ve listed the works below, without the annotations/descriptions.</p>
<p>Note that I’m still trying to find links to everything. Amazon links below are all affiliate links.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="womens-ordination-from-an-evangelical-perspective">Women’s Ordination from an Evangelical Perspective</h2>
<hr>
<h3 id="books-in-favor-of-womens-ordination">Books in favor of Women’s Ordination</h3>
<h4 id="collections-of-essays">Collections of Essays</h4>
<ul>
<li>Mickelsen, Alvera (editor), <a href="http://amzn.to/2UrIUf9"><em>Women, Authority &amp; the Bible.</em></a> InterVarsity Press, 1986.</li>
<li>Pierce, Ronald W. and Rebecca Merrill Groothius (editors), <a href="http://amzn.to/2ShMk6H"><em>Discovering Biblical Equality: Complementarity Without Hierarchy,</em></a> Second Edition (InterVarsity Press, 2005).</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="general-works-on-women-in-the-new-testament-and-the-early-church">General Works on Women in the New Testament and the Early Church</h4>
<ul>
<li>Bauckham, Richard, <a href="http://amzn.to/2TlNrPZ"><em>Gospel Women: Studies of the Named Women in the Gospels.</em></a> Eerdmans, 2002.</li>
<li>Cooper, Kate, <a href="http://amzn.to/2WvkZx5"><em>Band of Angels: The Forgotten World of Early Christian Women.</em></a> The Overlook Press, 2013.</li>
<li>Keener, Craig S., <a href="http://amzn.to/2WoeFaC"><em>Paul, Women &amp; Wives: Marriage and Women’s Ministry in the Letters of Paul.</em></a> Hendrickson Publishers,1992.</li>
<li>Macy, Gary, <a href="http://amzn.to/2Uqfi1C"><em>The Hidden History of Women’s Ordination: Female Clergy in the Medieval West.</em></a> Oxford University Press, 2008.</li>
<li>Payne, Philip B., <a href="http://amzn.to/2DJ9Txf"><em>Man and Woman, One in Christ: An Exegetical and Theological Study of Paul’s Letters.</em></a> Zondervan, 2009</li>
<li>Witherington, Ben III, <a href="http://amzn.to/2DLQI5R"><em>Women and the Genesis of Christianity.</em></a> Cambridge University Press, 1990.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="commentaries-on-i-corinthians-111-16-and-1434-34">Commentaries on I Corinthians (11:1-16 and 14:34-34)</h4>
<ul>
<li>Peppiatt, Lucy, <a href="http://amzn.to/2GdKAVt"><em>Women and Worship at Corinth: Paul’s Rhetorical Arguments in I Corinthians.</em></a> Cascade Books, 2015.</li>
<li>Thiselton, Anthony C., <a href="http://amzn.to/2Wuf3V7"><em>The First Epistle to the Corinthians.</em></a> Eerdmans, 2000: in The New International Greek Testament Commentary).</li>
<li>Witherington, Ben III, <a href="http://amzn.to/2CU5ANV"><em>Conflict &amp; Community in Corinth: A Socio-Rhetorical Commentary on I and II Corinthians.</em></a> Eerdmans, 1995.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="commentaries-on-i-timothy-2-8-8-15">Commentaries on I Timothy 2: 8-8-15</h4>
<ul>
<li>Fee, Gordon D., <a href="http://amzn.to/2SfZO2O"><em>1 &amp; 2 Timothy, Titus.</em></a> Baker Books, 2011.</li>
<li>Kroeger, Catherine Clark and Richard Clark Kroeger, <a href="http://amzn.to/2DLEhal"><em>I Suffer Not a Woman: Rethinking I Timothy 2:11-15 in Light of Ancient Evidence.</em></a> Baker Book House, 1992.</li>
<li>Wright, N.T., <em>1 &amp; 2 Timothy and Titus.</em> InterVarsity Press, 2009 [Here’s <a href="http://amzn.to/2GgEl3c">the commentary</a>. Here’s <a href="http://amzn.to/2Ga7zky">the study guide</a>.]</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="books-containing-a-variety-of-views">Books containing a variety of views</h3>
<h4 id="collections-of-essays-1">Collections of Essays</h4>
<ul>
<li>Clouse, Bonnidell and Robert G., eds., <a href="http://amzn.to/2UtANyq"><em>Women in Ministry: Four Views.</em></a> Downers Grove: IVP, 1989.</li>
<li>Beck, James R. and Blomberg, Craig L., eds., <em>Two Views on Women in Ministry.</em> Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2001. (See the <a href="http://amzn.to/2RXjl8U">Revised Edition, published in 2005</a>.)</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="books-not-in-favor-of-womens-ordination">Books not in favor of women’s ordination</h3>
<h4 id="collections-of-essays-2">Collections of Essays</h4>
<ul>
<li>Piper, John and Grudem, Wayne, eds., <a href="http://amzn.to/2GbTD9t"><em>Recovering Biblical Manhood and Womanhood: A Response to Evangelical Feminism.</em></a> Wheaton, Ill.: Crossway, 1991.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="general-works-on-women-in-the-new-testament-and-the-early-church-1">General Works on Women in the New Testament and the Early Church*</h4>
<ul>
<li>Mitchell, Patrick, <a href="http://amzn.to/2SaZItp"><em>The Scandal of Gender: Early Christian Teaching on the Man and the Woman.</em></a> Salisbury, Mass.: Regina Orthodox Press, 1998.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="works-discussing-mens-and-womens-roles-in-the-church-and-society">Works discussing Men’s and Women’s roles in the Church and Society</h4>
<ul>
<li>Clark, Stephen B., <a href="http://amzn.to/2MFlVuh"><em>Man and Woman in Christ: An Examination of the Roles of Men and Women in Light of Scripture and the Social Sciences.</em></a> Ann Arbor, Mich.: Servant, 1980.</li>
<li>Harper, Michael, <a href="http://amzn.to/2CZmiLI"><em>Equal and Different: Male and Female in Church and Family.</em></a> London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1994.</li>
<li>Hurley, James B., <a href="http://amzn.to/2FYFUUb"><em>Man and Woman in Biblical Perspective.</em></a> Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 1981.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="works-discussing-relevant-scripture-passages">Works discussing relevant Scripture Passages</h4>
<ul>
<li>Hauke, Manfred, <a href="http://amzn.to/2CT23PN"><em>Women in the Priesthood?: A Systematic Analysis in the Light of the Order of Creation and Redemption,</em></a> tr. David Kipp. San Francisco: Ignatius, 1986.</li>
<li>Köstenberger, Andreas J., Schreiner, Thomas R., and Baldwin, H. Scott, eds., <a href="http://amzn.to/2GaPxOV"><em>Women in the Church: A Fresh Analysis of 1 Timothy 2:9-15.</em></a> Grand Rapids: Baker, 1995.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="studies-and-articles">Studies and Articles</h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.paludavia.com/anglican/w.pdf">“A Report of the Study Concerning the Ordination of Women Undertaken by the Anglican Mission in America: A survey of the Leading Theological Convictions,”</a> unpublished paper by the Rt. Rev. John H. Rodgers and the Women’s Ordination Study Team (July 31, 2003)</li>
<li>This is the 2003 AMIA Report upon which Section 4 of the 2017 ACNA Report relies.</li>
<li><a href="http://enit-syd.sds.asn.au/Site/104629.asp?ph=cp">“The Doctrine of the Trinity and Its Bearing on the Relationship of Men and Women,”</a> the 1999 Sydney Anglican Diocesan Doctrine Commission Report</li>
<li><a href="http://www.tsm.edu/2014/09/03/women_ordination_and_the_bible/">“Women, Ordination and the Bible”,</a> written by Rod Whitacre, 28 August 2014</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="womens-ordination-from-an-anglo-catholic-perspective">Women’s Ordination from an Anglo-catholic Perspective</h2>
<h3 id="general-anglican-sources">General Anglican Sources</h3>
<ul>
<li>[Church of England]. <em>The Priesthood of the Ordained Ministry.</em> London: Church House Publishing, 1986.</li>
<li>[Church of England]. <a href="http://amzn.to/2TnRQSC"><em>The Ordination of Women to the Priesthood: A Second Report by the House of Bishops of the General Synod of the Church of England</em>.</a> London: Church House Publishing, 1988.</li>
<li>[Church of England]. <a href="http://amzn.to/2UtBhoe"><em>Women Bishops in the Church of England? A Report of the House of Bishops’ Working Party on Women in the Episcopate.</em></a> London: Church House Publishing, 2004.</li>
<li>Avis, Paul, ed. <a href="http://amzn.to/2UtB3NU"><em>Seeking the Truth of Change in the Church: Reception, Communion and the Ordination of Women</em>.</a> London: T and T Clark, 2004.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="catholic-perspectivenotable-sources">Catholic Perspective—Notable Sources</h3>
<ul>
<li>Beattie, Tina. <a href="http://amzn.to/2GcUg2w"><em>God’s Mother, Eve’s Advocate: A Marian Narrative of Women’s Salvation</em>.</a> London: Continuum, 2002.</li>
<li>Kirk, Geoffrey. <a href="http://amzn.to/2SfyjGt"><em>Without Precedent: Scripture, Tradition, and the Ordination of Women</em>.</a> Eugene, OR: Wipf and Stock, 2016.</li>
<li>Lewis, C.S. <a href="http://www.episcopalnet.org/TRACTS/priestesses.html">‘Priestesses in the Church?’</a> In <em>Undeceptions: Essays on Theology and Ethics</em>. London: Geoffrey Bles, 1971. 191-196. Also printed in <em>God in the Dock</em>.</li>
<li>Loades, Ann. ‘On Women.’ In <a href="http://amzn.to/2WxNKJt"><em>The Cambridge Companion to C.S. Lewis</em></a>, ed. Robert MacSwain and Michael Ward. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2010. 160-173.</li>
<li>Mascall, E.L. <a href="http://trushare.com/Mascall%20Women%20Priests.htm">‘Women Priests?’</a> London: The Church Literature Association, 1972.</li>
<li>Podmore, Colin, ed. <a href="http://amzn.to/2WxrAqH"><em>Fathers in God? Resources for Reflection on Women in the Episcopate.</em></a> Norwich: Canterbury Press, 2015.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="ecumenical-sources">Ecumenical Sources</h3>
<ul>
<li>[Paul VI.] <a href="http://www.vatican.va/roman_curia/congregations/cfaith/documents/rc_con_cfaith_doc_19761015_inter-insigniores_en.html"><em>Inter insigniores (Declaration on the Question of Admission of Women to the Ministerial Priesthood).</em></a> Rome: Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith, 1976.</li>
<li>[John Paul II.] <a href="http://w2.vatican.va/content/john-paul-ii/en/apost_letters/1994/documents/hf_jp-ii_apl_19940522_ordinatio-sacerdotalis.html"><em>Ordinatio sacerdotalis (Apostolic Letter of John Paul II to the Bishops of the Catholic Church on Reserving Priestly Ordination to Men Alone).</em></a> Rome: Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith, 1992.</li>
<li>[John Paul II.] <a href="http://www.vatican.va/roman_curia/congregations/cfaith/documents/rc_con_cfaith_doc_19951028_dubium-ordinatio-sac_en.html"><em>Responsum ad propositum dubitum Concerning the Teaching Contained in ‘Ordinatio sacerdotalis.’</em></a> Rome: Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith, 1995.</li>
<li>Butler, Sr. Sara. <a href="http://amzn.to/2WueMl3"><em>The Catholic Priesthood and Women: A Guide to the Teaching of the Church</em>.</a> Chicago: Hillenbrand Books, 2007.</li>
<li>Behr-Sigel, Elizabeth and Kallistos Ware, <a href="http://amzn.to/2WueElz"><em>The Ordination of Women in the Orthodox Church</em>.</a> Geneva: World Council of Churches, 2000.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="catholic-perspectiveother-sources">Catholic Perspective—Other Sources</h3>
<ul>
<li>Baker, Jonathan, ed. <a href="http://amzn.to/2SjCtgw"><em>Consecrated Women? A Contribution to the Women Bishops Debate.</em></a> Norwich: Canterbury Press, 2004.</li>
<li>Beattie, Tina. ‘Vision and Vulnerability: The Significance of Sacramentality and the Woman Priest for Feminist Theology.’ In <a href="http://amzn.to/2SgU6O9"><em>Exchanges of Grace: Essays in Honour of Ann Loades</em>.</a> London: SCM Press, 2008. 235-249.</li>
<li>Bridge, G.R. <a href="http://amzn.to/2WqdCXT"><em>Women and the Apostolic Ministry?</em></a> Parry Sound, ON: The Convent Society, 1997.</li>
<li>Loades, Ann. <a href="http://biblicalstudies.org.uk/pdf/anvil/21-2_113.pdf">‘Women in the Episcopate?’</a> <em>Anvil</em> 21 no. 2 (2004): 113-119.</li>
<li>MacKinnon, Donald. <a href="http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0040571X9209500206">‘The <em>Icon Christi</em> and Eucharistic Theology.’</a> <em>Theology</em> (March/April 1992): 109-113.</li>
<li>Mascall, E.L. <a href="http://www.womenpriests.org/ecumenism/women-and-the-priesthood-of-the-church-by-e-l-mascall-from-why-not-priesthood-and-the-ministry-of-women/">‘Women and the Priesthood of the Church.’</a> London: The Church Literature Association, 1960.</li>
<li>Richardson, Alan. ‘Women and the Priesthood.’ In <a href="http://amzn.to/2MIcZEG"><em>Lambeth Essays on Ministry: Essays Written for the Lambeth Conference 1968.</em></a> Ed. Arthur Michael Ramsey. London: SPCK, 1969. 75-78.</li>
<li>Underhill, Evelyn. ‘Ideals of the Ministry of Women.’ In <a href="http://amzn.to/2WuEvK2"><em>Mixed Pasture: Twelve Essays and Addresses</em>.</a> Eugene, OR: Wipf and Stock 2015. 113-122.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="works-not-mentioned-in-the-task-force-report">Works Not Mentioned in the Task Force Report</h2>
<ul>
<li>Lynn H. <strong>Cohick</strong> and Amy <strong>Brown Hughes</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/2Wu90Qp"><em>Christian Women in the Patristic World: Their Influence, Authority, and Legacy in the Second through Fifth Centuries</em></a>, Baker Academic, 2017.</li>
<li>Gordon P. <strong>Hugenberger</strong>, <a href="http://womeninthechurch.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/hugenberger%20women%20in%20church%20office%20re%20husbands%20and%20wives%20issue%20in%201%20timothy%202.pdf">“Women in Church Office: Hermeneutics or Exegesis? A Survey of Approaches to 1 TIM 2:8-15,”</a> <em>JETS</em> 35/3 (1992): 341–60.</li>
<li>Michael <strong>Lee-Barnewall</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/2SfN2RU"><em>Neither Complementarian nor Egalitarian: A Kingdom Corrective to the Evangelical Gender Debate</em></a>, Baker Academic, 2016.</li>
<li>Kevin <strong>Madigan</strong> and Carolyn <strong>Osiek</strong>, eds., <a href="http://amzn.to/2WsBWIt"><em>Ordained Women in the Early Church: A Documentary History</em></a>, Johns Hopkins, 2011.</li>
<li>Scot <strong>McKnight</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/2RcCxgN"><em>The Blue Parakeet: Rethinking How You Read the Bible</em></a>, 2nd edition, Zondervan, 2018. Especially Part 5 (chs. 14–19), “Women in Church Ministries Today.”</li>
<li>Lucy <strong>Peppiatt</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/3auozPd"><em>Rediscovering Scripture’s Vision for Women: Fresh Perspectives on Disputed Texts</em></a>, IVP Academic, 2019.</li>
<li>John G. <strong>Stackhouse</strong>, Jr., <a href="http://amzn.to/38oEKeT"><em>Partners in Christ: A Conservative Case for Egalitarianism</em></a>, IVP Academic, 2015.</li>
<li>Kallistos <strong>Ware</strong>, <a href="http://www.womenpriests.org/articles-books/man-woman-and-the-priesthood-of-christ-by-kallistos-ware-from-man-woman-and-priesthood/">“Man, Woman, and the Priesthood of Christ,” pp. 68-90 in <em>Man, Woman, and Priesthood</em></a>, edited by Peter Moore, SPCK London, 1978.</li>
<li>Cynthia <strong>Long Westfall</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/2RYQyRp"><em>Paul and Gender: Reclaiming the Apostle’s Vision for Men and Women in Christ</em></a>, Baker Academic, 2016.</li>
<li>Ben <strong>Witherington</strong> III, <a href="http://amzn.to/2WsBLNj"><em>Women in the Earliest Churches (Society for New Testament Studies Monograph Series)</em></a>, Cambridge, 1991.</li>
<li>William <strong>Witt</strong>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Icons-Christ-Biblical-Systematic-Ordination/dp/1481313193?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr=&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=anglicanpasto-20&amp;linkId=8e8fa373219652321476ab03ffe6ffb0&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"><em>Icons of Christ: A Biblical and Systematic Theology for Women’s Ordination</em></a>, Baylor University Press, 2020.</li>
<li>William <strong>Witt</strong>‘s <a href="http://willgwitt.org/category/theology/womens-ordination/">series of blog posts on women’s ordination</a>.</li>
<li>N.T <strong>Wright</strong>, <a href="http://ntwrightpage.com/2016/07/12/womens-service-in-the-church-the-biblical-basis/">“Women’s Service in the Church: The Biblical Basis”</a></li>
</ul>
<p>What works would you add to this reading list?</p>
<p>What specific questions do you have?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
