<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 16:22:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/productivity/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Questions at the Start of My Notebook</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/questions-at-the-start-of-my-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:04:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/questions-at-the-start-of-my-notebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve loosely followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://bulletjournal.com/&#34;&gt;the &amp;ldquo;Bullet Journal&amp;rdquo; method of note-taking&lt;/a&gt;. Usually in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/4aiTbCs&#34;&gt;Leuchtturm1917 Hardcover A5 notebook with dotted pages&lt;/a&gt; (the best!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I finish one notebook and start another, among other things, I like to write down some key questions and mental models at the front of the new notebook, so that I can easily refer back to them whenever I need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve written at the start of my current notebook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the past few years, I&rsquo;ve loosely followed <a href="https://bulletjournal.com/">the &ldquo;Bullet Journal&rdquo; method of note-taking</a>. Usually in a <a href="https://amzn.to/4aiTbCs">Leuchtturm1917 Hardcover A5 notebook with dotted pages</a> (the best!).</p>
<p>Whenever I finish one notebook and start another, among other things, I like to write down some key questions and mental models at the front of the new notebook, so that I can easily refer back to them whenever I need to.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ve written at the start of my current notebook.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="questions-to-improve-results"><a href="https://joshkaufman.net/49-questions-better-results/">Questions to Improve Results</a></h2>
<h3 id="do-i-use-my-body-optimally">Do I use my body optimally?</h3>
<ul>
<li>What is the quality of my current diet?</li>
<li>Do I get enough sleep?</li>
<li>Am I managing my energy well each day?</li>
<li>How do I manage daily stress?</li>
<li>Do I have good posture and poise?</li>
<li>What can I do to improve my ability to observe the world around me?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="do-i-know-what-i-want">Do I know what I want?</h3>
<ul>
<li>What achievements would make me really excited?</li>
<li>What “states of being” do I want to experience each day?</li>
<li>Are my priorities and values clearly defined?</li>
<li>Am I capable of making decisions quickly and confidently?</li>
<li>Do I consistently focus my attention on what I want vs. what I don’t want?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="what-am-i-afraid-of">What am I afraid of?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Have I created an honest and complete list of the fears I’m holding on to?</li>
<li>Have I confronted each fear to imagine how I would handle it if it came to pass?</li>
<li>Am I capable of recognizing and correcting self-limitation?</li>
<li>Am I appropriately pushing my own limits?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="is-my-mind-clear-and-focused">Is my mind clear and focused?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Do I systematically externalize (write or record) what I think about?</li>
<li>Am I making it easy to capture my thoughts quickly, as I have them?</li>
<li>What has my attention right now?</li>
<li>Am I regularly asking myself appropriate guiding questions?</li>
<li>Do I spend most of my time focusing on a single task, or constantly flipping between multiple tasks?</li>
<li>Do I spend enough time actively reflecting on my goals, projects, and progress?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="am-i-confident-relaxed-and-productive">Am I confident, relaxed, and productive?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Have I found a planning method that works for me?</li>
<li>Am I “just organized enough”?</li>
<li>Do I have an up-to-date list of my projects and active tasks?</li>
<li>Do I review all of my commitments on a regular basis?</li>
<li>Do I take regular, genuine breaks from my work?</li>
<li>Am I consciously creating positive habits?</li>
<li>Am I working to shed non-productive habits?</li>
<li>Am I comfortable with telling other people “no”?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="how-do-i-perform-best">How do I perform best?</h3>
<ul>
<li>What do I particularly enjoy?</li>
<li>What am I particularly good at doing?</li>
<li>What environment do I find most conducive to doing good work?</li>
<li>How do I tend to learn most effectively?</li>
<li>How do I prefer to work with and communicate with others?</li>
<li>What is currently holding me back?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="what-do-i-really-need-to-be-happy-and-fulfilled">What do I really need to be happy and fulfilled?</h3>
<ul>
<li>How am I currently defining “success”?</li>
<li>Is there another way of defining “success” that I may find more fulfilling?</li>
<li>How often do I compare myself to my perceptions of other people?</li>
<li>Am I currently living below my means?</li>
<li>If I could only own 100 things, what would they be?</li>
<li>Am I capable of separating necessity and luxury?</li>
<li>What do I feel grateful for in my life and work?</li>
</ul>
<p>(For more great questions, see my <a href="/questions-worth-asking/">&ldquo;Questions Worth Asking&rdquo; post</a>.)</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="ivy-lee-method">Ivy Lee Method</h2>
<ol>
<li>Write down the 6 most important things you need to accomplish tomorrow. (No more than 6!)</li>
<li>Prioritize those 6 items in order of their true importance.</li>
<li>Tomorrow, focus on the first task until it is completed before moving on to the second task, and so on.</li>
<li>At the end of the day, move any unfinished items to a new list of 6 tasks for the following day.</li>
</ol>
<p>Repeat! <strong>Do the most important things first.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="impact-vs-effort-matrix">Impact vs. Effort Matrix</h2>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th></th>
          <th><strong>Low Effort</strong></th>
          <th><strong>High Effort</strong></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>High Impact</strong></td>
          <td>Quick Wins</td>
          <td>Major Projects</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>Low Impact</strong></td>
          <td>Low-Hanging Fruit</td>
          <td>Not worth doing!</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<h2 id="decisions">Decisions</h2>
<h3 id="prediction">Prediction</h3>
<ul>
<li>What&rsquo;s the current reality?</li>
<li>What&rsquo;s the range of likely future outcomes?</li>
<li>What do I expect will happen?</li>
<li>What does the consensus think?</li>
<li>How do my expectations differ from the consensus?</li>
<li>What is the worst-case scenario? Am I willing to accept it?</li>
<li>What is the best-case scenario? How likely is it?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="decision">Decision</h3>
<ul>
<li>What&rsquo;s my decision?</li>
<li>What&rsquo;s the probability that I&rsquo;m correct?</li>
<li>If I ignored experience and only considered facts, what choice would I make?</li>
<li>What am I giving up? By making this decision, what am I not doing?</li>
<li>How do I feel right now, physically and emotionally?</li>
<li>How will I feel about this decision when I&rsquo;m 100 years old?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="review">Review</h3>
<ul>
<li>What actually happened?</li>
<li>If good, did I just get lucky? Or was my decision process correct?</li>
<li>If bad, did I just get unlucky? Or was my decision process incorrect?</li>
<li>What did I learn?</li>
<li>How can I improve my decision-making process in the future?</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="second-order-thinking">Second-Order Thinking</h2>
<ul>
<li>If A, then B. And then what?</li>
<li>What will the consequences be in 10 minutes, 10 months, and 10 years?</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="simple-check-in">Simple Check-In</h2>
<p>Notice and write down your objections to this statement: &ldquo;Everything in my life is exactly the way I want it to be.&rdquo;</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="five-minute-journal-questions">Five-Minute Journal Questions</h2>
<ul>
<li>Morning
<ul>
<li>What are 3 things I&rsquo;m grateful for?</li>
<li>What would make today great?</li>
<li>Daily affirmations: I am…</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Evening
<ul>
<li>What are 3 amazing things that happened today?</li>
<li>How could I have made today even better?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="morning-questions">Morning Questions</h2>
<ol>
<li>What’s one thing I’m grateful for?</li>
<li>What’s one thing I’m excited about?</li>
<li>What’s one virtue I want to exhibit?</li>
<li>What’s one thing I’m avoiding?</li>
<li>What’s the one thing I need to do?</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="evening-questions">Evening Questions</h2>
<ol>
<li>What were my biggest wins of the day?</li>
<li>Did I have any major realizations?</li>
<li>What’s on the agenda for tomorrow?</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h2 id="8020-questions">80/20 Questions</h2>
<ol>
<li>Where am I feeling satisfied?</li>
<li>Where am I feeling dissatisfied?</li>
<li>For each of the above, what are the 20% of places, habits, people, beliefs, etc. that are responsible for 80% of the positive and negative results?</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h2 id="bottleneck-breaker">Bottleneck Breaker</h2>
<ol>
<li>What’s the biggest bottleneck to achieving my next goal?</li>
<li>Why aren’t I working on it today?</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h2 id="compounding">Compounding</h2>
<ol>
<li>If I repeated every action from today for one year, where would I end up?</li>
<li>Is this the place I want to be?</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h2 id="important-vs-urgent-the-eisenhower-matrix">Important vs. Urgent: The Eisenhower Matrix</h2>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th></th>
          <th><strong>Urgent</strong></th>
          <th><strong>Not Urgent</strong></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>Important</strong></td>
          <td>Do</td>
          <td>Schedule</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>Not Important</strong></td>
          <td>Delegate</td>
          <td>Delete</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
