<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Anglican Compass on Joshua P. Steele</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/anglican-compass/</link><description>Recent content in Anglican Compass on Joshua P. Steele</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 06:00:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/anglican-compass/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I'm a Female Priest and I Support My Opponents in the Women's Ordination Debate</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-a-female-priest-and-i-support-my-opponents-in-the-womens-ordination-debate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 06:00:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-a-female-priest-and-i-support-my-opponents-in-the-womens-ordination-debate/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is not unanimous agreement about women’s ordination in the worldwide Anglican Communion. Godly and thoughtful Christians hold opposing convictions about Holy Orders and who is called to ordained ministry. You often see the results of this debate at the Provincial level—a national expression of the Church may or may not ordain women, in accordance with their conviction. But for the Anglican Church in North America this disagreement is internal to the Province, varying from diocese to diocese and bishop to bishop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For the Good of the Order: A Plea for Charity on the Ordination of Women</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/for-the-good-of-the-order-a-plea-for-charity-on-the-ordination-of-women/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 06:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/for-the-good-of-the-order-a-plea-for-charity-on-the-ordination-of-women/</guid><description>&lt;p>Almost every vocational deacon I know, when asked why he or she has not become a priest, will respond, “I have never felt called to the priesthood.” Some will add emphatically, “not for a minute!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not one of those deacons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t share this story often, rarely in its fullness, and never in public non-anonymous writing. Be gentle with my soul, O Church. The words which follow are all too raw.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Letter to Fellow ACNA Clergy: On Anti-Racism and a More Diverse and Just Anglicanism</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>NOTE&lt;/strong>: As is our policy with &lt;em>all&lt;/em> Anglican Compass content, we ask that you &lt;a href="https://anglicancompass.com/republishing-guidelines/">please submit a request before republishing content&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://adoc.church/a-letter-concerning-the-death-of-george-floyd-and-so-many-others/">&lt;em>recently wrote&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &lt;em>in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care. Whether you’re ACNA clergy, a layperson, or a Christian leader outside the ACNA, we invite your consideration of the following and your &lt;a href="#sign">signature&lt;/a> in support.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don’t Stir the Pot?</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dont-stir-the-pot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:21:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dont-stir-the-pot/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m pondering the “don’t stir the pot” reaction that reliably happens every time we publish something on women’s ordination—most especially anything in &lt;em>favor&lt;/em> of women’s ordination—&lt;a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">over at Anglican Compass&lt;/a>, where I’m the Managing Editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>(Note: This post is not a subtweet of anyone in particular. It’s just me thinking out loud about a phenomenon that keeps occurring.)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almost every time we post something about women’s ordination, a controversial issue has been whether or not doing so needlessly “stirs the pot,” as in “causes trouble, unrest, dissent.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Altar and the Arena: What Slaves and Martyrs Have to Teach Us About Women’s Ordination</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-altar-and-the-arena-what-slaves-and-martyrs-have-to-teach-us-about-womens-ordination/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-altar-and-the-arena-what-slaves-and-martyrs-have-to-teach-us-about-womens-ordination/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Compass does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Over the past several months, readers of Anglican Compass have engaged with many opinions on &lt;a href="http://anglicancompass.com/tag/womens-ordination/">the topic of women’s ordination&lt;/a>. One wonders, given the state of dual integrities within the ACNA and the ever-churning blog debates between our public intellectuals, what is the point of another take on this issue?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>We switched Anglican Compass over from HostGator Shared to Bluehost VPS Hosting</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 15:28:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</guid><description>&lt;p>As of this morning, it looks like everything for &lt;a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">Anglican Compass&lt;/a> has been successfully moved over from our HostGator shared hosting to Bluehost VPS hosting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m hoping that this new arrangement works well for us! Although, to be honest, it’s still an open question in my mind whether or not managed WordPress hosting with WPEngine would be a better fit. I just can’t quite tell whether or not it would be worth the extra cost, given our current traffic and budget.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taking Scripture and Women’s Ordination Seriously: A Response to Blake Johnson and Lee Nelson</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:31:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Editor’s Note: Thank you to the Rev. Dr. Emily McGowin for writing this rejoinder to &lt;a href="http://theopolisinstitute.com/sacramental-representation-and-the-created-order/">Fr. Blake Johnson’s&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/">Fr. Lee Nelson’s&lt;/a> responses to &lt;a href="http://anglicancompass.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/">her original blog post&lt;/a> about the&lt;/em> in persona Christi &lt;em>argument against women’s ordination. While we invite this conversation (about McGowin’s original blog post) to continue in our comments section and elsewhere—and we plan to publish more about women’s ordination in the future—we will not be adding surrejoinder blog posts.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If Women Can Be Saved, Then Women Can Be Priests: A Critique of the 'in persona Christi' Argument Against Women's Ordination</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 05:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Pastor does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>After reading this piece, please see &lt;a href="http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/">Lee Nelson’s response&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://anglicancompass.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/">Emily McGowin’s rejoinder&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="the-connection-between-christology-and-soteriology">The connection between christology and soteriology&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A cornerstone of orthodox Christian theology is summed up in the phrase “what is not assumed is not healed”. The phrase is echoed by many early church fathers, but it is credited to St. Gregory of Nazianzus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Want to Learn More about Women’s Ordination Debates within Anglicanism? Start With These Resources</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:31:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maybe you, like me, are coming to Anglicanism from a different tradition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If that’s the case, then one thing you should know is that Anglican debates about women’s ordination can often be quite different from debates about the same topic in other church contexts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is due to Anglicans having different views on, among other things:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ecclesiology (the doctrine of the church),&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the sacraments, and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ordination.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For example, in my broadly evangelical/non-denominational/Baptist upbringing, debates about women in ministry centered on whether or not women were allowed to preach and teach.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>