<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 21:40:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/writing/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ph.D. Plan (Or the Lack Thereof)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 21:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For months and months now, I’ve been praying for either (1) a breakthrough on my “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” dissertation or (2) a clear sign that I should quit the Ph.D. Unfortunately, after countless confusing dead ends in my endeavors to put Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer into precise conversation with each other regarding specific passages of the Bible, I’ve now realized that such an approach is not going to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Shameless Request: Help Me Buy More Books?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 21:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After realizing just how easy it was to lose access to the physical books that I own (now sequestered in my library carrel at Wheaton), on a bit of a whim &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/donate/573962246651661/&#34;&gt;I created a fundraiser to help my upgrade my Logos Bible Software library&lt;/a&gt; to either the Anglican Gold ($216) or Anglican Platinum ($582) libraries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Upgrading would help me in my preaching, teaching, and writing roles (as a pastor-theologian and as the Managing Editor of AnglicanCompass.com). I’ve already benefited immensely from the Anglican Silver package I bought when I got into the Logos Bible Software ecosystem a couple years ago (mainly to gain easy digital access to Barth and Bonhoeffer’s writings for my dissertation). I plan to stick with Logos—especially for biblical commentaries, systematic theologies, and reference works—because it allows me to quickly research, prepare for sermons, answer questions from readers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They Say, I Say Writing Templates</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 17:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOURCE: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3eOMlXF&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;They Say / I Say: The Moves that Matter in Academic Writing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 4th edition (affiliate link). Perhaps the most helpful and practical book on academic writing!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;disagreeing-without-being-disagreeable&#34;&gt;Disagreeing Without Being Disagreeable&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While I understand the impulse to A, my own view is B.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While I agree with X that Y, I cannot accept her overall conclusion that Z.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While X argues Y, and I argue Z, in a way we’re both right.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-template-of-templates&#34;&gt;The Template Of Templates&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent discussions of A, a controversial issue has been whether B. On the one hand, some argue that C. From this perspective, D. On the other hand, however, others argue that E. In the words of F, one of this view’s main proponents, “G.” According to this view, H. In sum, then, the issue is whether I or J.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balderdash! 12 Suggestions for Overcoming Writer’s Block (From Andrew T. Le Peau’s “Write Better”)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 13:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writer’s block sucks. I’m currently facing it with regard to &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/&#34;&gt;my dissertation&lt;/a&gt; and I’ve decided to hit pause on research and writing until I regain access to my library carrell at Wheaton.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I’ve come across some helpful advice on overcoming writer’s block in Andrew T. Le Peau’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ZuTZC3&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Writer Better: A Lifelong Editor on Craft, Art, and Spirituality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book is &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; with helpful and practical advice on writing, rewriting, publishing, etc. To whet your appetite, I’d like to share some of Le Peau’s tips for conquering writer’s block. These all come from chapter 7, pages. 72–80.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Writing Templates</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/helpful-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 14:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/helpful-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following templates come from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/33TJdor&#34;&gt;They Say / I Say: The Moves That Matter in Academic Writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-what-they-say&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing What They Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A number of $$$ have recently suggested that $$$.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It has become common today to dismiss $$$.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In their recent work, Y and Z have offered harsh critiques of Dr. X for $$$.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-standard-views&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing Standard Views&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;American today tend to believe that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Conventional wisdom has it that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Common sense seems to dictate that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The standard way of thinking about topic X has it that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is often said that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My whole life I have heard it said that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You would think that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many people assumed that $$$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making What They Say Something You Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desperate Times, Desperate Measures: Writing My Dissertation vs. Funding Abortion</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/desperate-times-desperate-measures-writing-my-dissertation-vs-funding-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 13:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/desperate-times-desperate-measures-writing-my-dissertation-vs-funding-abortion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m two years in to my PhD program, and I need to finish writing this dissertation soon, or it’s going to be the death of me!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong. I love Wheaton’s program. My supervisor and second reader are fantastic. And I think that this Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible project is worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But I’ve got a wife, a kid, a commitment to the Church, and I need to move on with my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tree of Religion: Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge in Genesis 2:4–3:24</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-tree-of-religion-karl-barth-and-dietrich-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-in-genesis-24-324/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 15:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-tree-of-religion-karl-barth-and-dietrich-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-in-genesis-24-324/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Here’s a PDF of this paper: &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/STEELE_The-Tree-of-Religion-Barth-and-Bonhoeffer-on-the-Tree-of-Knowledge.pdf&#34;&gt;STEELE_The Tree of Religion Barth and Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The precise meaning of the “tree of the knowledge of good and evil” (=TK) has long vexed interpreters of Genesis 2:4–3:24.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#post-41779-footnote-1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; While the “tree of life” (=TL) is mentioned and alluded to throughout the Bible, the TK is explicitly mentioned by its full name just twice (Gen. 2:9, 17).&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#post-41779-footnote-2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Nevertheless, because of the significant role that the TK plays in the narrative, both Dietrich Bonhoeffer and Karl Barth highlight the TK in their theological interpretations of Genesis 1–3. Furthermore, both theologians describe the TK and the knowledge of good and evil (=KGE) in ways that resemble their theological critiques of “religion” as an improper response to divine revelation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When will Thy Kingdom Come? The Timing and Agency of the Kingdom of God in the Lord&#39;s Prayer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/when-will-thy-kingdom-come-the-timing-and-agency-of-the-kingdom-of-god-in-the-lords-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 15:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/when-will-thy-kingdom-come-the-timing-and-agency-of-the-kingdom-of-god-in-the-lords-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Here’s a PDF of this paper: &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/STEELE_When-Will-Thy-Kingdom-Come.pdf&#34;&gt;STEELE_When Will Thy Kingdom Come&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-thy-kingdom-haswill-come&#34;&gt;Introduction: “Thy Kingdom [Has/Will] Come”?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just how &lt;em&gt;eschatological&lt;/em&gt; is the Lord’s Prayer (=LP; Matt. 6:9–13; Luke 11:2–4), particularly in light of its second petition, “Your kingdom come” (ἐλθέτω ἡ βασιλεία σου, Matt. 6:10a; Luke 11:2d)? In other words, when will God’s kingdom come? Has it already arrived (not eschatological)? Is it in the process of arriving? Or will it arrive at some point in the future (eschatological)? Furthermore, who brings the kingdom about? Humans? God? Or some combination of the two? Settling the question of eschatology involves both the timing and the agency, the &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt;, of the kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spirit, Flesh, Restoration, and Sublimation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 18:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s an intriguing passage in Bonhoeffer’s Letters and Papers from Prison where he discusses the relationship between “spirit” and “flesh,” in the context of discussing “restoration” and “sublimation,” in the context of discussing lyrics from certain hymns and songs that were meaningful to him in prison.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here it is, from a December 19, 1943 (the Fourth Sunday of Advent) letter to Eberhard Bethge:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent weeks this line has been running through my head over and over: “Calm your hearts, dear friends; / whatever plagues you, / whatever fails you, / I will restore it all.” What does that mean, “I will restore it all”? Nothing is lost; in Christ all things are taken up, preserved, albeit in transfigured form, transparent, clear, liberated from the torment of self-serving demands. Christ brings all this back, indeed, as God intended, without being distorted by sin. The doctrine originating in Eph. 1:10 of the restoration of all things, ἀνακεφαλαίωσις—re-capitulatio (Irenaeus), is a magnificent and consummately consoling thought. (DBWE 8:229–30)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me StickK to my writing habit</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need to finish &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/&#34;&gt;this dissertation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I’ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it’s been a bear to get back on!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a fantastic wooden pencil (Mitsubishi 9850)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to give a quick shout-out to this fantastic pencil: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2QcXI2B&#34;&gt;the Mitsubishi 9850&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Mitsubishi-Pencil-pencil-hardness-K9850HB/dp/B001BKZVWU/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=li3&amp;amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;linkId=e6e38efe0138c6a5bb4092270163728e&amp;amp;language=en_US&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B001BKZVWU&amp;amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;language=en_US&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;l=li3&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B001BKZVWU&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s cheap, writes well, erases well, and looks great!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more on wooden pencils, read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-wooden-pencils/pt/633&#34;&gt;this JetPens guide to the best wooden pencils&lt;/a&gt;. And, while you’re at it, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-pencil-sharpeners/pt/710&#34;&gt;JetPens’ recommendations for the best pencil sharpeners&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Need to Develop a Writing Habit. Do You?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because good writing = good thinking, I believe that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; could benefit from developing the habit of regular writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, because I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Am a Ph.D. student about to begin work on his dissertation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Edit a blog (&lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/&#34;&gt;Rookie Anglican&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write this personal blog&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need to develop the habit of regular writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Up until now, I’ve largely relied upon writing in fits and starts, when the Muse descends, as it were.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
