<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <title>Theology on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theology on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
=======
    <title>theology on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in theology on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 13:46:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/theology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Logos 10 Bible Software: The Ultimate Theological Learning Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 13:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: If you’re serious about biblical and theological studies, you should invest in Logos 10 Bible Software. &lt;a href=&#34;https://partners.faithlife.com/click.track?CID=431490&amp;amp;AFID=529204&#34;&gt;Do so via my exclusive partner offer for Logos 10 here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I could go back in time and chat with Joshua Steele when he was a Bible &amp;amp; Spanish major in college, there are a few things I’d tell my younger self:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quit laughing at &lt;em&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/em&gt; by Mortimer J. Adler and READ the thing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baba ghanoush is superior to hummus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Study computer science sooner rather than later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bite the bullet and INVEST IN A LOGOS BIBLE SOFTWARE LIBRARY.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong. I love physical books as much as anyone, and I own quite a few (hundred)!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/logos-10-bible-software-the-ultimate-theological-learning-tool/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: If you’re serious about biblical and theological studies, you should invest in Logos 10 Bible Software. Do so via my exclusive partner offer for Logos 10 here!
If I could go back in time and chat with Joshua Steele when he was a Bible &amp;amp; Spanish major in college, there are a few things I’d tell my younger self:
Quit laughing at How to Read a Book by Mortimer J.</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help! I’m looking for the best Christian resources on the Bible, social justice, racism, Critical Race Theory, and Marxism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 17:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Help me out. I’m looking for the best, clearest, and most charitable explanations of the following three things:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the biblical and theological reasons for caring about social justice and systemic racism,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the unfair ways in which some have used accusations of Critical Race Theory (CRT) and Cultural Marxism to sideline legitimate Christian concerns about social justice and systemic racism, and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the legitimate Christian critiques of CRT and Marxism.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that there are plenty of resources out there that address each of the three items above!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</guid>
      <description>Help me out. I’m looking for the best, clearest, and most charitable explanations of the following three things:
the biblical and theological reasons for caring about social justice and systemic racism, the unfair ways in which some have used accusations of Critical Race Theory (CRT) and Cultural Marxism to sideline legitimate Christian concerns about social justice and systemic racism, and the legitimate Christian critiques of CRT and Marxism. Now, I know that there are plenty of resources out there that address each of the three items above!</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s more than one kind of &#34;priesthood&#34; in the New Testament</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/theres-more-than-one-kind-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 20:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/theres-more-than-one-kind-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/nbfr.12440&#34;&gt;this article in New Blackfriars&lt;/a&gt;, and it looks helpful, especially in the context of Anglican debates about women’s ordination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Title: “The Four Types of Priesthood in the New Testament: On Avoiding Confusions about What ‘Priesthood’ Means”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Author: Geoffrey Turner&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian discourse tends to treat the concept of ‘priesthood’ univocally, so that ordained priests are seen to share the priesthood of Christ. But a careful reading of Hebrews shows clearly that the priesthood of Christ is unique to him. There are four (even five) types of priest in the New Testament and each of them is distinct and not to be confused.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theres-more-than-one-kind-of-priesthood-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>Just came across this article in New Blackfriars, and it looks helpful, especially in the context of Anglican debates about women’s ordination.
Title: “The Four Types of Priesthood in the New Testament: On Avoiding Confusions about What ‘Priesthood’ Means”
Author: Geoffrey Turner
Abstract:
Christian discourse tends to treat the concept of ‘priesthood’ univocally, so that ordained priests are seen to share the priesthood of Christ. But a careful reading of Hebrews shows clearly that the priesthood of Christ is unique to him.</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the relationship between biblical and systematic/dogmatic theology?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 15:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the question we’re considering this week in our doctoral seminar on biblical and theological integration. Two of us are theologians and the other four are bible scholars. Should be interesting!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: we’ll have to save the difference(s) between systematic, historical, and dogmatic theology for another post!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the articles we were assigned to read for this week:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;D.A. Carson, “Systematic Theology and Biblical Theology” in the New Dictionary of Biblical Theology, pp. 89-104.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;D.A. Carson, “Unity and Diversity in the New Testament: The Possibility of Systematic Theology” in Scripture and Truth, D. A. Carson and J. D. Woodbridge, eds. (Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 1983), pp. 65-95.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;G. Hasel, “The Relationship between Biblical Theology and Systematic Theology” Trinity Journal 5 (1984): 113-27;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I.H. Marshall, “Climbing Ropes, Ellipses and Symphonies: The Relation between Biblical and Systematic Theology” in A Pathway into the Holy Scripture, P.E. Satterthwaite and D.F. Wright, eds. (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1994), 199–219.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;E.A. Martens, “Moving from Scripture to Doctrine” Bulletin for Biblical Research 15.1 (2005): 77-103.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kevin Vanhoozer, “Interpreting Scripture between the Rock of Biblical Studies and the Hard Place of Systematic Theology: The State of the Evangelical (Dis)union” in Richard Lints, ed., Renewing the Evangelical Mission (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2013), 201-25.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other than that, for the rest of the semester, we’re reading at least selections from the following works. The goal is to learn from examples of biblical and theological integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</guid>
      <description>This is the question we’re considering this week in our doctoral seminar on biblical and theological integration. Two of us are theologians and the other four are bible scholars. Should be interesting!
(Note: we’ll have to save the difference(s) between systematic, historical, and dogmatic theology for another post!)
Here are the articles we were assigned to read for this week:
D.A. Carson, “Systematic Theology and Biblical Theology” in the New Dictionary of Biblical Theology, pp.</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Christian Theology: A Draft Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 22:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a part of my “pedagogical experience” at Wheaton College this semester, I was required to draft a syllabus for an introduction to Christian theology. Feel free to let me know what you think in the comments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: the length of this syllabus doesn’t necessarily correspond to the difficulty of this course&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-information&#34;&gt;Contact Information&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Email: [REDACTED]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Phone: [REDACTED]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Office Hours (Buswell Library Carrell): T, W, R, 15:00–17:00.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course is an introduction to the methods of systematic theology and the major topics within biblical revelation. Special attention is given to the rationale for these Christian doctrines, their systematic interconnections as well as their development within the history of Christian thought, and their contemporary challenges. This class is your opportunity to reinforce why you believe what you believe and to examine how it impacts your life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>As a part of my “pedagogical experience” at Wheaton College this semester, I was required to draft a syllabus for an introduction to Christian theology. Feel free to let me know what you think in the comments.
Note: the length of this syllabus doesn’t necessarily correspond to the difficulty of this course
Contact Information Email: [REDACTED] Phone: [REDACTED] Office Hours (Buswell Library Carrell): T, W, R, 15:00–17:00. Course Description This course is an introduction to the methods of systematic theology and the major topics within biblical revelation.</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Models: A Helpful Model for Theology?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 15:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This idea has been bouncing around in my head for a bit. It’s not fully-formed by any means, but I’d like to get it out there and hear what you think of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here it is: “Mental Models” could be a helpful model for theology.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-mental-model&#34;&gt;What is a “mental model”?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition-of-mental-models&#34;&gt;Definition of mental models&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Put simply, a “mental model” is a concept used to help explain how the world works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</guid>
      <description>This idea has been bouncing around in my head for a bit. It’s not fully-formed by any means, but I’d like to get it out there and hear what you think of it.
Here it is: “Mental Models” could be a helpful model for theology.
What is a “mental model”? Definition of mental models Put simply, a “mental model” is a concept used to help explain how the world works.</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
