<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <image>
      <title>Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/default-social.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/default-social.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 16:22:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/writing/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ph.D. Plan (Or the Lack Thereof)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 21:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For months and months now, I’ve been praying for either (1) a breakthrough on my “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” dissertation or (2) a clear sign that I should quit the Ph.D. Unfortunately, after countless confusing dead ends in my endeavors to put Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer into precise conversation with each other regarding specific passages of the Bible, I’ve now realized that such an approach is not going to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For months and months now, I’ve been praying for either (1) a breakthrough on my “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” dissertation or (2) a clear sign that I should quit the Ph.D. Unfortunately, after countless confusing dead ends in my endeavors to put Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer into precise conversation with each other regarding specific passages of the Bible, I’ve now realized that such an approach is not going to work.</p>
<p>Perhaps I’ve missed something. Perhaps there’s a passage of Scripture out there that both Barth and Bonhoeffer wrote about that contains a theologically significant exegetical disagreement worth writing home about.</p>
<p>More likely: Barth and Bonhoeffer handled the Bible in different enough ways that comparing them as if they were two modern Bible commentators is a fool’s errand. Sure, it would have been great if, for example, they had a lengthy exegetical disagreement on whether or not Romans 7 describes the current Christian life. But I’ve been searching and searching for things like that, and I simply haven’t found them. Instead, I’ve found a cryptic student note here, a missing sermon manuscript there. This approach is simply not the dissertation that the subject matter requires. And it certainly hasn’t yielded anything <em>constructive</em> enough to meet Wheaton’s Ph.D. requirements!</p>
<p>This is the closest thing I’ve had to a breakthrough since starting the project. And, given that focusing on specific passages of Scripture was going to be the main thing that distinguished my project from other Barth and Bonhoeffer studies, this is a pretty crushing realization.</p>
<p>What’s more, I’ve essentially given up on using the “theological critique of religion” as a theological lens/scaffold, because getting clear on what Barth and Bonhoeffer meant by “religion” (an important step in understanding their relationship, I believe) was <em>not</em> helping me zero-in on particular biblical material. “Religion” is a slippery term in general, and it has many thematic tentacles, as it were, in Barth and Bonhoeffer’s writings. Construed a certain way, anything and everything that they said could be about “religion.”</p>
<p>So, where does that leave me?</p>
<p>Well, I’m convinced that <em>something</em> needs to change. I’m not prepared to continue sacrificing my mental, emotional, physical, and relational health on the altar of this Ph.D. Unfortunately, this isn’t exactly the clear sign that I should <em>quit</em> that I was hoping for. There are still other dissertation options within the realm of “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible.” They each have their downsides, and I’m not getting my hopes up, but they’re intriguing enough that I feel like I need to at least explore them before I call it quits.</p>
<p>The first step would be to revisit the secondary literature on Barth and the Bible and on Bonhoeffer and the Bible. Originally, I’d planned to briefly summarize this literature, mainly focusing on how what I was doing (examining particular Bible passages and reading them alongside Barth and Bonhoeffer) was different. <em>That</em> didn’t work!</p>
<p>So now it looks like I need to find an organic contribution to the secondary literature. I need to find some way that the particulars of Barth and Bonhoeffer’s theological exegesis goes beyond the portrait of the two theologians that’s been painted in the secondary literature. Hopefully I’ll be able to salvage some of my work on Genesis 1–3 and/or Matthew 5–7 to make an argument that goes beyond the secondary literature.</p>
<p>OR: I’ll realize that I have nothing of substance to contribute to this discussion, that others have done the work better than I could hope to, and I can go my not-so-merry way. In many ways, this <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/sunniegiles/2018/04/30/how-to-fail-faster-and-why-you-should/#6949cc94c177">“fail fast” option</a> seems preferable. I doubt that either Barth or Bonhoeffer would be happy with me for spending so much time thinking and writing about <em>their writings</em>, instead of thinking and writing about the identity and acts of the Triune God.</p>
<p>This means that, instead of transitioning to full-time work with Anglican Compass ASAP, I’m planning to remain a full-time doctoral student for this fall semester. If, by the end of the year, I don’t have any more clarity on this project, then I think I’ll throw in the towel. Perhaps I’m not supposed to be the Rev. Dr. Steele. At least not yet.</p>
<p>Sorry for the depressing post! Prayers are much appreciated. As I prepare for my fourth year as a Ph.D. student, I’m quickly running out of ideas and motivation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Shameless Request: Help Me Buy More Books?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 21:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After realizing just how easy it was to lose access to the physical books that I own (now sequestered in my library carrel at Wheaton), on a bit of a whim &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/donate/573962246651661/&#34;&gt;I created a fundraiser to help my upgrade my Logos Bible Software library&lt;/a&gt; to either the Anglican Gold ($216) or Anglican Platinum ($582) libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrading would help me in my preaching, teaching, and writing roles (as a pastor-theologian and as the Managing Editor of AnglicanCompass.com). I’ve already benefited immensely from the Anglican Silver package I bought when I got into the Logos Bible Software ecosystem a couple years ago (mainly to gain easy digital access to Barth and Bonhoeffer’s writings for my dissertation). I plan to stick with Logos—especially for biblical commentaries, systematic theologies, and reference works—because it allows me to quickly research, prepare for sermons, answer questions from readers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After realizing just how easy it was to lose access to the physical books that I own (now sequestered in my library carrel at Wheaton), on a bit of a whim <a href="https://www.facebook.com/donate/573962246651661/">I created a fundraiser to help my upgrade my Logos Bible Software library</a> to either the Anglican Gold ($216) or Anglican Platinum ($582) libraries.</p>
<p>Upgrading would help me in my preaching, teaching, and writing roles (as a pastor-theologian and as the Managing Editor of AnglicanCompass.com). I’ve already benefited immensely from the Anglican Silver package I bought when I got into the Logos Bible Software ecosystem a couple years ago (mainly to gain easy digital access to Barth and Bonhoeffer’s writings for my dissertation). I plan to stick with Logos—especially for biblical commentaries, systematic theologies, and reference works—because it allows me to quickly research, prepare for sermons, answer questions from readers, etc.</p>
<h2 id="within-a-single-day-the-fundraiser-received-341-that-leaves-just-241-to-reach-the-582-platinum-goal">Within a single day, the fundraiser received $341!! That leaves just $241 to reach the $582 Platinum goal!</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/donate/573962246651661/">If you can give a few bucks, I’d be very grateful</a>! And, whether or not you give money to the fundraiser, please always feel free to send me any questions you have about Anglicanism, the Bible, Christian theology, Church history, etc.! I want to put my resources and training to good use!</p>
<p>In case you’re curious, here are some of the resources I’m most excited to own digitally in the Anglican Platinum library. I’d get 447 resources total, but here are the ones I’m most excited about:</p>
<ul>
<li>The complete Ancient Christian Commentary on Scripture (I have the NT now but would gain access to the OT)</li>
<li>The Ancient Christian Doctrine Series</li>
<li>The Pillar New Testament Commentary Series</li>
<li>The Encyclopedia of Ancient Christianity</li>
<li>The Oxford Dictionary of the Christian Church</li>
<li>N.T. Wright’s Christian Origins and the Question of God Series</li>
<li>The 10-volume Theological Dictionary of the New Testament</li>
<li>The 8-volume Dictionary of Classical Hebrew</li>
<li>Thomas Oden’s 3-volume Systematic Theology</li>
<li>Wolfhart Pannenberg’s 3-volume Systematic Theology</li>
<li>Braaten and Jenson’s 2-volume Christian Dogmatics</li>
<li>The Encyclopedia of Christianity</li>
<li>The Oxford Library of Practical Theology</li>
<li>The 7-volume Lancelot Andrewes Collection</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They Say, I Say Writing Templates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 17:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOURCE: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3eOMlXF&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;They Say / I Say: The Moves that Matter in Academic Writing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 4th edition (affiliate link). Perhaps the most helpful and practical book on academic writing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disagreeing-without-being-disagreeable&#34;&gt;Disagreeing Without Being Disagreeable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I understand the impulse to A, my own view is B.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I agree with X that Y, I cannot accept her overall conclusion that Z.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While X argues Y, and I argue Z, in a way we’re both right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-template-of-templates&#34;&gt;The Template Of Templates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent discussions of A, a controversial issue has been whether B. On the one hand, some argue that C. From this perspective, D. On the other hand, however, others argue that E. In the words of F, one of this view’s main proponents, “G.” According to this view, H. In sum, then, the issue is whether I or J.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SOURCE: <a href="https://amzn.to/3eOMlXF"><em>They Say / I Say: The Moves that Matter in Academic Writing</em></a>, 4th edition (affiliate link). Perhaps the most helpful and practical book on academic writing!</p>
<h2 id="disagreeing-without-being-disagreeable">Disagreeing Without Being Disagreeable</h2>
<ul>
<li>While I understand the impulse to A, my own view is B.</li>
<li>While I agree with X that Y, I cannot accept her overall conclusion that Z.</li>
<li>While X argues Y, and I argue Z, in a way we’re both right.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-template-of-templates">The Template Of Templates</h2>
<p>In recent discussions of A, a controversial issue has been whether B. On the one hand, some argue that C. From this perspective, D. On the other hand, however, others argue that E. In the words of F, one of this view’s main proponents, “G.” According to this view, H. In sum, then, the issue is whether I or J.</p>
<p>My own view is that K. Though I concede that L, I still maintain that M. For example, N. Although some might object that O, I would reply that P. The issue is important because Q.</p>
<h2 id="introducing-what-they-say">Introducing What “They Say”</h2>
<ul>
<li>A number of have recently suggested that X.</li>
<li>It has become common today to dismiss X.</li>
<li>In their recent work, A and B have offered harsh critiques of C for D.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-standard-views">Introducing “Standard Views”</h2>
<ul>
<li>Americans today tend to believe that X.</li>
<li>Conventional wisdom has it that X.</li>
<li>Common sense seems to dictate that X.</li>
<li>The standard way of thinking about topic X has it that Y.</li>
<li>It is often said that X.</li>
<li>My whole life I have heard it said that X.</li>
<li>You would think that X.</li>
<li>Many people assume that X.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="making-what-they-say-something-you-say">Making What “They Say” Something You Say</h2>
<ul>
<li>I’ve always believed that X.</li>
<li>When I was a child, I used to think that X.</li>
<li>Although I should know better by now, I cannot help thinking that X.</li>
<li>At the same time that I believe X, I also believe Y.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-something-implied-or-assumed">Introducing Something Implied Or Assumed</h2>
<ul>
<li>Although none of them have ever said so directly, my teachers have often given me the impression that X.</li>
<li>One implication of X’s treatment of Y is that Z.</li>
<li>Although X does not say so directly, she apparently assumes that Y.</li>
<li>While they rarely admit as much, X often take for granted that Y.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-an-ongoing-debate">Introducing An Ongoing Debate</h2>
<ul>
<li>In discussions of X, one controversial issue has been A. On the one hand, B argues C. On the other hand, D contends E. Others even maintain F. My own view is G.</li>
<li>When it comes to the topic of X, most of us will readily agree that A. Where this agreement usually ends, however, is on the question of B. Whereas some are convinced that C, others maintain that D.</li>
<li>In conclusion, then, as I suggested earlier, defenders of X can’t have it both ways. Their assertion that Y is contradicted by their claim that Z.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="capturing-authorial-action">Capturing Authorial Action</h2>
<ul>
<li>X acknowledges that .</li>
<li>X agrees that .</li>
<li>X argues that .</li>
<li>X believes that .</li>
<li>X celebrates the fact that .</li>
<li>X claims that .</li>
<li>X complains that .</li>
<li>X concedes that .</li>
<li>X demonstrates that .</li>
<li>X denies/does not deny that .</li>
<li>X deplores the tendency to .</li>
<li>X emphasizes that .</li>
<li>X insists that .</li>
<li>X observes that .</li>
<li>X questions whether .</li>
<li>X refutes the claim that .</li>
<li>X reminds us that .</li>
<li>X reports that .</li>
<li>X suggests that .</li>
<li>X urges us to .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-quotations">Introducing Quotations</h2>
<ul>
<li>X states, “ .”</li>
<li>As the prominent philosopher X puts it, “ .”</li>
<li>According to X, “ .”</li>
<li>X himself writes, “ .”</li>
<li>In her book, , X maintains that “ ”</li>
<li>Writing in the journal , X complains that “ .”</li>
<li>In X’s view, “ .”</li>
<li>X agrees when she writes, “ .”</li>
<li>X disagrees when he writes, “ .”</li>
<li>X complicates matters further when he writes, “ .”</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="explaining-quotations">Explaining Quotations</h2>
<ul>
<li>Basically, X is saying .</li>
<li>In other words, X believes .</li>
<li>In making this comment, X urges us to .</li>
<li>X is corroborating the age-old adage that .</li>
<li>X’s point is that .</li>
<li>The essence of X’s argument is that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="disagreeing-with-reasons">Disagreeing, With Reasons</h2>
<ul>
<li>I think X is mistaken because she overlooks .</li>
<li>X’s claim that rests upon the questionable assumption that .</li>
<li>I disagree with X’s view that because, as recent research has shown, .</li>
<li>X contradicts herself / can’t have it both ways. On the one hand, she argues . On the other hand, she also says .</li>
<li>By focusing on , X overlooks the deeper problem of .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="agreeingwith-a-difference">Agreeing—With A Difference</h2>
<ul>
<li>I agree that because my experience confirms it.</li>
<li>X surely is right about because, as she may not be aware, recent studies have shown that .</li>
<li>X’s theory of is extremely useful because it sheds insight on the difficult problem of .</li>
<li>Those unfamiliar with this school of thought may be interested to know that it basically boils down to .</li>
<li>I agree that , a point that needs emphasizing since so many people believe .</li>
<li>If group X is right that , as I think they are, then we need to reassess the popular assumption that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="agreeing-and-disagreeing-simultaneously">Agreeing And Disagreeing Simultaneously</h2>
<ul>
<li>Although I agree with X up to a point, I cannot accept his overall conclusion that .</li>
<li>Although I disagree with much that X says, I fully endorse his final conclusion that .</li>
<li>Though I concede that , I still insist that .</li>
<li>Whereas X provides ample evidence that , Y and Z’s research on and convinces me that instead.</li>
<li>X is right that , but she seems on more dubious ground when she claims that .</li>
<li>While X is probably wrong when she claims that , she is right that .</li>
<li>I’m of two minds about X’s claim that . On the one hand, I agree that . On the other hand, I’m not sure if .</li>
<li>My feelings on the issue are mixed. I do support X’s position that , but I find Y’s argument about and Z’s research on to be equally persuasive.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="signaling-who-is-saying-what">Signaling Who Is Saying What</h2>
<ul>
<li>X argues .</li>
<li>According to both X and Y, .</li>
<li>Politicians , X argues, should .</li>
<li>Most athletes will tell you that .</li>
<li>My own view, however, is that .</li>
<li>I agree, as X may not realize, that .</li>
<li>But are real and, arguably, the most significant factor in .</li>
<li>But X is wrong that .</li>
<li>However, it is simply not true that .</li>
<li>Indeed, it is highly likely that .</li>
<li>X’s assertion that does not fit the facts.</li>
<li>X is right that .</li>
<li>X is wrong that .</li>
<li>X is both right and wrong that .</li>
<li>Yet a sober analysis of the matter reveals .</li>
<li>Nevertheless, new research shows .</li>
<li>Anyone familiar with should agree that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="embedding-voice-markers">Embedding Voice Markers</h2>
<ul>
<li>X overlooks what I consider an important point about .</li>
<li>My own view is that what X insists is a is in fact a .</li>
<li>I wholeheartedly endorse what X calls .</li>
<li>These conclusions, which X discusses in , add weight to the argument that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="entertaining-objections">Entertaining Objections</h2>
<ul>
<li>At this point I would like to raise some objections that have been inspired by the skeptic in me. She feels that I have been ignoring . “ ,” she says to me, “ .”</li>
<li>Yet some readers may challenge the view that .</li>
<li>Of course, many will probably disagree with this assertion that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="naming-your-naysayers">Naming Your Naysayers</h2>
<ul>
<li>Here many would probably object that .</li>
<li>But would certainly take issue with the argument that .</li>
<li>, of course, may want to question whether .</li>
<li>Nevertheless, both followers and critics of will probably argue that .</li>
<li>Although not all think alike, some of them will probably dispute my claim that .</li>
<li>are so diverse in their views that it’s hard to generalize about them, but some are likely to object on the grounds that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-objections-informally">Introducing Objections Informally</h2>
<ul>
<li>But is my proposal realistic? What are the chances of its actually being adopted?</li>
<li>Yet is it always true that ? Is it always the case, as I have been suggesting, that ?</li>
<li>However, does the evidence I’ve cited prove conclusively that ?</li>
<li>“Impossible,” some will say. “You must be reading the research selectively.”</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="making-concessions-while-still-standing-your-ground">Making Concessions While Still Standing Your Ground</h2>
<ul>
<li>Although I grant that , I still maintain that .</li>
<li>Proponents of X are right to argue that . But they exaggerate when they claim that .</li>
<li>While it is true that , it does not necessarily follow that .</li>
<li>On the one hand, I agree with X that . But on the other hand, I still insist that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="indicating-who-cares">Indicating Who Cares</h2>
<ul>
<li>used to think . But recently [or within the past few decades] suggests that .</li>
<li>These findings challenge the work of earlier researchers, who tended to assume that .</li>
<li>Recent studies like these shed new light on , which previous studies had not addressed.</li>
<li>Researchers have long assumed that . For instance, one eminent scholar of cell biology, , assumed in , her seminal work on cell structures and functions, that fat cells . As herself put it, “ ” (2012). Another leading scientist, , argued that fat cells “ ” (2011). Ultimately, when it came to the nature of fat, the basic assumption was that .</li>
<li>But a new body of research shows that fat cells are far more complex and that .</li>
<li>If sports enthusiasts stopped to think about it, many of them might simply assume that the most successful athletes . However, new research shows .</li>
<li>These findings challenge neoliberals’ common assumptions that .</li>
<li>At first glance, teenagers appear to . But on closer inspection .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="establishing-why-your-claims-matter">Establishing Why Your Claims Matter</h2>
<ul>
<li>X matters / is important because .</li>
<li>Although X may seem trivial, it is in fact crucial in terms of today’s concern over .</li>
<li>Ultimately, what is at stake here is .</li>
<li>These findings have important consequences for the broader domain of .</li>
<li>My discussion of X is in fact addressing the larger matter of .</li>
<li>These conclusions / This discovery will have significant applications in as well as in .</li>
<li>Although X may seem of concern to only a small group of , it should in fact concern anyone who cares about .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="commonly-used-transitions">Commonly Used Transitions</h2>
<h3 id="addition">Addition</h3>
<ul>
<li>also</li>
<li>and</li>
<li>besides</li>
<li>furthermore</li>
<li>in addition</li>
<li>in fact</li>
<li>indeed</li>
<li>moreover</li>
<li>so too</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="elaboration">Elaboration</h3>
<ul>
<li>actually</li>
<li>by extension</li>
<li>in other words</li>
<li>in short</li>
<li>that is</li>
<li>to put it another way</li>
<li>to put it bluntly</li>
<li>to put it succinctly</li>
<li>ultimately</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="example">Example</h3>
<ul>
<li>after all</li>
<li>as an illustration</li>
<li>consider</li>
<li>for example</li>
<li>for instance</li>
<li>specifically</li>
<li>to take a case in point</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="cause-and-effect">Cause and Effect</h3>
<ul>
<li>accordingly</li>
<li>as a result</li>
<li>consequently</li>
<li>hence</li>
<li>it follows, then</li>
<li>since</li>
<li>so</li>
<li>then</li>
<li>therefore</li>
<li>thus</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="comparison">Comparison</h3>
<ul>
<li>along the same lines</li>
<li>in the same way</li>
<li>likewise</li>
<li>similarly</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="contrast">Contrast</h3>
<ul>
<li>although</li>
<li>but</li>
<li>by contrast</li>
<li>conversely</li>
<li>despite</li>
<li>even though</li>
<li>however</li>
<li>in contrast</li>
<li>nevertheless</li>
<li>nonetheless</li>
<li>on the contrary</li>
<li>on the other hand</li>
<li>regardless</li>
<li>whereas</li>
<li>while</li>
<li>yet</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="concession">Concession</h3>
<ul>
<li>admittedly</li>
<li>although it is true that</li>
<li>granted</li>
<li>I concede that</li>
<li>naturally</li>
<li>of course</li>
<li>to be sure</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>as a result</li>
<li>consequently</li>
<li>hence</li>
<li>in conclusion, then</li>
<li>in short</li>
<li>in sum, then</li>
<li>it follows, then</li>
<li>so</li>
<li>the upshot of all this is that</li>
<li>therefore</li>
<li>thus</li>
<li>to sum up</li>
<li>to summarize</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="translation-recipes">Translation Recipes</h2>
<ul>
<li>Scholar X argues, “ .” In other words, .</li>
<li>Essentially, X argues .</li>
<li>X’s point, succinctly put, is that .</li>
<li>Plainly put, .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="adding-metacommentary">Adding Metacommentary</h2>
<ul>
<li>In other words, .</li>
<li>What really means by this is .</li>
<li>Ultimately, my goal is to demonstrate that .</li>
<li>My point is not , but .</li>
<li>To put it another way, .</li>
<li>In sum, then, .</li>
<li>My conclusion, then, is that, .</li>
<li>In short, .</li>
<li>What is more important, .</li>
<li>Incidentally, .</li>
<li>By the way, .</li>
<li>Chapter 2 explores , while Chapter 3 examines .</li>
<li>Having just argued that , let us now turn our attention to .</li>
<li>Although some readers may object that , I would answer that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="linking-to-what-they-say">Linking To What “They Say”</h2>
<ul>
<li>As X mentions in this article, “ .”</li>
<li>In making this comment, X warns that .</li>
<li>Economists often assume ; however, new research by X suggests .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-gaps-in-the-existing-research">Introducing Gaps In The Existing Research</h2>
<ul>
<li>Studies of X have indicated . It is not clear, however, that this conclusion applies to .</li>
<li>often take for granted that . Few have investigated this assumption, however.</li>
<li>X’s work tells us a great deal about . Can this work be generalized to ?</li>
<li>Our understanding of remains incomplete because previous work has not examined .</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balderdash! 12 Suggestions for Overcoming Writer’s Block (From Andrew T. Le Peau’s “Write Better”)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 13:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writer’s block sucks. I’m currently facing it with regard to &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/&#34;&gt;my dissertation&lt;/a&gt; and I’ve decided to hit pause on research and writing until I regain access to my library carrell at Wheaton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I’ve come across some helpful advice on overcoming writer’s block in Andrew T. Le Peau’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ZuTZC3&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Writer Better: A Lifelong Editor on Craft, Art, and Spirituality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; with helpful and practical advice on writing, rewriting, publishing, etc. To whet your appetite, I’d like to share some of Le Peau’s tips for conquering writer’s block. These all come from chapter 7, pages. 72–80.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Writer’s block sucks. I’m currently facing it with regard to <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/">my dissertation</a> and I’ve decided to hit pause on research and writing until I regain access to my library carrell at Wheaton.</p>
<p>Thankfully, I’ve come across some helpful advice on overcoming writer’s block in Andrew T. Le Peau’s <a href="https://amzn.to/2ZuTZC3"><em>Writer Better: A Lifelong Editor on Craft, Art, and Spirituality</em></a> (affiliate link).</p>
<p>The book is <em>filled</em> with helpful and practical advice on writing, rewriting, publishing, etc. To whet your appetite, I’d like to share some of Le Peau’s tips for conquering writer’s block. These all come from chapter 7, pages. 72–80.</p>
<ol>
<li>Read lots of stuff. Fill up the tank!</li>
<li>Keep an idea file. Gather tidbits whenever and wherever you can.</li>
<li>Take notes on anything and everything.</li>
<li>Copy the greats. Literally. Take out a classic passage and start copying it down verbatim.</li>
<li>Get some rest. Do something different than you normally do.</li>
<li>Play Balderdash. It’s good practice for coming up with words on the spot without overthinking.</li>
<li>Don’t judge yourself just yet. First, write as a “Madman.” Anything goes! Then, go over what you’ve written as an “Architect.” Then, as a “Carpenter.” Finally, as a “Judge.”</li>
<li>Hit pause, especially if writer’s block is due to a life event.</li>
<li>If you are an extrovert, try talking things out with a friend. Then, if the friend is willing to stick around, try writing while they’re still there! (This might have to be adapted via Zoom these days.)</li>
<li>If you’re a detail person, then research the crap out of your topic. Just set a deadline for yourself so you don’t research forever!</li>
<li>If you can’t land the plane, find an accountability partner (“who is not a peer,” Le Peau specifies. “It needs to be someone you respect and will listen to, who has some authority in your life” pg. 79) and set a deadline.</li>
<li>Remember that writing is difficult! You shouldn’t expect good writing to come easy.</li>
</ol>
<p>Again, I really need to take Le Peau’s advice when I get back to working on my dissertation after the stay-at-home order is lifted in Illinois! If you find any of these suggestions helpful, or if you work with words in any way, I highly recommend that you read Le Peau’s <a href="https://amzn.to/2ZuTZC3"><em>Write Better</em></a>! You should also check out his blog at <a href="https://andyunedited.com/">https://andyunedited.com/</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Writing Templates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/helpful-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 14:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/helpful-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following templates come from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/33TJdor&#34;&gt;They Say / I Say: The Moves That Matter in Academic Writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-what-they-say&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing What They Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A number of $$$ have recently suggested that $$$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has become common today to dismiss $$$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In their recent work, Y and Z have offered harsh critiques of Dr. X for $$$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-standard-views&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing Standard Views&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;American today tend to believe that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conventional wisdom has it that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common sense seems to dictate that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The standard way of thinking about topic X has it that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is often said that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My whole life I have heard it said that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You would think that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many people assumed that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making What They Say Something You Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The following templates come from <em><a href="https://amzn.to/33TJdor">They Say / I Say: The Moves That Matter in Academic Writing</a></em>.</p>
<h2 id="introducing-what-they-say"><strong>Introducing What They Say</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>A number of $$$ have recently suggested that $$$.</li>
<li>It has become common today to dismiss $$$.</li>
<li>In their recent work, Y and Z have offered harsh critiques of Dr. X for $$$.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-standard-views"><strong>Introducing Standard Views</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>American today tend to believe that $$$</li>
<li>Conventional wisdom has it that $$$</li>
<li>Common sense seems to dictate that $$$</li>
<li>The standard way of thinking about topic X has it that $$$</li>
<li>It is often said that $$$</li>
<li>My whole life I have heard it said that $$$</li>
<li>You would think that $$$</li>
<li>Many people assumed that $$$</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Making What They Say Something You Say</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I’ve always believed that $$$</li>
<li>When I was a child, I used to think that $$$</li>
<li>Although I should know better by now, I cannot help thinking that $$$</li>
<li>At the same time that I believe $$$, I also believe $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-something-implied-or-assumed"><strong>Introducing Something Implied or Assumed</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Although none of them have ever said so directly, my teachers have often given me the impression that $$$</li>
<li>One implication of X’s treatment of $$$ is that $$$</li>
<li>Although X does not say so directly, she apparently assumes that $$$</li>
<li>While they rarely admit as much, $$$ often take for granted that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-an-ongoing-debate"><strong>Introducing an Ongoing Debate</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>In discussions of X, one controversial issue has been $$$. On the other hand, $$$ argues $$$. On the other hand, $$$ contends $$$. Others even maintain $$$. My own view is $$$.</li>
<li>When it comes to the topic of $$$, most of us will readily agree that $$$. Where this agreement usually ends, however, is on the question of $$$. Whereas some are convinced that $$$, others maintain that $$$.</li>
<li>In conclusion, then, defenders of $$$ can’t have it both ways. Their assertion that $$$ is contradicted by their claim that $$$.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="capturing-authorial-action"><strong>Capturing Authorial Action</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X <strong>acknowledges</strong> that $$$.</li>
<li>X <strong>agrees</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>argues</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>believes</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>denies</strong> / does <strong>not</strong> deny that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>claims</strong> that</li>
<li>X <strong>complains</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>conceded</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>demonstrates</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>deplores</strong> the tendency to $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>celebrates</strong> the fact that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>emphasizes</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>insists</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>observes</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>questions</strong> whether $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>refutes</strong> the claim that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>reminds</strong> us that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>suggests</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>urges</strong> us to $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-quotations"><strong>Introducing Quotations</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X <strong>states</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
<li>As the prominent philosopher X <strong>puts</strong> it, “$$$.”</li>
<li><strong>According</strong> to X, “$$$.”</li>
<li>X himself <strong>writes</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
<li>In her book, $$$, X <strong>maintains</strong> that “$$$.”</li>
<li><strong>Writing</strong> in the journal $$$, X <strong>complains</strong> that “$$$.”</li>
<li><strong>In X’s view</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
<li>X <strong>agrees/disagrees</strong> when she <strong>writes</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
<li>X <strong>complicates matters further</strong> when he <strong>writes</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="explaining-quotations"><strong>Explaining Quotations</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Basically, X is saying $$$.</li>
<li>In other words, X believes $$$.</li>
<li>In making this comment, X argues that $$$.</li>
<li>X is insisting that $$$</li>
<li>X’s point is that $$$</li>
<li>The essence of X’s argument is that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="disagreeing-with-reasons"><strong>Disagreeing, with Reasons</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>I think X is mistaken because she overlooks $$$</li>
<li>X’s claim that $$$ rests upon the questionable assumption that $$$.</li>
<li>I disagree with X’s view that $$$ because, as recent research has show, $$$</li>
<li>X contradicts herself /can’t have it both ways. On the one hand, she argues $$$, but on the other hand, she also says $$$</li>
<li>By focusing on $$$, X overlooks the deeper problem of $$$</li>
<li>X claims $$$, but we don’t need X to tell us that. Anyone familiar with $$$ has long know that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="agreeing-with-a-difference"><strong>Agreeing, with a Difference</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>I agree that $$$ because my experience confirms it.</li>
<li>X surely is right about $$$ because, as she may not be aware, recent studies have shown that $$$.</li>
<li>X’s theory of $$$ is extremely useful because it sheds insight on the difficult problem of $$$</li>
<li>I agree that $$$, a point that needs emphasizing since so many people believe $$$</li>
<li>Those unfamiliar with this school of thought may be interested to know that it basically boils down to $$$</li>
<li>If group X is right that $$$, as I think they are, then we need to reassess the popular assumption that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="agreeing-and-disagreeing-simultaneously"><strong>Agreeing and Disagreeing Simultaneously</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Although I agree with X up to a point, I cannot accept his overall conclusion that $$$</li>
<li>Although I disagree with much that X says, I fully endorse his final conclusion that $$$</li>
<li>Though I concede that $$$, I still insist that $$$</li>
<li>Whereas X provides ample evidence that $$$, Y and Z’s research on $$$ and $$$ convinces me that $$$ instead.</li>
<li>X is right that $$$, but she seems on more dubious ground when she claims that $$$</li>
<li>While X is probably wrong when she claims that $$$, she is right that $$$</li>
<li>I’m of two minds about X’s claim that $$$. On the one hand, I agree that $$$. On the other hand, I’m not sure if $$$</li>
<li>My feelings on the issue are mixed. I do support X’s positions that $$$, but I find Y’s argument about $$$ and Z’s research on $$$ to be equally persuasive.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="signaling-who-is-saying-what"><strong>Signaling Who Is Saying What</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X argues $$$</li>
<li>According to both X and Y, $$$</li>
<li>Politicians $$$, X argues, should $$$</li>
<li>Most athletes will tell you that $$$</li>
<li>My own view, however, is that $$$</li>
<li>I agree, as X may not realize, that $$$, but $$$ are real and, arguably, the most significant factor in $$$</li>
<li>However X is wrong that $$$</li>
<li>However, it is simply not true that $$$</li>
<li>Indeed, it is highly likely that $$$</li>
<li>Nonetheless, the view that $$$ does not fit all the facts.</li>
<li>X is right that $$$</li>
<li>X is wrong that</li>
<li>X is both right and wrong that $$$</li>
<li>A sober analysis of the matter reveals $$$</li>
<li>Nevertheless, new research shows $$$</li>
<li>Anyone familiar with $$$ should see that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="embedding-voice-markers"><strong>Embedding Voice Markers</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X overlooks what I consider an important point about $$$</li>
<li>My own view is that what X insists is a $$$ is in fact a $$$</li>
<li>I wholeheartedly endorse what X calls $$$</li>
<li>These conclusions, which X discusses in $$$, add weight to the argument that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="entertaining-objections"><strong>Entertaining Objections</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>At this point, I would like to raise some objections that have been inspired by the skeptic in me. She feels that I have been ignoring $$$., “$$$,” she says to me, “$$$.”</li>
<li>Thus far some readers may challenge the view that $$$. After all, many believe $$$. Indeed, my own argument that $$$ seems to ignore $$$ and $$$</li>
<li>Of course, many will probably disagree with the assertion that $$$</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Naming Your Nay Sayers</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Here many $$$ would probably object that $$$</li>
<li>However/But $$$ would certainly take issue with the argument that $$$</li>
<li>$$$, of course, may want to question whether/dispute my claim that $$$</li>
<li>Nevertheless, both followers and critics of $$$ will probably argue that $$$</li>
<li>Although not all $$$ think alike, some of them will probably dispute my claim that $$$</li>
<li>$$$ are so diverse in their views that it’s hard to generalize about them, but some are likely to object on the grounds that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-objections-informally"><strong>Introducing Objections Informally</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>However/But is my proposal realistic? What are the chances of its actually being adopted?</li>
<li>Yet is it always true that $$$? Is it always the case, as I have been suggesting, that $$$?</li>
<li>However, does the evidence cited prove conclusively that $$$?</li>
<li>“Impossible,” some will say. “You must be reading the research selectively.”</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="making-concessions-while-still-standing-your-ground"><strong>Making Concessions while Still Standing Your Ground</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Although I grant that $$$, I still maintain that $$$</li>
<li>Proponents of X are right to argue that $$$. But they exaggerate when they claim that $$$</li>
<li>While it is true that $$$, it does not necessarily follow that $$$</li>
<li>On the one hand, I agree with X that $$$. But on the other hand, I still insist that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="indicating-who-cares"><strong>Indicating Who Cares</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>$$$ used to think $$$, but recently (or within the past few decades) $$$ suggests that $$$</li>
<li>What his new research does, then, is correct the mistaken impression, held by many earlier researchers, that $$$</li>
<li>These findings challenge the work of earlier researchers, who tended to assume that $$$</li>
<li>Recent studies like these shed new light on $$$, which previous studies had not addressed.</li>
<li>Researchers have long assumed that $$$. For instance, one eminent scholar of cell biology, $$$ assumed in $$$, her seminal work on cell structures and functions, that fate cells $$$. As $$$ herself put it, “$$$.” Another leading scientist, $$$, argued that fat cells “$$$.” Ultimately, when it came to the nature of fat, the basic assumption was that $$$. But a new body of research shows that fat cells are far more complex and that $$$</li>
<li>If sports enthusiasts stopped to think about it, any of them might simply assume that the most successful athletes $$$. However, new research shows $$$.</li>
<li>These findings challenge $$$’s common assumptions that $$$</li>
<li>At first glance, teenagers appear to $$$, but on closer inspection $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="establishing-why-your-claims-matter"><strong>Establishing Why Your Claims Matter</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X matters/is important because $$$</li>
<li>Although X may seem trivial, it is in fact crucial in terms of today’s concern over $$$</li>
<li>Ultimately, what is at stake here is $$$</li>
<li>These findings have important consequences for the broader domain of $$$</li>
<li>My discussion of X is in fact addressing the larger matter of $$$</li>
<li>These conclusions / This discovery will have significant application in $$$ as well as in $$$</li>
<li>Although X may seem of concern to only a small group of $$$, it should in fact concern anyone who cares about $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="adding-meta-commentary"><strong>Adding Meta-commentary</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>In other words, $$$</li>
<li>What $$$ really means by this is $$$</li>
<li>My point is $$$</li>
<li>Essentially, I am arguing that $$$</li>
<li>My point is not that we should $$$, but that we should $$$</li>
<li>What $$$ really means is $$$</li>
<li>In other words, $$$</li>
<li>To put it another way, $$$</li>
<li>In sum, then, $$$</li>
<li>My conclusion, then is that, $$$</li>
<li>In short, $$$</li>
<li>What is more important, $$$</li>
<li>Incidentally, $$$</li>
<li>By the way, $$$</li>
<li>Chapter two explores $$$, while Chapter three examines $$$</li>
<li>Having just argued that $$$, let us now turn our attention to $$$.</li>
<li>Although some readers may object that $$$, I would answer that $$$.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="commonly-used-transitions"><strong>Commonly Used Transitions</strong></h2>
<h3 id="cause-and-effect"><strong>Cause and Effect</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Accordingly</li>
<li>As a result</li>
<li>Consequently</li>
<li>Hence</li>
<li>It follows, then</li>
<li>Since</li>
<li>So</li>
<li>Then</li>
<li>Therefore</li>
<li>Thus</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="conclusion"><strong>Conclusion</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>As a result</li>
<li>Consequently</li>
<li>Hence</li>
<li>In conclusion, then</li>
<li>In short</li>
<li>In sum, then</li>
<li>It follows, then</li>
<li>So</li>
<li>The upshot of all this is that</li>
<li>Therefore</li>
<li>Thus</li>
<li>To sum up</li>
<li>To summarize</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="comparison"><strong>Comparison</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Along the same line</li>
<li>In the same way</li>
<li>Likewise</li>
<li>Similarly</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="contrast"><strong>Contrast</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Although</li>
<li>But</li>
<li>By contrast</li>
<li>Conversely</li>
<li>Despite the fact that</li>
<li>Even though</li>
<li>However</li>
<li>In contrast</li>
<li>Nevertheless</li>
<li>Nonetheless</li>
<li>On the contrary</li>
<li>On the other hand</li>
<li>Regardless</li>
<li>Whereas</li>
<li>While</li>
<li>Yet</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="addition"><strong>Addition</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Also</li>
<li>And</li>
<li>Besides</li>
<li>Furthermore</li>
<li>In addition</li>
<li>In fact</li>
<li>Indeed</li>
<li>Moreover</li>
<li>So too</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="concession"><strong>Concession</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Admittedly</li>
<li>Although it is true that</li>
<li>Granted</li>
<li>I concede that</li>
<li>Of course</li>
<li>Naturally</li>
<li>To be sure</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="example"><strong>Example</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>After all</li>
<li>As an illustration</li>
<li>Consider</li>
<li>For example</li>
<li>For instance</li>
<li>Specifically</li>
<li>To take/taking a case in point</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="elaboration"><strong>Elaboration</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Actually</li>
<li>By extension</li>
<li>In short</li>
<li>That is</li>
<li>In other words</li>
<li>To put it another way</li>
<li>To put it bluntly</li>
<li>To put it succinctly</li>
<li>Ultimately</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desperate Times, Desperate Measures: Writing My Dissertation vs. Funding Abortion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/desperate-times-desperate-measures-writing-my-dissertation-vs-funding-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 13:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/desperate-times-desperate-measures-writing-my-dissertation-vs-funding-abortion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m two years in to my PhD program, and I need to finish writing this dissertation soon, or it’s going to be the death of me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong. I love Wheaton’s program. My supervisor and second reader are fantastic. And I think that this Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible project is worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I’ve got a wife, a kid, a commitment to the Church, and I need to move on with my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m two years in to my PhD program, and I need to finish writing this dissertation soon, or it’s going to be the death of me!</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong. I love Wheaton’s program. My supervisor and second reader are fantastic. And I think that this Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible project is worthwhile.</p>
<p>But I’ve got a wife, a kid, a commitment to the Church, and I need to move on with my life.</p>
<p>SO, in order to give myself a daily kick in the pants, I’ve used Stickk.com to commit to writing 500 words OR editing 5 pages (1,250 words), related to my dissertation, 5 days a week.</p>
<p>I got the 5-5-5 idea from <a href="https://twitter.com/pankisseskafka/status/1002981118482763777">Rebecca Schuman’s tweet</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Academics, or anyone who has a long writing project, here is some gratis coaching. The ideal default pace is 5-5-5: 500 words OR 5 pages of editing, 5 days a week. Telling yourself that’s not enough is essentially giving yourself permission to do nothing. 5-5-5 will get it done.</p></blockquote><p>If I don’t achieve this goal each week, $250.00 will go to an “anti-charity” of my choice. In this case, I’ve picked the NARAL Pro-Choice America Foundation.</p>
<p>I’d rather my money <em>not</em> go to this organization, so I plan to succeed in my commitment.</p>
<p>You can <a href="https://t.co/Rc5Z8JW9ct">track my progress here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tree of Religion: Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge in Genesis 2:4–3:24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-tree-of-religion-karl-barth-and-dietrich-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-in-genesis-24-324/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 15:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-tree-of-religion-karl-barth-and-dietrich-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-in-genesis-24-324/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Here’s a PDF of this paper: &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/STEELE_The-Tree-of-Religion-Barth-and-Bonhoeffer-on-the-Tree-of-Knowledge.pdf&#34;&gt;STEELE_The Tree of Religion Barth and Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The precise meaning of the “tree of the knowledge of good and evil” (=TK) has long vexed interpreters of Genesis 2:4–3:24.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#post-41779-footnote-1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; While the “tree of life” (=TL) is mentioned and alluded to throughout the Bible, the TK is explicitly mentioned by its full name just twice (Gen. 2:9, 17).&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#post-41779-footnote-2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Nevertheless, because of the significant role that the TK plays in the narrative, both Dietrich Bonhoeffer and Karl Barth highlight the TK in their theological interpretations of Genesis 1–3. Furthermore, both theologians describe the TK and the knowledge of good and evil (=KGE) in ways that resemble their theological critiques of “religion” as an improper response to divine revelation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>(Here’s a PDF of this paper: <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/STEELE_The-Tree-of-Religion-Barth-and-Bonhoeffer-on-the-Tree-of-Knowledge.pdf">STEELE_The Tree of Religion Barth and Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge</a>.)</em></p>
<h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1>
<p>The precise meaning of the “tree of the knowledge of good and evil” (=TK) has long vexed interpreters of Genesis 2:4–3:24.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-1">[1]</a></sup> While the “tree of life” (=TL) is mentioned and alluded to throughout the Bible, the TK is explicitly mentioned by its full name just twice (Gen. 2:9, 17).<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-2">[2]</a></sup></sup> Nevertheless, because of the significant role that the TK plays in the narrative, both Dietrich Bonhoeffer and Karl Barth highlight the TK in their theological interpretations of Genesis 1–3. Furthermore, both theologians describe the TK and the knowledge of good and evil (=KGE) in ways that resemble their theological critiques of “religion” as an improper response to divine revelation.</p>
<p>Before proceeding, I must first clarify what Barth and Bonhoeffer meant by “religion.” In <em>The Epistle to the Romans</em> and in <em>Church Dogmatics</em> (esp. <em>CD</em> I/2, §17, “The Revelation of God as the <em>Aufhebung</em> of Religion”), Barth developed a systematic definition of religion as idolatrous self-justification, which the early Bonhoeffer inherited.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-3">[3]</a></sup></sup> As Barth defined it in the <em>Leitsatz</em> to <em>CD</em> §17, “the world of human religion” is “the realm of attempts by man to justify and sanctify himself before a willfully and arbitrarily devised image of God.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-4">[4]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>However, although maintaining an emphasis on religion as self-justification and idolatry, in prison Bonhoeffer developed a historical/psychological definition of religion as an inward, metaphysical, and partial approach to human life.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-5">[5]</a></sup></sup> Bonhoeffer described “the age of religion” as “the age of inwardness and conscience” which is now past.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-6">[6]</a></sup></sup> He critiqued religion’s “metaphysical” emphasis on otherworldly escapism.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-7">[7]</a></sup></sup> And, perhaps most importantly for what follows, he critiqued religion as a partial, fragmented, and segmented posture towards human life. In prison, Bonhoeffer wrote that “the ‘religious act’ is always something partial,” focused on distinctions between the outward and inward life, between human strength and weakness, and between religious and non-religious acts. However, for Bonhoeffer, “‘faith’ is something whole and involves one’s whole life.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-8">[8]</a></sup></sup> <a id="post-41779-Introduction"></a></p>
<p>In this paper, I argue (1) that Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s interpretations of the TK and the KGE help to explain the similarity and differences between their theological critiques of religion. For Bonhoeffer, the KGE is primarily “disunion.” What he would call “religion” in prison is an inward and partial response to the disunion caused by the KGE. For Barth, the KGE is primarily God’s prerogative to judge what ought and ought not to be. “Religion” is a repetition of humanity’s attempt to grasp the KGE and justify itself. Nevertheless, (2) given the text of Genesis 2:4–3:24, Bonhoeffer’s and Barth’s interpretations need some exegetical adjustments. Bonhoeffer’s view adequately describes the consequences of humans grasping the KGE, but it is insufficient to the degree that it fails to describe the essence of the KGE, how the KGE is spoken of in the rest of the OT, and how the KGE is originally and properly God’s. Barth’s view is more exegetically robust, but it needs to be softened in order to make it clear how humans now have the KGE. Yet, despite these adjustments, (3) I believe that the TK and the KGE can be used to advance a theological critique of religion along the same lines as both Barth and Bonhoeffer.</p>
<h1 id="barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-and-a-critique-of-religion"><a id="post-41779-Barth_and_Bonhoeffer_the_Tree_"></a>Barth and Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge and a Critique of Religion</h1>
<p>Although the links are admittedly indirect and thematic, I argue that the same similarities and differences can be seen in (1) Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s theological critiques of religion and (2) their theological interpretations of the TK and the KGE in Genesis 2:4–3:24.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-9">[9]</a></sup> Barth emphasized the relationship between the KGE (God’s prerogative to judge) and humanity’s idolatrous desire to justify itself. Although these elements are also present in some of Bonhoeffer’s discussions, Bonhoeffer places much more emphasis on the relationship between the KGE (disunion) and the fragmentation of human life.</p>
<h2 id="bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-and-religion"><a id="post-41779-Bonhoeffer_on_the_Tree_of_Know"></a>Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge and Religion</h2>
<p>“Good and evil” played an important role throughout Bonhoeffer’s theological career. Already in his February 1929 lecture, “Basic Questions of a Christian Ethic,” Bonhoeffer was using Genesis 2–3 to defend the claim that “[t]he Christian message stands beyond good and evil” because it emphasizes unity with God as opposed to the duality suggested by the oppositional pair “good and evil.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-10">[10]</a></sup></sup> Later, in January 1933, Bonhoeffer addressed the TK and the KGE in his lectures on Genesis 2–3.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-11">[11]</a></sup> In describing the primal state, Bonhoeffer emphasizes the unity of Adam’s life in “unbroken obedience to the Creator,” an “obedience that issues from freedom” to obey God’s command.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-12">[12]</a></sup></sup> In terms that echo his insistence in the prison letters on speaking “non-religiously” of God “not at the boundaries but in the center,” Bonhoeffer interprets the prohibition against eating from the TK as God’s boundary/limit [Grenze] which encounters Adam in the center [Mitte] of his own existence.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-13">[13]</a></sup></sup> According to Bonhoeffer, heeding the divine boundary in the middle of life was to secure human life in its unified totality. Instead, transgressing the boundary led to knowledge of good <em>and</em> evil, so that humans now “suffer from an inner split [Zwiespalt].”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-14">[14]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>This emphasis, on disunion and fragmentation, is by far the strongest theme related to the TK and the KGE in <em>Creation and Fall</em>.</p>
<blockquote><p>Good and evil, tob and ra, thus have a much wider meaning here than good and evil in our terminology. The words tob and ra speak of an ultimate split [Zwiespalt] in the world of humankind in general that goes back behind even the moral split, so that tob means also something like “pleasurable” [lustvoll] and ra “painful” [leidvoll] (Hans Schmidt). Tob and ra are concepts that express what is in every respect the deepest divide [Entzweiung] in human life. The essential point about them is that they appear as a pair, that in being split apart [in ihrer Zwiespaltigkeit] they belong inseparably together.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-15">[15]</a></sup></sup></p></blockquote><p>Bonhoeffer proceeds to discuss how, in human life, there is nothing pleasurable that exists apart from that which is painful, and vice versa. He writes that, “in all pleasure a person desires eternity, but knows that pleasure is transient and will end.” And, on the other hand, “in the depth of pain a person feels pleasure in transience, pleasure in the obliteration of apparently endless pain, pleasure in death.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-16">[16]</a></sup></sup> Bonhoeffer therefore draws a strong connection between the KGE and death as a necessary consequence.</p>
<p>Although Bonhoeffer later (in his discussion of Gen. 3:7) links the KGE with sexuality, the primary characteristic of KGE is still disunion. He writes that “the knowledge of good and evil is for Adam, who lives in unity, an impossible knowledge of duality, of the whole as torn apart.”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-17">[17]</a></sup> This can be seen in the shame and division that the KGE yields in the relationship between Adam and Eve. Although Bonhoeffer links the KGE to both shame and conscience, he repeatedly emphasizes division and disunion.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-18">[18]</a></sup></p>
<p>This emphasis on disunion resembles the distinction Bonhoeffer later makes in prison between “the religious act” as something <em>partial</em> and faith which involves one’s whole life.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-19">[19]</a></sup></sup> Religion distinguishes between (1) human strength, knowledge, and autonomy and (2) weakness, ignorance, and boundaries—exploitatively minimizing the former and emphasizing the latter.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-20">[20]</a></sup> ] Bonhoeffer also writes of the religious distinction between private/inner and public/outer life, claiming that “[w]hat used to be the servants’ secrets—to put it crudely—that is, the intimate areas of life (from prayer to sexuality)—became the hunting ground of modern pastors.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-21">[21]</a></sup></sup> In response to such “religious blackmail,” Bonhoeffer argues that “the Bible does not know the distinction that we make between the outward and the inward life.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-22">[22]</a></sup></sup> Although he does not mention Genesis 1–3 here, I think it makes best sense to interpret what Bonhoeffer calls “religion” in prison as an improper response to the disunion ultimately caused by the KGE.</p>
<p>However, with such a strong emphasis on division, in what sense, if any, does the KGE make humans “like God” (Gen. 3:5, 22)? Bonhoeffer at least attempts to make the link:</p>
<blockquote><p>There can at this point be no more doubt that the serpent was right in the promise it made. The Creator confirms the truth of that promise: Humankind has become like one of us. It is sicut deus. Humankind has got what it wants; it has itself become creator, source of life, fountainhead of the knowledge of good and evil. It is alone by itself, it lives out of its own resources, it no longer needs any others, it is the lord of its own world, even though that does mean now that it is the solitary lord and despot of its own mute, violated, silenced, dead, ego-world [Ichwelt].<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-23">[23]</a></sup></sup></p></blockquote><p>However, it is unclear (1) how this description coheres with Bonhoeffer’s earlier descriptions of KGE as the source of disunion and (2) how such disunion could be an appropriate description of God. In order to link the KGE to God, it appears as though Bonhoeffer had to momentarily step back from his emphasis on disunion.</p>
<p>In 1942, Bonhoeffer returned to a discussion of the TK and the KGE in <em>Ethics</em>, particularly in the manuscript titled “God’s Love and the Disintegration of the World.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-24">[24]</a></sup></sup> Here again the emphasis is on the KGE as a split/disunion—a Zwiespalt, Zerfall, and an Entzweiung. In knowing good and evil, Bonhoeffer argues, humans fall away from reality into possibilities, and from knowledge of God into knowledge of self.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-25">[25]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>Nevertheless, here Bonhoeffer, like Barth, links the fall to (1) humanity’s desire to be its own judge and (2) divine election.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-26">[26]</a></sup></sup> He also tries harder to describe how the KGE is God’s knowledge:</p>
<blockquote><p>In knowing good and evil, they now know what only the origin, that is, God, can and may know. Even Holy Scripture speaks only with the utmost reservation about God’s knowing about good and evil. It is the first hint of the secret here of predestination, the secret of an eternal disunion that has its origin in the eternal One, the secret of an eternal choice and election by the One in whom there is no darkness but only light. To know good and evil means to understand oneself as the origin of good and evil, as the origin of an eternal choice and election. How this is possible remains the secret of the One in whom there is no disunion, since God is the undivided and eternal origin, and the overcoming of all disunion.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-27">[27]</a></sup></p></blockquote><p>As for how/whether humans become “like God” when they obtain the KGE, Bonhoeffer writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>They have become like God—but opposed to God. This is the serpent’s deceit. Human beings know what is good and evil. They are not the origin, however, but instead have bought this knowledge only by paying the price of disunion from the origin. Therefore the good and evil that they know is not God’s own good and evil, but a good and evil opposed to God. It is a good and evil of their own choosing against the eternal election of God. As god-against-God [Gegengott], the human being has become like God.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-28">[28]</a></sup></sup></p></blockquote><p>And yet, in the end, due to the KGE, “everything is pulled into the process of disunion [Entzweiung].”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-29">[29]</a></sup></sup> Although Bonhoeffer arguably sounds a bit more like Barth when discussing the KGE in <em>Ethics</em> (as opposed to in <em>Creation and Fall</em>), Bonhoeffer still retains a distinctive emphasis on the KGE as the source of all disunion—with God, with others, and with ourselves. What he would later call “religion” in prison is an inward and partial response to this disunion.</p>
<h2 id="barth-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-and-religion"><a id="post-41779-Barth_on_the_Tree_of_Knowledge"></a>Barth on the Tree of Knowledge and Religion</h2>
<p>Although Bonhoeffer offered a lengthy exposition of Genesis 1–3 over a decade before Barth, Barth had previously addressed these chapters of Genesis in his discussion of Romans 7:7–13 (“The Meaning of Religion”) in the second and subsequent editions of his <em>Römerbrief.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-30">[30]</a></sup></sup></em> In <em>Romans</em>, Barth interpreted the KGE as the divine secret that humans are merely humans. Such knowledge</p>
<blockquote><p>is God’s secret. Men ought not to be independently what they are in dependence upon God; they ought not, as creatures, to be some second thing by the side of the Creator. Men ought not to know that they are merely—men. God knows this, but in His mercy He has concealed it from them. So long as ignorance prevailed, the Lord walked freely in the garden in the cool of the day [Gen. 3:8], as though in the equality of friendship.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-31">[31]</a></sup></p></blockquote><p>Without undermining the creator/creature distinction, Barth nevertheless maintains that, before the fall, humans were (and ought to have remained) ignorant of the distinction. The prohibition of eating from the tree of knowledge <em>concealed</em> the creator/creature distinction and was meant to enable a direct relationship between God and humans. Instead, human disobedience revealed the distinction and led to the rise of religion, an independent action over against their creator.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-32">[32]</a></sup></p>
<p>However, Barth’s interpretation of the TK in <em>CD</em> differs sharply from his previous interpretation in <em>Romans</em>. Instead of referring to a divinely <em>concealed</em> distinction between creator and creatures, the knowledge of good and evil is <em>revealed</em>—precisely through the prohibition of eating from the TK—as God’s ability and prerogative “to distinguish and therefore to judge between what ought to be and ought not to be” (<em>CD</em> III/1, 257). This revelation of the creator/creature distinction was meant to prompt humans to acknowledge and praise their creator, thereby enjoying full fellowship with God. Instead, humans disobediently attempted to abolish the distinction. They thereby became like God, for “[t]o know good and evil, to be able to distinguish and therefore judge between what ought to be and ought not to be, between Yes and No, between salvation and perdition, between life and death, is to be like God, to be oneself the Creator and Lord of the creature.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-33">[33]</a></sup></sup> This usurpation of God’s KGE is a burden that creatures are unable to bear. It leads to the rise of religion as the idolatrous and self-justifying worship of false gods—including self-worship. But it also necessarily leads to death, for “[i]t is impossible for any other being to occupy the position of God. In that position it can only perish.”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-34">[34]</a></sup></p>
<p>Barth returned to Genesis 3 at some length in <em>CD</em> IV/1, §60, “The Pride and Fall of Man.” The <em>Leitsatz</em> for §60 describes the sinful human “who willed to be as God, himself lord, the judge of good and evil.”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-35">[35]</a></sup> Barth continued to interpret the KGE as God’s ability and prerogative to judge. Furthermore, in Barth’s interpretation of Genesis 3 in <em>CD</em> IV/1, the primary concealment is not God’s concealment of the creator/creature distinction, but rather the serpent’s and humanity’s concealment of the pernicious nature of wanting (1) to be like God, (2) to be lord, (3) to be one’s own judge, and (4) to help oneself.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-36">[36]</a></sup> Regarding the desire to be one’s own judge, Barth argues that, not only do humans lack the capacity to judge between good and evil, they actively choose evil. And although the creator is in fact the judge, he is not the egotistic victor in need of approval that humans make him out to be in their endeavor to join him in judging. That is a false god, an idol. Instead, the true God is the self-sacrificial judge who gives himself to be judged in our place.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-37">[37]</a></sup></p>
<h2 id="similarities-and-differences-between-barth-and-bonhoeffer">Similarities and Differences between Barth and Bonhoeffer</h2>
<p>The first similarity between Barth and Bonhoeffer on the TK and the KGE is that both theologians’ explanations of the TK/KGE correlate with their theological critiques of religion. For Bonhoeffer in prison, religion is an inward and partial attempt to address the disunion caused by the KGE. For Barth, religion is the same kind of idolatrous self-justification as humans grasping after God’s KGE. And yet both theologians speak of self-justification and a false idea of God at the fall. Given the paucity of citations of Genesis 2–3 in Bonhoeffer’s prison letters, it would be very difficult to “prove” that their differences on the TK and the KGE directly “caused” their differences on religion, but the correlations here should not be ignored.</p>
<p>Second, both theologians interpret the prohibition from eating from the TK as a gracious gift of God meant to secure a truly free relationship with human beings. Instead of God planting and then prohibiting the TK as a temptation or test, both Barth and Bonhoeffer claim that the divine command secures human freedom. God gives humans the opportunity to freely obey him and, therefore, to enjoy full fellowship with him.</p>
<p>Third, both theologians are trying to make sense of the contours of the passage, which seem to indicate that the KGE is (1) originally and properly God’s knowledge and (2) something that humans now have (Gen. 3:5, 22). But here is where their differences also begin to emerge. Bonhoeffer’s definition of the KGE in terms of disunion makes better sense of (2) than (1). That is, it is easier to understand how humans suffer from disunion post-fall than it is to understand how such disunion was originally and properly God’s. Barth’s definition of the KGE in terms of judgment and decision makes better sense of (1) than (2). It is easier to understand how God has the prerogative to judge between what ought to and ought not to be than it is to understand how humans now have such an ability.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-38">[38]</a></sup></p>
<h1 id="an-exegetical-evaluation-of-barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge">An Exegetical Evaluation of Barth and Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge</h1>
<p>So far, I have argued that the similarities and differences between Barth and Bonhoeffer on the TK and the KGE help to make sense of the similarities and differences between their theological critiques of religion. I will now evaluate their interpretations of the TK and the KGE in light of the text of Genesis 2:4–3:24.</p>
<p>Regarding the meaning of the KGE, there have been several proposals, to say the least. Because every overview of the proposals slightly differs in order and scope, I find it most helpful to consider the proposals along a spectrum between those which make the most sense of how <em>humans</em> now have the KGE and those that make the best sense of how the KGE was originally and properly <em>God’s</em> knowledge.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-39">[39]</a></sup></sup> Moving roughly from the human to the divine, then, scholars have proposed that the KGE means: (1) sexual/carnal knowledge, (2) ethical discernment, (3) cultural advancement, (4) moral autonomy, (5) knowledge of everything or omniscience. There is also (6) the “consequence” view that the TK and the KGE are “a description of the consequences of obeying or disobeying the commandments.”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-40">[40]</a></sup> I do not have space to give all the arguments for and against these positions. However, as an example of the reasoning often used to adjudicate between the positions, regarding the KGE as sexual/carnal knowledge fails to make sense of how the KGE was originally and properly God’s knowledge.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-41">[41]</a></sup> And regarding the KGE as omniscience fails to make sense of how humans now have the KGE.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-42">[42]</a></sup></p>
<p>In terms of the framework I have just summarized, Bonhoeffer held a “consequence” view and Barth a “moral autonomy” view. Put simply, I think that Bonhoeffer’s view has difficulty explaining whether/how the KGE is God’s knowledge, and Barth’s view has difficulty in explaining whether/how the KGE is now also humanity’s knowledge. That is, an exegetical difficulty that both Bonhoeffer and Barth share is in making sense of Genesis 3:5 alongside 3:22. Taken together, those verses seem to suggest (1) that the KGE is a kind of knowledge that is appropriate to God and (2) that, though inappropriately seized, humans now have the KGE.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-43">[43]</a></sup></p>
<p>I will begin by evaluating Bonhoeffer’s interpretation. As for Bonhoeffer’s claim that “[g]ood and evil, tob and ra, thus have a much wider meaning here than good and evil in our terminology,” he is correct (in both German and English).<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-44">[44]</a></sup> However, Bonhoeffer seems to be on much shakier exegetical ground when he claims that “[t]he words tob and ra speak of an ultimate split [Zwiespalt] in the world of humankind in general that goes back even behind the moral split, so that tob means also something like ‘pleasurable’ [lustvoll] and ra ‘painful’ [leidvoll] (Hans Schmidt).”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-45">[45]</a></sup> Although in Hebrew “good” can mean “pleasurable” and “evil” can mean “painful,” to arrive at such an “ultimate split” conclusion, one would have to consider whether or not this makes sense of how “good” and “evil” are used elsewhere in the Old Testament.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-46">[46]</a></sup> But Bonhoeffer fails to do so.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-47">[47]</a></sup></p>
<p>Nevertheless, Bonhoeffer’s emphasis on the KGE as an “inner split” and “disunion” clearly makes good theological sense of post-lapsarian human life. However, this seems to have more to do with the <em>consequences</em> of the KGE, and less with the <em>essence</em> of the KGE itself. Otherwise, it is difficult to understand how God has always appropriately had the KGE. Granted, Bonhoeffer does attempt to explain how humans are now like God: “Humankind has got what it wants; it has itself become creator, source of life, fountainhead of the knowledge of good and evil. It is alone by itself, it lives out of its own resources, it no longer needs any others, it is the lord of its own world. . .”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-48">[48]</a></sup></sup> However, it is difficult to understand how this coheres with his previous (and arguably primary) explanation of the KGE in terms of “pleasure” and “pain” always going together in “ihrer Zwiespaltigkeit.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-49">[49]</a></sup></sup> If, as Bonhoeffer suggests, the KGE means a Zwiespalt, Zerfall, or Entzweiung, then God’s words in Genesis 3:22 make little sense. The same goes for Bonhoeffer’s explanation of the KGE in terms of sexuality and shame.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-50">[50]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>And yet Bonhoeffer’s interpretation is not far off from a “consequence” view of the KGE. As Kidner puts it:</p>
<blockquote><p>[i]n the context, however, the emphasis falls on the prohibition [2:17] rather than the properties of the tree. It is shown to us as forbidden. It is idle to ask what it might mean in itself; this was Eve’s error. As it stood, prohibited, it presented the alternative to discipleship: to be self-made, wresting one’s knowledge, satisfactions and values from the created world in defiance of the Creator (cf. 3:6). . . . In all this the tree plays its part in the opportunity it offers, rather than the qualities it possesses; like a door whose name announces only what lies beyond it.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-51">[51]</a></sup></p></blockquote><p>As Vlachos notes, this “consequence” interpretation makes good sense of (1) ידע as meaning experiential knowledge, (2) the consequence that actually takes place in 3:7, and (3) that the TL and the TK both seem to get their names from their effects—eating from the TL yields life, and eating from the TK yields the KGE.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-52">[52]</a></sup> So, perhaps Bonhoeffer’s interpretation is not as wide of the mark as it originally sounds.</p>
<p>And yet, there is the problem of Genesis 3:22. If Bonhoeffer is correct, how is the KGE originally and properly <em>God’s</em> knowledge? Even if 3:22 does not require an exact correspondence between human and divine knowledge, there seems to be something more going on here than just God knowing in advance what would happen if humans disobeyed. Therefore, while I do not think that Bonhoeffer’s interpretation of the TK and the KGE is in serious error (when viewed as a description of the <em>consequences</em> of human disobedience), it is insufficient. We need to make better sense of (1) how “good” and “evil” are used in the OT and (2) how the KGE is God’s.</p>
<p>These are both strengths of Barth’s interpretation of the TK and the KGE in <em>CD</em> III/1. Before arriving at the exegetical small print section, Barth relates the Eden narrative to the subsequent history of Israel.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-53">[53]</a></sup> Then, in the small print section, Barth first cites with approval the interpretations of Augustine, Luther, and Calvin. The common thread in their interpretations is, according to Barth, that “the tree itself has nothing whatever to do with evil, but like the prohibition is . . . . a kind of test. Everything depended on its formal fulfillment, so that there is no need to ask concerning its meaning and content and therefore the nature of the tree.”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-54">[54]</a></sup> This resembles the “consequence” view of which Bonhoeffer was a proponent. Overall, Barth agrees with this interpretation that the TK was meant to establish “a proof of obedience and faith in the initiation of a relationship between man and God accomplished in man’s conscious decision.”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-55">[55]</a></sup></p>
<p>Nevertheless, I agree with Barth that, because the TK is given a particular name and is said to mediate particular knowledge—a knowledge that led to death after humans disobeyed—“all this deserves much fuller consideration than is given to it on this view.”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-56">[56]</a></sup> So, Barth then addresses the meaning of the KGE. He argues against the view(s) that (1) it relates to “science and our general knowledge of things,” (2) the prohibition of eating from the TK is about “progress from childish innocence” to the KGE as moral decision and “intellectual maturity,” and (3) the KGE refers to sexual knowledge and desire.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-57">[57]</a></sup></p>
<p>Having found these views unsatisfactory, Barth proceeds to survey what the OT has to say about the KGE. He argues that Deuteronomy 1:39, Isaiah 7:15–16, 2 Samuel 19:35 [Hebrew: 36], and even Jonah 4:11 are examples where the KGE “means the capacity—not yet possessed in childhood and perhaps no longer possessed in old age—to be responsible and to act.”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-58">[58]</a></sup> However, Barth presses beyond this meaning, noting how other passages (Lev. 27:33; Gen. 31:24) seem to indicate decision and judgment. Furthermore, for Barth it is very significant that Solomon asks God from the ability to discern between good and evil, so that he might be a good ruler and judge (1 Kgs. 3:9). And, in 2 Samuel 14:17, David’s ability to discern between good and evil is compared to “the angel of God.” For Barth, these last two passages link the KGE to a judicial capacity of God.<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-59">[59]</a></sup> He then cites a long list of other passages from across the OT to demonstrate that “primarily and ultimately it is to God alone that this capacity belongs.”<sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-60">[60]</a></sup></p>
<p>Based upon his survey, Barth returns to Genesis 2:16–17 and concludes that</p>
<blockquote><p>[t]o transgress the Word of the Lord means to do good or evil after one’s own will. But this is something which must not be done because it is God who must decide concerning good and evil, commanding the one and prohibiting the other, whereas man, choosing after his own heart, cannot attain good but will do evil. This, then, is what God prohibited. This is the possibility indicated by the tree of knowledge in the Garden of Eden but also prevented by the commandment.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-61">[61]</a></sup></sup></p></blockquote><p>Barth concludes that to know good and evil “is to know right and wrong, salvation and perdition, life and death; and to know them is to have power over them and therefore over all things.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41779-footnote-62">[62]</a></sup></sup> Here Barth comes very close to the view that “good and evil” is a merism, although he places more emphasis on discernment, judgment, and even omnipotence than on omniscience.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Barth’s moral autonomy view is perhaps cast in such strong terms that it suffers from the same weakness as the omniscience view. Although I am persuaded that, given how “good” and “evil” are spoken of in the rest of the OT, something like moral autonomy (stronger than mere ethical discernment) must be in view, the KGE should be defined as “mere” moral autonomy—the ability to make decisions about what is right and wrong—in order to help make it clear that, although humans now possess the KGE, it is but a pale imitation and coveting of God’s absolute KGE.</p>
<h1 id="conclusion-the-tree-of-knowledge-and-a-biblicaltheological-critique-of-religion-today"><a id="post-41779-Conclusion"></a>Conclusion: The Tree of Knowledge and a Biblical/Theological Critique of Religion Today</h1>
<p>In this paper, I have argued that (1) Barth and Bonhoeffer’s interpretations of the TK and the KGE help to explain the similarity and differences between their theological critiques of religion. For Bonhoeffer, the KGE is primarily “disunion”—with God, with others, and with ourselves. What he would call “religion” in prison is an inward and partial response to the disunion caused by the KGE. For Barth, the KGE is primarily God’s prerogative to judge what ought and ought not to be. “Religion” is a repetition of humanity’s attempt to exercise the KGE and justify itself.</p>
<p>Based upon the text of Genesis 2:4–3:24, (2) both Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s interpretations need some exegetical adjustments. Bonhoeffer’s view makes the best sense as describing the <em>consequences</em> of humans grasping the KGE, but it is insufficient to the degree that it fails to describe the essence of the KGE, how the KGE is spoken of in the rest of the OT, and how the KGE is originally and properly God’s. Barth’s moral autonomy view is much more exegetically robust, but it needs to be reined-in a bit in order to make it clear how humans now have the KGE.</p>
<p>Given these adjustments and a moral autonomy view of the KGE, (3) can the TK be used to advance a theological critique of religion along the same lines as both Barth and Bonhoeffer? Yes. With both theologians, we can maintain that the point of the TK was obedience to God’s command—a command which was also an instance of divine self-revelation. God is not against human beings acquiring ethical discernment and wisdom, but they are to do so through reverent worship and obedience in response to divine revelation, and not through attempting to seize godlike autonomy. If humans had obeyed God’s command, then the TK would have remained a tree of worship and wisdom, as it were, securing the unity and the freedom of human life. Instead, both in Eden and today, the error of religion is to grasp after God—to justify oneself before one’s own idea of “god,” instead of obeying and worshiping God as he has revealed himself to be. Because humans tried to grasp moral autonomy through consumption, instead of through worship and obedience, the TK thereby became the tree of religion. It would take an act of reverent obedience on a different tree to solve humanity’s religious predicament.</p>
<h2 id="bibliography"><a id="post-41779-Bibliography"></a> BIBLIOGRAPHY</h2>
<p>Baez, Enrique. “Tree of Knowledge.” In <em>The Lexham Bible Dictionary</em>, edited by John D. Barry et al. Bellingham, WA: Lexham Press, 2016.</p>
<p>Barth, Karl. <em>Church Dogmatics</em>. Edited by G. W. Bromiley and T. F. Torrance. 4 vols. in 14 parts. Edinburgh: T&amp;T Clark, 1956–1975.</p>
<p>———. <em>The Epistle to the Romans</em>. Translated from the 6th ed. by Edwyn C. Hoskyns. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1968.</p>
<p>———. <em>On Religion: The Revelation of God as the Sublimation of Religion</em>. Translated by Garrett Green. London: T&amp;T Clark, 2006.</p>
<p>Bonhoeffer, Dietrich. <em>Barcelona, Berlin, New York: 1928-1931</em>. Edited by Clifford J. Green. Translated by Douglas W. Stott. DBWE 10. Minneapolis: Fortress, 2008.</p>
<p>———. <em>Creation and Fall: A Theological Exposition of Genesis 1-3</em>. Edited by John W. de Gruchy. Translated by Douglas Stephen Bax. DBWE 3. Minneapolis: Fortress, 1997.</p>
<p>———. <em>Ethics</em>. Edited by Clifford J. Green. Translated by Reinhard Krauss, Charles C. West, and Douglas W. Stott. DBWE 6. Minneapolis: Fortress, 2005.</p>
<p>———. <em>Letters and Papers from Prison</em>. Edited by John W. de Gruchy. Translated by Isabel Best, Lisa E. Dahill, Reinhard Krauss, and Nancy Lukens. DBWE 8. Minneapolis: Fortress, 2009.</p>
<p>Cassuto, Umberto. <em>A Commentary on the Book of Genesis: Part One, from Adam to Noah, Genesis I–VI 8.</em> Jerusalem: Magnes, 1961.</p>
<p>Clark, W. A. M. “A Legal Background to the Yahwist’s Use of ‘Good and Evil’ in Genesis 2–3,” <em>JBL</em> 88 (1969), 266–78.</p>
<p>Collins, C. John. <em>Genesis 1–4: A Linguistic, Literary, and Theological Commentary.</em> Phillipsburg, NJ: P&amp;R, 2006.</p>
<p>Day, John. <em>From Creation to Babel: Studies in Genesis 1–11</em>. London: Bloomsbury Academic, 2013.</p>
<p>deClaissé-Walford, Nancy. “Tree of Knowledge, Tree of Life.” In vol 5 of <em>The New Interpreter’s Dictionary of the Bible</em>, 659–61. Nashville: Abingdon, 2009.</p>
<p>DiNoia, Joseph A. O.P., “Religion and the Religions.” In <em>The Cambridge Companion to Karl Barth</em>, edited by John Webster, 243–57. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2000.</p>
<p>Engnell, I. “‘Knowledge’ and ‘Life’ in the Creation Story,” In <em>Wisdom in Israel and in the Ancient Near East Presented to Professor Harold Henry Rowley</em>, 103–19. VTSup 3. Leiden: Brill, 1955.</p>
<p>Faro, Ingrid. “Tree of Life.” In <em>The Lexham Bible Dictionary</em>, edited by John D. Barry et al. Bellingham, WA: Lexham Press, 2016.</p>
<p>Feil, Ernst. <em>The Theology of Dietrich Bonhoeffer</em>. Translated by Martin Rumscheidt. Minneapolis: Fortress, 2007.</p>
<p>French, Nathan S. “A Theocentric Interpretation of הדעת טוב ורע: The Knowledge of Good and Evil as the Knowledge for Administering Reward and Punishment.” Ph.D. diss., University of Aberdeen, 2018.</p>
<p>Frick, Peter. “Friedrich Nietzsche’s Aphorisms and Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Theology.” In <em>Understanding Bonhoeffer</em>, 78–104. Tübingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2017.</p>
<p>———. “Nietzsche’s <em>Übermensch</em> and Bonhoeffer’s <em>mündiger Mensch</em>: Are They of Any Use for a Contemporary Christian Anthropology?” In <em>Understanding Bonhoeffer</em>, 105–26. Tübingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2017.</p>
<p>Gordis, Robert. “The Knowledge of Good and Evil in the Old Testament and the Qumran Scrolls.” <em>JBL</em> 76 (1957): 123–38.</p>
<p>Green, Clifford J. <em>Bonhoeffer: A Theology of Sociality</em>. Rev. ed. Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1999.</p>
<p>———. “Bonhoeffer’s Concept of Religion,” <em>USQR</em> 19 (1963): 11–21.</p>
<p>Gunkel, Hermann. <em>Genesis</em>. Translated by Mark E. Biddle. Mercer Library of Biblical Studies. Macon, GA: Mercer University Press, 1997.</p>
<p>Hamilton, Victor P. <em>The Book of Genesis: Chapters 1–17.</em> NICOT. Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1990.</p>
<p>Jacob, Benno. <em>Genesis: The First Book of the Bible</em>. Abridged, edited, and translated by Ernest I. Jacob and Walter Jacob. New York: Ktav, 1974.</p>
<p>Joüon, P., and T. Muraoka. <em>A Grammar of Biblical Hebrew.</em> Rev. English ed., Second Print of 2nd ed. Rome: Pontificio Istituto Biblico, 2006.</p>
<p>Kidner, Derek. <em>Genesis: An Introduction and Commentary</em>. TOTC. Downers Grove, IL: IVP, 1967.</p>
<p>Koehler, Ludwig, and Walter Baumgartner. <em>The Hebrew and Aramaic Lexicon of the Old Testament</em>. Revised by Walter Baumgartner and Johann Jakob Stamm. Translated by M. E. J. Richardson. 5 vols. Leiden: Brill, 1994–2000.</p>
<p>Ross, Allen P. <em>Creation and Blessing: A Guide to the Study and Exposition of Genesis</em>. Grand Rapids: Baker, 1988.</p>
<p>Schmidt, Hans. <em>Die Erzählung von Paradies und Sündenfall.</em> Tübingen: J.C.B. Mohr (P. Siebeck), 1931.</p>
<p>Speiser, E. A. <em>Genesis.</em> 3rd ed. AB 1. Garden City, NY: Doubleday, 1982.</p>
<p>Treier, Daniel J., Dustyn E. Keepers, and Ty D. Kieser. “The Tree of Life in Modern Theological Thought.” In <em>The Tree of Life</em>, edited by Douglas Estes. Leiden: Brill, Forthcoming.</p>
<p>Vlachos, Chris A. <em>The Law and the Knowledge of Good and Evil: The Edenic Background of the Catalytic Operation of the Law in Paul</em>. Eugene, OR: Pickwick, 2009.</p>
<p>von Rad, Gerhard. <em>Genesis: A Commentary</em>. Rev. ed. OTL. Philadelphia: Westminster, 1972.</p>
<p>Wallace, Howard N. “Tree of Knowledge and Tree of Life.” In vol 6 of <em>Anchor Bible Dictionary</em>, 656–60. New York: Doubleday, 1992.</p>
<p>Waltke, Bruce K with Cathi J. Fredricks. <em>Genesis: A Commentary</em>. Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2001.</p>
<p>Walton, John H. <em>Genesis</em>. NIVAC. Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2001.</p>
<p>Wenham, Gordon J. <em>Genesis 1–15</em>. WBC 1. Waco, TX: Word, 1987.</p>
<p>Westermann, Claus. <em>Genesis 1–11: A Commentary</em>. Translated by John B. Scullion. CC. Minneapolis: Augsburg, 1984.</p>
<p>Wüstenberg, Ralf K. <em>A Theology of Life: Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Religionless Christianity</em>. Translated by Doug Stott. Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1998.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<ol>
<li>For a sense of the endless debate, see the history of research in Nathan S. French, “A Theocentric Interpretation of הדעת טוב ורע: The Knowledge of Good and Evil as the Knowledge for Administering Reward and Punishment” (Ph.D. diss., University of Aberdeen, 2018), 1–74. For other overviews, see Enrique Baez, “Tree of Knowledge,” in <em>The Lexham Bible Dictionary</em>, ed. John D. Barry et al. (Bellingham, WA: Lexham Press, 2016); John Day, <em>From Creation to Babel: Studies in Genesis 1–11</em> (London: Bloomsbury Academic, 2013), 41–44; Nancy deClaissé-Walford, “Tree of Knowledge, Tree of Life,” in <em>The New Interpreter’s Dictionary of the Bible</em> (Nashville: Abingdon, 2009), 5:659–91; Victor P. Hamilton, <em>The Book of Genesis: Chapters 1–17</em>, NICOT (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1990), 160–66; Chris A. Vlachos, <em>The Law and the Knowledge of Good and Evil: The Edenic Background of the Catalytic Operation of the Law in Paul</em> (Eugene, OR: Pickwick, 2009), 138–43, 167–74; Howard N. Wallace, “Tree of Knowledge and Tree of Life,” in <em>ABD</em> (New York: Doubleday, 1992), 6:656–60; Bruce K. Waltke with Cathi J. Fredricks, <em>Genesis: A Commentary</em> (Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2001), 86–96; Gordon J. Wenham, <em>Genesis 1–15</em>, WBC 1 (Waco, TX: Word, 1987), 62–64; Claus Westermann, <em>Genesis 1–11: A Commentary</em>, trans. John B. Scullion, CC (Minneapolis: Augsburg, 1984), 211–14, 222–25, 242–48. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-1">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>For the TL elsewhere, see Gen. 2:9; 3:22, 24; Prov. 3:18; 11:30; 13:12; 15:4; 2 Esdr. 2:12; 8:52; 4 Macc. 18:16; Rev. 2:7; 22:2, 14, 19. For an overview of the TL in modern theological thought, including Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s treatments, see Daniel J. Treier, Dustyn E. Keepers, and Ty D. Kieser, “The Tree of Life in Modern Theological Thought,” in <em>The Tree of Life</em>, ed. Douglas Estes (Leiden: Brill, Forthcoming). The identity of the tree in question in Gen. 3 is debated. However, the prohibition from eating of the TK in Gen. 2:17 makes it very likely that the TK is the tree that is in view from 3:3–21. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-2">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>See Karl Barth, <em>The Epistle to the Romans</em>, trans. from the 6th ed. Edwyn C. Hoskyns. (Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1968); idem, <em>On Religion: The Revelation of God as the Sublimation of Religion</em>, trans. Garrett Green. London: T&amp;T Clark, 2006); Joseph A. DiNoia, O.P., “Religion and the Religions,” in <em>The Cambridge Companion to Karl Barth</em>, ed. John Webster (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2000), 243–57; Clifford J. Green, “Bonhoeffer’s Concept of Religion,” <em>USQR</em> 19 (1963): 11–21; Ralf K. Wüstenberg, <em>A Theology of Life: Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Religionless Christianity</em>, trans. Doug Stott (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1998). <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-3">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Barth, <em>On Religion</em>, 33; idem, <em>Church Dogmatics</em> [<em>CD</em>] I/2, 280; “[der] Bereich der Versuche des Menschen sich vor einem eigensinnig und eigenmächtig entworfenen Bilde Gottes selber zu rechtfertigen und zu heiligen.” idem, <em>Kirkliche Dogmatik</em> [<em>KD</em>] I/2, 304. This adequately summarizes what Barth meant by “religion” earlier in <em>Romans.</em> Arguably, the only new element in <em>CD</em> §17 is Barth’s willingness to consider how, despite its religious idolatry, Christianity is “the true religion.” <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-4">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Bonhoeffer’s “new” theology from prison—including his theological critique of religion—can be found in the text of the following “theological letters” from Bonhoeffer to Bethge in 1944: April 30 (<em>Letters and Papers from Prison</em>, ed. John W. de Gruchy, trans. Isabel Best, Lisa E. Dahill, Reinhard Krauss, and Nancy Lukens, <em>DBWE</em> 8 [Minneapolis: Fortress, 2009], 361–367); May 5 (371–74); “Thoughts on the Day of Baptism of Dietrich Wilhelm Rüdiger Bethge,” May 18 (383–90; sent with the letter of May 18 to Renate and Eberhard Bethge); May 29 (404–07); June 8 (424–31); June 27 (446–48); June 30 (448–52); July 8 (454–58); July 16 (473–80); July 18 (480–82); July 21 (485–87); “Outline for a Book,” August 3 (499–504; sent with the letter of August 3 to Eberhard Bethge). For important secondary discussions on Bonhoeffer’s view of religion, including the relevance of Bonhoeffer’s reading of Wilhelm Dilthey and others while in prison, see Ernst Feil, <em>The Theology of Dietrich Bonhoeffer</em>, trans. Martin Rumscheidt (Minneapolis: Fortress, 2007),160–202; Clifford J. Green, <em>Bonhoeffer: A Theology of Sociality</em>, rev. ed. (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1999), 258–82; Wüstenberg, <em>A Theology of Life</em>. For Bonhoeffer on the “false god” in religion, see <em>Creation and Fall: A Theological Exposition of Genesis 1-3</em>, ed. John W. de Gruchy, trans. Douglas Stephen Bax, <em>DBWE</em> 3 (Minneapolis: Fortress, 1997), 106–108; <em>DBWE</em> 8:366–67; cf. 405-07, 479-80, 482. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-5">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 8:362; cf. 364, 455–57. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-6">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 8:364, 372–73, 447–48, 480, 485–86, 501. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-7">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 8:482; cf. 455–57. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-8">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>With the exception of Barth’s discussion of Gen. 1–3 in chapter 7 of <em>Romans</em>, neither theologian discusses Genesis at length in their central theological critique of religion texts (<em>CD</em> I/2, §17; <em>DBWE</em> 8). However, in many ways, this indirect/thematic link is to be expected, because neither theologian (esp. Bonhoeffer in prison) made a habit of comprehensively citing all the texts related to their theological argumentation. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-9">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Bonhoeffer, <em>Barcelona, Berlin, New York: 1928-1931</em>, ed. Clifford J. Green, trans. Douglas W. Stott, <em>DBWE</em> 10 (Minneapolis: Fortress, 2008), 363. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-10">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>His lectures on Genesis 1–3 during the winter 1932–33 term at the University of Berlin were later published as <em>Creation and Fall</em>, <em>DBWE</em> 3. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-11">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:84. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-12">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:86; cf. 8:366. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-13">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:89. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-14">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:88. In a rare departure from his practice (in <em>Creation and Fall</em>) of not citing his interlocutors, Bonhoeffer here references Hans Schmidt, <em>Die Erzählung von Paradies und Sündenfall</em> (Tübingen: J.C.B. Mohr [P. Siebeck], 1931)<em>.</em> The editors also note connections to Hegel and Nietzsche in this section. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-15">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:90. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-16">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:122. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-17">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>For shame, see <em>DBWE</em> 3:124–26. For conscience, see <em>DBWE</em> 3:128–30. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-18">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 8:455–57; 482. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-19">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 8:366, 405–7, 426–27, 450, 455–57, 475–78. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-20">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 8:455. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-21">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 8:456. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-22">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:142. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-23">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Bonhoeffer, <em>Ethics</em>, ed. Clifford J. Green, trans. Reinhard Krauss, Charles C. West, and Douglas W. Stott, <em>DBWE</em> 6 (Minneapolis: Fortress, 2005), 299–338. On the dating of this manuscript to 1942, see <em>DBWE</em> 6:471–72. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-24">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 6:300. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-25">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 6:301. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-26">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 6:301–302. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-27">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 6:301–302. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-28">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 6:308. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-29">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Barth, <em>Romans</em>, 240–57. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-30">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Barth, <em>Romans</em>, 247. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-31">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>See Barth, <em>Romans</em>, 240–57. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-32">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> III/1, 257–58. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-33">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> III/1, 262. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-34">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> IV/1, 358. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-35">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> IV/1, 418–78. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-36">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> IV/1, 450–53. Although Barth does not use the term “religion” very often here in <em>CD</em> §60.2, the thematic resonances (particularly “unbelief,” “self-justification,” and “idolatry”) with his mature theological critique of religion in <em>CD</em> I/2, §17 make it likely that he has the problematic aspects of religion very much in view here. Compare Barth’s section on “Religion as Unbelief [Unglaube]” (<em>CD</em> I/2, §17.2, 297–325) with his description of “the pride of man” in terms of “unbelief” (<em>CD</em> IV/1, §60.2, 413–18). <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-37">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Another difference is that Bonhoeffer’s interpretation of the KGE was demonstrably influenced by Nietzsche*.* See <em>DBWE</em> 3:87–93; cf. 10:363, 366–67. For a good overview and analysis of Nietzsche’s influence on Bonhoeffer’s thought, see Peter Frick, “Friedrich Nietzsche’s Aphorisms and Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s Theology” and “Nietzsche’s <em>Übermensch</em> and Bonhoeffer’s <em>mündiger Mensch</em>: Are They of Any Use for a Contemporary Christian Anthropology?,” in <em>Understanding Bonhoeffer</em> (Tübingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2017), 78–104; 105–26. Although both Barth and Bonhoeffer felt free to appreciate and critique Nietzsche, Barth’s interpretation of the KGE was arguably much less influenced by Nietzsche than Bonhoeffer’s. Note the lack of “beyond good and evil” language in Barth’s discussion of the TK and the KGE in <em>CD</em>. For Barth’s appreciative critique of Nietzsche, see <em>CD</em> III/2, 231–42. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-38">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>My overview of positions here is nowhere near exhaustive. See Day, <em>From Creation to Babel</em>, 41–44; French, “A Theocentric Interpretation,” 1–74; Hamilton, <em>Genesis 1–17</em>, 162–66; Vlachos, <em>The Law and the Knowledge of Good and Evil</em>, 167–74; Wenham, <em>Genesis 1–15</em>, 62–64; Westermann, <em>Genesis 1–11</em>, 242–45. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-39">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Wenham, <em>Genesis 1–15</em>, 63. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-40">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>I agree with Day that the sexual knowledge view is the easiest to refute, because—although “to know” can refer to sex and the couple becomes aware of their nakedness after eating from the tree of knowledge—KGE is not used elsewhere to refer to sexual knowledge and God, whom the couple becomes “like” after eating (Gen. 3:22), is not portrayed in Scripture as a sexual being. Day, <em>From Creation to Babel</em>, 43. It is also difficult to understand how humans were to “be fruitful and multiply” (Gen. 1:28), or how Adam was to “cling to his wife, and … become one flesh” (2:24) without sexual knowledge. For arguments for variations of the sexual knowledge view, see I. Engnell, “‘Knowledge’ and ‘Life’ in the Creation Story,” in <em>Wisdom in Israel and in the Ancient Near East Presented to Professor Harold Henry Rowley</em>, VTSup 3 (Leiden: Brill, 1955), 114–19; Robert Gordis, “The Knowledge of Good and Evil in the Old Testament and the Qumran Scrolls,” <em>JBL</em> 76 (1957): 123–38. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-41">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Although the omniscience view seemingly has support from other biblical passages (see 2 Sam. 14:17, 20; Job 15:7–8; Ezek. 28:3, 12) and makes good sense of “good and evil” as a merism, I agree with Day, who argues that this interpretation is out of keeping with the rest of Genesis 3, “which provides aetiologies of the state of humanity as the Israelites knew it, which was not omniscient.” Day, <em>From Creation to Babel</em>, 43. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-42">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>I acknowledge that (1) is contested by those who claim that Gen. 3:5 and 3:22 depict the KGE as belonging to “gods” or “divine beings.” This relates to the contested meaning of the first-person plural in Gen. 1:26. Nevertheless, I think that Gen. 3:5 and 3:22 are about God himself, as opposed to gods, divine beings, a divine council, etc. It seems most natural to take both occurrences of אֱלֹהִים in 3:5 as referring to the same person, and the first occurrence seems to refer to God, as opposed to divine beings. Gen. 3:22 is more difficult to adjudicate, but I take the first-person plural there as a plural of deliberation for much the same reasons as in Gen. 1:26. However, even if a divine council is in view, the KGE is still something that God properly has. For the arguments for and against the major positions here, see Hamilton, <em>Genesis 1–17</em>, 132–34, 208–209; Wenham, <em>Genesis 1–15</em>, 27–28, 85; and Westermann, <em>Genesis 1–11</em>, 144–45, 272–73; cf. Joüon and Muraoka, <em>A Grammar of Biblical Hebrew</em>, §114e. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-43">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:88. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-44">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:88. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-45">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>See <em>HALOT</em> 2:370–72; 3:1250–53. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-46">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Was Solomon asking God for an ultimate split in 1 Kgs. 3:9? Or consider the often-cited verses where “to know,” “good,” and “evil” occur together (Deut. 1:39; 2 Sam. 19:36 [English: 35]; Isa. 7:15–16). It is hard to see how they would be referring to an ultimate split that is present in human life, yet absent from both childhood and old age. Do not children and the elderly know both pleasure and pain? <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-47">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:142. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-48">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:88. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-49">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>DBWE</em> 3:122–26. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-50">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Derek Kidner, <em>Genesis: An Introduction and Commentary</em>, TOTC (Downers Grove, IL: IVP, 1967), 63. A similar view is held by Benno Jacob, <em>Genesis: The First Book of the Bible</em>, abridged, ed., and trans. Ernest I. Jacob and Walter Jacob (New York: Ktav, 1974), 18–20; Allen P. Ross, <em>Creation and Blessing: A Guide to the Study and Exposition of Genesis</em> (Grand Rapids: Baker, 1988), 123–24. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-51">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Vlachos, <em>The Law and the Knowledge of Good and Evil</em>, 138–43. Vlachos also argues that this view makes good sense of Deut. 1:39 (“. . . your children, who today do not yet know right from wrong . . .”) but I am not convinced by this. Instead, I think that either moral discernment or legal responsibility is in view there. See W. A. M. Clark, “A Legal Background to the Yahwist’s Use of ‘Good and Evil’ in Genesis 2–3,” <em>JBL</em> 88 (1969): 274. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-52">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>See <em>CD</em> III/1, 267–76. For Barth, the “decisive parallel” is between the two trees and the revelation of God to his people. On the one hand, God’s revelation resembles the TL—the sign of God’s goodness and provision. On the other hand, it resembles the TK—a warning sign of God’s judgment. Barth links the KGE to the idolatry of the other nations from which Israel was supposed to keep herself distinct. Much like the prohibition from eating of the TK was meant to graciously protect humans from the inevitable consequences of usurping God’s role as creator and judge, God’s revelation to Israel graciously prohibits idolatry in order to protect Israel from necessarily dying when left to her own devices. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-53">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> III/1, 284–85. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-54">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> III/1, 285. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-55">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> III/1, 285. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-56">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Regarding (1), Barth thinks the phrase is much more specific/concrete. He also wonders why God would prohibit such knowledge, and why it would lead to death. As for (2), Barth points out that the knowledge comes from eating from the TK, not from avoiding it. It is also unclear why such moral discernment would be deadly. Regarding (3), Barth admits that the KGE results in the distortion of the sexual relationship between man and woman, but he denies that the OT anywhere condemns/discredits awareness of the sexual relationship. Even if the first consequence of the KGE was sexual, Barth argues that “the knowledge itself and as such is deeper and more embracing and cannot possibly be equated with sexual knowledge or its perversion.” <em>CD</em> III/1, 285–86. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-57">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> III/1, 286. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-58">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Barth’s argument here is remarkably similar (and two decades prior!) to Clark’s. See “A Legal Background,” esp. 267–69. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-59">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> III/1, 286. In the order he mentions them, Barth cites: Job 2:10; Jer. 4:26; Isa. 45:7; 41:23–24; Jer. 10:5; Zeph. 1:12; Exod. 7:2f.; 1 Sam. 2:6–7; 1 Kgs. 22:9f.; Job 1:6f.; Deut. 30:15; Josh. 24:20; Zech. 8:14–15; Num. 24:13. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-60">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol>
<li><em>CD</em> III/1, 287. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-61">↑</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>CD</em> III/1, 287. <a href="#post-41779-footnote-ref-62">↑</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When will Thy Kingdom Come? The Timing and Agency of the Kingdom of God in the Lord&#39;s Prayer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/when-will-thy-kingdom-come-the-timing-and-agency-of-the-kingdom-of-god-in-the-lords-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 15:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/when-will-thy-kingdom-come-the-timing-and-agency-of-the-kingdom-of-god-in-the-lords-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Here’s a PDF of this paper: &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/STEELE_When-Will-Thy-Kingdom-Come.pdf&#34;&gt;STEELE_When Will Thy Kingdom Come&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-thy-kingdom-haswill-come&#34;&gt;Introduction: “Thy Kingdom [Has/Will] Come”?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just how &lt;em&gt;eschatological&lt;/em&gt; is the Lord’s Prayer (=LP; Matt. 6:9–13; Luke 11:2–4), particularly in light of its second petition, “Your kingdom come” (ἐλθέτω ἡ βασιλεία σου, Matt. 6:10a; Luke 11:2d)? In other words, when will God’s kingdom come? Has it already arrived (not eschatological)? Is it in the process of arriving? Or will it arrive at some point in the future (eschatological)? Furthermore, who brings the kingdom about? Humans? God? Or some combination of the two? Settling the question of eschatology involves both the timing and the agency, the &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt;, of the kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>(Here’s a PDF of this paper: <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/STEELE_When-Will-Thy-Kingdom-Come.pdf">STEELE_When Will Thy Kingdom Come</a>.)</em></p>
<h2 id="introduction-thy-kingdom-haswill-come">Introduction: “Thy Kingdom [Has/Will] Come”?</h2>
<p>Just how <em>eschatological</em> is the Lord’s Prayer (=LP; Matt. 6:9–13; Luke 11:2–4), particularly in light of its second petition, “Your kingdom come” (ἐλθέτω ἡ βασιλεία σου, Matt. 6:10a; Luke 11:2d)? In other words, when will God’s kingdom come? Has it already arrived (not eschatological)? Is it in the process of arriving? Or will it arrive at some point in the future (eschatological)? Furthermore, who brings the kingdom about? Humans? God? Or some combination of the two? Settling the question of eschatology involves both the timing and the agency, the <em>when</em> and the <em>who</em>, of the kingdom.</p>
<p>When it comes to the LP, the literature is vast.<sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-1">[1]</a></sup> To get a grasp on the positions involved, Luz provides the following framework: “[t]here are essentially three basic types of interpretations in various combinations”: (a) the “dogmatic,” (b) the “ethical,” and (c) the “eschatological.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-2">[2]</a></sup></sup> The dogmatic interpretation views the LP as a summary statement of the Christian message/faith. The ethical interpretation views the LP as a guide for Christian living. These two interpretations have often gone together in the history of the Church. However,</p>
<blockquote><p>[t]o these by no means mutually exclusive interpretations there has been added since the history-of-religions school (c) the <em>eschatological</em> interpretation, which relates the individual petitions more or less consistently to the eschaton and interprets the Lord’s Prayer from the situation of Jesus’ eschatological proclamation without regard for its relevance.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-3">[3]</a></sup></sup></p></blockquote><p>Without discounting the importance of “dogmatic” interpretations of the LP, the relationship between the ethical and eschatological interpretations will be the focus of this paper. At this point, it helps to notice that discussions about the LP have tended to resemble discussions about the kingdom of God more broadly.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-4">[4]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>When it comes to the kingdom of God, the question of the kingdom’s timing, the <em>when</em> question, has tended to dominate recent discussions.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-5">[5]</a></sup></sup> There are three main schools of thought: (1) “already,” (2) “not yet,” and (3) “already-not-yet.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-6">[6]</a></sup></sup> Again, note the connection between <strong>when/timing</strong> and <strong>who/agency</strong> in what follows.</p>
<p>First, scholars in the tradition of Albrecht Ritschl and Adolf von Harnack have interpreted the second petition to mean something like “Thy kingdom has already come, let it grow among us.” Consider Ritschl’s interpretation of the second petition: “On the lips of [Jesus’] disciples, the petition that God’s dominion may come presupposes that in the full sense this dominion has already been set in motion by Christ precisely in their own circle.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-7">[7]</a></sup></sup> This fits well with Ritschl’s definition of the kingdom of God as</p>
<blockquote><p>the divinely ordained highest good of the community founded through God’s revelation in Christ; but it is the highest good only in the sense that it forms at the same time the ethical ideal for whose attainment the members of the community bind themselves to each other through a definite type of reciprocal action.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-8">[8]</a></sup></sup></p></blockquote><p>For Ritschl and his ilk, <strong>the kingdom of God has already arrived (when/timing)</strong>, because it is a largely invisible ethical ideal (what), brought about by God in the inner lives of <strong>human individuals as they participate in his ethical agenda (who/agency</strong>, how, and where), in order to reveal God’s love and the value of humans in their relationships with one another (why).<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-9">[9]</a></sup></sup> I will refer to this interpretation as the “already,” “ethical,” or “non-eschatological” view.</p>
<p>Second, and in reaction to the “already” view, scholars in the tradition of Johannes Weiss and Albert Schweitzer have interpreted the second petition to mean something like “Thy kingdom has not yet come, let it arrive soon.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-10">[10]</a></sup></sup> For example, in his 1892 argument for the future, apocalyptic, and eschatological nature of the kingdom of God, Weiss himself argued that “[w]hat speaks more forcefully than all else” against an identification of the kingdom of God as already realized in Jesus’ disciples is “the fact that Jesus put in the mouths of his disciples . . . the words ἐλθέτω ἡ βασιλεία σου.”</p>
<blockquote><p>Let us be careful lest somehow or other we play down this fact and these words. The meaning is not “may thy Kingdom grow,” “may thy Kingdom be perfected,” but rather, “may thy Kingdom come.” For the disciples, the βασιλεία is not yet here, not even in its beginnings; therefore Jesus bids them: ζητεῖτε τὴν βασιλείαν (Luke 12:31). . . . We would import an opaque and confusing element into this unified and clearly unambiguous religious frame of mind were we to think somehow of a “coming in an ever higher degree” or of a growth or increase of the Kingdom. Just as there can be no different stages of its being . . . so likewise there are no stages of its coming. Either the βασιλεία is here, or it is not yet here. For the disciples and for the early church it is not yet here.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-11">[11]</a></sup></sup></p></blockquote><p>For Weiss and company, <strong>the kingdom has not yet arrived (when/timing)</strong>, because it is the visible apocalyptic and eschatological reign of God upon the earth (what and where), which will bring this age to a close (why). <strong>Only God can bring it about, and the best humans can do is to prepare themselves for its arrival (who/agency</strong> and how). I will refer to this as the “not yet” or “eschatological view.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-12">[12]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>Third, scholars in the tradition of Joachim Jeremias, Werner Kümmel, George Ladd, and George Beasley-Murray have argued for some combination of present and future, non-eschatological and eschatological.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-13">[13]</a></sup></sup> Although the precise way in which the combination is achieved varies from scholar to scholar, an interpretation of the second petition along these lines yields the paraphrase: “Thy kingdom has already begun to arrive, let it arrive soon in its fullness.” These kinds of views are sometimes labeled “inaugurated eschatology,” as opposed to a “realized” eschatology (the “already” view) or a “futurist” eschatology (the “not yet” view). In addition to using this terminology, I will refer to this as the “already-not-yet” interpretation.</p>
<p>So, which is it? When Christians today pray “Your kingdom come” in the LP, does that mean that the kingdom is already here, that it is not yet here, or some combination of the two? Furthermore, do humans bring the kingdom about, does God, or some combination of the two? Again, note the connection between the <em>when</em> and the <em>who</em>, the timing and the agency, of the kingdom. Broadly speaking, to the extent that the kingdom has <em>already</em> arrived, <em>humans</em> participate in bringing about the kingdom. However, to the extent that the kingdom has <em>not yet</em> arrived, <em>God</em> brings about the kingdom.</p>
<p>It has become common either to argue that the LP is entirely eschatological, or that the first half of the prayer is more eschatological, while the second half is more ethical, focused on disciples’ daily needs.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-14">[14]</a></sup></sup> In this paper, I argue that, especially due to the noncompetitive view of divine and human agency in the first, third, and fifth petitions, the “already-not-yet” view does the best job of explaining the entire LP, with elements of the “already” and the “not yet” throughout the prayer.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-15">[15]</a></sup></sup> <a id="post-41777-Introduction_Thy_Kingdom_HasWi"></a>According to the LP, the kingdom of God, I argue, is eschatological, but not otherworldly. It has ethical implications, but it is not thereby a non-eschatological ethical ideal. By “noncompetitive agency,” I mean that <em>both</em> God <em>and</em> God’s people hallow God’s name, do God’s will, forgive debts, and, I argue, bring about God’s kingdom—even as God is given the clear priority in each of those actions.<sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-16">[16]</a></sup> In order to support this argument, I will make a cumulative case by working through the LP petition by petition, critically examining arguments for the “already” and “not yet” interpretations.</p>
<h2 id="preliminary-considerations"><a id="post-41777-Preliminary_Considerations"></a>Preliminary Considerations</h2>
<p>However, before discussing the content of the LP in detail, I would like to briefly argue that the “already-not-yet” interpretation of the kingdom of God makes the best sense of (1) the “kingdom of God” content in the Gospels, (2) the content and context of the two versions of the LP (Matt. 6; Luke 11), and (3) the unity of the LP.</p>
<h3 id="the-kingdom-of-god-in-the-gospels"><a id="post-41777-The_Kingdom_of_God_in_the_Gosp"></a>The Kingdom of God in the Gospels</h3>
<p>First, the “already-not-yet” position makes the best sense of the kingdom of God content in the Gospels. Due to the LP’s brevity, everyone has to appeal to evidence about the kingdom of God in the Gospels more generally. Although this paper is not the place for a comprehensive examination of the kingdom of God in the Gospels, I believe that an “already-not-yet” reading of the LP is supported but the fact that there are passages in the Gospels that seem to indicate that the kingdom is (1) present/already here, (2) imminent/coming, and (3) future/not yet here.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-17">[17]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>Given this mixed bag of evidence regarding the kingdom’s timing, both the “already” and the “not yet” perspectives have to find some way to either ignore or reinterpret the passages used by the other side. Consider how Harnack ignored Jesus’ eschatological pronouncements by relegating them to his Jewish context, rather than his unique contributions to history. Responding to those who would claim that Jesus’ apocalyptic/eschatological pronouncements were primary and his ethical ones were secondary, Harnack wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>In this view I cannot concur. It is considered a perverse procedure in similar cases to judge eminent, epoch-making personalities first and foremost by what they share with their contemporaries, and on the other hand to put what is great and characteristic in them into the background. . . . There can be no doubt about the fact that the idea of the two kingdoms, of God and of the devil, and their conflicts, and of that last conflict at some future time when the devil, long since cast out of heaven, will be also defeated on earth, was an idea which Jesus simply shared with his contemporaries. He did not start it, but he grew up in it and he retained it. The other view, however, that the kingdom of God ‘cometh not with observation,’ that it is already here, was his own.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-18">[18]</a></sup></sup></p></blockquote><p>On the other hand, Weiss claimed that, if Jesus had contradicted his contemporaries’ eschatological conceptions of the kingdom, he would have done so (and the evangelists would have highlighted it) much more explicitly.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-19">[19]</a></sup></sup> Furthermore, he argued that the parables that seem to indicate that the kingdom is present (such as the parables of the seed growing secretly, tares, mustard seed, and leaven) are really about something else, such as “the fate of the proclaimed word.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-20">[20]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>In contrast to both of these approaches, the “already-not-yet” reading does the best job of making sense of the entire body of evidence we have regarding the kingdom of God in the Gospels.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-21">[21]</a></sup></sup></p>
<h3 id="the-content-and-contexts-of-the-two-versions-of-the-lp">The Content and Contexts of the Two Versions of the LP</h3>
<p>Second, the “already-not-yet” position helps to make good sense of the content and contexts of the two versions of the LP (Matt. 6:9–13; Luke 11:2–4), without having to play them against each other. It is intriguing to note the similarities in the differences between the Beatitudes and the LP in Matthew and Luke. Both sets of differences can be interpreted as Luke mitigating Matthew’s eschatological focus with his own emphasis on the ethical. As Houlden observes, the content of Luke’s LP</p>
<blockquote><p>is probably best seen, as far as Luke’s intention goes, as diverging from Matthew in the more practical and ethical way in which it sees the life of the kingdom. In this, too, as in its pithiness, it is parallel to his treatment of the Beatitudes (6:20-22). Line 5 in particular seems to substitute a concern with daily bread for Matthew’s hope for the “bread of the kingdom”. . . ; just as his blessing (6:21) is for those who “hunger now” rather than Matthew’s “hunger and thirst for righteousness” (5:6) and for the poor (6:21) rather than the “poor in spirit” (Matt 5:3). We recall, too, the strongly realistic picture of the new order Jesus brings depicted in the Nazareth sermon in Luke 4:16-20. It is possible that in line 7 Luke edges the sense of “temptation” toward a notion of everyday testing of faith in various moral predicaments and away from the ultimate (eschatological) test that will precede the End and that Matthew presumably has in mind.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-22">[22]</a></sup></sup></p></blockquote><p><a id="post-41777-The_Two_Versions_and_Contexts_"></a> And yet, even if it is legitimate to see Matthew’s LP as placing slightly more emphasis on the “not yet” than Luke’s LP, it is equally important to note the contexts of the two versions, which, I suggest, seem to push in the opposite directions. That is, while Matthew’s LP perhaps emphasizes the “not yet,” its placement in the middle of the Sermon on the Mount should militate against a strong divide between eschatology and ethics. And, while Luke’s LP perhaps emphasizes the “already,” its introduction as a distinctive communal prayer of Jesus’ disciples (vis-a-vis John’s, see Luke 11:1) should militate against a collapsing of the LP into an ethical ideal for individuals.<sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-23">[23]</a></sup></p>
<p>Whereas a thoroughgoing “already” reading would have to find some way to account for the eschatological emphases in the content of Matthew’s LP and the context of Luke’s, and thoroughgoing “not yet” reading would have to find some way to account for the ethical emphases in the content of Luke’s LP and the context of Matthew’s, an “already-not-yet” reading is able to allow both the content and the contexts of the two versions of the LP to stand in helpful tension.</p>
<h3 id="the-unity-of-the-lp">The Unity of the LP</h3>
<p>Third, an “already-not-yet” reading makes the best sense of the unity of the LP. In both Matthew and Luke, there is a clear twofold structure, delineated by the shift from the second-person singular (Matt. 6:9–10; Luke 11:2) to the first-person plural (Matt. 6:11–13; Luke 11:3–4). At first glance, there appears to be a shift from the eschatological to the ethical, from God and the coming of his kingdom to the daily needs of God’s people. However, I will argue below that this oversimplifies things and that there is an interweaving of the “already” and the “not yet” throughout the prayer. I therefore believe that an “already-not-yet” reading of the prayer does the best job of securing the unity of the LP.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-24">[24]</a></sup></sup></p>
<h2 id="our-father-in-heaven-πάτερ-ἡμῶν-ὁ-ἐν-τοῖς-οὐρανοῖς-matt-69b-par-luke-112b">Our Father in heaven (Πάτερ ἡμῶν ὁ ἐν τοῖς οὐρανοῖς; Matt. 6:9b; par. Luke 11:2b)</h2>
<p>When it comes to the opening words of the LP, there has been a longstanding debate on just how innovative and unique Jesus’ address of God as “father” (Πάτερ) was. Jeremias argued for the underlying Aramaic <em>abba</em>, claiming that Jesus’ address of God as such was entirely unique in his context, transcending a Jewish view of God with one of childlike intimacy.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-25">[25]</a></sup></sup> As can be seen in Harnack’s well-known emphasis of “the fatherhood of God” as one of the pillars of Jesus’ kingdom proclamation, a non-eschatological reading of the LP emphasizes the distinctiveness of addressing God in such intimate terms.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-26">[26]</a></sup></sup> At first glance, then, the “already” reading seems to win out.</p>
<p>However, Jeremias’ arguments about <em>abba</em>/father have come under criticism in subsequent decades.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-27">[27]</a></sup></sup> It is now recognized that, although Jesus’ use of the Aramaic <em>abba</em> was perhaps distinctive, referring to God as father was not.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-28">[28]</a></sup></sup> Rather than overplaying the uniqueness of Jesus vis-a-vis his Jewish context, it seems far better to note the profound connections between “our father” and the narrative of the Hebrew Bible.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-29">[29]</a></sup></sup> I agree with Perrin, who argues (based on, among other passages, Jeremiah 3:18–19 and Exodus 4:22–23) that the language of God as father recalls the covenantal relationship between God and his people—a relationship that spans from Abraham to Moses through exodus, from David to Jesus through exile, and from Jesus to his followers through new exodus and return from exile.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-30">[30]</a></sup></sup> The covenantal resonances would also seem to suggest the importance of covenantal faithfulness on the part of those praying “our father,” and not just on God’s part alone.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the combination of Matthew’s “our father” with Luke’s introduction of the LP vis-a-vis John’s disciples (Luke 11:1) suggests a distinctive communal emphasis here. As mentioned above, this emphasis seems to militate against the “already” position’s tendency to collapse the kingdom of God into an ethical ideal for individuals. Nevertheless, I will argue below that this communal emphasis should shape our understanding of both God and his people hallowing God’s name and doing God’s will.</p>
<p>Finally, although the phrase “in heaven” (ὁ ἐν τοῖς οὐρανοῖς) surely <em>at least</em> distinguishes between God and earthly fathers (see Matt. 23:9), the difference is already so sufficiently obvious that it most likely is doing more.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-31">[31]</a></sup></sup> At the very least, “in heaven” (6:9b), along with “on earth as in heaven” (ὡς ἐν οὐρανῷ καὶ ἐπὶ γῆς; 6:10c) does suggest a dualistic emphasis on otherworldly realms common in apocalyptic eschatology.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-32">[32]</a></sup></sup> <a id="post-41777-Our_Father_in_heaven"></a></p>
<p>On balance, then, “our father in heaven,” despite an ethical reading’s emphasis on the fatherhood of God, seems to support the eschatological reading. Indeed, theologically-speaking, it is hard to imagine a petitionary prayer that does not have at least an eschatological component, given that a request is being made to God, presumably regarding something that is not already the case! However, the covenantal resonances in “our father” at least open to the door to a non-competitive account of divine and human agency in which covenantal faithfulness is the main concern.</p>
<h2 id="your-kingdom-come-matt-69c10-par-luke-112cd"><a id="post-41777-Your_Kingdom_Come_Matt_6"></a>Your Kingdom Come (Matt. 6:9c–10; par. Luke 11:2c–d)</h2>
<p>A core of my argument is that the petitions in the first half of the LP are mutually interpreting. That is, for both Matthew and Luke, for God’s kingdom to come means that his name is hallowed—by both God and God’s people. And, for Matthew, it means that God’s name is hallowed and his will is done on earth—by both God and God’s people—as both of those things are already done in heaven. The grammatical structure of the petitions seems to at least allow for—if not support—this reading. After all, the subject of the verbs ἁγιασθήτω, ἐλθέτω and γενηθήτω is not God (though he is being addressed), but rather God’s name, kingdom, and will.</p>
<p>Therefore, although “your kingdom come,” if read on its own, <em>might</em> be clearly eschatological, as interpreted by the other two positions, it is best read as an “already-not-yet” request involving both divine and human agency coming together in a noncompetitive way. It is not an either/or but a both/and. God’s name is hallowed and his will is done by both God and his people. Therefore, this noncompetitive agency should, I argue, extend to the second petition as well. God brings the kingdom, but his people participate in this process.</p>
<h2 id="hallowed-be-your-name-ἁγιασθήτω-τὸ-ὄνομά-σου-matt-69c-par-luke-112c"><a id="post-41777-Hallowed_be_your_name"></a>Hallowed be your name (ἁγιασθήτω τὸ ὄνομά σου; Matt. 6:9c; par. Luke 11:2c)</h2>
<p>God’s “name” refers to his reputation, essence, and identity. It is already holy (Lev. 20:3; Ps. 30:4; Isa. 57:15; Ezek. 20:39; Amos 2:7). So ἁγιάζω here means not “to make holy,” but rather “to treat or reverence as holy,” distinct and set apart.<sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-33">[33]</a></sup> But who treats God’s name as holy? God or God’s people? The aorist passive imperative ἁγιασθήτω at first suggests a punctiliar divine passive—God hallowing his own name at single future point in time. However, the regular use of aorist imperatives in prayers complicates the decision about timing.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-34">[34]</a></sup></sup> Furthermore, regarding divine vs. human agency, there is OT evidence that points in both directions.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-35">[35]</a></sup></sup> As Nolland observes, “An eschatological orientation would connect with the thought of Ez. 36:23: ‘I [God] will sanctify my great name’. There the sanctification in view is exclusively an act of God.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-36">[36]</a></sup></sup> However, a non-eschatological reading can appeal to Isaiah 29:23, where Israel sanctifies God’s name, “and where, though God is clearly involved, it is people who are to honour God’s name in action and in praise.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-37">[37]</a></sup></sup> Furthermore, as Luz notes, in Judaism “‘[h]allowing the name’ is a widespread expression that means obedience to God’s commandments. . . . For Jews its highest expression is martyrdom.”<sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-38">[38]</a></sup></p>
<p>Due to the brevity of the petition and the evidence available for both positions, a decision is difficult.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-39">[39]</a></sup></sup> However, I do not believe we have to make a choice.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-40">[40]</a></sup></sup> Rather, I interpret this petition as an “already-not-yet” request that both God and God’s people (including the one praying the prayer) would sanctify God’s name—God, by bringing his people back from exile, and God’s people, by doing God’s will in obedience to God’s commands.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-41">[41]</a></sup></sup></p>
<h2 id="your-kingdom-come-ἐλθέτω-ἡ-βασιλεία-σου-matt-610a-par-luke-112d">Your kingdom come (ἐλθέτω ἡ βασιλεία σου; Matt. 6:10a; par. Luke 11:2d)</h2>
<p>Here I agree with Luz’s assessment that “[w]ith the second petition of the Lord’s Prayer . . . the eschatological interpretation of the prayer has its strongest pillar.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-42">[42]</a></sup></sup> On a purely grammatical level, it is hard to refute Weiss’ claim that, if the disciples of Jesus are told to pray that the kingdom would come, that means that the kingdom is not yet here.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-43">[43]</a></sup></sup> <a id="post-41777-Your_kingdom_come"></a></p>
<p>However, this is only the case if the second petition is interpreted on its own. We cannot ignore all the evidence in the Gospels that portrays the kingdom as having, in some sense, already arrived. Furthermore, as I am arguing, the first and the third petitions help to interpret the second. Therefore, although the future, final arrival of God’s kingdom is primarily in view here (otherwise we would not be praying for its coming), human participation in the hallowing of God’s name and the doing of God’s will in the present means that they are, in some sense, bringing about the kingdom’s arrival already, even if God is surely given priority in agency.</p>
<h2 id="your-will-be-done-γενηθήτω-τὸ-θέλημά-σου-matt-610b">Your will be done (γενηθήτω τὸ θέλημά σου; Matt. 6:10b)</h2>
<p>Regardless of one’s stance on the precise historical relationship between Matthew’s and Luke’s versions of the LP, I argue that, on the basis of accepting Matthew as canonical Scripture, Christian interpreters ought not ignore the third petition when interpreting the second. I agree with C. Clifton Black, who argues that, “[w]hile it is conceptually possible to separate petitions for the coming kingdom (Luke 11:2c = Matt. 6:10a) and the fulfillment of God’s will (Matt. 6:10b), that is theologically ill-advised,” because there is considerable conceptual overlap between kingdom and God’s will.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-44">[44]</a></sup></sup> Jesus’ words in Matthew 7:21 are important in this connection: “‘Not everyone who says to me, “Lord, Lord,” will enter the kingdom of heaven, but only the one who does the will of my Father in heaven.’” After all, a kingdom is the realm in which the will of the king is carried out.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-45">[45]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>But, much like with the first petition, the question arises: who does God’s will? God? Or God’s people? An eschatological interpretation of this petition claims the former, and a non-eschatological the latter. The answer, again, is surely both. I agree with Luz that Matthew 6:33 (ζητεῖτε δὲ πρῶτον τὴν βασιλείαν [τοῦ θεοῦ] καὶ τὴν δικαιοσύνην αὐτοῦ) “offers a clue to Matthew’s understanding [of the third petition] in that the evangelist adds ‘righteousness’ to ‘God’s kingdom,’ much in the same way he puts the third petition alongside the second. Strive for the kingdom by doing the righteousness appropriate to it.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-46">[46]</a></sup></sup> <a id="post-41777-Your_will_be_done"></a>We are also aided by Jesus’ verbatim repetition of γενηθήτω τὸ θέλημά σου in 26:42. There, the sense of the prayer is that both Jesus and the Father might accomplish the Father’s will. Jesus is surely not praying that the Father would do whatever he wants to, without any corresponding implications for Jesus’ own actions. Here, I argue, the same noncompetitive relationship between divine and human agency is in view. The prayer is that both God himself and the person praying the prayer (and, most likely, other human beings as well) would accomplish God’s will.</p>
<h2 id="on-earth-as-it-is-in-heaven-ὡς-ἐν-οὐρανῷ-καὶ-ἐπὶ-γῆς-matt-610c">On earth as it is in heaven (ὡς ἐν οὐρανῷ καὶ ἐπὶ γῆς; Matt. 6:10c)</h2>
<p>As mentioned above, both “in heaven” (6:9b) and “on earth as it is in heaven” (6:10c) perhaps suggest the kind of dualistic/otherworldly thinking found in apocalyptic eschatology. However, just as I have argued that the first three petitions of the LP are mutually interpreting, I also argue that this clause should be taken to apply to all three petitions, and not merely to the third. It is perhaps better to translate the clause more literally than the NRSV: “as in heaven, [so] also on earth.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-47">[47]</a></sup></sup> <a id="post-41777-On_earth_as_it_is_in_heaven"></a>The clause seems to imply that God’s will is already done in heaven, and at least not yet fully done on earth. Given the conceptual overlap between (1) the hallowing of God’s name, (2) God’s kingdom/rule, and (3) the doing of God’s will, I argue that God’s name is hallowed and his kingdom/rule is already present and recognized in heaven, and at least not yet fully so on earth. This is the “not yet” aspect of both the clause in question and the first half of the LP. However, because humans participate in the hallowing of God’s name and the doing of God’s will on earth, there is also an “already” aspect to both this clause and the entire first half of the LP.</p>
<h2 id="give-us-this-day-our-daily-bread-τὸν-ἄρτον-ἡμῶν-τὸν-ἐπιούσιον-δὸς-ἡμῖν-σήμερον-matt-611-par-luke-113">Give us this day our daily bread (τὸν ἄρτον ἡμῶν τὸν ἐπιούσιον δὸς ἡμῖν σήμερον; Matt. 6:11; par. Luke 11:3)</h2>
<p>So far, I have argued, against those who claim that either the entire LP or its first half are eschatological, that an “already-not-yet” perspective makes better sense of the first half of the prayer, especially given the noncompetitive relationship between human and divine agency that seems to be in view in the first, third, and (I argue) second petitions. That is, I have been pushing back against the apparent upper hand of the “not yet” position in the first half of the LP.</p>
<p>As we turn to the second half of the LP, however, the “already” position seems to have the upper hand. After all, what could be more mundane and quotidian than the request for daily bread? However, the fourth petition is not nearly as straightforward as its traditional English translation implies. The contested etymology and meaning of ἐπιούσιον has bearing on whether the bread petition of the LP is eschatological or not. Traditionally, the word has been translated as “daily,” which supports a non-eschatological interpretation. However, the word is so rare in Greek that interpreters since Origen have long suspected it is a neologism.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-48">[48]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>Depending on its etymology, ἐπιούσιον could mean (1) “necessary for existence,” (2) “for the current day, for today,” (3) “for the following day,” or (4) “coming,” in the sense of (a) “future,” (b) “coming/belonging to today”, (c) “next,” (d) “coming upon (us, from the Father),” or (e) “pertaining to the coming kingdom.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-49">[49]</a></sup></sup> A non-eschatological reading could rely on (1), (2), (3), (4b), (4c), or (4d). An eschatological reading could rely on (3), (4a), (4e), or a spiritualized interpretation of (1). Interpretation (3) seems to have the best lexical support, but this does not settle the eschatological question.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-50">[50]</a></sup></sup> “Give us this day our bread for the following day” could be “already,” referring to literal bread/sustenance for the immediate future, or “not yet,” referring to the coming messianic banquet.</p>
<p>On the one hand, even the staunchest advocates for the “not yet” interpretation of the fourth petition have to admit that literal, present bread is still in view. Consider Hagner, who, despite glossing the bread petition as “give to us today the eschatological bread that will be ours in the future,” admits that “[t]he prayer <em>is</em> nevertheless a prayer for bread. And there is a sense in which the bread (by synecdoche, ‘food’) we partake of daily is an anticipation of the eschatological banquet.”<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-51">[51]</a></sup></sup> On the other hand, given (1) the allusion here to the provision of manna in Exodus 16, (2) Jewish expectations of the return of manna in the final redemption,<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-52">[52]</a></sup></sup> and (3) the connections in the Gospels (esp. Luke) between Jesus’ table fellowship, the Last Supper, and the messianic banquet to come, the eschatological edge to this petition, even if indirect, should not be forgotten.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-53">[53]</a></sup></sup> <a id="post-41777-Give_us_this_day_our_daily_bre"></a>On balance, the evidence seems to favor an “already-not-yet” interpretation.</p>
<h2 id="and-forgive-us-our-debts-as-we-also-have-forgiven-our-debtors-καὶ-ἄφες-ἡμῖν-τὰ-ὀφειλήματα-ἡμῶν-ὡς-καὶ-ἡμεῖς-ἀφήκαμεν-τοῖς-ὀφειλέταις-ἡμῶν-matt-612-par-luke-114a">And forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors (καὶ ἄφες ἡμῖν τὰ ὀφειλήματα ἡμῶν, ὡς καὶ ἡμεῖς ἀφήκαμεν τοῖς ὀφειλέταις ἡμῶν; Matt. 6:12; par. Luke 11:4a)</h2>
<p>Yet again, the question of agency arises. Who forgives debts/sins?<sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-54">[54]</a></sup> God or God’s people? However, whereas the first and third petitions were ambiguous, the fifth position is clear: both God and God’s people forgive. Without getting into the interesting questions about whether this petition implies that divine forgiveness is a <em>quid pro quo</em> for human forgiveness,<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-55">[55]</a></sup></sup> <a id="post-41777-And_forgive_us_our_debts_as_we"></a>I would merely like to note that the <em>reciprocity</em> of the forgiveness petition implies a noncompetitive view of divine and human agency. This noncompetitive agency—at least when it comes to the hallowing of God’s name, the doing of God’s will, and the forgiveness of debts—supports an “already-not-yet” interpretation of the LP and the kingdom of God. Although it does not settle the question of timing, it militates against the “not yet” view that, because we still await the final arrival of God’s kingdom, only God (and not human beings) participate in such an arrival. And, regarding the fifth petition specifically, the emphasis on the need for divine forgiveness of debts militates against the “already” view that the kingdom of God is an ethical ideal and the only salvation that is required is <em>epistemological</em>, the recognition that God is closer to us than we had previously thought.</p>
<h2 id="and-do-not-bring-us-to-the-time-of-trial-but-rescue-us-from-the-evil-one-καὶ-μὴ-εἰσενέγκῃς-ἡμᾶς-εἰς-πειρασμόν-ἀλλὰ-ῥῦσαι-ἡμᾶς-ἀπὸ-τοῦ-πονηροῦ-matt-613-par-luke-114b">And do not bring us to the time of trial, but rescue us from the evil one (καὶ μὴ εἰσενέγκῃς ἡμᾶς εἰς πειρασμόν, ἀλλὰ ῥῦσαι ἡμᾶς ἀπὸ τοῦ πονηροῦ; Matt. 6:13; par. Luke 11:4b)</h2>
<p>I argued above that the LP begins on an eschatological note with “our Father in heaven.” Does it end on an eschatological note as well? The answer depends upon just what πειρασμόν and τοῦ πονηροῦ mean. Although <em>peirasmos</em> has traditionally been translated as “temptation” (which in English connotes a temptation to sin or do wrong), the word in Greek can also mean testing or trial. The first thing that comes to mind is the <em>peirasmos</em> of Jesus himself in the wilderness, where perhaps both senses of the word are in play (Matt. 4:1–11). However, the question remains whether μὴ εἰσενέγκῃς ἡμᾶς εἰς πειρασμόν has a specific, final temptation/trial in view (the “not yet” reading), or the many temptations/trials faced by disciples on a daily basis (the “already” reading).</p>
<p>While it is possible that, as Perrin argues, μὴ plus the aorist imperative εἰσενέγκῃς implies a specific πειρασμόν, even though it lacks the article, the common use of the aorist imperative in prayers (mentioned above with regard to ἁγιασθήτω in 6:9c) should perhaps prevent us from drawing strong conclusions here.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-56">[56]</a></sup></sup> Furthermore, even if a specific πειρασμόν is in view, it is debatable whether or not this term had a technical apocalyptic/eschatological meaning.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-57">[57]</a></sup></sup></p>
<p>When the phrase εἰς πειρασμόν occurs elsewhere in the Gospels, it is in Jesus’ injunction(s) in the Gethsemane to his disciples to stay awake and pray that they would not enter εἰς πειρασμόν (Matt. 26:41; Mark 14:38; Luke 22:40; 22:46). There, as here in the LP, the prayer seems to be for faithful perseverance in spite of temptation/trial, and not just for the complete absence of temptation/trial. Although Perrin is right to note the eschatological dimensions of the cosmic battle taking place at this point in the Gospel narratives, I think that France is also right to note that the immediate danger/testing was also in view, and not merely a final trial.<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-58">[58]</a></sup></sup> An “already-not-yet” interpretation of the LP allows for an inaugurated eschatological perspective in which disciples encounter temptations/trials now that are foretastes/echoes of the final <em>peirasmos</em> to come.</p>
<p>As for the debate about whether τοῦ πονηροῦ refers to “evil” in general (neuter) or to “the evil one” (masculine), the evidence seems to slightly favor the latter interpretation. As France notes, Matthew’s use of the same term in 13:19 and 13:38 seems to clearly have “the evil one” in view. And the connection between πειρασμόν, and τοῦ πονηροῦ here seems to recall the temptation narrative in Matthew 4:1–11, where the devil is referred to as ὁ πειράζων (4:3).<sup><sup><a href="#post-41777-footnote-59">[59]</a></sup></sup> <a id="post-41777-And_do_not_bring_us_to_the_tim"></a>Therefore, it seems legitimate to equate τοῦ πονηροῦ with “the devil” with “the tempter.”</p>
<p>There is, therefore, a clearly eschatological aspect to both the LP’s opening address and its final petitions. However, once again, an “already-not-yet” inaugurated eschatological interpretation, and not a futurist one, makes the best sense of the LP’s ending.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion-the-lps-answers-to-the-kingdom-questions"><a id="post-41777-Conclusion_The_Lords_Prayers_A"></a>Conclusion: The LP’s Answers to the “Kingdom Questions”</h2>
<p>While it has become common either to argue that the LP is entirely eschatological, or that the first half of the prayer is more eschatological and the second half is more ethical, I have argued that the “already-not-yet” view does the best job of explaining the entire LP, with elements of the “already” and the “not yet” throughout the prayer.</p>
<p>While “Our father in heaven” is, I admit, predominantly eschatological, it recalls the covenantal relationship—and the expectation of covenantal faithfulness—between God and God’s people. The first three petitions (“hallowed be your name, your kingdom come, your will be done”) are a mixture of the “already” and the “not yet.” Because both God and humans hallow God’s name and do God’s will, I argue that they both bring about the kingdom’s arrival in the present, even if God is surely given the priority in agency and the full arrival of the kingdom is still future. The fifth petition (“forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors”) makes the reciprocal, noncompetitive relationship explicit. Yet it also militates against collapsing the kingdom of God into a mere ethical ideal. The fourth (“give us this day our ἐπιούσιον bread”) and final petitions (“do not bring us to πειρασμόν, but rescue us from τοῦ πονηροῦ”) are also a mixture of the “already” and the “not yet,” although they clearly acknowledge that human beings need divine provision and protection in order to cooperate with God in the doing of his will.</p>
<p>Both God and God’s people hallow God’s name, do God’s will, forgive debts, and bring about God’s kingdom—even as God is given the clear priority in each of those actions. Put simply, God initiates the kingdom, but his people participate in it. To the degree that we lose sight of the fact that God, not humans, is the primary agent of the kingdom, we forget that it is <em>God’s</em> kingdom we are praying about in the second petition and the LP. However, to the extent that we ignore how we are called to participate in the kingdom even as we pray for its full arrival, we forget that it is God’s <em>kingdom</em>—and every kingdom has its subjects. According to the LP, the kingdom of God is eschatological, but not otherworldly. It has ethical implications, but it is not a non-eschatological ethical ideal.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>To get a grasp on the voluminous LP literature, see Hans Dieter Betz, <em>The Sermon on the Mount</em>, Hermeneia (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 1995), 369–415; C. Clifton Black, <em>The Lord’s Prayer</em> Interpretation (Louisville, KY: WJK, 2018), 283–324; W.D. Davies and Dale C. Allison, <em>The Gospel According to St. Matthew</em>, ICC (Edinburgh: T&amp;T Clark, 1988), 1:572–75, 590–615, 620–24; R.T. France, <em>The Gospel of Matthew</em>, NICNT (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2007), 229–33, 241–52; Donald A. Hagner, <em>Matthew 1–13</em>, WBC 33A (Dallas, TX: Word, 1993), 143–52; James Leslie Houlden, “Lord’s Prayer,” in <em>The Anchor Bible Dictionary</em> [<em>ABD</em>] (New York: Doubleday, 1992), 4:356–62; Ulrich Luz, <em>Matthew 1: Chapters 1-7</em>, Hermeneia (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2007), 307–26; John Y.H. Yieh, “Lord’s Prayer,” in <em>The New Interpreter’s Dictionary of the Bible</em> (Nashville: Abingdon, 2008), 3:690–95; idem, “Lord’s Prayer,” Oxford Bibliographies Online: Biblical Studies. Cited 02 April, 2019. Online: <a href="http://www.oxfordbibliographies.com/view/document/obo-9780195393361/obo-9780195393361-0138.xml">http://www.oxfordbibliographies.com/view/document/obo-9780195393361/obo-9780195393361-0138.xml</a>. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-1">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 313. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-2">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 313–14. According to Luz, Theodor Zahn (<em>Das Evangelium des Matthäus</em> [Kommentar zum Neuen Testament 1; Leipzig: Deichert, 1903], 268–74) interprets the first three petitions of the LP eschatologically. Albert Schweitzer (<em>The Mysticism of Paul the Apostle</em> [trans. William Montgomery; New York: Holt, 1931], 239–41), Alfred F. Loisy (<em>Les Évangiles synoptiques</em> [2 vols.; Paris: Ceffonds, 1907–8], 1:603–4), and Robert Eisler (“Das letzte Abendmahl,” <em>ZNW</em> 24 [1925], 190–92) interpret the entire LP eschatologically. Luz observes that “[t]he eschatological interpretation has become the dominant interpretation today through the influence of esp. Green, Jeremias, Lohmeyer, Schürmann, Brown, and Schulz . . . as well as Davies–Allison and Gnilka.” Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 314n54. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-3">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For overviews of discussions on the kingdom of God, see Bruce Chilton, “Kingdom of God, Kingdom of Heaven,” in <em>The New Interpreter’s Dictionary of the Bible</em> (Nashville: Abingdon, 2008), 3:512–23; Dennis C. Duling, “Kingdom of God, Kingdom of Heaven,” in <em>ABD</em> 4:49–69; R.T. France, “Kingdom of God,” in <em>Dictionary for Theological Interpretation of the Bible</em> (Grand Rapids: Baker, 2005), 420–22; Joel B. Green, “Kingdom of God/Heaven,” in <em>Dictionary of Jesus and the Gospels</em>, 2nd ed. (Downers Grove, IL: IVP Academic, 2013), 468–81. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-4">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Green, “Kingdom of God/Heaven,” 469. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-5">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>This is a common and accurate enough framework to organize the discussion. However, I admit that more nuanced frameworks are possible. For example, Black summarizes Gerd Theissen and Annette Merz’s (<em>The Historical Jesus: A Comprehensive Guide</em> [trans. John Bowden; Minneapolis: Fortress, 1998], 242–45) eightfold framework: the kingdom (1) de-eschatologized (Ritschl; Martin Luther); (2) of a thoroughly futurist eschatology (Weiss, Schweitzer, Allison); (3) eschatologically realized in Jesus himself (Dodd); (4) as a reality both present and future (Kümmel, Jeremias); (5) existentialized (Bultmann, Fuchs, Käsemann, Weder); (6) symbolized (Norman Perrin, Boring, Keck); (7) unmasked (Gager); and (8) the non-eschatological kingdom (Crossan, Borg). See Black, <em>The Lord’s Prayer</em>, 117–18. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-6">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ritschl, “Instruction in the Christian Religion,” in <em>Three Essays</em> (Philadelphia: Fortress, 1972), 256. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-7">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ritschl, 222. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-8">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Nicholas Perrin provides this six-question framework (what, who, when, where, why, how) for analyzing the kingdom of God. <em>The Kingdom of God: A Biblical Theology</em>, Biblical Theology for Life (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2019), 28–36. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-9">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For a summary of modern kingdom of God research along these lines, as an eschatological reaction to a non-eschatological interpretation, see Green, “Kingdom of God/Heaven,” 469; Perrin, <em>The Kingdom of God</em>, 28–33. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-10">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Johannes Weiss, <em>Jesus’ Proclamation of the Kingdom</em> <em>of God</em> (Philadelphia: Fortress, 1971), 73–74. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-11">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Of course, for Weiss and many of his theological descendants, this describes Jesus’ mistaken view of the kingdom of God. Jesus expected the kingdom to arrive either during his lifetime or very soon after his death, but, Weiss and others would argue, he was obviously wrong. Nevertheless, I would like to point out that an eschatological interpretation of the LP does not necessarily entail the view that Jesus was mistaken about the future nature of the kingdom. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-12">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Green, “Kingdom of God/Heaven,” 469. See George R. Beasley-Murray, <em>Jesus and the Kingdom of God</em>, (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1986); Joachim Jeremias, <em>The Parables of Jesus</em>, trans. S.H. Hooke (3rd ed.; London: SCM, 1972); Werner G. Kümmel, <em>Promise and Fulfillment: The Eschatological Message of Jesus</em>, trans. D.M. Barton (2nd ed.; SBT 23; London: SCM, 1961); George E. Ladd, <em>The Presence of the Future: The Eschatology of Biblical Realism</em> (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 1974). <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-13">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Grant R. Osborne, <em>Matthew</em>, ZECNT (Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2010), 227. For eschatological arguments, see Raymond Edward Brown, “The Pater Noster as an Eschatological Prayer,” <em>Theological Studies</em> 22 (1961): 175–208; David H. Milling, “The Interpretation of the Lord’s Prayer in Terms of Future Eschatology,” <em>Bangalore Theological Forum</em> 3 (1969): 13–25; Paul Trudinger, “The ‘Our Father’ in Matthew as Apocalyptic Eschatology,” <em>The Downside Review</em> 107, no. 366 (1989): 49–54. For a critique of the eschatological interpretation, see Jeffrey B. Gibson, “Matthew 6:9-13//Luke 11:2-4: An Eschatological Prayer?,” <em>Biblical Theology Bulletin</em> 31 (2001): 96–105. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-14">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The question of the precise relationship between the two versions of the LP in the Gospels (Matt. 6:9–13; Luke 11:2–4) has long occupied biblical scholars. For a sense of the debate, see Betz, <em>The Sermon on the Mount</em> (Minneapolis: Fortress, 1995), 370–86; Black, <em>The Lord’s Prayer</em>, 43–49; Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 309–11. Without discounting the importance of this question, I will focus on the Matthean version of the LP in this paper, mainly because Matthew’s version is closer to the versions commonly prayed by Christians today. Nevertheless, Luke’s version of the LP, read within the context of Luke’s Gospel, also seems to support (1) a noncompetitive view of divine and human agency and, therefore, (2) the “already-not-yet” view of the kingdom of God. I will comment upon Luke’s version as necessary. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-15">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I am merely trying to argue that, when it comes to these actions, the question of agency is not a zero-sum game. Just because God hallows his name, brings his kingdom, does his will, and forgives debts, that does not mean that human beings do not do so as well. This is therefore much less ambitious than the account of “non-competitive relations” between Creator and creatures in Kathryn Tanner, <em>Jesus, Humanity, and the Trinity: A Brief Systematic Theology</em> (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress, 2001), although I think that Tanner is on the right track. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-16">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For an overview, see Black, <em>The Lord’s Prayer</em>, 117–28; Perrin*, The Kingdom of God*, 152–212; N.T. Wright, <em>Jesus and the Victory of God</em> (Minneapolis: Fortress, 1996), 467–72. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-17">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Adolf von Harnack, <em>What Is Christianity? Sixteen Lectures Delivered in the University of Berlin during the Winter-Term 1899–1900</em> (trans. Thomas Bailey Saunders, Theological Translation Library; London: Williams and Norgate; G. P. Putnam’s Sons, 1901), 53–54. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-18">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Weiss, <em>Jesus’ Proclamation of the Kingdom</em>, 67–69. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-19">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Weiss, <em>Jesus’ Proclamation of the Kingdom</em>, 72. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-20">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Here I agree with N.T. Wright’s assessment that both the “already” and the “not yet” are “strongly present through the various strands of gospel tradition, and to excise one of them because we deem them incompatible is anachronistic criticism of the worst sort. Better by far to hold them together, and to discover the framework of belief and intention within which both make sense.” <em>Jesus and the Victory of God</em>, 467. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-21">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>J.L. Houlden, “Lord’s Prayer,” <em>ABD</em> 4:360. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-22">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Furthermore, as Gibson argues, the context of the LP in <em>both</em> Matthew and Luke suggests a focus on the disciples avoiding the apostasy of “this generation.” “An Eschatological Prayer?,” 99. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-23">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>This is <em>contra</em> Milling, who claims that only an eschatological reading of the entire LP secures the unity of the prayer. He characterizes other, non-eschatological readings as “sacrific[ing] the unity of the Prayer, in an attempt to make a few individual clauses relevant and practical<a id="post-41777-The_Unity_of_the_Lords_Prayer"></a>” (“The Interpretation of the Lord’s Prayer in Terms of Future Eschatology,” 13). But I think this is an example of the pot calling the kettle black. Both the “already” and the “not yet” readings have to work hard to explain (away) at least a few lines of the LP in order to arrive at either a thoroughgoing ethical or eschatological interpretation. The “already-not-yet” position, however, is able to allow both elements of the LP to stand in unity-in-tension. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-24">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>See Joachim Jeremias, <em>New Testament Theology: The Proclamation of Jesus</em> (London: SCM, 1971), 36–37, 61–68; idem, <em>The Prayers of Jesus</em> (London: SCM, 1967), 11–65, 95–98; idem, <em>The Central Message of the New Testament</em> (New York: Charles Scribner’s Sons, 1965), 9–30; idem, <em>The Lord’s Prayer</em> (Philadelphia: Fortress, 1964), 17–21. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-25">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>See Harnack, <em>What is Christianity?</em>, 63–70. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-26">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Houlden, “Lord’s Prayer,” <em>ABD</em> 4:360; see Géza Vermès, <em>Jesus the Jew</em> (New York: Macmillan, 1973), 210; James Barr, “’Abbā Isn’t ‘Daddy,’” <em>The Journal of Theological Studies</em> 39:1 (1988): 28–47. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-27">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>R.T. France, <em>The Gospel of Matthew</em>, NICNT (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2007), 245n56; Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 314–16. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-28">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The editors of NA28 note connections between Matt. 6:9 and Isa. 63:16; 64:8; Wisd. 2:16; Sir. 23:1,4; Jub. 1:24f. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-29">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Perrin, <em>The Kingdom of God</em>, 224–26. Perrin also argues that, “in encouraging his disciples to call on God as ‘Father,’ Jesus is implying the restoration of the Adamic image.” Perrin previously argues that “[t]he homology shared by Adam and the creator God inevitably implies some kind of filial relationship (sonship), as becomes clear when Adam has a son ‘in his own likeness’ (Gen 5:3)” (43). However, I am more hesitant to make this connection, because I think there is a difference, revealed in the use of Hebrew prepositions, between Adam being created “in our <em>image</em>, according to our <em>likeness</em>” (בְּצַלְמֵ֖נוּ כִּדְמוּתֵ֑נוּ; Gen. 1:26) and Seth being “in [Adam’s] <em>likeness</em>, according to his <em>image</em>” (בִּדְמוּתֹ֖ו כְּצַלְמֹ֑ו; Gen. 5:3). See David J.A. Clines, “The Image of God in Man,” <em>Tyndale Bulletin</em> 19 (1968): 53–103, at 78. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-30">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Lohmeyer and Perrin suggest that there is an implied critique of the temple here, God having withdrawn his presence from Jerusalem. Ernst Lohmeyer, <em>The Lord’s Prayer</em> (London: Collins, 1965), 60–61; Perrin, <em>The Kingdom of God</em>, 227. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-31">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>B.J. Pitre, “Apocalypticism and Apocalyptic Teaching,” in <em>Dictionary of Jesus and the Gospels</em>, 2nd ed. (Downers Grove: IVP Academic, 2013), 23–33, at 26. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-32">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>See BDAG, 9–10. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-33">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Betz, <em>Sermon on the Mount</em>, 389; Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 316; cf. BDF §337 (4). <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-34">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Luz lists Lev. 10:3; Ezek. 36:22–23; 38:23; and 39:7 as texts where God hallows his own name, and Exod. 20:7; Lev. 22:32; and Isa. 29:23 as texts where humans hallow God’s name. <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 317. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-35">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>John Nolland, <em>The Gospel of Matthew</em>, NIGTC (Grand Rapids: Eerdmans, 2005), 286. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-36">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Nolland, <em>Matthew</em>, 286–87. Nolland also cites similarities between the LP and the Jewish Qaddish/Kaddish prayer as evidence in favor of a non-eschatological reading. However, I am not so sure that the Qaddish’s “May he establish his kingdom in your lifetime” is non-eschatological. Much like the petition of the LP in question here, it appears ambiguous. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-37">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 317. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-38">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Luz considers OT and other Jewish parallels before arriving at an “open interpretation” of the petition. <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 317–18; cf. Betz, <em>Sermon on the Mount</em>, 389–90. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-39">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I agree with Luz’s assessment that “[o]nly for an exclusively eschatological interpretation of the petition are there no arguments.” <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 318. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-40">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>As Perrin notes, the context of Ezek. 36 and Isa. 29 seems to demand such a “return from exile” interpretation. However, although he does briefly note that Ezek. 36 speaks of the people’s renewed obedience to the covenant, I think that the connection between divine and human agency in this petition of the LP deserves more emphasis than he gives it. See <em>The Kingdom of God</em>, 228–29. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-41">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Luz, 318. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-42">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Weiss, <em>Jesus’ Proclamation of the Kingdom</em> <em>of God</em>, 73–74. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-43">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Black, <em>The Lord’s Prayer</em>, 105. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-44">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Regarding the will of the Father in Matthew, see also 12:50; 18:14; 21:31; and 26:42. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-45">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 319. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-46">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>See France, <em>Matthew</em>, 230; Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 309, 319; BDF §453 (1). <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-47">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Luz, <em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 319n95; cf. Origen, <em>De Orat.</em> 27.7. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-48">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>From BDAG, 376–77. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-49">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For an examination of the possible Semitic background, see Davies and Allison, <em>Matthew</em>, 1:607–10. For an examination of the Greek evidence, see Colin J. Hemer, “Epiousios,” <em>Journal for the Study of the New Testament</em> 7:22 (1984): 81–94. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-50">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Hagner, <em>Matthew 1–13</em>, 149–50. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-51">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>See Davies and Allison, <em>Matthew</em>, 1:609 for the citations. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-52">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Perrin cites connections with Exod. 16, 24, and Luke 14:12–15. <em>Kingdom of God</em>, 215–17. Gibson argues for a connection between the “Massah” tradition (Exod. 17:1–7; Num. 14; Deut. 6–8; Pss. 78, 95, 106; 1 Cor. 10) and the entire LP, particularly the bread petition. The focus would then be on avoiding the unfaithfulness of the wilderness generation. “An Eschatological Prayer?,” 101–102. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-53">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Monetary debts might be in view, but personal sins/offences seem to be primary. After all, we don’t owe God money. France, <em>Matthew</em>, 249–50; cf. Matt 6:14–15; 18:21–35; Luke 11:4. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-54">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It does not. See Matt. 18:21–35 for a similarly reciprocal depiction of forgiveness that emphasizes God’s merciful initiative. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-55">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Perrin, <em>The Kingdom of God</em>, 220. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-56">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>France (<em>Matthew</em>, 252) and Luz (<em>Matthew 1–7</em>, 322) both argue that <em>peirasmos</em> did not have such a meaning, although Luz admits Rev. 3:10 (“Because you have kept my word of patient endurance, I will keep you from the hour of trial [τῆς ὥρας τοῦ πειρασμοῦ] that is coming on the whole world to test the inhabitants of the earth”) as an exception. It seems like an important exception(!), though not definitive. As Hagner (<em>Matthew 1–13</em>, 151) notes, <em>peirasmos</em> has the definite article in Rev. 3:10. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-57">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>See Perrin, <em>The Kingdom of God</em>, 220–23; France, <em>Matthew</em>, 252. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-58">↑</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>France, <em>Matthew</em>, 231n14, 251. <a href="#post-41777-footnote-ref-59">↑</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spirit, Flesh, Restoration, and Sublimation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 18:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s an intriguing passage in Bonhoeffer’s Letters and Papers from Prison where he discusses the relationship between “spirit” and “flesh,” in the context of discussing “restoration” and “sublimation,” in the context of discussing lyrics from certain hymns and songs that were meaningful to him in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is, from a December 19, 1943 (the Fourth Sunday of Advent) letter to Eberhard Bethge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent weeks this line has been running through my head over and over: “Calm your hearts, dear friends; / whatever plagues you, / whatever fails you, / I will restore it all.” What does that mean, “I will restore it all”? Nothing is lost; in Christ all things are taken up, preserved, albeit in transfigured form, transparent, clear, liberated from the torment of self-serving demands. Christ brings all this back, indeed, as God intended, without being distorted by sin. The doctrine originating in Eph. 1:10 of the restoration of all things, ἀνακεφαλαίωσις—re-capitulatio (Irenaeus), is a magnificent and consummately consoling thought. (DBWE 8:229–30)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There’s an intriguing passage in Bonhoeffer’s Letters and Papers from Prison where he discusses the relationship between “spirit” and “flesh,” in the context of discussing “restoration” and “sublimation,” in the context of discussing lyrics from certain hymns and songs that were meaningful to him in prison.</p>
<p>Here it is, from a December 19, 1943 (the Fourth Sunday of Advent) letter to Eberhard Bethge:</p>
<blockquote><p>In recent weeks this line has been running through my head over and over: “Calm your hearts, dear friends; / whatever plagues you, / whatever fails you, / I will restore it all.” What does that mean, “I will restore it all”? Nothing is lost; in Christ all things are taken up, preserved, albeit in transfigured form, transparent, clear, liberated from the torment of self-serving demands. Christ brings all this back, indeed, as God intended, without being distorted by sin. The doctrine originating in Eph. 1:10 of the restoration of all things, ἀνακεφαλαίωσις—re-capitulatio (Irenaeus), is a magnificent and consummately consoling thought. (DBWE 8:229–30)</p></blockquote><p>…</p>
<blockquote><p>I also occasionally think of the p 231 from the Augustinian “O bone Jesu,” by Schütz. In a certain way, namely, in its devotion—ecstatic, aching, and nevertheless so pure—isn’t this passage something like the “restoration” of all earthly desire? By the way, “restoration” is, of course, not to be confused with “sublimation”! “Sublimation” is σάρξ, (and pietistic?!), whereas “restoration” is spirit, meant not in the sense of “spiritualization” (which is also σάρξ) but of καινή κτίσις through the πνεῦμα ἅγιον. (DBWE 8:230–31)</p></blockquote><p>It’s intriguing (to me) because, in other prison letters, Bonhoeffer uses “spirit” and/vs. “flesh,” as well as the word “restoration,” to describe Barth’s theological critique of religion.</p>
<p>On April 30, 1944, Bonhoeffer wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>How can Christ become Lord of the religionless as well? Is there such a thing as a religionless Christian? If religion is only the garb in which Christianity is clothed—and this garb has looked very different in different ages—what then is religionless Christianity? Barth, who is the only one to have begun thinking along these lines, nevertheless did not pursue these thoughts all the way, did not think them through, but <strong>ended up with a positivism of revelation, which in the end essentially remained a restoration.</strong> (DBWE 8:363–64, emphasis added)</p></blockquote><p>Then, on June 8, 1944, Bonhoeffer wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>Barth was the first to recognize the error of all these attempts (which were basically all still sailing in the wake of liberal theology, without intending to do so) in that they all aim to save some room for religion in the world or over against the world. <strong>He led the God of Jesus Christ forward to battle against religion, πνεῦμα against σάρξ.</strong> This remains his greatest merit (the second edition of The Epistle to the Romans, despite all the neo-Kantian eggshells!). Through his later Dogmatics he has put the church in a position to carry this distinction in principle all the way through. (DBWE 8:428–29, emphasis added)</p></blockquote><p><em>Furthermore</em>, “sublimation” is a very important word for Barth’s theological critique of religion as found in Church Dogmatics I/2, §17, “The Revelation of God as the Sublimation [Aufhebung, sometimes translated “abolition”] of Religion”!</p>
<p>For a moment, I thought I might be on to something here. What was going on with Bonhoeffer’s collocation of “flesh,” “spirit,” “restoration,” and “sublimation”?</p>
<p>However, I took a closer look and realized that, in the December 19, 1943 letter, Bonhoeffer uses the word <em>Wiederbringung</em> for “restoration,” as opposed to <em>Restauration</em>, which he uses to describe Barth’s positivism of revelation in the April 30, 1944 letter.</p>
<p>Furthermore, he uses <em>Sublimierung</em> for “sublimation,” and not <em>Aufhebung</em>, the term Barth uses in CD I/2.</p>
<p>So now I’m trying to parse out the differences between “Wiederbringung” and “Restauration,” and between “Sublimierung” and “Aufhebung.” Not to mention the connection between Barth and Bonhoeffer on the theme of spirit vs. flesh!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me StickK to my writing habit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need to finish &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/&#34;&gt;this dissertation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I’ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it’s been a bear to get back on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I need to finish <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/">this dissertation</a>.</p>
<p>To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.</p>
<p>Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I’ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it’s been a bear to get back on!</p>
<p>So, I’ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.</p>
<p>If I don’t write 500 words related to my dissertation every day, StickK will donate $35 dollars every week I fail to the NRA.</p>
<p><em>(I do not like the NRA.)</em></p>
<p>I’m giving this a try for 8 weeks. If it works well, I’ll continue the commitment via StickK!</p>
<p>If you’d like to support me and keep track of my progress on StickK, you can do so by clicking <a href="https://stik.to/r2N">here</a>.</p>
<p>If you have a habit you’d like to stick to, give StickK a try!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a fantastic wooden pencil (Mitsubishi 9850)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to give a quick shout-out to this fantastic pencil: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2QcXI2B&#34;&gt;the Mitsubishi 9850&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Mitsubishi-Pencil-pencil-hardness-K9850HB/dp/B001BKZVWU/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=li3&amp;amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;linkId=e6e38efe0138c6a5bb4092270163728e&amp;amp;language=en_US&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B001BKZVWU&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;language=en_US&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=joshuapsteele-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001BKZVWU&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s cheap, writes well, erases well, and looks great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on wooden pencils, read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-wooden-pencils/pt/633&#34;&gt;this JetPens guide to the best wooden pencils&lt;/a&gt;. And, while you’re at it, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-pencil-sharpeners/pt/710&#34;&gt;JetPens’ recommendations for the best pencil sharpeners&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just wanted to give a quick shout-out to this fantastic pencil: <a href="https://amzn.to/2QcXI2B">the Mitsubishi 9850</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mitsubishi-Pencil-pencil-hardness-K9850HB/dp/B001BKZVWU/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=e6e38efe0138c6a5bb4092270163728e&amp;language=en_US"><img loading="lazy" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&ASIN=B001BKZVWU&Format=_SL250_&ID=AsinImage&MarketPlace=US&ServiceVersion=20070822&WS=1&tag=joshuapsteele-20&language=en_US"></a><img loading="lazy" src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=joshuapsteele-20&language=en_US&l=li3&o=1&a=B001BKZVWU"></p>
<p>It’s cheap, writes well, erases well, and looks great!</p>
<p>For more on wooden pencils, read <a href="https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-wooden-pencils/pt/633">this JetPens guide to the best wooden pencils</a>. And, while you’re at it, check out <a href="https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-pencil-sharpeners/pt/710">JetPens’ recommendations for the best pencil sharpeners</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Need to Develop a Writing Habit. Do You?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because good writing = good thinking, I believe that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; could benefit from developing the habit of regular writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, because I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am a Ph.D. student about to begin work on his dissertation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit a blog (&lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/&#34;&gt;Rookie Anglican&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write this personal blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need to develop the habit of regular writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until now, I’ve largely relied upon writing in fits and starts, when the Muse descends, as it were.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Because good writing = good thinking, I believe that <em>everyone</em> could benefit from developing the habit of regular writing.</p>
<p>However, because I</p>
<ul>
<li>Am a Ph.D. student about to begin work on his dissertation</li>
<li>Edit a blog (<a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/">Rookie Anglican</a>)</li>
<li>Write this personal blog</li>
</ul>
<p>I <em>really</em> need to develop the habit of regular writing.</p>
<p>Up until now, I’ve largely relied upon writing in fits and starts, when the Muse descends, as it were.</p>
<p>This, however, is not good enough (as Stephen Pressfield forcefully says in his book, <a href="http://amzn.to/2DDHfu7"><em>The War of Art: Break Through the Blocks and Win Your Inner Creative Battles</em></a>). It won’t get my dissertation written, nor will it help me stay on top of two different blogs!</p>
<p>What’s the solution? A regular writing habit, day in and day out.</p>
<h1 id="how-to-developchange-a-habit">How to develop/change a habit</h1>
<p>There are plenty of guides out there on the internet about the process of habit formation. Here are a few:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://jamesclear.com/habits">The Habits Guide: How to Build Good Habits and Break Bad Ones </a>[James Clear]</li>
<li><a href="https://www.npr.org/2012/03/05/147192599/habits-how-they-form-and-how-to-break-them">Habits: How They Form and How to Break Them</a> [NPR]</li>
<li><a href="https://zenhabits.net/habitses/">The Four Habits that Form Habits</a> [Zen Habits]</li>
</ul>
<p>Furthermore, there are two excellent books on habit formation that I highly recommend:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2HHVT5Z"><em>The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business</em></a> by Charles Duhigg</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2pnd5Xz"><em>Better than Before: What I Learned About Making and Breaking Habits–to Sleep More, Quit Sugar, Procrastinate Less, and Generally Build a Happier Life</em></a> by Gretchen Rubin</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="habit--trigger--behavior--reward">Habit = Trigger + Behavior + Reward</h2>
<p>If you look through those resources, you’ll notice a particular model that appears again and again. A habit boils down to three things (this version of the framework mainly comes from Charles Duhigg’s <a href="http://amzn.to/2pkxfBO"><em>The Power of Habit</em></a><em>.</em> You can read the appendix of the book for free <a href="http://charlesduhigg.com/how-habits-work/">here</a>.) :</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>TRIGGER</strong>: The cue or reminder that prompts the behavior. Frequently, cues involve
<ul>
<li>Time</li>
<li>Location</li>
<li>People (who are you with?)</li>
<li>Preceding Action (what did you just do?)</li>
<li>Emotion</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>BEHAVIOR</strong>: The behavior itself, whether something good for you, like writing 500 words every day, or something bad for you, like smoking a pack of cigarettes.</li>
<li><strong>REWARD</strong>: The benefit you get from the behavior.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="to-change-an-old-habit-taken-from-this-helpful-flowchart-from-charles-duhigg">To change an old habit (taken from <a href="http://charlesduhigg.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Flowchart-How-to-Change-a-Habit.pdf">this helpful flowchart</a> from Charles Duhigg):</h2>
<ul>
<li>Isolate the consistent TRIGGER. When you feel the craving to do the thing you’re trying to stop doing, ask yourself:
<ul>
<li>What time is it?</li>
<li>Where are you?</li>
<li>Who else is around?</li>
<li>What did you just do?</li>
<li>What emotion are you feeling?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Isolate the consistent REWARD. What benefit/craving is this habit providing/satisfying? Come up with an idea and test the theory by substituting different rewards until you find something that makes the craving goes away. This is what you’re really craving as a result of the behavior.</li>
<li>Insert a new BEHAVIOR between the trigger and the reward.
<ul>
<li>Choose a new activity that is triggered by the old trigger and provides the old reward.</li>
<li>Write this commitment down in the following form: “When [TRIGGER occurs], I will [do the new BEHAVIOR], because it provides me with [the REWARD].”</li>
<li>Follow through on your plan!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="to-develop-a-new-habit-taken-from-this-helpful-flowchart-from-charles-duhigg">To develop a new habit (taken from <a href="http://charlesduhigg.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Flowchart-How-to-Create-a-Habit.pdf">this helpful flowchart</a> from Charles Duhigg):</h2>
<ul>
<li>Come up with a TRIGGER:
<ul>
<li>Time?</li>
<li>Location?</li>
<li>People around?</li>
<li>Immediately preceding action?</li>
<li>Emotion?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Come up with a REWARD for after the behavior:
<ul>
<li>Make sure you actually enjoy it!</li>
<li>Make sure that you crave this reward when exposed to the trigger from the previous step!</li>
<li>Ideally, you will eventually desire the habit for its intrinsic reward. That’s what you’re shooting for.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Insert the BEHAVIOR into a routine:
<ul>
<li>Write it down in the following form: “When [TRIGGER occurs], I will [perform desired BEHAVIOR], because it provides me with [the REWARD].”</li>
<li>Follow through on your plan!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="how-to-develop-a-writing-habit-my-example">How to develop a writing habit: my example</h1>
<p>In theory, it’s pretty simple, actually. We just need to take the previous outline, for how to develop a new habit, and apply it to the specific behavior of writing consistently. 500 words a day is a great goal, and it’s the one I’ll be using.</p>
<p>First, however, we need a TRIGGER. For me, the trigger I’m going to try out for the next few days is “When I arrive at the library in the morning, before doing anything else…”</p>
<p>The REWARD I’m going to experiment with is: “…I will go for a 20-minute walk outside.”</p>
<p>Put together, my commitment looks like: “When I arrive at the library in the morning, before doing anything else, I will write 500 words, because then I get to go for a 20-minute walk outside.”</p>
<h1 id="what-about-you-what-will-your-writing-habit-look-like">What about you? What will your writing habit look like?</h1>
<p>Would you like to create a writing habit?</p>
<p>If so, what’s your trigger going to be?</p>
<p>What’s your reward going to be?</p>
<p>What’s your writing behavior going to look like? How often will you write? How many words?</p>
<h1 id="get-specific-let-me-know-what-youre-planning-in-the-comments-below"><strong>Get specific! Let me know what you’re planning in the comments below!</strong></h1>
<hr>
<p><em>Note: some of the links above are Amazon affiliate links. This means that, if you click the link and make a purchase on Amazon, I receive a small commission (at no extra cost to you). I only ever recommend things I think that my readers will find helpful.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
