<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sermon on the Mount on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sermon-on-the-mount/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sermon on the Mount on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:46:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sermon-on-the-mount/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are the Beatitudes “Renunciations” (Verzichte)?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 12:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/are-the-beatitudes-renunciations-verzichte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Discipleship&lt;/em&gt; (DBWE 4), Dietrich Bonhoeffer frames all of the Beatitudes in terms of Jesus’ disciples living in &lt;em&gt;renunciation&lt;/em&gt; (Verzicht) and &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; (Mangel).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, for Bonhoeffer, Jesus is only speaking to his disciples in the Beatitudes (he makes this argument on the basis of Luke 6:20ff.). And the disciples’ renunciation and want are &lt;em&gt;caused&lt;/em&gt; by Jesus’s call to discipleship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus sees&lt;/em&gt;: his disciples are over there. They have visibly left the people to join him. He has called each individual one. They have given up everything in response to his call. Now they are living in renunciation and want; they are the poorest of the poor, the most tempted of the tempted, the hungriest of the hungry. They have only him. Yes, and with him they have nothing in the world, nothing at all, but everything, everything with God. (DBWE 4:101).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Beatitudes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 19:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interpretive-approaches-to-the-beatitudes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I said in my previous post, “&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/&#34;&gt;Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount&lt;/a&gt;,” I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, when interpreting the Sermon on the Mount, the best place to start is at the beginning! This means beginning with the Beatitudes in Matthew 5:1–12.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beatitudes-matt-5112&#34;&gt;The Beatitudes (Matt. 5:1–12)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 When Jesus saw the crowds, he went up the mountain; and after he sat down, his disciples came to him. 2 Then he began to speak, and taught them, saying:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretive Approaches to the Sermon on the Mount</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 22:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m working on how Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-order-to-help-situate-my-discussion-of-barths-and-bonhoeffers-readings-im-trying-to-get-a-better-grasp-of-the-various-interpretive-approaches-to-the-sermon-on-the-mount&#34;&gt;In order to help situate my discussion of Barth’s and Bonhoeffer’s readings, I’m trying to get a better grasp of the various interpretive approaches to the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, the most exhaustive Sermon on the Mount “interpretive taxonomy” that I’ve found has been from Grant &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/37oTuuA&#34;&gt;Osborne’s &lt;em&gt;Matthew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Zondervan Exegetical Commentary on the New Testament; Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2010), 159.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
