<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Personal on Joshua P. Steele</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Joshua P. Steele</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 11:39:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/personal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>10 Things I Love About My Kids</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/10-things-i-love-about-my-kids/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 11:39:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/10-things-i-love-about-my-kids/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lest &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/i-love-my-kids-but-i-sometimes-regret-having-them/">my previous parenting post&lt;/a> suggest that things are all doom-and-gloom at the Steele-haus, here are 10 things I love about my kids.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>I got to baptize all 3 of them as babies, a poignant reminder that they are beloved children of God.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They all love books, which warms my nerdy heart.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The way Eleanor (1yo) greets me. It used to be a very excited squeal. Now it’s “Ah! Daddy!”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Andrew (4yo) has a great memory for stories, especially Bible stories. I was redoing our fire pit, and spraying it with a hose to cut down on dust as I re-leveled the ground. Andrew: “Elijah put water on the fire, too!” (see 1 Kings 18).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eva (6yo) is smart as a whip. She asks great questions, and I’m looking forward to (re-)learning with her as she gets older.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eleanor’s recently learned how to do an overly-exaggerated “angry eyebrows” face, and I find it absolutely hilarious. She now does it to get a laugh.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Andrew loves Spiderman, and he goes back-and-forth on whether or not he thinks superheroes are real. Listening to him as he narrates Spiderman scenarios while running around in his Spiderman costume is always entertaining.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eva will sometimes read books to Andrew and Eleanor. They will then imitate her–Andrew, by reciting stories from memory as he turns through the books, and Eleanor, by babbling to herself as she flips the pages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I can get them all to watch things with me like This Old House, DIY videos, tool reviews, etc. Partially because they’re all curious and enjoy learning about tools. Partially (OK, mostly) because they’re thankful they’re watching *something* on the TV.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They’re all still young enough that they frequently want hugs and snuggles.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>I Love My Kids, But I Sometimes Regret Having Them</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-love-my-kids-but-i-sometimes-regret-having-them/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 08:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-love-my-kids-but-i-sometimes-regret-having-them/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love my kids, but I sometimes regret having them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pardon the clickbait-y title and opening sentence. But are we parents allowed to say that? Are we allowed to feel both of those things at once?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ve got a 6-year-old, a 4-year-old, and an almost-2-year-old. And, no, I don’t actually begrudge them their existence! I want what’s best for their lives and futures. And don’t get me wrong; &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/10-things-i-love-about-my-kids/">there are moments of laughter, poignancy, joy, etc.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Know Thyself: Unveiling Your Unique Strengths and Personality Traits</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/know-thyself-unveiling-your-unique-strengths-and-personality-traits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:41:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/know-thyself-unveiling-your-unique-strengths-and-personality-traits/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the quest for personal and professional growth, understanding our unique strengths and personality traits can be incredibly enlightening. Today, I want to share my insights from various personality paradigms and how they shape my approach to work and life.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cliftonstrengths-harnessing-core-talents">CliftonStrengths: Harnessing Core Talents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The CliftonStrengths assessment has been instrumental in identifying my core talents. Here are my top five strengths:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Input&lt;/strong>: I have an insatiable curiosity and a constant desire to collect information. This strength fuels my drive to learn and gather knowledge from diverse sources.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Intellection&lt;/strong>: My love for deep thinking and intellectual discussions is a hallmark of this strength. It allows me to explore complex ideas and engage in thoughtful analysis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Learner&lt;/strong>: The process of learning excites me. Whether it’s acquiring new skills or understanding new concepts, I thrive in environments that offer continuous growth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ideation&lt;/strong>: Creativity and innovation are my playgrounds. I enjoy brainstorming and generating new ideas, which often leads to novel solutions and approaches.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Analytical&lt;/strong>: I have a keen ability to dissect problems and examine them from different angles. This strength helps me make informed decisions based on solid data and evidence.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>For more on CliftonStrengths, check out &lt;a href="https://www.gallup.com/cliftonstrengths/en/home.aspx">Gallup’s CliftonStrengths&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Finding a Hat for My Big, Bald Head</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/finding-a-hat-for-my-big-bald-head/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:48:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/finding-a-hat-for-my-big-bald-head/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been on a lifelong journey to find hats that will fit my big ol’ head. Now that I’m bald, and the summer months are approaching, I figured it would be good to find one or two more hats to add to my rotation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve narrowed this round down to trying the following hats, in case you’re interested (Amazon affiliate links below):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>TOO SMALL FOR ME&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3xVZv3O">Carhartt Men’s Rugged Professional Series Canvas Mesh-Back Cap&lt;/a> (Shadow, One Size)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3Wi6GgS">Carhartt Men’s 100289 Odessa Ball Cap&lt;/a> (Carhartt Brown, One Size)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I’m a sucker for Carhartt and Carhartt brown!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This hat is comfortable&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I like that it looks different than my other hats, which tend to be black, gray, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3UzLvWa">Ankor Ultra Performance Water-Resistant UPF 50 Baseball Hat&lt;/a> (Charcoal Gray, One Size)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Charcoal gray is my favorite color (not sure what that says about me…)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I really like the look and fit of this one&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3xLtY4j">Flexfit Men’s Delta Seamless Cap&lt;/a> (Dark Grey, XX-Large)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Love the look and color of this&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Very comfortable!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I wonder if it’s a tad *too* big for my head, though&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/4aI6v2F">Flexfit Mens Cool &amp;amp; Dry Sport&lt;/a> (Grey, X-Large-XX-Large)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This hat gets here in the mail today! I’m excited to try it out&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/IMG_8778-2-1024x1024.jpg" alt="Me and my big head" />
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Home Gym Upgrades</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/home-gym-upgrades/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:15:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/home-gym-upgrades/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve often enjoyed lifting weights, but I’ve never enjoyed going to the gym. So, I’ve long wanted a nice home gym.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we lived in a basement apartment, space was very limited, but I was able to fit a &lt;a href="https://valorfitness.com/products/bd-9-independent-power-squat-stands">Valor Fitness BD-9 squat rack/stands&lt;/a> and an &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3Tawich">Amazon Basics flat bench&lt;/a> in, along with a &lt;a href="https://www.dickssportinggoods.com/p/fitness-gear-300-lbolympic-weight-set-16fgeu300lbstwth7brb/16fgeu300lbstwth7brb">300-lb Olympic barbell and weight set&lt;/a> from Dicks Sporting Goods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(If you’re similarly pressed for space, I highly recommend those items above!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back in the Saddle</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/back-in-the-saddle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 21:24:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/back-in-the-saddle/</guid><description>&lt;p>I know I’m not alone in this, but the past few years have been pretty rough for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I’ve gained at least 50 pounds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I had a fun part-time gig as a managing editor come to an end.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I’ve come to terms with some &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/its-time-to-get-some-help/">long-term depression and anxiety&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I had a job offer ripped out from under me.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/its-official-im-hitting-pause-on-my-ph-d-for-a-year/">hit pause&lt;/a> on and eventually dropped out of my Ph.D. program.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I’ve &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/">resigned from ordained ministry in the ACNA&lt;/a>, my previous denomination.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Sure, some things have gone well. I’ve got a loving wife (who’s a superhero) and three healthy children. I’ve got a new career (as a software developer) that I very much enjoy. We’ve got a roof over our heads. I make more money now than I ever have.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I'm Resigning from Ordained Ministry in the Anglican Church in North America</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 19:50:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/</guid><description>&lt;p>After a considerable period of discernment, coupled with my growing disaffection with the Anglican Church in North America, I sense God calling me to step away from ordained ministry in the ACNA and instead to focus on my family and my career as a software engineer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This also coincides with plans to move closer to family in NW Ohio (where there is not much of an ACNA presence to speak of) and to then pursue church involvement outside of the ACNA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life Lessons: 32 Things I've Learned So Far</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/life-lessons/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:45:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/life-lessons/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here are 32 things I’ve learned from life, so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>You are not your thoughts. There is a “you” behind and above your inner voice/monologue/dialogue. Pay attention to what you pay attention to. Think about what you think about.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We always only have the present moment. Focusing too much on the future leads to anxiety. Focusing too much on the past leads to depression. Wherever you are, be fully there, now! (Read &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/400hFeH">&lt;em>The Power of Now&lt;/em> by Eckhart Tolle&lt;/a> [affiliate link here and throughout] for more on this.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It’s OK not to be OK. Feeling anxious, depressed, angry, etc. is fine. However, avoid the trap of feeling anxious about how anxious you feel, feeling depressed about how depressed you feel, etc. (Learned this from &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/404talb">&lt;em>The Happiness Trap&lt;/em> by Russ Harris&lt;/a>.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you never make mistakes, you’re not learning/growing as well as you could be. Perfectionism is a deadly prison. Break free with “good enough” and “always learning.”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You are stronger than you think you are. You are weaker than you think you are.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ask more questions. Ask better questions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>God is not a thing among things. There is an “infinite qualitative difference” between God and everything that is not God, everything that exists.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jesus of Nazareth is the living Lord of all. ___ is not.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Beware of overconfidence in what the Bible (or any other sacred text, for that matter) “clearly”does or does not say.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>God is devoted to the poor and powerless. Those who speak and act on God’s behalf should speak and act &lt;em>for&lt;/em> the poor and powerless.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To do better with people, ask them questions about themselves. (Read the classic &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3QlSsrR">&lt;em>How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/em> by Dale Carnegie&lt;/a>.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can’t out-exercise your appetite forever. &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/4018XfY">Eat food. Mostly plants. Not too much.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Get enough sleep. You probably don’t get enough sleep.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lift heavy things.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go outside. Take a walk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open a Roth IRA. Invest consistently in low-cost mutual funds or lifecycle funds as soon as you can. (Learned this from &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/48Uc65D">&lt;em>I Will Teach You to Be Rich&lt;/em> by Ramit Sethi&lt;/a>.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reading is a superpower. You can learn from as many other lives and lifetimes as you want. &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/46YrOdW">Learn how to read&lt;/a>. Then &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/46Dgm7J">learn how to learn.&lt;/a> Then, learn whatever you want!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Always read with a pen or pencil in your hand. If you really want to learn from a book, buy a physical copy and annotate the heck out of it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You always have to earn and keep your audience’s attention. Before/while communicating, ask yourself “Why should they care? What’s in it for them?”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Humans are incredibly good at misunderstanding each other. Before/while communicating, ask yourself “How might I be misunderstood? How might I be misunderstanding others?”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remember that you and your loved ones are all going to die. What do you want to be known for?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eulogize people BEFORE they die.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Everyone should go to therapy for at least a few months.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Slow is smooth. Smooth is fast.” Feeling nervous/stressed/angry/etc.? SLOW DOWN, especially if you’re in front of other people.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Courage is a choice, not a feeling. No matter how nervous you are, you can always ACT courageously.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Everyone is trying to figure it out as they go along. Do you often feel like an imposter? Join the club!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Act like you’ve been here before. Act like you’ve done this before. Act calm, comfortable, and confident, if for no other reason than to help the people around you feel calm, comfortable, and confident.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leadership is service. Leadership is the willingness to make a decision for the good of the group even when it’s awkward or uncomfortable to do so.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Focus on what you can control.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Journal. What do you really want? What are you afraid of? What’s the most important thing you need to get done today? Get a notebook and write it down!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In many domains, 80% of the outcomes/effects come from 20% of the inputs/causes. Find the “vital few” things that have outsized impacts, both positive and negative, on your life. Double-down on what’s helping you. Get rid of what’s hurting you.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use smoked paprika. You’re welcome.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>My Coding Bootcamp Journey: How a Pastor Became a Programmer</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 17:42:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I changed my major from Mechanical Engineering to Bible shortly before my first semester of college, I realized that what I was studying was not going to make me rich.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, throughout undergrad, seminary, and into a Ph.D. program in theology, the notion of “bi-vocational ministry” (serving the church while also making money outside of the church doing something else) was on my radar screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, for a few months between finishing seminary and starting my Ph.D. program, I tried to teach myself the basics of web design (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) and Ruby on Rails. (I signed up for an account on &lt;a href="https://teamtreehouse.com/">Treehouse&lt;/a> and on &lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/">freeCodeCamp&lt;/a> and I got to work!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Color is My Parachute? The Flower Petal Exercise</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-color-is-my-parachute-the-flower-petal-exercise/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 22:34:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-color-is-my-parachute-the-flower-petal-exercise/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m working my way through the classic job search guide &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3O8cnYK">What Color Is Your Parachute&lt;/a>&lt;/em>. First, I’ll summarize the 7-part “Flower Petal” exercise—a comprehensive self-assessment geared toward the workplace. Then, I’ll share *my* results from the self-assessment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, but first, my &lt;strong>TL;DR&lt;/strong>: &lt;strong>If you’re looking for work, or going to be looking for work soon, do yourself a huge favor and buy the latest edition of &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/3O8cnYK">What Color Is Your Parachute&lt;/a>&lt;/em>.&lt;/strong> Work through the book, especially the Flower Petal Exercise. It’s well-worth your time!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It's Official. I'm Hitting Pause on My Ph.D. for a Year</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-official-im-hitting-pause-on-my-ph-d-for-a-year/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 18:09:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-official-im-hitting-pause-on-my-ph-d-for-a-year/</guid><description>&lt;p>I received word yesterday that the Ph.D. Committee voted to approve my request for “Excused Program Leave” beginning in January 2021 and lasting until January 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the risk of sounding like Captain Obvious, 2020 has been a particularly difficult year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Attempting to complete my “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” dissertation has taken a toll on my mental health as I ran into some major research and writing roadblocks right before and during the COVID pandemic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I'm looking for a new role to supplement my part-time work for Anglican Compass</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-looking-for-a-new-role-to-supplement-my-part-time-work-for-anglican-compass/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 21:07:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/im-looking-for-a-new-role-to-supplement-my-part-time-work-for-anglican-compass/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey everyone! Just a brief update to note that I’m looking for a new role to supplement my part-time work as Managing Editor of &lt;a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">Anglican Compass&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m pretty flexible at this point, but I want to do something that benefits the church. I think I would make a great Assistant Rector! 🙂&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any advice, opportunities, or connections you can offer would be appreciated!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/portfolio/cv/">view/share my CV here&lt;/a>. And &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuapsteele/">here’s my LinkedIn profile&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Josh+? On the use of the sign of the cross (plus sign) in clergy signatures</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/josh-on-the-use-of-the-sign-of-the-cross-plus-sign-in-clergy-signatures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 13:57:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/josh-on-the-use-of-the-sign-of-the-cross-plus-sign-in-clergy-signatures/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is, admittedly, a half-baked opinion. However, I need to get back in the habit of blogging/writing regularly, so here goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my opinion, the use of the sign of the cross in clergy names/signatures—unless it’s done in official ecclesiastical communication or immediately after a blessing or prayer for the recipient—is pretentious. It’s showy. At the very least, it conveys or connotes pretentiousness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that I’m not making a claim about the *people* who use crosses in their signatures, their inner thoughts, or their intentions. For all I know, every single clergyperson out there says a prayer of blessing for their recipients every single time they use the sign of the cross in a signature. I’m also not writing this about any person in particular.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It's Time to Get Some Help</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-to-get-some-help/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 17:19:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-to-get-some-help/</guid><description>&lt;p>Due to increased symptoms of depression and anxiety in recent weeks, I’ve decided to try out a combination of counseling and medication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure, I’ve still been able to get out of bed in the morning. And I wasn’t having any serious thoughts about hurting myself. But still, I was feeling hopeless and &lt;em>trapped&lt;/em> often enough that I decided it was time to seek out help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know, I know. That’s pretty personal for a blog post for the whole internet to read!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Prayer for Trustfulness in Times of Worry and Anxiety</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-for-trustfulness-in-times-of-worry-and-anxiety/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 13:03:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-for-trustfulness-in-times-of-worry-and-anxiety/</guid><description>&lt;p>I needed this prayer this morning, and I plan to return to it often in the days ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most loving Father, you will us to give thanks for all things, to dread nothing but the loss of you, and to cast all our care on the One who cares for us. Preserve us from faithless fears and worldly anxieties, and grant that no clouds of this mortal life may hide from us the light of that love which is immortal, and which you have manifested unto us in your Son, Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Day of 24th Grade!</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/first-day-of-24th-grade-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 14:45:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/first-day-of-24th-grade-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not sure how this is going to go, or even why I’m doing this anymore, but here we go! Still praying for either a dissertation break-through or a clear sign that I should quit. I hope to receive or discover one of those before the end of the calendar year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It’s time for another social media fast!</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-for-another-social-media-fast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 15:52:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-for-another-social-media-fast/</guid><description>&lt;p>After listening to &lt;a href="https://www.blinkist.com/en/books/deep-work-en">the Blinkist summary of Cal Newport’s &lt;em>Deep Work&lt;/em>&lt;/a> (I’ve read the book, this was just for a refresher), I’m convinced that it’s time for another 30-day fast from Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I’ll still keep &lt;a href="https://micro.blog/joshuapsteele">my micro.blog up and running&lt;/a>, but between &lt;a href="https://anglicancompass.com">running Anglican Compass&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/">sprinting for some last-ditch clarity on my increasingly frustrating dissertation&lt;/a>, I need all the extra bandwidth I can get!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you need to get in touch for some reason, please &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/contact/">use the contact form on my website&lt;/a>. You can also &lt;a href="https://buttondown.email/joshuapsteele">sign up for my very occasional email newsletter here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ph.D. Plan (Or the Lack Thereof)</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 21:40:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid><description>&lt;p>For months and months now, I’ve been praying for either (1) a breakthrough on my “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” dissertation or (2) a clear sign that I should quit the Ph.D. Unfortunately, after countless confusing dead ends in my endeavors to put Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer into precise conversation with each other regarding specific passages of the Bible, I’ve now realized that such an approach is not going to work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Shameless Request: Help Me Buy More Books?</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 21:08:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</guid><description>&lt;p>After realizing just how easy it was to lose access to the physical books that I own (now sequestered in my library carrel at Wheaton), on a bit of a whim &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/donate/573962246651661/">I created a fundraiser to help my upgrade my Logos Bible Software library&lt;/a> to either the Anglican Gold ($216) or Anglican Platinum ($582) libraries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upgrading would help me in my preaching, teaching, and writing roles (as a pastor-theologian and as the Managing Editor of AnglicanCompass.com). I’ve already benefited immensely from the Anglican Silver package I bought when I got into the Logos Bible Software ecosystem a couple years ago (mainly to gain easy digital access to Barth and Bonhoeffer’s writings for my dissertation). I plan to stick with Logos—especially for biblical commentaries, systematic theologies, and reference works—because it allows me to quickly research, prepare for sermons, answer questions from readers, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>With baby #2 on the way, I'm looking for work!</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/with-baby-2-on-the-way-im-looking-for-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 16:14:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/with-baby-2-on-the-way-im-looking-for-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m a husband to Rachel and a father to Eva.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m also:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>An Anglican Priest (serving/volunteering without pay)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A Ph.D. Student at Wheaton College (full-time, including a fellowship as a Teaching/Research Assistant)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Managing Editor of AnglicanPastor.com (part-time)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In May 2020, my full-time residential obligations to Wheaton’s Ph.D. program will come to an end. I’ll still need to finish my dissertation in the following 1-2 years (the sooner, the better!), but I will no longer have to work on campus as a teaching/research assistant.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Here's a video of my ordination to the Priesthood</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-a-video-of-my-ordination-to-the-priesthood/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 22:50:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-a-video-of-my-ordination-to-the-priesthood/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio">&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nfRMqjhNhzs?feature=oembed" title="Church of the Savior Ordination Service (2019-11-02)" width="750">&lt;/iframe>&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>My Bishop, Todd Hunter, preached [an excellent, challenging sermon (“Love Your Enemies, Really?”)](https://friendsofthesavior.org/sermons/love-your-enemies-really-bishop-todd-hunter). It’s definitely worth a listen!</description></item><item><title>Help me achieve my home gym dream</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-achieve-my-home-gym-dream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 18:46:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-achieve-my-home-gym-dream/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m trying to put together a basic home gym in our basement apartment. Mainly, I’m interested in doing squats for now. Then, I’ll expand to deadlifts and benchpress. Our ceilings are too low for overhead presses, however.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, I just ordered the Valor Fitness BD-9 squat rack from Amazon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still need a decent Olympic bar and Olympic plates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use Rapoport's Rules for Better Conversations and Disagreements</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 17:06:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m reading Walter Sinnott-Armstrong’s excellent book, &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2BNTlTq">&lt;em>Think Again: How to Reason and Argue&lt;/em>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In it (on pages 25–26), I came across &lt;a href="https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Rapoport%27s_Rules">“Rapoport’s Rules.”&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First formulated by mathematical psychologist Anatol Rapoport and discussed by Daniel Dennett (&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2NmrH4m">&lt;em>Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, 31–35), here they are:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>1: You should attempt to re-express your target’s position so clearly, vividly, and fairly that your target says, “Thanks, I wish I’d thought of putting it that way.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Women's Ordination Debates in Anglicanism: The 2017 ACNA Report and the 2003 AMIA Report</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/womens-ordination-debates-in-anglicanism-the-2017-acna-report-and-the-2003-amia-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:17:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/womens-ordination-debates-in-anglicanism-the-2017-acna-report-and-the-2003-amia-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>I became an “egalitarian” in college, before I became an Anglican in seminary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s taken some time for me to get used to the different contours of the women’s ordination debate within Anglicanism. Growing up, the debate was all about particular Bible verses and whether or not women could teach and preach. However, in Anglicanism, although those same questions/arguments are present, I hear much more about whether or not women can administer the sacraments as priests.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>StickKing to the Slow Carb Diet</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/stickking-to-the-slow-carb-diet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 02:14:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/stickking-to-the-slow-carb-diet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night, the scale read 192.4. I’d really like it to read 180 or less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, in lieu of how effective &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/">putting money on the line via StickK&lt;/a> has been for my daily writing habit these past two weeks, I’ve decided to put money on the line as motivation to stick to the Slow Carb Diet for a month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For my writing habit, I’ve committed to writing 500 words toward my dissertation every day for 8 weeks. For every week I’m unsuccessful, $35 goes to the NRA. (I’m a pacifist. I do not like the NRA.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What blogs are you reading?</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:53:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</guid><description>&lt;p>Right now, I’m using the RSS readers &lt;a href="https://www.inoreader.com/">Inoreader&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://reederapp.com/">Reeder&lt;/a> to subscribe to the following blogs:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.ayjay.org">Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://fs.blog">Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://seths.blog">Seth’s Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://calnewport.com/blog/">Study Hacks – Decoding Patterns of Success – Cal Newport&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://jamesclear.com">James Clear&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.bakadesuyo.com">Barking Up The Wrong Tree – How to be awesome at life.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://appademic.tech">The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.mcsweeneys.net">McSweeney’s Internet Tendency&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://lifehacker.com">Lifehacker – Do everything better&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>What are you reading?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Help me StickK to my writing habit</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I need to finish &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/">this dissertation&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I’ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it’s been a bear to get back on!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I’ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eva Joy Steele: A Birth Story</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/eva-joy-steele-a-birth-story/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 15:56:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/eva-joy-steele-a-birth-story/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a self-indulgently long story. The gist of it is that my wife, Rachel, was unexpectedly induced due to gestational hypertension at 37 weeks, right before we were supposed to head to Pennsylvania for her sister’s wedding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a lengthy induction and labor, our beautiful daughter, Eva Joy Steele, was born at 5:46am on Friday, July 20, 2018.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If that’s all you’d like to know, great! If you’d like to know more about what went down, keep reading.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Please Don't Leave Me Alone: On Male Friendships, or the Lack Thereof</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 18:15:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maybe you, like me, consider yourself quite the introvert. Maybe you, like me, have a difficult time walking the tightrope between feeling quickly overwhelmed by interpersonal relationships, on the one hand, and feeling incredibly lonely, on the other hand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe you, like me, feel these problems acutely as a male (although I’m sure that females are having their own relational struggles as our culture increasingly pressures us all to be “alone together,” looking at our screens instead of looking each other in the eye).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting back on the "Getting Things Done" Productivity Bandwagon</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 22:06:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting Things Done (“GTD” for short) is a wildly popular personal productivity system invented and popularized by David Allen. However, as &lt;a href="https://lifehacker.com/getting-things-done-ten-years-in-1795707084">Nicole Dieker at Lifehacker pointed out in 2017&lt;/a>, “You don’t hear a lot of people talk about the &lt;a href="http://gettingthingsdone.com/">&lt;em>Getting Things Done&lt;/em>&lt;/a> productivity system anymore.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that’s a shame, because it’s a very effective system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I first tried Getting Things Done after reading “&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2tMiX1w">What’s Best Nex&lt;/a>t” by Matt Perman, and then reading “&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2HvNJxv">Getting Things Done&lt;/a>” by David Allen (in its newly revised 2015 edition) shortly thereafter.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>This Song is a Beautiful Picture of the Theological Journey</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-truth-is-not-a-cave/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 21:36:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-truth-is-not-a-cave/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was recently privileged to see one of my favorite bands, &lt;a href="http://theohhellos.com/">The Oh Hellos&lt;/a>, in concert at the House of Blues in downtown Chicago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love all of The Oh Hellos’ music, but one song, in particular, has remained poignant to me ever since I first heard it. The song is called “The Truth is a Cave,” and I think it provides a beautiful picture of what I’m calling “the theological journey” – the stages one goes through in one’s knowledge of God.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dangerous Beauty: Phoenix and Grand Canyon Trip 2018</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dangerous-beauty-phoenix-grand-canyon-trip-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 14:47:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dangerous-beauty-phoenix-grand-canyon-trip-2018/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="rachel-and-i-just-got-back-from-our-very-first-trip-to-the-southwest">Rachel and I just got back from our very first trip to the Southwest.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The main reason for the trip was to visit some good friends of ours, the Smith family, in Phoenix, AZ. Here’s a picture of the group of us together after church at &lt;a href="https://livingfaithanglican.org/">Living Faith Anglican Church in Tempe, AZ&lt;/a>, where my friend Peter Smith is the rector.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/IMG_3626-1024x768.jpg" alt="" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The trip was a blast. It was great to catch up with the Smiths and to see their new home and church in Arizona.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 Confessions of an Expectant Father</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/3-confessions-expectant-father/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 12:29:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/3-confessions-expectant-father/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="were-expecting">We’re Expecting!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In case you haven’t heard the news, my wife Rachel and I are expecting our firstborn child this August! Rachel is currently 16 weeks along, and we won’t find out the gender of the baby (whom I am affectionately calling “Lump”) for another month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/IMG_3515-e1519734672450-1024x777.jpg" alt="" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-last-few-months-have-been-quite-busy-for-us-since-we-found-out-rachel-is-pregnant">The last few months have been quite busy for us since we found out Rachel is pregnant.&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>She works full-time as a Family Nurse Practitioner.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I’m a full-time Ph.D. student.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We’re both actively involved in our church.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Etc. etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="however-the-next-few-months-also-promise-to-be-busy-as-well">However, the next few months also promise to be busy as well!&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I’ve got a dissertation proposal to defend.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We’ll be traveling for our siblings’ high school graduation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(Lord-willing and baby-waiting) we’ll both be in my sister-in-law’s wedding this Summer (I’m the officiant).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And then? Then Lump makes his or her appearance!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Testimony: A Faith Story, In Brief</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/testimony-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 07:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/testimony-brief/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>The following is an attempt to tell my testimony, the story of my Christian faith, in approximately 500 words. It was challenging to do, but also a helpful exercise! I challenge you to write out your own story in approximately 500 words.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="testimony">Testimony&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>For as long as I can remember, I have known and followed Jesus Christ as my Lord and Savior. However, there has been a lingering problem in our relationship – on my end. Of course, this problem is called “sin.” But, I mean an even more specific problem: my struggle to &lt;em>know&lt;/em> Jesus, and not merely to know &lt;em>about&lt;/em> Jesus.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thank God, I Went to Cedarville</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/thank-god-i-went-to-cedarville/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 20:20:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/thank-god-i-went-to-cedarville/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I prepare for my final semester at &lt;a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/">Beeson Divinity School&lt;/a>, it strikes me just how well I was prepared for my seminary education by my undergraduate professors at Cedarville University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All things considered, my time at CU &lt;strong>exposed me to the riches of biblical and theological studies, and it left me hungry for more&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>College gave me a &lt;strong>love for Christ’s gospel and Christ’s Church&lt;/strong> – which has only increased since I arrived at Beeson.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Do You Want To Be Remembered?</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:49:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</guid><description>&lt;p>Do you know what the worst thing about &lt;em>&lt;strong>death&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> is?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s not the &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;">dying&lt;/span> itself – its the &lt;strong>separation&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is, we don’t suffer the most from our own deaths (a one-time occurrence), but from suffering the deaths of others (repeatedly). Instead of living relationships, we are left with distant memories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A sad reality, to be sure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-if-however-we-could-use-death-to-our-own-advantage">What if, however, we could use death to our own advantage?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I’m convinced this is the truth behind Ecclesiastes 7:2 –&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What are you afraid of?</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 20:02:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m scared. Are you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Specifically, as I wrote in my journal this very morning:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I’m scared – I’m scared of wasting my life, I’m scared of not being worth anything outside of the classroom.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Fear drives so many aspects of our lives – from how we dress, to how we raise our children, to how we elect our leaders. And, if we’re honest with ourselves, fear can play a large role in what/whom we worship.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I'm Reading</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 14:56:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ah, the joys of summer reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="gallery galleryid-3824 gallery-columns-3 gallery-size-medium" id="gallery-1">&lt;figure class="gallery-item">&lt;div class="gallery-icon landscape"> [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0493-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0493-2/) &lt;/div> &lt;figcaption class="wp-caption-text gallery-caption" id="gallery-1-3829"> Hoping to be able to read German with a dictionary by the end of the summer! &lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>&lt;figure class="gallery-item">&lt;div class="gallery-icon landscape"> [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0492-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0492-2/) &lt;/div> &lt;figcaption class="wp-caption-text gallery-caption" id="gallery-1-3828"> Karl Barth’s theological bombshell. &lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>&lt;figure class="gallery-item">&lt;div class="gallery-icon landscape"> [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0494-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0494-2/) &lt;/div> &lt;figcaption class="wp-caption-text gallery-caption" id="gallery-1-3830"> I’m trying the Slow-Carb Diet and kettlebell swings. &lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>&lt;figure class="gallery-item">&lt;div class="gallery-icon landscape"> [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0500-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0500-2/) &lt;/div> &lt;figcaption class="wp-caption-text gallery-caption" id="gallery-1-3834"> I’ve wanted to get my hands on a copy of the Homilies for some time. &lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>&lt;figure class="gallery-item">&lt;div class="gallery-icon landscape"> [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0495-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0495-2/) &lt;/div> &lt;figcaption class="wp-caption-text gallery-caption" id="gallery-1-3831"> Finally getting around to reading this classic! &lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>&lt;figure class="gallery-item">&lt;div class="gallery-icon landscape"> [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0499-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0499-2/) &lt;/div> &lt;figcaption class="wp-caption-text gallery-caption" id="gallery-1-3833"> My very first Seth Godin book. &lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>&lt;figure class="gallery-item">&lt;div class="gallery-icon landscape"> [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0496-300x225.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading/img_0496-2/) &lt;/div> &lt;figcaption class="wp-caption-text gallery-caption" id="gallery-1-3832"> What has Barth to do with Plantinga? I’m hoping Diller can tell me. &lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure> &lt;/div>**What about you? What are you reading?**
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Is there anything I should add to this eclectic assortment?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Theology in Outline: What Do I Believe?</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theology-outline/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:45:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theology-outline/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Theology is confusing enough, much more so when you attempt to summarize it all in a single essay! Nevertheless, such was my assignment in seminary in 2015. Here are the results.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>“At the centre of Christian faith is the history of Christ. At the centre of the history of Christ is his passion and his death on the cross.” ~ Jürgen Moltmann&lt;/em>&lt;a href="#_ftn1">&lt;sup>&lt;sup>[1]&lt;/sup>&lt;/sup>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h1 id="theology-in-outline-an-attempted-summary-of-the-christian-faith">Theology in Outline: A[n Attempted] Summary of the Christian Faith&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We believe that, during the prefecture of Pontius Pilate, God died on a Roman cross.&lt;a href="#_ftn2">[2]&lt;/a> We also believe that, the third day thereafter, Jesus of Nazareth – the same person who had been crucified – rose again from the dead.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Uncle, Timothy Steele</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20150424my-uncle-timothy-steele/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20150424my-uncle-timothy-steele/</guid><description>&lt;p>(This post is about my late uncle, Timothy Steele. It’s long, and I swear toward the end. Sorry.)&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“It is better to go to a funeral than a feast. For death is the destiny of every person, and the living should take this to heart. Sorrow is better than laughter, because sober reflection is good for the heart.” (Ecclesiastes 7:2-3)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/image.png">&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/image.png" alt="Image" />
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="timothy-steele">Timothy Steele&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The juxtaposition is staggering. The funeral of the man I most associate with laughter and joy. It hurts. No Steele family gathering was complete without hearing his boisterous laugh, receiving one of his legendary bear hugs, and – if you were lucky – getting one heck of a sloppy kiss on the cheek.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Presenting on Karl Barth at 2015 Southeastern ETS</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/presenting-on-barth-at-2015-southeastern-ets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/presenting-on-barth-at-2015-southeastern-ets/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just received the news today that my student paper submission for the &lt;a href="https://lru.hobsonsradius.com/ssc/eform/N70x7m7aEx6G0x67128L.ssc">2015 Southeast Regional Meeting of the Evangelical Theological Society&lt;/a> has been accepted!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My theme lately has been to write on &lt;u>Karl Barth and the unity of the Church&lt;/u>. At last year&amp;rsquo;s Regional ETS (hosted by my seminary, &lt;a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/">Beeson Divinity School&lt;/a>), I presented an edited version of my undergraduate thesis: &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/steele-southeast-ets-2014-paper-final-presesntation-edit.pdf">Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof: Atonement, Ecclesiology, and the Unity of God&lt;/a>. Click the link if you&amp;rsquo;d like to read the PDF. Here&amp;rsquo;s the thesis:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who am I to be a theologian?</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-am-i-to-be-a-theologian/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-am-i-to-be-a-theologian/</guid><description>&lt;p>For my 20th Century History &amp;amp; Doctrine course at &lt;a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/">Beeson Divinity School&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading through &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Barth">Karl Barth&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Evangelical-Theology-Introduction-Karl-Barth/dp/0802818196">Evangelical Theology: An Introduction&lt;/a>&lt;/em>. If you&amp;rsquo;re involved in the life and ministry of the Church in any respect, I strongly recommend that you buy and read this book!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a particularly challenging portion from the chapter on &amp;ldquo;Wonder,&amp;rdquo; beginning on page 71. I wish the language were gender-inclusive, but Karl&amp;rsquo;s words still ring true:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;After all, &lt;u>who am I to be a theologian?&lt;/u>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ok, Maybe a Bit More on Cedarville!</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ok-maybe-a-bit-more-on-cedarville/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 11:46:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ok-maybe-a-bit-more-on-cedarville/</guid><description>&lt;p>You’ll notice that &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2014/03/18/cedarville-2/">the previous post on Cedarville&lt;/a> ends with a link to &lt;a href="http://www.cedarville.edu/courses/schedule/2014fa_bi_beth.htm">the Course Schedule&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/untitled.png">&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/untitled.png?w=650" alt="Image" />
&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Class Limited to Women” … I know, ludicrous. Especially considering Joy Fagan’s previous track record of making the first class, Scriptural Interpretation of Gender Issues (or SIGI), a truly excellent course by all accounts from former students, male and female.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Equally ludicrous? The &lt;a href="http://cedarville.verbacompare.com/compare/1?src=2&amp;amp;type=2&amp;amp;stoid=10&amp;amp;trm=FALL%2014&amp;amp;cid=2014_4144">textbook choices&lt;/a>! Are you ready for what CU students will be reading to form an even-handed perspective of what the Bible has to say on gender? Maybe some &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2013/11/10/volf-on-gender/">Miroslav Volf&lt;/a>? &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Junia-Not-Alone-Scot-McKnight-ebook/dp/B006H4PFZ8">“Junia is Not Alone” by Scot McKnight&lt;/a>? NOPE.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Concerning Romans</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/concerning-romans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 11:29:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/concerning-romans/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="http://www.treybailey.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/romans_title.jpg" alt="" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, judging by my blog stats for the past 48 hours — as compared with the past few months — I’d get many more views on this post if it &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2014/03/18/cedarville-2/">concerned the chaos at Cedarville University&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, my schedule and blood pressure won’t allow me to devote any more time to &lt;a href="http://fiatlux125.wordpress.com/">my shameful alma mater&lt;/a> at the moment. I’ve got a presentation at the &lt;a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/ets">2014 Southeast Regional Meeting of ETS&lt;/a> tomorrow (see&lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2014/03/07/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/"> my previous post&lt;/a>, and come to my presentation at &lt;strong>5:00pm in room S009!&lt;/strong>), and even though Beeson Divinity School’s Spring Break is right around the corner, I’ve still got a fair share of reading to get done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cedarville!</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 17:11:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="http://img2.findthebest.com/sites/default/files/10/media/images/Cedarville_University_220560.gif" alt="" />
I wish I could say I was proud of my alma mater…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite my Lenten Facebook fast, I was made aware of &lt;strong>the following post&lt;/strong> by my friend &lt;a href="http://marlenagraves.com/">&lt;strong>Marlena Graves&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>. I thought I’d share it, just in case anyone is considering Cedarville as a choice for college. I’d still strongly recommend you attend another institution, where you can trust the administration. My &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2013/01/13/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/">previous thoughts&lt;/a> on&lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2013/02/19/oh-cedarville/"> these matters&lt;/a> still &lt;a href="http://fiatlux125.wordpress.com/">stand&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>======&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Dear friends,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Peru 2014!</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/peru-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 17:46:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/peru-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.youcaring.com/mission-trip-fundraiser/peru-or-bust-deboer-and-steele/147648">&lt;img loading="lazy" src="http://afc726434ed5e9fb25d7-167fb5fa80ab95bdc8384d427ef6a062.r6.cf1.rackcdn.com/e1a5366a-4bc0-410e-b2a7-f7c40c65b852_profile.jpg" alt="" />
&lt;/a>I’m happy to announce that Rachel and I will be completing my required &lt;a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/cross-culturalministrypracticums">Cross Cultural Ministry Practicum&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/">Beeson Divinity School&lt;/a> along with our good friends Kyle, Rebekah, and baby Luke DeBoer in Lima, Peru this summer!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our goal is to assist &lt;a href="http://www.abweperu.org/page_family/pagefamily.php?id=12">the Stone families&lt;/a> (Dave &amp;amp; Evelyn; Jonathan &amp;amp; Angela) in their various local ministries, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.stblima.org/">Seminario Teológico Bautista&lt;/a> (Seminary)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://luzdelcaminosb.wix.com/luzdelcamino/">Luz del Camino Iglesia&lt;/a> (Church)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.centroprenatal.org/">Vida Nueva Centro Prenatal&lt;/a> (Pregnancy Center)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The goal of Beeson’s required Cross Cultural Ministry Practicum is to “&lt;em>expose students to issues related to cross-cultural ministry through first-hand experience in a cross-cultural ministry setting&lt;/em>.” In addition to fulfilling this goal, we believe that this trip to Peru will be &lt;strong>influential in determining the future involvement of both our families in global missions&lt;/strong>. God’s given each of us unique gifts — ranging from medicine to math, theology to linguistics. But &lt;strong>He’s blessed us all with a heart for His global Gospel and his global Church&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alabama Update</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20130719alabama-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 09:26:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20130719alabama-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rachel and I are in the middle of our second month of calling Birmingham, Alabama “home.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While we could both do with a little less humidity (!), we’re enjoying ourselves and our surroundings down here in Alabama.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-happening-in-birmingham-al">What’s Happening in Birmingham, AL:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I don’t start my &lt;a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/masterofdivinity">M.Div.&lt;/a> coursework at &lt;a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/">Beeson Divinity School&lt;/a> until late August, but I’ve already started working at &lt;a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/mediacenter">Beeson’s Media Center&lt;/a> (follow our nascent &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BeesonMedia">Twitter account here&lt;/a>). It’s an incredibly convenient on-campus job. I’m already thankful for the hospitality of my boss and coworkers. It’s helpful as I learn the ropes of AV, IT, and sundry other tasks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Requiescas in Pace, Mi Avia</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/requiescas-in-pace-mi-avia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 17:41:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/requiescas-in-pace-mi-avia/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://fbcdn-sphotos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/996164_10152895104580316_41022478_n.jpg" alt="" />
“Depart, O Christian soul, out of this world;&lt;br>
In the Name of God the Father Almighty who created you;&lt;br>
In the Name of Jesus Christ who redeemed you;&lt;br>
In the Name of the Holy Spirit who sanctifies you.&lt;br>
May your rest be this day in peace,&lt;br>
and your dwelling place in the Paradise of God.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heads up! Guest post on the way.</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heads-up-guest-post-on-the-way/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 13:19:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heads-up-guest-post-on-the-way/</guid><description>&lt;p>Great news! The first ever guest post on this blog is coming soon from my good friend Amy Chase, an incoming student this Fall at &lt;a href="http://www.asburyseminary.edu/">Asbury Theological Seminary&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her post? A sermon titled &lt;strong>“&lt;a href="http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Jeremiah%2029:11&amp;amp;version=NET">Jeremiah 29:11&lt;/a>, Scripture: Handle with Care.”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stay tuned!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Unforgettable Cedarville Experience (pt 2)</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience-pt-2-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 09:26:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience-pt-2-2/</guid><description>&lt;div class="sfy-html">&lt;div class="s-story noborder">&lt;div class="s-header">Since my [previous post](https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/12/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/ "My Unforgettable Cedarville Experience"), quite a few things have happened at my alma mater. Here’s a [Storify overview](https://storify.com/fiatlux125/cedarville-2012-2013/) of my crazy final year at Cedarville University.
&lt;/div>&lt;/div>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>A Farewell to Cedarville</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-farewell-to-cedarville/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 06:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-farewell-to-cedarville/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>(Originally posted in &lt;a href="http://www.theventriloquist.us/">The Ventriloquist&lt;/a>. Go check out the rest of &lt;a href="http://www.theventriloquist.us/">Issue 10&lt;/a>!)&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;">&lt;strong>“A Farewell to Cedarville” – Joshua Steele&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>As what was once a vision for the future has become an agenda for returning to the past, the list of people who no longer fit the Cedarville mold is growing.&lt;/strong> I contacted former vice president of Student Life, Dr. &lt;a href="http://www.carlruby.com/">Carl Ruby&lt;/a>; former professor Dr. &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/site/michaelpahl/">Michael Pahl&lt;/a>; current professors Dr. TC Ham, Dr. Shawn Graves, and Dr. David Mills; and former trustees Dr. William Rudd and Rev. Chris Williamson to see where things stand as this academic year comes to a close.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Honors, Grace, and Generosity</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/honors-grace-and-generosity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 22:31:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/honors-grace-and-generosity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yahweh and others have been too good to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I received two awards at Cedarville University’s &lt;a href="http://www.cedarville.edu/cf/calendar/viewsingleevent/id/b30deaf6-2481-ade4-b080-a503cd1527b2">49th Annual Academic Honors Day Chapel&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first: The Oxford University Press Award in Preseminary Bible, given to the graduating senior with the highest cumulative GPA in the preseminary major.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second: &lt;a href="http://www.cedarville.edu/financialaid/Daniel+Award">The Daniel Award.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Established in 2001 by David and Jean Heyd, this endowed award was created to honor their parents, Charles and E. LaRue Wilcox and Elmer and Kathy Heyd. The scholarship assists a graduating full-time male senior student who has been accepted by a conservative evangelical seminary. The recipient must have a minimum cumulative GPA of 3.3, demonstrate the spiritual qualifications and godly leadership skills necessary to excel in this ministry, and plan to serve as full-time pastor of a church. […] The Department of Biblical and Ministry Studies faculty select the recipients.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Building/Burning Bridges</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-buildingburning-bridges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:07:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-buildingburning-bridges/</guid><description>&lt;p>DISCLAIMER: there’s a fair bit about the Church that frustrates me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, I’d like to address those frustrations in a way that builds bridges, not burns them down. Especially since sin and justice are both relational. It does no good to flee the former for the latter in a way that creates more rifts than it heals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Therefore, any criticisms I level against my sisters and brothers in Christ, (many of those criticisms coming from outside the walls of the Church), I’d like first to aim them at myself. After all, if I want to witness self-righteous pride, xenophobia, misplaced anger, etc., I need look no further than the mirror.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let There Be Light: My Resignation</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/let-there-be-light-my-resignation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 16:45:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/let-there-be-light-my-resignation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;color:#ff0000;">&lt;em>&lt;strong>**Please read:&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> &lt;/span>&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;">&lt;em>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://fiatlux125.wordpress.com/2013/02/26/leadership-transfer-2/">Let There Be Light – Leadership Transfer&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;color:#ff0000;">&lt;em>&lt;strong>**&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/span>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Until further notice, I hereby rescind my use of the Let There Be Light platform&lt;/strong> (including &lt;a href="http://fiatlux125.wordpress.com/">blog&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/fiatlux125">Facebook&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fiatlux125">Twitter&lt;/a>) &lt;strong>to protest recent changes at Cedarville University.&lt;/strong> The LTBL platform will now be &lt;em>&lt;strong>exclusively alumni-run&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>, and I encourage everyone interested in developments at the University to follow their posts and make subsequent judgments regarding Cedarville’s identity and vision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My goal in all of this is &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;">&lt;strong>to honor my Messiah by following him well and furthering his Kingdom with justice, unity, and true peace.&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Apology</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-apology/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 23:36:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-apology/</guid><description>&lt;p>To whomever the following concerns:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I’d like to apologize publicly to any persons I may have offended during the past few months of my student activism efforts at Cedarville University.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After all, I recognize that some of my statements/claims about the perceived injustices at my University have seemed quite shocking, especially without further context. So I apologize for the times when I put pithiness before precision and unwittingly ostracized many good people whom I was not intending to criticize at all.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For shame, Cedarville</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/2320/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 08:48:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/2320/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is ridiculous and dangerous. For shame, Mr. Scharnberg and Dr. Gredy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How dare you try and accomplish this (already concerning) return to fundamentalism in an unethical manner! How dare you sacrifice good men and their families on the altar of your own agenda, and then proceed to bathe your actions in lies!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oh Cedarville!</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/oh-cedarville/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 07:38:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/oh-cedarville/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever been extremely frustrated with someone/thing you love?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s been my experience during my final year here at Cedarville University. See, &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/12/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/">I love this place.&lt;/a> And that’s why I can’t stand it sometimes. There are still so many good and godly women and men here, so much potential for God’s Kingdom. And that’s why recent decisions made by Cedarville Admins and Trustees are so heartbreaking. &lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2013/01/13/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/" title="Open Letter to Cedarville Admins and Trustees">I’ve written about this before&lt;/a> (Open Letter).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Letter to Cedarville Admins and Trustees</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 21:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/</guid><description>&lt;p>To my sisters and brothers in Christ, entrusted with the arduous task of leading and directing Cedarville University: greetings, grace, and peace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Allow me to thank you all for your countless hours of service to this institution. I do not want to underestimate your care and concern for this place. In fact, I want to reassure you that &lt;a href="http://windowinthesky.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/" title="My Unforgettable Cedarville Experience">I share your passion&lt;/a>. Here at Cedarville I have been blessed with the opportunity of meeting, falling in love with, and marrying my wife. Even more importantly, at Cedarville I have fallen in love with the Gospel. Thanks to godly men and women here – whose vision of God, his Word, and his world I’ve been privileged to catch – my eyes have been opened to the richness, complexity, and scope of God’s redemptive mission.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An Explanation</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/an-explanation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 13:04:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/an-explanation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>If you haven’t read my previous two blog posts, &lt;a href="http://windowinthesky.wordpress.com/2012/09/20/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-1/" title="Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 1)">“Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 1&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://windowinthesky.wordpress.com/2012/09/21/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-2/" title="Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 2)">pt. 2)&lt;/a>,” please go do so before reading this post.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary&lt;/strong>: I’ve been blogging in order to raise awareness of Cedarville University’s recent dismissal of Dr. Michael Pahl from his teaching post. Using the University’s statement on Dr. Pahl, I’ve raised some uncomfortable questions that I believe need to be asked in this situation. For example:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 2)</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 07:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://windowinthesky.wordpress.com/2012/09/20/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-1/" title="Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 1)">Read Part One&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="further-questions-all-relating-to-the-university-statement-on-dr-pahls-dismissal">Further Questions, All Relating to the University Statement on Dr. Pahl’s Dismissal:&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If Dr. Pahl’s book, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Beginning-End-Rereading-Revelations/dp/1608999270">&lt;em>The Beginning and the End&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, was controversial enough to lead to his dismissal, why was the book allowed to be used as a textbook last school year?
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Shouldn’t we trust the Bible professors’ judgment in their selection of the book as a text?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If we should, then was it worth firing Dr. Pahl over a book which other CU professors approved of enough to require as a text for their courses?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If not, why not? Why don’t we trust these highly-trained men and women as an institution? Shouldn’t they be a resource instead of a feared danger? Does this potential fear have anything to do with Dr. Pahl being dismissed?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do all members of the Board of Trustees agree with “each and every position of Cedarville University’s Doctrinal Statement” in the way Dr. Pahl was expected to in order to still be allowed to teach?
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>If he was dismissed, despite the apparent alignment of his personal views and those expressed in his writing to the Doctrinal Statement, is there a possibility that some of the trustees should also be dismissed according to such strict standards?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Was Dr. Pahl dismissed for something that wrote which contradicts the Doctrinal Statement? If so, what was it exactly that he wrote? (I have been unable to find anything in &lt;em>The Beginning and the End&lt;/em>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If Dr. Pahl was not fired for something he wrote, was he fired for something that he &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;">&lt;em>didn’t&lt;/em> &lt;/span>write? Again, if so, what was it exactly that he didn’t affirm?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Furthermore, is firing someone for not affirming something fair? Are all professors required to affirm the Doctrinal Statement in its entirety in everything they write and/or publish?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is the administration’s vision for the future of the Bible Department at Cedarville University?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How does firing an orthodox, promising scholar who is committed to Scripture and to the gospel help to achieve that vision?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Has Dr. Pahl been cared for by the University in any way during this process? As our brother in Christ, have we dismissed him in a way that is honoring to God and helpful to him and his family?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What explanation has been given to the students who have been affected by Dr. Pahl’s dismissal (i.e. the ones registered for his classes)? Has that explanation been accurate and forthright?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Are any other professors currently being considered for dismissal by the University for things they have written and published?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/22/an-explanation/" title="An Explanation">(CONTINUED: An Explanation)&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 1)</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 15:07:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-1/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-statement">The Statement:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>“Dr. Michael Pahl has been relieved of his teaching duties because he is unable to concur fully with each and every position of&lt;a href="http://www.cedarville.edu/About/Doctrinal-Statement.aspx"> Cedarville University’s doctrinal statement&lt;/a>. This decision was made following a review by the University administration and &lt;a href="http://www.cedarville.edu/Offices/Public-Relations/Board-of-Trustees.aspx">trustees&lt;/a> prompted by Dr. Pahl’s recent book, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Beginning-End-Rereading-Revelations/dp/1608999270">The Beginning and the End: Rereading Genesis’s Stories and Revelation’s Visions.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dr. Pahl’s orthodoxy and commitment to the gospel are not in question, nor is his commitment to Scripture’s inspiration, authority and infallibility. He is a promising scholar and a dedicated teacher, and he will be missed by his colleagues and students. Nevertheless, the University has determined this decision to be in the best interests of its constituency at this time.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sacrificing Scripture on the Altars of Our Own Agendas</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sacrificing-scripture-on-the-altars-of-our-own-agendas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 16:21:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sacrificing-scripture-on-the-altars-of-our-own-agendas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Undoubtedly the title of this blog post could be taken in hundreds of different directions. However, given recent developments close to home, and &lt;a href="http://www.cedarville.edu/Offices/Public-Relations/CampusNews/2012/Cedarville-to-Host-Answers-in-Genesis-Conference.aspx">the Answers in Genesis conference coming to Cedarville University on Sept. 23-24&lt;/a>, I’d like to get people thinking about Ken Ham, his organization’s agenda, and &lt;strong>how Scripture might very well be getting abused for the sake of Young Earth Creationism&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I say this as someone who used to be a zealous defender of everything that Answers in Genesis stands for. I viewed the Creationism vs. Evolution debate as central and foundational to the Christian life. I would sit for hours on end and listen to guys like Kent Hovind and their defenses of Young Earth Creationism…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Unforgettable Cedarville Experience</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 19:19:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>(The following is an expanded version of the speech I gave at this year’s CU Scholar Dessert Reception.)&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing I ever decided about Cedarville University was that I would not, under any circumstances, attend. Since my administrator’s son, Drew Flamm, worked in admissions at CU, I had been inundated since before I could remember with calls to become a yellow-jacket, and out of sheer stubbornness of heart, I refused.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wedding Vows: My Personal Take on the Traditional Version</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wedding-vows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 20:20:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wedding-vows/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-traditional-wedding-vows">The Traditional Wedding Vows&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In case you didn’t know, the “traditional” wedding vows – in English, at least – are found in the &lt;a href="http://www.bcponline.org/">Book of Common Prayer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the &lt;a href="http://justus.anglican.org/resources/bcp/1662/baskerville.htm">1662 Book of Common Prayer&lt;/a>, the marriage vows read as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I M. take thee N. to my wedded wife, to have and to hold,&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>from this day forward, for better for worſe, for richer for poorer, in ſickneſs and in health, to love and to cheriſh, till death us do part, according to God’s holy ordinance; and thereto I plight thee my troth.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unity?</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 19:22:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unity/</guid><description>&lt;p>The more I study the New Testament, I become more convinced that the unity of the Church is of utmost importance to God.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What bothers me is that this has never been taught to me before. All of the things I’ve learned (specifically in my studies on Philippians, Galatians, and now Romans) about the importance of unity for the sake of the Gospel mission and the Kingdom of God have come as somewhat of a shock.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My High School Graduation Valedictorian Speech was a Poem</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-valediction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 21:44:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-valediction/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-valedictorian-address-a-poem">My Valedictorian Address, a Poem&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The following is my valedictorian speech, delivered at my high school graduation in 2009. As you’ll see below, the majority of the speech was an original poem. Sure, I’m tempted to be a bit embarrassed by the poem today, but I’m also proud that I went for it. Let me know what you think!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="graduation">GRADUATION!&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Such a mix of emotions comes with this simple word…&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>