<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/drafts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drafts on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 16:26:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/drafts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Home Improvement Roadmap and Roadblocks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home-improvement-roadmap-and-roadblocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 16:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home-improvement-roadmap-and-roadblocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We bought our first house in late 2023 and, since moving-in in January 2024, I’ve been chipping away at home improvement projects. Since I’m a software engineer and spend my day in front of a screen, I enjoy working with tools as a change of pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, some upcoming projects will clearly outstrip my capabilities and I plan to hire professionals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Replace roof and gutters&lt;br&gt;
– Replace furnace and central air conditioning&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We bought our first house in late 2023 and, since moving-in in January 2024, I’ve been chipping away at home improvement projects. Since I’m a software engineer and spend my day in front of a screen, I enjoy working with tools as a change of pace.</p>
<p>Now, some upcoming projects will clearly outstrip my capabilities and I plan to hire professionals:</p>
<p>– Replace roof and gutters<br>
– Replace furnace and central air conditioning</p>
<p>Other projects are probably beyond my capabilities, and I will most likely hire professionals. But, I still spend a fair bit of time thinking about doing them myself:</p>
<p>– Get/build a shed<br>
– Trim and/or take down tall oak trees (they’re quite tall and we’re in a residential neighborhood…if we lived out in the country, I’d totally try to do this myself!)<br>
– Install a handrail with columns on basement stairway (to prevent falling-off the stairs into the basement)</p>
<p>Other things I plan to do myself:</p>
<p>– Install water-powered backup sump pump (in progress!)<br>
– Clean gutters (which have really old and difficult-to-remove sheet metal “leaf guards” on them)<br>
– Fix oddly-wired light switches in bedrooms<br>
– Power-wash house, driveway, and sidewalk<br>
– Re-caulk exterior of house (ugh, really not looking forward to this…lots of scraping old caulk required!)<br>
– Install a new duct and register in main, finished basement room<br>
– Install new PVC drain pipes for kitchen sink and garbage disposal<br>
– Build my own garage workbench</p>
<p>I’ve got a bunch of hand and power tools already, but I’m running into a roadblock when it comes to obtaining and moving larger objects: I don’t have a truck!</p>
<p>This is currently preventing me from doing things like:</p>
<p>– Getting plywood and 2x4s for my workbench<br>
– Getting an extension ladder for cleaning out my gutters, trimming tree branches, etc.<br>
– Purchasing a used refrigerator for our garage<br>
– Purchasing a used table saw for our garage</p>
<p>Instead, we’ve got a 2007 Honda Civic sedan and a 2019 Kia Sedona minivan. Neither of which have roof bars or a towing hookup.</p>
<p>I’m debating installing a roof rack on one or both cars. I’m also considering purchasing a towing hookup for the minivan and getting a trailer from Harbor Freight.</p>
<p>Otherwise, I’m on the lookout for a good deal on a used truck!</p>
<p>Given the truck roadblock, I’m also trying to figure out the best order to tackle these projects in.</p>
<p>I think it makes sense to start with getting a shed, since that would clear out more space in my garage for a work bench.</p>
<p>After that, though, I’m not sure. But “figure out a way to be able to transport large things” is definitely floating around at the top of the mental list.</p>
<p>Any thoughts on how best to tackle some of these home improvement projects? Am I making too big of a deal about not having a truck, and should I just suck it up and either rent one or buy one? Let me know!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem of Ecclesiastical Evil</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-problem-of-ecclesiastical-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 12:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-problem-of-ecclesiastical-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard of “the problem of evil” (if not, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Problem_of_evil&#34;&gt;here’s an overview&lt;/a&gt;). But there’s a specific version/aspect of it that I find even more devastating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If God is omnipotent (all-powerful), ommniscient (all-knowing(, and omnibenevolent (completely good)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Church is God’s main plan for the redemption of humanity and the cosmos (consider the “body of Christ” paradigm in the New Testament)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the gospel of Jesus Christ has had ~2K years to percolate in and through the Church…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You’ve probably heard of “the problem of evil” (if not, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Problem_of_evil">here’s an overview</a>). But there’s a specific version/aspect of it that I find even more devastating.</p>
<p>If God is omnipotent (all-powerful), ommniscient (all-knowing(, and omnibenevolent (completely good)…</p>
<p>If the Church is God’s main plan for the redemption of humanity and the cosmos (consider the “body of Christ” paradigm in the New Testament)…</p>
<p>If the gospel of Jesus Christ has had ~2K years to percolate in and through the Church…</p>
<p>Whence so much evil, corruption, abuse, etc. in the Church?</p>
<p>Why hasn’t the Church, on the whole, produced better people (myself included)?</p>
<p>Sure, it’s <em>easy</em> to appeal to the Church as a “corpus permixtum” (mixed body) and say that it’s all just tares mixed in with the wheat (see Matthew 13:24-30, 36-43).</p>
<p>But doing so often feels like a “No True Scotsman” fallacy to me. <a href="https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/no-true-scotsman">Here’s what that means</a>.</p>
<p>(Also, sidebar: Notice how the “field” is the “world” in Matthew 13:38. Not the “kingdom” or the “church.” So, is the Church a mixed body? Or is the world a mixed body?)</p>
<p>Every time I read <a href="https://www.newadvent.org/fathers/2802.htm"><em>On the Incarnation</em> by Athanasius</a>, I’m struck by how much he is willing to stake the truth of the gospel on the actual observed behavior of Christians.</p>
<p>Here are some examples below, but go and read the entire “Answer to the Greeks” / “Refutation of the Gentiles” section (paragraphs 41–55). Note how often Athanasius argues for the truth of Christ by appealing to the changed behaviors of human beings:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When did human beings begin to abandon the worship of idols, except since the true God Word of God came among human beings?</p>
<p>Or when have the oracles amongst the Greeks and everywhere ceased and become empty, except since the Savior revealed himself upon earth?</p>
<p>Or when did those who are called gods and heroes by the poets begin to be condemned as merely mortal humans, except since the Lord erected the trophy over death and preserved incorruptible the body which he took, raising it from the dead?</p>
<p>Or when were the deceit and madness of the demons despised, except when the Power of God, the Word, the Master of all, even of these, condescended, because of the weakness of humans, to appear on earth? When did the craft and teachings of magic begin to be trampled underfoot, except when the divine manifestation of the Word took place among human beings?</p>
<p>And when, in short, did the wisdom of the Greeks become foolish (cf. 1 Cor 1:18–24) except when the true Wisdom of God revealed itself upon earth?</p>
<p>For formerly the whole inhabited world and every place were led astray by the worship of idols, and human beings regarded nothing else but idols as gods.</p>
<p>Now, however, throughout the whole inhabited world, human beings are deserting the superstition of idols, taking refuge in Christ, and worshipping him as God, and through him they know the Father, of whom they had been ignorant.</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §46</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Now these things said by us are not merely words, but have the witness of their truth from experience itself. Let him who wishes come up and behold the proof of virtue in the virgins of Christ and in the youth who live a pure life in chastity, and the belief in immortality in so great a company of martyrs.</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §48</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>And who thus delivered human beings from the natural passions, so that adulterers are chaste, murderers no longer take up the sword, and those overcome by cowardice are courageous? Or, in short, what persuaded human beings from the barbarians and the Gentile regions to lay aside their madness, and to mind peace, except the faith of Christ and that sign of the cross?</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §50</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Who then among human beings, after death or even while alive, taught about virginity and did not think that this virtue was impossible among human beings? But our Savior and king of all, Christ, so prevailed in the teaching of this that even children not yet arrived at the lawful age profess the virginity that is above the law.</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §51</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>To speak concisely, behold how the teaching of the Savior increases everywhere, while all idolatry and everything opposed to the faith of Christ daily diminish and weaken and fall.</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §55</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I couldn’t make a similar argument in good faith today.</p>
<p>Instead, I believe the good news about Jesus <strong>in spite of</strong> how his Church has, on the whole, behaved.</p>
<p>Which, even though I know all of the theological pressure-release valves one can use here, bugs me quite a bit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back in the Saddle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/back-in-the-saddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 21:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/back-in-the-saddle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know I’m not alone in this, but the past few years have been pretty rough for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve gained at least 50 pounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had a fun part-time gig as a managing editor come to an end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve come to terms with some &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/its-time-to-get-some-help/&#34;&gt;long-term depression and anxiety&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had a job offer ripped out from under me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/its-official-im-hitting-pause-on-my-ph-d-for-a-year/&#34;&gt;hit pause&lt;/a&gt; on and eventually dropped out of my Ph.D. program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/&#34;&gt;resigned from ordained ministry in the ACNA&lt;/a&gt;, my previous denomination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, some things have gone well. I’ve got a loving wife (who’s a superhero) and three healthy children. I’ve got a new career (as a software developer) that I very much enjoy. We’ve got a roof over our heads. I make more money now than I ever have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know I’m not alone in this, but the past few years have been pretty rough for me.</p>
<ul>
<li>I’ve gained at least 50 pounds.</li>
<li>I had a fun part-time gig as a managing editor come to an end.</li>
<li>I’ve come to terms with some <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/its-time-to-get-some-help/">long-term depression and anxiety</a>.</li>
<li>I had a job offer ripped out from under me.</li>
<li>I <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/its-official-im-hitting-pause-on-my-ph-d-for-a-year/">hit pause</a> on and eventually dropped out of my Ph.D. program.</li>
<li>I’ve <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/im-resigning-from-ordained-ministry-in-the-anglican-church-in-north-america/">resigned from ordained ministry in the ACNA</a>, my previous denomination.</li>
</ul>
<p>Sure, some things have gone well. I’ve got a loving wife (who’s a superhero) and three healthy children. I’ve got a new career (as a software developer) that I very much enjoy. We’ve got a roof over our heads. I make more money now than I ever have.</p>
<p>But, overall, I definitely feel less focused and energized than I used to.</p>
<p>Do I have a sure solution or a grand commitment to make? No.</p>
<p>But I decided that I can at least start blogging about turning things around. I can write about my experiences as I try to get back into the personal development saddle.</p>
<p>As a first step, I need to get a better grip of everything I’ve got “in flight” at the moment. I’ve got far too many things bouncing around in my head, and I need to get them down on paper and/or a digital system to manage them.</p>
<p>So I’ve dusted-off my copy of <a href="https://amzn.to/3wJO5iZ"><em>Getting Things Done: The Art of Stress-Free Productivity</em> by David Allen</a>. And I’ve started a “brain dump” in my main notebook (a Bullet Journal-like combination of journaling, to-dos, and notes).</p>
<p>Any other crestfallen personal development/productivity junkies out there? Let me know how it’s going!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Truth to Power</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/truth-to-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/truth-to-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark 6:13-29. John the Baptist lost his life for speaking truth to power. Are we willing to speak truth to power? To tell the truth about power and the power of truth? Or will we abandon the truth to obtain and maintain power?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mark 6:13-29. John the Baptist lost his life for speaking truth to power. Are we willing to speak truth to power? To tell the truth about power and the power of truth? Or will we abandon the truth to obtain and maintain power?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
