<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Copywriting on Joshua P. Steele</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/copywriting/</link><description>Recent content in Copywriting on Joshua P. Steele</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:06:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/copywriting/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>"They laughed when I became an Anglican, but when I started to pray!" 27 Anglican Headline Ideas</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:06:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m reading my way through &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2KdNASw">the new (4th) edition of Robert Bly’s classic &lt;em>The Copywriter’s Handbook&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. On pages 33–36, Bly offers “38 Model Headlines for Your ‘Swipe File.&amp;rsquo;” Here are some headlines ideas that came to mind, all geared to an Anglican context (&lt;a href="https://anglicanpastor.com/">due to my work at AnglicanCompass.com&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Why are Anglicans so angry?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How do I use the Book of Common Prayer?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can I become an Anglican?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What do Anglicans believe?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Why “Clarity &amp;amp; Charity” is the best way forward for the Church in a pluralistic age&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Announcing an ancient way to reclaim your days and years for God&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Don’t become an Anglican!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can now do the Daily Office with just this booklet and a Bible&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The 5 Anglican books you should own NOW&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using the BCP—Once difficult, now easy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A feast for the senses: The richness of Anglican worship&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“I was about to give up on the Church when I was introduced to the Anglican tradition”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FREE booklet helps you pray&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to avoid the biggest mistakes you can make when visiting an Anglican church&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The WORST Article in the Thirty-Nine Articles. Hint: It’s NOT what you think!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Anglican clergy’s best-kept secret&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We’re looking for people who want to leave Anglicanism better than they found it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It’s never too late to start doing the Daily Office&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sick of iChurch and McChurch? Give Anglicanism a try&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Will your church pass the Word &amp;amp; Sacrament test?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 reasons why you should NOT become an Anglican Christian&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Why most people leave the Church—and what you can do about it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Crazy as it sounds, the Daily Office could save your marriage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 reasons why written prayers are better than extemporaneous prayers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>7 questions to ask when you visit an Anglican church&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Now you can create a personalized discipleship plan—for FREE&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Where’s #27? Read the title for this piece.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>