<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Anglicanism on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/anglicanism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anglicanism on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 16:22:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/anglicanism/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>If Women Can Be Saved, Then Women Can Be Priests: A Critique of the &#39;in persona Christi&#39; Argument Against Women&#39;s Ordination</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 05:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Pastor does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After reading this piece, please see &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/&#34;&gt;Lee Nelson’s response&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/&#34;&gt;Emily McGowin’s rejoinder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-connection-between-christology-and-soteriology&#34;&gt;The connection between christology and soteriology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cornerstone of orthodox Christian theology is summed up in the phrase “what is not assumed is not healed”. The phrase is echoed by many early church fathers, but it is credited to St. Gregory of Nazianzus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Pastor does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.</em></p>
<p><em>After reading this piece, please see <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/">Lee Nelson’s response</a> and <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/">Emily McGowin’s rejoinder</a>.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-connection-between-christology-and-soteriology">The connection between christology and soteriology</h2>
<p>A cornerstone of orthodox Christian theology is summed up in the phrase “what is not assumed is not healed”. The phrase is echoed by many early church fathers, but it is credited to St. Gregory of Nazianzus.</p>
<p>I teach this principle to undergraduates in my theology classes every semester when we are discussing the development of classical christology (the doctrine of Christ). And my students usually grasp the significance of this principle quite easily.</p>
<p>As the early church fathers sought to make sense of the revelation of God in Jesus Christ, they recognized that if Christ were not fully human—human in every way as we are, yet without sin—then Christ could not redeem humanity.</p>
<p>Thus, Jesus Christ had to have:</p>
<ul>
<li>a real human body,</li>
<li>a real human mind,</li>
<li>real human emotions, and</li>
<li>a real human soul.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the words of St. Gregory of Nazianzus:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“For that which he has not assumed he has not healed; but that which is united to his Godhead is also saved. If only half Adam fell, then that which Christ assumes and saves may be half also; but if the whole of his nature fell, it must be united to the whole nature of him that was begotten, and so be saved as a whole” (Epistle 101, 32).</p></blockquote>
<p>In this way, christology and soteriology (the doctrine of salvation) are intimately connected. To rescue us from the dominion of Sin, Evil, and Death, the Word, the Second Person of the Trinity, had to become like us.</p>
<p>As the divine Word, he could descend into the darkest depths of human sin and suffering without being overcome by them. And, as the Word-made-flesh, he could ascend to the heights of heaven following his resurrection—and bring us, now reconciled and united with God, along with him.</p>
<h2 id="implications">Implications</h2>
<p>If “what is not assumed is not healed” is a crucial, non-negotiable aspect of orthodox Christianity, then we do well to consider carefully its implications.</p>
<p>For example, if the flesh that the Word assumed in Jesus Christ was ethnically Jewish, does that mean Jesus cannot save Gentiles?</p>
<p>The church has consistently answered: No, of course not. In the logic of “what is not assumed is not healed,” what matters in the incarnation is Jesus’ <em>humanness</em>, not his Jewishness.</p>
<p>(To be clear, Jesus’ Jewishness is crucial to his person and work. Without recognizing that Jesus was a first-century Jew, and all the religious, social, and cultural implications that entails, one cannot fully understand Jesus and what he has done on our behalf. But what I’m exploring here is the logic at work in orthodox reasoning about christology and soteriology.)</p>
<p>Indeed, it is precisely in the particularities of Jesus Christ’s person that he can save all people. The particularity of the incarnation is the pathway to the universality of salvation. “[H]e had to be made like them, fully human in every way, in order that he might become a merciful and faithful high priest in service to God, and that he might make atonement for the sins of the people” and “not only for ours but also for the sins of the whole world” (Heb. 2:17; 1 Jn. 2:2).</p>
<p>As Beth Felker Jones says in her book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Practicing-Christian-Doctrine-Introduction-Theologically/dp/0801049334/ref=as_li_ss_tl?keywords=Practicing+Christian+Doctrine&amp;pd_rd_i=0801049334&amp;pd_rd_r=01c428a0-07cc-4048-8894-9d6ce2c96457&amp;pd_rd_w=P9xKu&amp;pd_rd_wg=KXfEi&amp;pf_rd_p=39e7c2a0-69e1-4a3f-8d8f-4c4ee1aefdb5&amp;pf_rd_r=66AKMKQNSQTGPJWF63JS&amp;psc=1&amp;qid=1569494218&amp;s=gateway&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=anglicanpasto-20&amp;linkId=6d704c46c306131181f6420e60ccefbf&amp;language=en_US"><em>Practicing Christian Doctrine</em></a>, “Jesus does not come among us as a generic human being; he comes as we do, with particulars.” The truth is, there is no such thing as a generic human being. So, in order to be human, the Word had to become a particular human being, with ethnicity, culture, language, sex, gender, and more.</p>
<p>What, then, of Jesus’ maleness? Can a male Christ save women?</p>
<p>Yes, orthodox theologians reply. Yes, of course he can.</p>
<p>Why? Because in assuming the flesh and blood, soul and spirit, of a particular human being, the Word has assumed the flesh and blood, soul and spirit of <em>all</em> human beings—including women.</p>
<p>(It is worth observing that, according to orthodox Christian teaching, the human nature of Jesus Christ was formed in the womb of the Virgin Mary, without the contribution of male “flesh” whatsoever. The Word-made-flesh receives his human flesh from a woman. I am grateful to my colleague, Rev. Dr. Amy Peeler, for bringing this to my attention.)</p>
<p>Again, what matters for salvation is Jesus’ <em>humanness</em>, not Jesus’ maleness.</p>
<h2 id="now-what-does-all-this-have-to-do-with-womens-ordination">Now, what does all this have to do with women’s ordination?</h2>
<p>Quite a lot, actually.</p>
<p>Many arguments are proffered against women’s ordination, some biblical, some theological, some historical, some even biological and psychological. Of course, there is far more to the arguments for and against women’s ordination than this short piece is able to address.</p>
<p>For now, due to space constraints, I choose to focus on one argument against women’s ordination that I find particularly theologically problematic: The assertion that women cannot represent Christ in the celebration of the Eucharist; the claim that women cannot act <em>in persona Christi</em> (“in the person of Christ”).</p>
<p>The argument, in short, goes something like this: Because women have female bodies and Jesus Christ has a male body, women cannot serve as a sacramental sign of Christ in the Eucharist.</p>
<p>To be more specific, women cannot act <em>in persona Christi</em> because their female bodies do not correspond to the body of the male Christ. In this view, female priests are not just <em>not allowed</em>; female priests are <em>false signifiers</em>. In their female persons, female priests lie, as it were, about the male person of Jesus Christ, who is presiding sacramentally at the altar.</p>
<p>And, as a result, women must not represent Christ at the Eucharistic feast.</p>
<p>Today, very often, though not always, this perspective is linked to a form gender essentialism gleaned from Pope John Paul II’s “<a href="http://amzn.to/2lXRIO3">theology of the body</a>” and his recent popularizer, <a href="http://amzn.to/2mV9kdy">Christopher West</a>.</p>
<p>In the theology of the body, male and female are seen as ontologically distinct, two parts of the one whole of the <em>imago Dei.</em> This “natural” gender division then serves as the foundation for structured gender roles.</p>
<p>When it comes to the function of the priesthood, then, the male sacramentally represents Christ while the female sacramentally represents the Church. Within this perspective, to have a woman priest is to usurp and upend a fundamental ontological reality of the world God has made.</p>
<p>But this brings us back to our christological and soteriological principle: “what is not assumed is not healed”. If women qua women are fundamentally incapable—and, according to some Christians, even <em>ontologically</em> incapable—of representing the male Jesus Christ in their female persons, then that calls into question whether their female persons can be redeemed by the male Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>But, of course, we know that isn’t the case.</p>
<p>All human beings—Jew and Greek, male and female, slave and free—are saved through the Incarnation of the Word (the life, death, resurrection and ascension of Jesus Christ).</p>
<p>The particularities of Jesus’ person—a poor, Jewish, male, unmarried, 30-something adult living in first-century, Roman-occupied Israel—are the means by which <em>all</em> human persons are redeemed. And, by becoming one with Christ in our baptism, all become partakers of his Royal Priesthood.</p>
<p>If that’s the case, then all persons are potentially capable of serving as sacramental signs of their Savior.</p>
<h2 id="responding-to-an-objection-arent-redemption-and-sacramental-representation-different">Responding to an objection: Aren’t redemption and sacramental representation different?</h2>
<p>But, some might object: “Jesus, though male, can redeem women. But women can’t sacramentally represent Jesus because redemption and sacramental representation are two different things.”</p>
<p>I would respond: On what basis does the concept of sacramental representation rest?</p>
<p>Many things could be addressed on this front, but I’ll specify only a few.</p>
<h3 id="first-the-idea-of-sacramentality-is-rooted-in-part-in-the-analogy-of-being">First, the idea of sacramentality is rooted, in part, in the analogy of being.</h3>
<p>An analogy does not require a pure one-to-one correspondence—indeed, in Christian theology it specifies the opposite. Between creature and Creator there are similarities, but never such that the dissimilarities are not always greater. Thus, all analogies between God and human beings are inadequate. They are able to speak some real truth, but always fall short in the end.</p>
<p>Similarly, the sacramental representation of the priest will always fall short of pure representation because it is based on analogy.</p>
<h3 id="second-sacramental-representation-means-the-priest-functions-not-as-christ-but-as-an-icon-of-christ">Second, sacramental representation means the priest functions not <em>as Christ</em>, but as an <em>icon</em> of Christ.</h3>
<p>As William Witt has argued, priests are jars of clay, pointing away from him- or herself and pointing to Christ the High Priest, particularly as they share in his suffering (2 Cor. 4:5-10).</p>
<p>What is central is not physical similarity to the male body of Christ, but the priest’s participation in the pattern of Christ, the Suffering Servant. Insofar as the priest demonstrates this participation, the priest serves as a sacramental representation.</p>
<h3 id="finally-if-the-sacramental-validity-of-the-priesthood-is-based-in-significant-part-upon-the-sexed-and-gendered-body-of-the-priest-that-is-a-male-body-to-match-the-male-christ-then-we-find-ourselves-in-a-bit-of-a-bind">Finally, if the sacramental validity of the priesthood is based in significant part upon the sexed and gendered body of the priest (that is, a male body to match the male Christ), then we find ourselves in a bit of a bind.</h3>
<p>As Sarah Coakley (among others) has shown, in the course of the Eucharistic service, the priest not only acts <em>in persona Christi</em>, but also <em>in persona Ecclesiae</em>, which, in the imagery of Eph. 5:22, is gendered female.</p>
<p>If a woman cannot act <em>in persona Christi</em> because her female body does not match the male body of Christ, then how will a man act <em>in persona Ecclesiae</em> when his male body does not match the female Church?</p>
<p>The answer, of course, is that they can; because the priestly body functions sacramentally, or analogically.</p>
<h3 id="no-matter-which-priestly-body-is-the-subject-of-scrutiny-all-bodies-inevitably-fall-short-of-a-pure-one-to-one-correspondence-between-the-sexed-and-gendered-body-of-human-beings-and-the-bride-and-bridegroom-they-are-meant-to-represent">No matter which priestly body is the subject of scrutiny, all bodies inevitably fall short of a pure one-to-one correspondence between the sexed and gendered body of human beings and the Bride and Bridegroom they are meant to represent.</h3>
<p>And that brings us back to the principle of analogy. No human body exactly, literally, univocally corresponds to our Great High Priest, Jesus Christ. But, they do not have to. They need only serve as analogues, which is, in fact, core to what sacrament means in the first place.</p>
<p>Let us return then to Gregory’s great insight, “what is not assumed is not healed,” and put my overall point as plainly as possible:</p>
<h2 id="conclusion-if-christ-in-his-male-body-saves-women-through-their-shared-humanity-then-women-through-their-shared-humanity-with-christ-can-represent-christ-at-the-altar">Conclusion: If Christ in his male body saves women through their shared humanity, then women, through their shared humanity with Christ, can represent Christ at the altar.</h2>
<p>If they cannot—if, in their female bodies, women are incapable of serving as sacramental signs of the male Savior, Jesus Christ—then women’s salvation is in jeopardy, as is the salvation of all who differ from Christ in their embodied particulars.</p>
<p>The good news of “what is not assumed is not healed” is that this jeopardy is decidedly <em>not</em> the case. The Word-made-flesh has made provision in his life, death, resurrection, and ascension for the salvation of all humankind. As Gregory of Nazianzus insisted: “[God] has assumed humanity for our salvation … that by one and the same person, who was perfect man and also God, the entire humanity fallen through sin might be created anew” (Epistle 101, 34).</p>
<p>Do women demonstrate bodily differences from the God-man, Jesus Christ? Yes, of course they do.</p>
<p>But it is by virtue of those very distinctions that women offer a powerful sacramental sign of our Great High Priest and the new creation he has inaugurated in his body. And we who feast at Eucharistic tables presided over by women priests get to see glimpses of this new creation every Sunday.</p>
<h2 id="postscript-further-reading">Postscript: Further Reading</h2>
<p>The argument offered here is inspired, in part, by the following resources. I recommend them to you for further reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>Thomas F. Torrance, <a href="http://amzn.to/2mVXCiM"><em>Royal Priesthood: A Theology of Ordained Ministry</em></a>, 2nd Edition (London: T &amp; T Clark, 2003).</li>
<li>Sarah Coakley, “<a href="http://www.anglicantheologicalreview.org/read/issue/13/">The Woman at the Altar: Cosmological Disturbance or Gender Subversion?</a>” <em>Anglican Theological Review</em>, 86.1 (2004): 75-93.</li>
<li>William G. Witt, “Concerning Women’s Ordination: Women’s Ordination and the Priesthood of Christ”, accessed September 12, 2019: <a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-and-the-priesthood-of-christ/">http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-and-the-priesthood-of-christ/</a>.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/adam_jones/27713547834">Featured image by Adam Jones via Flickr</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/">Want to learn more about women’s ordination debates within Anglicanism? Check out these resources.</a></p>
<p><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/write-for-anglican-pastor/">Want to write for Anglican Pastor? Check out our writing guidelines.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to Learn More about Women’s Ordination Debates within Anglicanism? Start With These Resources</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe you, like me, are coming to Anglicanism from a different tradition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that’s the case, then one thing you should know is that Anglican debates about women’s ordination can often be quite different from debates about the same topic in other church contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is due to Anglicans having different views on, among other things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ecclesiology (the doctrine of the church),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the sacraments, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in my broadly evangelical/non-denominational/Baptist upbringing, debates about women in ministry centered on whether or not women were allowed to preach and teach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maybe you, like me, are coming to Anglicanism from a different tradition.</p>
<p>If that’s the case, then one thing you should know is that Anglican debates about women’s ordination can often be quite different from debates about the same topic in other church contexts.</p>
<p>This is due to Anglicans having different views on, among other things:</p>
<ul>
<li>ecclesiology (the doctrine of the church),</li>
<li>the sacraments, and</li>
<li>ordination.</li>
</ul>
<p>For example, in my broadly evangelical/non-denominational/Baptist upbringing, debates about women in ministry centered on whether or not women were allowed to preach and teach.</p>
<p>In Anglican circles, although you can still find debates about preaching/teaching, I’ve found that people place much more focus on whether or not women can administer the sacraments as priests.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in learning more about the contours of Anglican debates on women’s ordination, I recommend that you start out by reading the <strong>2017 ACNA Holy Orders Task Force Report</strong>. It is an especially useful document for those coming from a USA evangelical background into Anglicanism.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-acna-holy-orders-task-force-report-2017">The ACNA Holy Orders Task Force Report (2017)</h2>
<p><em>Here’s an excerpt from <a href="http://anglicanchurch.net/?/main/page/1448">the official ACNA announcement of the report</a>, quoted from the ACNA website.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>In 2012 the College of Bishops appointed a Task Force on Holy Orders to provide the College with a scholarly and informed study on Holy Orders and, specifically, women in Holy Orders (the enabling resolution is reprinted in what follows). The Task Force, led by Bishop David Hicks, consisted of people representing differing perspectives and practices. They have met for the past 5 years and during that time have periodically released progress reports. This past January Bishop Hicks presented a report on the last phase of the process to the College, and we are now releasing the whole report to the Province.</p></blockquote>
<p>You can download a PDF of the entire report by <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce.pdf">clicking here</a>.</p>
<p>The report is quite long (318 pages). So, I’ve broken it up into shorter PDFS.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-1_The-Task-Force-and-its-Process.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 1_The Task Force and its Process.pdf">Section I: The Task Force and its Process</a> (pp. 1–11)</li>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-2_A-Unified-Approach-to-Scripture.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 2_A Unified Approach to Scripture.pdf">Section II: A Unified Approach to Scripture</a> (pp. 12–17)</li>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-3_Principles-of-Anglican-Ecclesiology.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 3_Principles of Anglican Ecclesiology.pdf">Section III: Principles of Anglican Ecclesiology</a> (pp. 18–256)</li>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-4_Arguments-For-and-Against.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 4_Arguments For and Against.pdf">Section IV: The Arguments For and Against [Women’s Ordination]</a> (pp. 257–311)</li>
<li>NOTE: The “evangelical” portion of this section relies heavily upon <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/AMIA_2003_Womens-Ordination-Report.pdf" title="AMIA_2003_Women's Ordination Report.pdf">this 2003 AMIA Report on Women’s Ordination</a>. In fact, when it comes to the exegesis of specific biblical texts, the ACNA report simply quotes from the AMIA report. See pages 269–74 of the ACNA Report and pages 37–105 of the AMIA Report.</li>
<li><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-5_Analysis-and-Conclusion.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 5_Analysis and Conclusion.pdf">Section V: Analysis and Conclusions</a> (pp. 312–18).</li>
</ul>
<p>As you can tell from the list above, <strong>if you’d like to read the arguments for and against women’s ordination, check out <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section-4_Arguments-For-and-Against.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Section 4_Arguments For and Against.pdf">section 4</a> on pages 257 to 311</strong>. You’ll also need to consult <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/AMIA_2003_Womens-Ordination-Report.pdf" title="AMIA_2003_Women's Ordination Report.pdf">this 2003 AMIA Report on Women’s Ordination</a>.</p>
<p>I <em>highly</em> recommend that you at least <strong>take the time to read Section 5, because it includes a final summary of the task force’s findings, including their recommendations to the College of Bishops</strong>.</p>
<p>Speaking of which, the College of Bishops issued a statement on the ordination of women on September 7, 2017.</p>
<h2 id="a-statement-from-the-acna-college-of-bishops-on-the-ordination-of-women">A Statement from the ACNA College of Bishops on the Ordination of Women</h2>
<p><em>Click <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/?/main/page/1519">here</a> to see the original version of this on the ACNA website, which includes an introduction from Archbishop Foley Beach.</em></p>
<p>In the preamble to the statement, the Bishops say the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In an act of mutual submission at the foundation of the Anglican Church in North America, it was agreed that each Diocese and Jurisdiction has the freedom, responsibility, and authority to study Holy Scripture and the Apostolic Tradition of the Church, and to seek the mind of Christ in determining its own convictions and practices concerning the ordination of women to the diaconate and the priesthood. It was also unanimously agreed that women will not be consecrated as bishops in the Anglican Church in North America. These positions are established within our Constitution and Canons and, because we are a conciliar Church, would require the action of both Provincial Council and Provincial Assembly to be changed.</p></blockquote>
<p>Then, they proceed to the statement itself:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Having gratefully received and thoroughly considered the five-year study by the Theological Task Force on Holy Orders, we acknowledge that there are differing principles of ecclesiology and hermeneutics that are acceptable within Anglicanism that may lead to divergent conclusions regarding women’s ordination to the priesthood. However, we also acknowledge that this practice is a recent innovation to Apostolic Tradition and Catholic Order. We agree that there is insufficient scriptural warrant to accept women’s ordination to the priesthood as standard practice throughout the Province. However, we continue to acknowledge that individual dioceses have constitutional authority to ordain women to the priesthood.</p></blockquote>
<p>Finally, the Bishops state their commitments moving forward:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As a College of Bishops, we confess that our Province has failed to affirm adequately the ministry of all Christians as the basic agents of the work of the Gospel. We have not effectively discipled and equipped all Christians, male and especially female, lay and ordained, to fulfill their callings and ministries in the work of God’s kingdom. We repent of this and commit to work earnestly toward a far greater release of the whole Church to her God-given mission.</p>
<p>Having met in Conclave to pray, worship, study, talk, and listen well to one another, we commit to move forward in unity to carry on the good witness and work that God has given us to do in North America (Ephesians 4:1-6; John 17). We invite and urge all members of the Province to engage with us in this endeavor to grow in understanding the mission and ministry of all God’s people.</p></blockquote>
<p>This statement was adopted unanimously by the ACNA College of Bishops in September 2017. It describes the current state of the issue in the ACNA.</p>
<h2 id="whats-the-acnas-position-on-womens-ordination">What’s The ACNA’s Position on Women’s Ordination?</h2>
<p>This question is included on the <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/index.php/main/faq/">ACNA’s FAQ page</a>. Here’s the answer:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>At the inception of the Anglican Church in North America, the lead Bishops unanimously agreed to work together for the good of the Kingdom. As part of this consensus, it was understood that there were differing understandings regarding the ordination of women to Holy Orders, but there existed a mutual love and respect for one another and a desire to move forward for the good of the Church. This commitment was deeply embedded in the Constitution and Canons overwhelmingly adopted by the Inaugural Assembly (2009).</p>
<p>In respect of the two integrities concerning Holy Orders, three matters were specifically agreed in Constitution and Canons:</p>
<p>(1) The Province shall make no canon abridging the authority of any member dioceses, clusters or networks (whether regional or affinity-based) and those dioceses banded together as jurisdictions with respect to its practice regarding the ordination of women to the diaconate or presbyterate (Constitution, Article VIII)<br>
(2) Except as hereinafter provided, the norms for ordination shall be determined by the Bishops having jurisdiction. (Title III Canon 1.4)<br>
(3) To be a suitable candidate for the episcopate (bishop), a person must: Be a male Presbyter at least 35 years old. (Title III Canon 8.3.7)</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="which-acna-dioceses-dodont-ordain-women">Which ACNA Dioceses Do/Don’t Ordain Women?</h2>
<p>To put some numbers to this debate, <a href="http://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QG0EDrpgGnfPf668T5qsnUcczUA_g6b3HjgbPC-aiTg/edit?usp=sharing">I’ve produced the following chart</a>. <a href="http://s3.amazonaws.com/acna/Congregational_Report_to_Provincial_Council_2018.pdf">The congregation/membership/attendance data comes from this 2018 report.</a> Please let me know if you spot any errors!</p>
<p>Click the image below to view the most recent version of the spreadsheet on Google Sheets.</p>
<p><a href="http://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QG0EDrpgGnfPf668T5qsnUcczUA_g6b3HjgbPC-aiTg/edit?usp=sharing"><img loading="lazy" src="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Screen-Shot-2020-01-14-at-11.33.22-AM.png"></a></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="bibliography-for-further-study">Bibliography for Further Study</h2>
<p>If you’d like to do some more reading and research on this topic, then the Task Force Report has a very helpful <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/HolyOrdersTaskForce_Bibliography-for-Further-Study.pdf" title="HolyOrdersTaskForce_Bibliography for Further Study.pdf">annotated Bibliography for Further Study</a> (pp. 300–11 of the Task Force Report).</p>
<p>Click the link above to download the PDF of just the bibliography. Otherwise, I’ve listed the works below, without the annotations/descriptions.</p>
<p>Note that I’m still trying to find links to everything. Amazon links below are all affiliate links.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="womens-ordination-from-an-evangelical-perspective">Women’s Ordination from an Evangelical Perspective</h2>
<hr>
<h3 id="books-in-favor-of-womens-ordination">Books in favor of Women’s Ordination</h3>
<h4 id="collections-of-essays">Collections of Essays</h4>
<ul>
<li>Mickelsen, Alvera (editor), <a href="http://amzn.to/2UrIUf9"><em>Women, Authority &amp; the Bible.</em></a> InterVarsity Press, 1986.</li>
<li>Pierce, Ronald W. and Rebecca Merrill Groothius (editors), <a href="http://amzn.to/2ShMk6H"><em>Discovering Biblical Equality: Complementarity Without Hierarchy,</em></a> Second Edition (InterVarsity Press, 2005).</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="general-works-on-women-in-the-new-testament-and-the-early-church">General Works on Women in the New Testament and the Early Church</h4>
<ul>
<li>Bauckham, Richard, <a href="http://amzn.to/2TlNrPZ"><em>Gospel Women: Studies of the Named Women in the Gospels.</em></a> Eerdmans, 2002.</li>
<li>Cooper, Kate, <a href="http://amzn.to/2WvkZx5"><em>Band of Angels: The Forgotten World of Early Christian Women.</em></a> The Overlook Press, 2013.</li>
<li>Keener, Craig S., <a href="http://amzn.to/2WoeFaC"><em>Paul, Women &amp; Wives: Marriage and Women’s Ministry in the Letters of Paul.</em></a> Hendrickson Publishers,1992.</li>
<li>Macy, Gary, <a href="http://amzn.to/2Uqfi1C"><em>The Hidden History of Women’s Ordination: Female Clergy in the Medieval West.</em></a> Oxford University Press, 2008.</li>
<li>Payne, Philip B., <a href="http://amzn.to/2DJ9Txf"><em>Man and Woman, One in Christ: An Exegetical and Theological Study of Paul’s Letters.</em></a> Zondervan, 2009</li>
<li>Witherington, Ben III, <a href="http://amzn.to/2DLQI5R"><em>Women and the Genesis of Christianity.</em></a> Cambridge University Press, 1990.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="commentaries-on-i-corinthians-111-16-and-1434-34">Commentaries on I Corinthians (11:1-16 and 14:34-34)</h4>
<ul>
<li>Peppiatt, Lucy, <a href="http://amzn.to/2GdKAVt"><em>Women and Worship at Corinth: Paul’s Rhetorical Arguments in I Corinthians.</em></a> Cascade Books, 2015.</li>
<li>Thiselton, Anthony C., <a href="http://amzn.to/2Wuf3V7"><em>The First Epistle to the Corinthians.</em></a> Eerdmans, 2000: in The New International Greek Testament Commentary).</li>
<li>Witherington, Ben III, <a href="http://amzn.to/2CU5ANV"><em>Conflict &amp; Community in Corinth: A Socio-Rhetorical Commentary on I and II Corinthians.</em></a> Eerdmans, 1995.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="commentaries-on-i-timothy-2-8-8-15">Commentaries on I Timothy 2: 8-8-15</h4>
<ul>
<li>Fee, Gordon D., <a href="http://amzn.to/2SfZO2O"><em>1 &amp; 2 Timothy, Titus.</em></a> Baker Books, 2011.</li>
<li>Kroeger, Catherine Clark and Richard Clark Kroeger, <a href="http://amzn.to/2DLEhal"><em>I Suffer Not a Woman: Rethinking I Timothy 2:11-15 in Light of Ancient Evidence.</em></a> Baker Book House, 1992.</li>
<li>Wright, N.T., <em>1 &amp; 2 Timothy and Titus.</em> InterVarsity Press, 2009 [Here’s <a href="http://amzn.to/2GgEl3c">the commentary</a>. Here’s <a href="http://amzn.to/2Ga7zky">the study guide</a>.]</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="books-containing-a-variety-of-views">Books containing a variety of views</h3>
<h4 id="collections-of-essays-1">Collections of Essays</h4>
<ul>
<li>Clouse, Bonnidell and Robert G., eds., <a href="http://amzn.to/2UtANyq"><em>Women in Ministry: Four Views.</em></a> Downers Grove: IVP, 1989.</li>
<li>Beck, James R. and Blomberg, Craig L., eds., <em>Two Views on Women in Ministry.</em> Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2001. (See the <a href="http://amzn.to/2RXjl8U">Revised Edition, published in 2005</a>.)</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="books-not-in-favor-of-womens-ordination">Books not in favor of women’s ordination</h3>
<h4 id="collections-of-essays-2">Collections of Essays</h4>
<ul>
<li>Piper, John and Grudem, Wayne, eds., <a href="http://amzn.to/2GbTD9t"><em>Recovering Biblical Manhood and Womanhood: A Response to Evangelical Feminism.</em></a> Wheaton, Ill.: Crossway, 1991.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="general-works-on-women-in-the-new-testament-and-the-early-church-1">General Works on Women in the New Testament and the Early Church*</h4>
<ul>
<li>Mitchell, Patrick, <a href="http://amzn.to/2SaZItp"><em>The Scandal of Gender: Early Christian Teaching on the Man and the Woman.</em></a> Salisbury, Mass.: Regina Orthodox Press, 1998.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="works-discussing-mens-and-womens-roles-in-the-church-and-society">Works discussing Men’s and Women’s roles in the Church and Society</h4>
<ul>
<li>Clark, Stephen B., <a href="http://amzn.to/2MFlVuh"><em>Man and Woman in Christ: An Examination of the Roles of Men and Women in Light of Scripture and the Social Sciences.</em></a> Ann Arbor, Mich.: Servant, 1980.</li>
<li>Harper, Michael, <a href="http://amzn.to/2CZmiLI"><em>Equal and Different: Male and Female in Church and Family.</em></a> London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1994.</li>
<li>Hurley, James B., <a href="http://amzn.to/2FYFUUb"><em>Man and Woman in Biblical Perspective.</em></a> Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 1981.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="works-discussing-relevant-scripture-passages">Works discussing relevant Scripture Passages</h4>
<ul>
<li>Hauke, Manfred, <a href="http://amzn.to/2CT23PN"><em>Women in the Priesthood?: A Systematic Analysis in the Light of the Order of Creation and Redemption,</em></a> tr. David Kipp. San Francisco: Ignatius, 1986.</li>
<li>Köstenberger, Andreas J., Schreiner, Thomas R., and Baldwin, H. Scott, eds., <a href="http://amzn.to/2GaPxOV"><em>Women in the Church: A Fresh Analysis of 1 Timothy 2:9-15.</em></a> Grand Rapids: Baker, 1995.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="studies-and-articles">Studies and Articles</h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.paludavia.com/anglican/w.pdf">“A Report of the Study Concerning the Ordination of Women Undertaken by the Anglican Mission in America: A survey of the Leading Theological Convictions,”</a> unpublished paper by the Rt. Rev. John H. Rodgers and the Women’s Ordination Study Team (July 31, 2003)</li>
<li>This is the 2003 AMIA Report upon which Section 4 of the 2017 ACNA Report relies.</li>
<li><a href="http://enit-syd.sds.asn.au/Site/104629.asp?ph=cp">“The Doctrine of the Trinity and Its Bearing on the Relationship of Men and Women,”</a> the 1999 Sydney Anglican Diocesan Doctrine Commission Report</li>
<li><a href="http://www.tsm.edu/2014/09/03/women_ordination_and_the_bible/">“Women, Ordination and the Bible”,</a> written by Rod Whitacre, 28 August 2014</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="womens-ordination-from-an-anglo-catholic-perspective">Women’s Ordination from an Anglo-catholic Perspective</h2>
<h3 id="general-anglican-sources">General Anglican Sources</h3>
<ul>
<li>[Church of England]. <em>The Priesthood of the Ordained Ministry.</em> London: Church House Publishing, 1986.</li>
<li>[Church of England]. <a href="http://amzn.to/2TnRQSC"><em>The Ordination of Women to the Priesthood: A Second Report by the House of Bishops of the General Synod of the Church of England</em>.</a> London: Church House Publishing, 1988.</li>
<li>[Church of England]. <a href="http://amzn.to/2UtBhoe"><em>Women Bishops in the Church of England? A Report of the House of Bishops’ Working Party on Women in the Episcopate.</em></a> London: Church House Publishing, 2004.</li>
<li>Avis, Paul, ed. <a href="http://amzn.to/2UtB3NU"><em>Seeking the Truth of Change in the Church: Reception, Communion and the Ordination of Women</em>.</a> London: T and T Clark, 2004.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="catholic-perspectivenotable-sources">Catholic Perspective—Notable Sources</h3>
<ul>
<li>Beattie, Tina. <a href="http://amzn.to/2GcUg2w"><em>God’s Mother, Eve’s Advocate: A Marian Narrative of Women’s Salvation</em>.</a> London: Continuum, 2002.</li>
<li>Kirk, Geoffrey. <a href="http://amzn.to/2SfyjGt"><em>Without Precedent: Scripture, Tradition, and the Ordination of Women</em>.</a> Eugene, OR: Wipf and Stock, 2016.</li>
<li>Lewis, C.S. <a href="http://www.episcopalnet.org/TRACTS/priestesses.html">‘Priestesses in the Church?’</a> In <em>Undeceptions: Essays on Theology and Ethics</em>. London: Geoffrey Bles, 1971. 191-196. Also printed in <em>God in the Dock</em>.</li>
<li>Loades, Ann. ‘On Women.’ In <a href="http://amzn.to/2WxNKJt"><em>The Cambridge Companion to C.S. Lewis</em></a>, ed. Robert MacSwain and Michael Ward. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 2010. 160-173.</li>
<li>Mascall, E.L. <a href="http://trushare.com/Mascall%20Women%20Priests.htm">‘Women Priests?’</a> London: The Church Literature Association, 1972.</li>
<li>Podmore, Colin, ed. <a href="http://amzn.to/2WxrAqH"><em>Fathers in God? Resources for Reflection on Women in the Episcopate.</em></a> Norwich: Canterbury Press, 2015.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="ecumenical-sources">Ecumenical Sources</h3>
<ul>
<li>[Paul VI.] <a href="http://www.vatican.va/roman_curia/congregations/cfaith/documents/rc_con_cfaith_doc_19761015_inter-insigniores_en.html"><em>Inter insigniores (Declaration on the Question of Admission of Women to the Ministerial Priesthood).</em></a> Rome: Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith, 1976.</li>
<li>[John Paul II.] <a href="http://w2.vatican.va/content/john-paul-ii/en/apost_letters/1994/documents/hf_jp-ii_apl_19940522_ordinatio-sacerdotalis.html"><em>Ordinatio sacerdotalis (Apostolic Letter of John Paul II to the Bishops of the Catholic Church on Reserving Priestly Ordination to Men Alone).</em></a> Rome: Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith, 1992.</li>
<li>[John Paul II.] <a href="http://www.vatican.va/roman_curia/congregations/cfaith/documents/rc_con_cfaith_doc_19951028_dubium-ordinatio-sac_en.html"><em>Responsum ad propositum dubitum Concerning the Teaching Contained in ‘Ordinatio sacerdotalis.’</em></a> Rome: Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith, 1995.</li>
<li>Butler, Sr. Sara. <a href="http://amzn.to/2WueMl3"><em>The Catholic Priesthood and Women: A Guide to the Teaching of the Church</em>.</a> Chicago: Hillenbrand Books, 2007.</li>
<li>Behr-Sigel, Elizabeth and Kallistos Ware, <a href="http://amzn.to/2WueElz"><em>The Ordination of Women in the Orthodox Church</em>.</a> Geneva: World Council of Churches, 2000.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="catholic-perspectiveother-sources">Catholic Perspective—Other Sources</h3>
<ul>
<li>Baker, Jonathan, ed. <a href="http://amzn.to/2SjCtgw"><em>Consecrated Women? A Contribution to the Women Bishops Debate.</em></a> Norwich: Canterbury Press, 2004.</li>
<li>Beattie, Tina. ‘Vision and Vulnerability: The Significance of Sacramentality and the Woman Priest for Feminist Theology.’ In <a href="http://amzn.to/2SgU6O9"><em>Exchanges of Grace: Essays in Honour of Ann Loades</em>.</a> London: SCM Press, 2008. 235-249.</li>
<li>Bridge, G.R. <a href="http://amzn.to/2WqdCXT"><em>Women and the Apostolic Ministry?</em></a> Parry Sound, ON: The Convent Society, 1997.</li>
<li>Loades, Ann. <a href="http://biblicalstudies.org.uk/pdf/anvil/21-2_113.pdf">‘Women in the Episcopate?’</a> <em>Anvil</em> 21 no. 2 (2004): 113-119.</li>
<li>MacKinnon, Donald. <a href="http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0040571X9209500206">‘The <em>Icon Christi</em> and Eucharistic Theology.’</a> <em>Theology</em> (March/April 1992): 109-113.</li>
<li>Mascall, E.L. <a href="http://www.womenpriests.org/ecumenism/women-and-the-priesthood-of-the-church-by-e-l-mascall-from-why-not-priesthood-and-the-ministry-of-women/">‘Women and the Priesthood of the Church.’</a> London: The Church Literature Association, 1960.</li>
<li>Richardson, Alan. ‘Women and the Priesthood.’ In <a href="http://amzn.to/2MIcZEG"><em>Lambeth Essays on Ministry: Essays Written for the Lambeth Conference 1968.</em></a> Ed. Arthur Michael Ramsey. London: SPCK, 1969. 75-78.</li>
<li>Underhill, Evelyn. ‘Ideals of the Ministry of Women.’ In <a href="http://amzn.to/2WuEvK2"><em>Mixed Pasture: Twelve Essays and Addresses</em>.</a> Eugene, OR: Wipf and Stock 2015. 113-122.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="works-not-mentioned-in-the-task-force-report">Works Not Mentioned in the Task Force Report</h2>
<ul>
<li>Lynn H. <strong>Cohick</strong> and Amy <strong>Brown Hughes</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/2Wu90Qp"><em>Christian Women in the Patristic World: Their Influence, Authority, and Legacy in the Second through Fifth Centuries</em></a>, Baker Academic, 2017.</li>
<li>Gordon P. <strong>Hugenberger</strong>, <a href="http://womeninthechurch.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/hugenberger%20women%20in%20church%20office%20re%20husbands%20and%20wives%20issue%20in%201%20timothy%202.pdf">“Women in Church Office: Hermeneutics or Exegesis? A Survey of Approaches to 1 TIM 2:8-15,”</a> <em>JETS</em> 35/3 (1992): 341–60.</li>
<li>Michael <strong>Lee-Barnewall</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/2SfN2RU"><em>Neither Complementarian nor Egalitarian: A Kingdom Corrective to the Evangelical Gender Debate</em></a>, Baker Academic, 2016.</li>
<li>Kevin <strong>Madigan</strong> and Carolyn <strong>Osiek</strong>, eds., <a href="http://amzn.to/2WsBWIt"><em>Ordained Women in the Early Church: A Documentary History</em></a>, Johns Hopkins, 2011.</li>
<li>Scot <strong>McKnight</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/2RcCxgN"><em>The Blue Parakeet: Rethinking How You Read the Bible</em></a>, 2nd edition, Zondervan, 2018. Especially Part 5 (chs. 14–19), “Women in Church Ministries Today.”</li>
<li>Lucy <strong>Peppiatt</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/3auozPd"><em>Rediscovering Scripture’s Vision for Women: Fresh Perspectives on Disputed Texts</em></a>, IVP Academic, 2019.</li>
<li>John G. <strong>Stackhouse</strong>, Jr., <a href="http://amzn.to/38oEKeT"><em>Partners in Christ: A Conservative Case for Egalitarianism</em></a>, IVP Academic, 2015.</li>
<li>Kallistos <strong>Ware</strong>, <a href="http://www.womenpriests.org/articles-books/man-woman-and-the-priesthood-of-christ-by-kallistos-ware-from-man-woman-and-priesthood/">“Man, Woman, and the Priesthood of Christ,” pp. 68-90 in <em>Man, Woman, and Priesthood</em></a>, edited by Peter Moore, SPCK London, 1978.</li>
<li>Cynthia <strong>Long Westfall</strong>, <a href="http://amzn.to/2RYQyRp"><em>Paul and Gender: Reclaiming the Apostle’s Vision for Men and Women in Christ</em></a>, Baker Academic, 2016.</li>
<li>Ben <strong>Witherington</strong> III, <a href="http://amzn.to/2WsBLNj"><em>Women in the Earliest Churches (Society for New Testament Studies Monograph Series)</em></a>, Cambridge, 1991.</li>
<li>William <strong>Witt</strong>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Icons-Christ-Biblical-Systematic-Ordination/dp/1481313193?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr=&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=anglicanpasto-20&amp;linkId=8e8fa373219652321476ab03ffe6ffb0&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl"><em>Icons of Christ: A Biblical and Systematic Theology for Women’s Ordination</em></a>, Baylor University Press, 2020.</li>
<li>William <strong>Witt</strong>‘s <a href="http://willgwitt.org/category/theology/womens-ordination/">series of blog posts on women’s ordination</a>.</li>
<li>N.T <strong>Wright</strong>, <a href="http://ntwrightpage.com/2016/07/12/womens-service-in-the-church-the-biblical-basis/">“Women’s Service in the Church: The Biblical Basis”</a></li>
</ul>
<p>What works would you add to this reading list?</p>
<p>What specific questions do you have?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
