<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Politics on Joshua P. Steele</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/politics/</link><description>Recent content in Politics on Joshua P. Steele</description><image><title>Joshua P. Steele</title><url>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</url><link>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 16:22:26 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/politics/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>This Shouldn't Be Controversial</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.com/this-shouldnt-be-controversial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 09:16:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/this-shouldnt-be-controversial/</guid><description>&lt;p>The following statements should not be controversial, but they sadly are. What would you add to this list?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Donald Trump lost the 2020 election.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>January 6th, 2021, was an insurrection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Congress, not the President (and much less the President&amp;rsquo;s unelected adviser), holds the power of the purse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Judicial branch, and not the Executive branch, interprets the law and the Constitution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No one, not even the President, is above the law.&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The following statements should not be controversial, but they sadly are. What would you add to this list?</p>
<p>Donald Trump lost the 2020 election.</p>
<p>January 6th, 2021, was an insurrection.</p>
<p>Congress, not the President (and much less the President&rsquo;s unelected adviser), holds the power of the purse.</p>
<p>The Judicial branch, and not the Executive branch, interprets the law and the Constitution.</p>
<p>No one, not even the President, is above the law.</p>
<p>DOGE is not an official, legal government agency.</p>
<p>Elon Musk is not the President of the United States.</p>
<p>Elon Musk has not been elected to any public office.</p>
<p>Elon Musk personally benefits from many government contracts, and should not be making spending decisions for the government.</p>
<p>Executive orders are not laws.</p>
<p>Russia invaded Ukraine. Ukraine did not start the war with Russia.</p>
<p>The United States of America is a democratic republic, not a dictatorship.</p>
<p>The United States of America is a secular nation, not a theocracy.</p>
<p>The United States of America is a country, not a corporation.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Stay Woke! Ephesians 5:11-14</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.com/stay-woke-ephesians-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 08:12:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/stay-woke-ephesians-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>With fascism on the rise in the United States of America and around the world, and with many so-called &amp;ldquo;Christians&amp;rdquo; gladly supporting the rise of the far-right and attributing it to the will of God, I was struck by these words from Ephesians 5 (which were assigned as one of the readings for Morning Prayer today).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ephesians 5:11-14 (New Living Translation, NLT)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>11 Take no part in the worthless deeds of evil and darkness; instead, expose them.&lt;br>
12 It is shameful even to talk about the things that ungodly people do in secret.&lt;br>
13 But their evil intentions will be exposed when the light shines on them, 14 for the light makes everything visible.&lt;br>
This is why it is said,&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With fascism on the rise in the United States of America and around the world, and with many so-called &ldquo;Christians&rdquo; gladly supporting the rise of the far-right and attributing it to the will of God, I was struck by these words from Ephesians 5 (which were assigned as one of the readings for Morning Prayer today).</p>
<p>Ephesians 5:11-14 (New Living Translation, NLT)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>11 Take no part in the worthless deeds of evil and darkness; instead, expose them.<br>
12 It is shameful even to talk about the things that ungodly people do in secret.<br>
13 But their evil intentions will be exposed when the light shines on them, 14 for the light makes everything visible.<br>
This is why it is said,</p>
<p>“Awake, O sleeper,<br>
rise up from the dead,<br>
and Christ will give you light.”</p></blockquote>
<p>What are these &ldquo;worthless deeds of evil&rdquo;? From the beginning of Ephesians 5:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>3 Let there be no sexual immorality, impurity, or greed among you. Such sins have no place among God’s people.<br>
4 Obscene stories, foolish talk, and coarse jokes—these are not for you. Instead, let there be thankfulness to God.<br>
5 You can be sure that no immoral, impure, or greedy person will inherit the Kingdom of Christ and of God.<br>
For a greedy person is an idolater, worshiping the things of this world.</p></blockquote>
<p>No doubt those who support the rise of the far-right would claim that they are not guilty of these things, but that they are themselves exposing the &ldquo;unfruitful works of darkness&rdquo; committed by those on the godless left!</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not so sure.</p>
<p>Of course, left-leaning political parties and movements are not without their own faults. But I think that the far greater danger within the church is that the far-right promise of political power and influence (and retribution against perceived enemies) has caused many to abandon the gospel of Jesus Christ in favor of a false gospel that is more concerned with power than with love, mercy, and justice.</p>
<p>Greed is idolatry.</p>
<p>Let judgment begin with the household of God. And may God have mercy on us all.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Christianity and Politics: My 2024 Reading List</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.com/christianity-and-politics-my-2024-reading-list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 14:03:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/christianity-and-politics-my-2024-reading-list/</guid><description>&lt;p>The relationship between Church and State, particularly the intersection of Christianity and politics, has been on my mind since I first started paying attention during the lead-up to the 2008 USA presidential election. Back then, I was just a high school student, but these themes have stuck with me ever since.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(For those curious, here’s a quick timeline: In 2012, I was studying biblical studies in college. By 2016, I was a seminarian, and in 2020, I was working on my Ph.D. in theology. Now, in 2024, I’m a software engineer! Yet political theology continues to weigh on my mind.)&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The relationship between Church and State, particularly the intersection of Christianity and politics, has been on my mind since I first started paying attention during the lead-up to the 2008 USA presidential election. Back then, I was just a high school student, but these themes have stuck with me ever since.</p>
<p>(For those curious, here’s a quick timeline: In 2012, I was studying biblical studies in college. By 2016, I was a seminarian, and in 2020, I was working on my Ph.D. in theology. Now, in 2024, I’m a software engineer! Yet political theology continues to weigh on my mind.)</p>
<p>As I’ve thought more about these topics, my reading list has grown, and I wanted to share it with you. It’s a mix of books I’ve read and some that are still on my to-read list. The first book that really shaped my thinking is <em><a href="https://amzn.to/43msglF">Resident Aliens</a></em>—a must-read if you’re interested in Christian political theology.</p>
<p>(All the links below are Amazon affiliate links, by the way.)</p>
<h3 id="christian-political-theology-reading-list">Christian Political Theology Reading List</h3>
<ul>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/4ebfuLH">20 Myths about Religion and Politics in America</a></em> by Ryan P. Burge</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3zeJSW6">Anointed with Oil: How Christianity and Crude Made Modern America</a></em> by Darren Dochuk</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3MBkjSj">Defending Democracy from Its Christian Enemies</a></em> by David P. Gushee</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/4eikNIy">Disarming Leviathan: Loving Your Christian Nationalist Neighbor</a></em> by Caleb E. Campbell</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3ZcuPqx">Jesus and John Wayne: How White Evangelicals Corrupted a Faith and Fractured a Nation</a></em> by Kristin Kobes Du Mez</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/49YDBLu">Jesus and the Powers: Christian Political Witness in an Age of Totalitarian Terror and Dysfunctional Democracies</a></em> by N.T. Wright and Michael Bird</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3Xi9ysL">The Kingdom, the Power, and the Glory: American Evangelicals in an Age of Extremism</a></em> by Tim Alberta</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/4d0kr8o">Mortal Goods: Reimagining Christian Political Duty</a></em> by Ephraim Radner</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/43msglF">Resident Aliens: Life in the Christian Colony</a></em> by Stanley Hauerwas and William Willimon</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/4a3XVdU">Religious Freedom in a Secular Age: A Christian Case for Liberty, Equality, and Secular Government</a></em> by Michael Bird</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/47n9RaE">Scandalous Witness: A Little Political Manifest for Christians</a></em> by Lee C. Camp</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="abortion-specific-reads">Abortion-Specific Reads</h3>
<p>When it comes to abortion, I think it’s a tragedy that needs to be reduced, ideally through a consistent pro-life ethic. However, I’m also curious about progressive theological arguments for a pro-choice stance. Here are a few books I’m reading to explore those ideas:</p>
<ul>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/4eh6V1f">Abortion and the Christian Tradition: A Pro-Choice Theological Ethic</a></em> by Margaret D. Kamitsuka</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3Xh0lkt">Pro-Choice and Christian: Reconciling Faith, Politics, and Justice</a></em> by Kira Schlesinger</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3XmUCcW">Trust Women: A Progressive Christian Argument for Reproductive Justice</a></em> by Rebecca Todd Peters</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="history-reading-list">History Reading List</h3>
<p>In addition to Christian political theology, I’ve also been diving into U.S. and world history, trying to get a better sense of where we’ve been and how it informs the present.</p>
<ul>
<li><em><a href="http://www.americanyawp.com/">The American Yawp: A Massively Collaborative Open U.S. History Textbook</a></em>, Volumes 1 and 2
<ul>
<li>Note: You can <em><a href="http://www.americanyawp.com/">read this for FREE online at americanyawp.com</a>!</em> You can also buy the paperbacks of <em><a href="https://amzn.to/4dUWuRd">Volume 1</a></em> and <em><a href="https://amzn.to/3XhFnSK">Volume 2 on Amazon</a></em></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3zkBS5N">A People’s History of the United States</a></em> by Howard Zinn</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/47isVqo">Democracy Awakening: Notes on the State of America</a></em> by Heather Cox Richardson</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3XzBdXD">It Can’t Happen Here</a></em> by Sinclair Lewis</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/4d1KXyl">Myth America: Historians Take on the Biggest Legends and Lies about Our Past</a></em> edited by Kevin M. Kruse and Julian E. Zelizer</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3XgZr7z">On Tyranny: Twenty Lessons from the Twentieth Century</a></em> by Timothy Snyder</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/47jfG8M">The Annotated U.S. Constitution and Declaration of Independence</a></em> edited by Jack N. Rakove</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3AZ1tC0">The Federalist (Annotated Gideon Edition)</a></em> edited by George W. Carey and James McClellan</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/4d0D3FB">The Lessons of History</a></em> by Will and Ariel Durant</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3zg1j8H">The World: A Brief Introduction</a></em> by Richard Haass</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>What do you think of this list? Are there any books that you think I should add? If you’ve read any of these, I’d love to hear your thoughts on them. Let me know in the comments below, and feel free to suggest your own favorite reads when it comes to political theology or U.S./world history!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>