<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>questions on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/questions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in questions on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 20:10:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/questions/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Questions Worth Asking (Self-Elicitation Questions)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-worth-asking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 20:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-worth-asking/</guid>
      <description>Five-Minute Journal Questions Morning I am grateful for… What would make today great? Daily affirmations: I am… Evening What are 3 amazing things that happened today? How could I have made today even better? Morning Questions (5 minutes) What’s one thing I’m grateful for? What’s one thing I’m excited about? What’s one virtue I want to exhibit? What’s one thing I’m avoiding? What’s the one thing I need to do? Evening Questions (5 minutes) What were my biggest wins of the day?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Me! 11 Questions I&#39;d Like You to Answer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mentor-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mentor-me/</guid>
      <description>Say what you will about Tim Ferriss, I’ve always really enjoyed the questions that he asks himself and others.
I also really enjoy LEARNING as much as I can from other people. And so, with that in mind, I’d like to “open source” my search for mentors and invite you, dear reader, to answer at least one of the questions below.
Please comment your answers below this post (that way others can benefit from your knowledge as well!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Questions to Ask While Reading Theology</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</guid>
      <description>While reading Beth Felker Jones’ Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically, I came across the following list of extremely helpful questions to ask while reading theology (on page 29).
What are the key Christian teachings being articulated? What is the author’s driving concern or main theme? What counts for the author as authoritative (Scripture, tradition, reason, experience…)? Is the author’s theological method implicit or explicit? How does the author deal with the witness of Scripture?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cut the &#34;Positivity&#34; Crap: What Frustrates You?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 17:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</guid>
      <description>I’ll keep this short, sweet, and to the point: I’m looking for problems that I can help solve, so I need you to rant at me in the comments.
That’s right, I basically want you to complain to me in the comments section of this post.
What’s causing you frustration, angst, or stress these days? What questions are you struggling to find the answers to? What obstacles are in the way of you achieving your goals?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Questions to Ask When You Study the Bible (Plus a Worksheet!)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 15:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/</guid>
      <description>The Problem: Studying the Bible can Quickly Feel Overwhelming Right? Even with helpful books out there like How to Read the Bible for All Its Worth (that’s an affiliate link, by the way, meaning that I get a small commission at no cost to you if you end up buying the book), there are still so many potential questions to ask of any biblical text when we study it.
How are we supposed to keep questions of authorship, genre, meaning, application, etc.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
