<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>the-christian-life on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/the-christian-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in the-christian-life on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 20:35:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/the-christian-life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer of Confession</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-of-confession/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 20:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-of-confession/</guid>
      <description>To start off the semester the other day, we prayed this prayer of confession together as a class. The professor didn’t remember where the prayer was from, so I tracked it down online. According to Justin Taylor, it was written by Bob Kauflin.
Holy and righteous God, we confess that like Isaiah, we are a people of unclean lips. But it is not only unclean lips we possess. We are people with unclean hands and unclean hearts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Attracts People to Anglicanism? Here&#39;s My Take</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 21:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</guid>
      <description>Based upon my work over at Rookie Anglican, I was asked by The Telos Collective to write a blog post about the different ways that people are coming into Anglicanism. What&amp;rsquo;s drawing them in?
You can read my full post over at the Telos Collective blog, but here&amp;rsquo;s a taste:
Anglican Christianity, precisely because of its weirdness, can remind us that, in the words of Brad Harper and Paul Louis Metzger in Exploring Ecclesiology, “The church is a cultural community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I catalogued a bunch of different takes on Jordan Peterson, before giving my own take.
Since that post, two other pieces about Jordan Peterson have been written that I&amp;rsquo;d like to share.
&amp;ldquo;Jordan Peterson, Custodian of the Patriarchy,&amp;rdquo; by Nellie Bowles (New York Times) Nellie Bowles writes
Mr. Peterson, 55, a University of Toronto psychology professor turned YouTube philosopher turned mystical father figure, has emerged as an influential thought leader.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Grain of the Gospel: Why Christians Should Care about Food Ethics</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grain-of-the-gospel-why-christians-should-care-about-food-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 06:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grain-of-the-gospel-why-christians-should-care-about-food-ethics/</guid>
      <description>The following is a guest post written by my friend and former college roommate, Zak Weston. Zak&amp;rsquo;s been working in the area of food ethics, and I asked him to write up a post about why Christians should care about these issues. It&amp;rsquo;s an area in which I need to make some changes in my own life. He delivered this thought-provoking and challenging piece. I hope you enjoy.
Introduction The three or so decisions you make each day about what to eat are some of the most consequential choices you make in your life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to make of Jordan Peterson? Some takes, then my own.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Read my post, &amp;ldquo;Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson.&amp;rdquo;
If I remember correctly, I first heard of and listened to Jordan Peterson on an episode of The Art of Manliness podcast. (Or perhaps it was this episode.)
However, I could be mistaken, because Peterson&amp;rsquo;s been popping up in conversation all over the place in my circles. Blog posts, podcast episodes, conversations with friends - Peterson has been popping up everywhere, so it seems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Please Don&#39;t Leave Me Alone: On Male Friendships, or the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 18:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you, like me, consider yourself quite the introvert. Maybe you, like me, have a difficult time walking the tightrope between feeling quickly overwhelmed by interpersonal relationships, on the one hand, and feeling incredibly lonely, on the other hand.
Maybe you, like me, feel these problems acutely as a male (although I’m sure that females are having their own relational struggles as our culture increasingly pressures us all to be “alone together,” looking at our screens instead of looking each other in the eye).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christian, Do the Daily Office: 5 Things You Can Learn from Morning and Evening Prayer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christian-daily-office-5-things-can-learn-morning-evening-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christian-daily-office-5-things-can-learn-morning-evening-prayer/</guid>
      <description>The Problem: We All Need to Grow, But We&amp;rsquo;re Not Sure How Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: to say the very least, we Christians all have room to grow when it comes to following Jesus. None of us has &amp;ldquo;arrived.&amp;rdquo;
There&amp;rsquo;s always more to learn about who God is, what God has done, and how we can join God&amp;rsquo;s mission to set the world right again. And, even if we know a bunch about those things in the previous sentence, we surely don&amp;rsquo;t always live based on that knowledge!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Reasons Why I&#39;m an Anglican Christian</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 05:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</guid>
      <description>Why am I an Anglican Christian? Here are 3 reasons.
1. Anglicanism as a Refuge from Fundamentalism First, for me, Anglicanism has been a refuge from fundamentalism. Now, to be sure, we do have our own fundamentalists within the Anglican Communion! But, compared to some &amp;ldquo;ingrown enclaves&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced in my Christian upbringing, Anglicanism has been a breath of fresh air. It has been an ecclesiological space for healing as I seek to &amp;quot; not throw the (gospel) baby out with the (fundamentalist) bathwater.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cut the &#34;Positivity&#34; Crap: What Frustrates You?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 17:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this short, sweet, and to the point: I&amp;rsquo;m looking for problems that I can help solve, so I need you to rant at me in the comments.
That&amp;rsquo;s right, I basically want you to complain to me in the comments section of this post.
What&amp;rsquo;s causing you frustration, angst, or stress these days? What questions are you struggling to find the answers to? What obstacles are in the way of you achieving your goals?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christians and Wealth: An Argument for Downward Mobility</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christians-and-wealth-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 01:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christians-and-wealth-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! If you only have a minute to read about wealth, here&amp;rsquo;s my argument in a nutshell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-my-argument&#34;&gt;Outline of My Argument&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Claim: American Christians should reduce their standards of living to what is necessary for human flourishing and give their excess resources beyond this standard to the poor and oppressed.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is the firmest advocate for human flourishing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pursuit of wealth is spiritually dangerous and crippling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our culture’s inclinations toward upward financial mobility go against the message of the New Testament and the life of Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is revealed in Scripture to have a special concern for the poor and the oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christians will be held accountable for how they treat the poor and the oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objections:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This line of reasoning is advocating asceticism and is unbiblical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christians have every right to keep what they have earned and to do what they wish with their excess funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because the poor are lazy, Christians should not feel pressured to give, in case their generosity is taken advantage of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warrant:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christians want to remain true to Scripture and submit to God’s way of life in order to find satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For more on Christianity, wealth, and poverty, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2011/02/10/20110210proverbs-topical-study-poverty/&#34;&gt;my topical study on what the book of Proverbs has to teach us about poverty&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still interested in reading about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christian_views_on_poverty_and_wealth&#34;&gt;this contentious topic&lt;/a&gt;? Continue below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our current context of wealth and poverty existing side by side in a milieu of materialistic consumerism, the Christian gospel of denying ourselves and making much of God is being abandoned for the American gospel of denying others and making much of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Christians have become content to live a baptized version of the American dream, a hollow faith that is about maximizing your earthly portfolio once your salvation is secured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main contention is that &lt;strong&gt;Christians in the United States should lower their standards of living to what is necessary for human flourishing and give their excess resources beyond this standard to the poor&lt;/strong&gt;. In doing so, they will remain faithful to Scripture and discover a more satisfactory way of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;isnt-that-asceticism&#34;&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t That Asceticism?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, some may claim that I am trying to advocate for a form of asceticism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Give Thanks!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/give-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/give-thanks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not the most thankful person.
However, I am a follower of Jesus, and one of the lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning this semester is that praise, thanksgiving, and gratitude are closely intertwined. Worship should involve the public proclamation of who God is and what He has done &amp;ndash; including specific, personal declarations of thanksgiving for God&amp;rsquo;s grace and good gifts.
If, like me, you have a hard time cultivating this worshipful practice of gratitude, then allow me to suggest the following prayers from the Book of Common Prayer to help get us started.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 2014 Regional ETS Paper: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 09:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, here&amp;rsquo;s the latest version of the Regional ETS paper I will present today at 5:00pm at Beeson Divinity School, room S009.
If you&amp;rsquo;re able to attend the presentation, that&amp;rsquo;s great! If not, feel free to give my paper a read and get back to me with any questions, comments, or suggestions. Atonement theology and the unity of the Church are two things about which I am very passionate, and intend to devote further study to these areas in the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Regional ETS Presentation: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 15:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the Birmingham area from March 21-22, 2014, and you&amp;rsquo;re interested in evangelical theology, please consider attending the Evangelical Theological Society&amp;rsquo;s Southeastern Regional Meeting at Beeson Divinity School! This year&amp;rsquo;s theme is &amp;ldquo;the theological interpretation of Scripture,&amp;rdquo; and the plenary speaker is Wheaton&amp;rsquo;s Daniel J. Treier (incidentally, Dr. Treier and I are both alumni of Cedarville&amp;hellip;go figure).
Furthermore, if you&amp;rsquo;re free from 5:00-5:30pm on Friday, March 21, consider swinging by room S009 to hear me present &amp;ldquo;Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof: Atonement, Ecclesiology, and the Unity of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Epistle to Philemon: Analysis and Application</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-epistle-to-philemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-epistle-to-philemon/</guid>
      <description>As the briefest member of the Pauline corpus, the epistle to Philemon is a letter of recommendation for the sake of reconciliation in which the apostle Paul brings the gospel truth of mutual participation in the body of Christ to bear on an estranged relationship – making a delicate request of his friend Philemon to receive back a certain Onesimus into full fellowship as a brother in Christ. [1]Comprehension of the passage’s contemporaneous Greco-Roman epistolary landscape facilitates a knowledgeable analysis of its constituent parts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Friday Book Recommendation: The Economy of Desire</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/black-friday-book-recommendation-the-economy-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 16:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/black-friday-book-recommendation-the-economy-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>Black Friday proves that the progress of (post)modernity has failed to eradicate the ills of idolatry. Lest we denizens of the &amp;ldquo;highly-developed&amp;rdquo; world think that we have left the primitive vestiges of wood, rock, and gold idolatry behind, our shopping patterns (and indeed our shopping identities as consumers) should remind us of our consumerism&amp;rsquo;s dark side -- a lethal one.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve put in &amp;ldquo;Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof&amp;rdquo;:
&amp;ldquo;Although physical idols may not be as universally common today as they once were, invisible idols are as prevalent as ever, especially within the context of Western materialism, where money, possessions, influence, and power are the modern-day Baal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silence and Violence</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/silence-and-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 18:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/silence-and-violence/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;] Silent Cross by Margot Krebs Neale[/caption]
&amp;ldquo;Violence is not human destiny because the God of peace is the beginning and the end of human history&amp;hellip;
&amp;ldquo;Granted, pushing the stone of peace up the steep hill of violence &amp;hellip; is hard. It is easier, however, than carrying one&amp;rsquo;s own cross in the footsteps of the crucified Messiah. This is what Jesus Christ asks Christians to do. Assured of God&amp;rsquo;s justice and undergirded by God&amp;rsquo;s presence, they are to break the cycle of violence by refusing to be caught in the automatism of revenge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down With the Pacifists!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/down-with-the-pacifists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 20:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/down-with-the-pacifists/</guid>
      <description>The past week has been a great one for slipshod attacks on pacifism. First, from First Things (Stephen H. Webb) on October 15 &amp;mdash;- &amp;ldquo;John Howard Yoder and the Violent Power of Pacifism&amp;rdquo; (emphasis added below):
&amp;ldquo;Nevertheless, pacifists, at least the ones I know, can be very enthusiastic about the rightness of their cause. Since there is no rational justification for pacifism, defenders typically turn their rhetoric against their critics by casting them as stooges of the status quo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scripture: What The Bible Is And Why It Matters</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 13:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-scripture/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION: THE NATURE OF SCRIPTURE As the illocutionary act which testifies to the Son of God 1 as the ultimate redemptive and revelatory locution of the the triune God, Scripture is used by the Spirit of God to accomplish the perlocutionary end of redemption of, in, and through the people of God. 2[Ahem, in order to understand my first paragraph, you must first be familiar with the basics of Speech Act Theory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>King Jesus&amp;#039; Kingdom Gospel</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 13:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</guid>
      <description>I highly encourage the following:
1. Read Scot McKnight&amp;rsquo;s The King Jesus Gospel.
2. Check out Tim Gombis&amp;rsquo; insightful series of posts on The Gospel of the Kingdom, pt. 1, 2, and 3.
Gombis hits the nail on the head here:
Over the last several months, I’ve had several conversations about how the Gospels’ language about “the gospel” should shape how Christians conceive of the gospel. Whereas the New Testament mainly envisions a broader announcement of a larger reality, many evangelicals associate “the gospel” with a brief presentation, or information about the mechanics of an individual transaction that can secure divine forgiveness and the establishment of a personal relationship with God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inductive Bible Study in 7 Steps: &#34;Scripture, Handle With Care,&#34; by Amy Chase Ashley</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/inductive-bible-study-7-steps-amy-chase-ashley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/inductive-bible-study-7-steps-amy-chase-ashley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Update (April 2017): I&amp;rsquo;ve gone back to update/clean-up the formatting in this wonderful June 2013 guest post on the basics of inductive Bible study from my friend &lt;strong&gt;Amy Elizabeth Chase Ashley,&lt;/strong&gt; one of the most gifted students of Scripture with whom I&amp;rsquo;ve been privileged to study. She blogs at &lt;a href=&#34;https://amyechase.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;https://amyechase.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;jeremiah-2911&#34;&gt;Jeremiah 29:11&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I accepted the invitation to speak at my parents’ church, I immediately started thinking about what message I would deliver.  I decided to give a message on something that is very important to me after my four years at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cedarville.edu/&#34;&gt;Cedarville&lt;/a&gt; and something I am very passionate about.  I hope it will be engaging; I hope it will make you think; and I hope it will bring glory to God.  If I can accomplish those three things, I will be satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Scripture I chose is Jeremiah 29:11 and I’m guessing that most Christians could recite the verse from memory.  If not, once you read it, you’ll probably remember or recognize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“’For I know the plans I have for you,’ declares the Lord, ‘plans to prosper you and not to harm you, plans to give you a hope and a future.’”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a familiar verse for a lot of Christians.  My question today is whether it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might seem like a strange question, but I think you’ll understand what I mean soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why is this verse so familiar to us?  Well, it’s used a lot.  Are you nervous about future uncertainties?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11&lt;/em&gt;.  Are you starting a new job? &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;  Graduating from high school or college?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;  That teenage girl had her boyfriend break up with her?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;  Car trouble that makes you late to work?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;  Lost your lucky pencil?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you’re catching my sarcasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://rlv.zcache.com/jeremiah_29_11_i_know_the_plans_bible_verse_denim_keychain-r143db7130dbe4fb3a239db30a4aeef88_x7j3z_8byvr_512.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;
And maybe you think I’m exaggerating.  But I did a Google search for Jeremiah 29:11 and you can buy folders, clocks, plaques, keychains, mugs, pictures, bumper stickers, aprons, tote bags, iPhone cases, tshirts, pillows, bracelets, and even playing cards that have this verse on them.  It might be rivaling the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Psalm%2023&amp;amp;version=NET&#34;&gt;23rd Psalm&lt;/a&gt; after all that.   And I know for a fact that it can be found on countless greeting cards whether they be sympathy, graduation, engagement, or congratulatory cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/this-is-not-a-bag-of-trail-mix-you-cant-just-pick-out-the-p.png&#34; alt=&#34;- this is not a bag of trail mix you cant just pick out the p&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a meme on the internet the other day.  It was an image of the Bible, and the text said: “This is not a bag of trail mix.  You can’t just pick out the pieces you like and ignore the rest.”  I’m afraid that the widespread use of Jeremiah 29:11 demonstrates a bigger problem: we really are guilty of treating the Bible like a bag of trail mix.  Jeremiah 29:11 is an M&amp;amp;M that we pull out time and time again while we ignore all the peanuts and raisins and cashews and granola all around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians claim to have a high view of Scripture—that is, we say that the Bible is the authoritative, divinely inspired Word of God.  We are quick to use it to tell the world what they’re doing wrong whether that be gay marriage or murder or how to raise children.  We say that we live by what the Bible says, but I’m afraid that we’re often guilty of not even knowing what the Bible says.  For me, the widespread use of Jeremiah 29:11 proves this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate, does anyone know what Jeremiah 29:10 says?  No, because it’s a peanut.  Jeremiah 29:12?  Sorry, I don’t like raisins.  But I am feeling uncertain about this new job/relationship/house/baby/friend/responsibility/accomplishment/etc., so I like to be told that God has good plans for me.  I like to imagine him saying, “I know the plans I have for you…”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Interpreting the Bible: Deuteronomy 6:1-15</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/deuteronomy-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 20:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/deuteronomy-6/</guid>
      <description>Deuteronomy 6:1-15 (NRSV) Now this is the commandment—the statutes and the ordinances—that the Lord your God charged me to teach you to observe in the land that you are about to cross into and occupy, 2 so that you and your children and your children’s children may fear the Lord your God all the days of your life, and keep all his decrees and his commandments that I am commanding you, so that your days may be long.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Reading Romans 13 Wrong! Here&#39;s How to Read It Correctly</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 07:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-13/</guid>
      <description>This study of Romans 13 rests upon a crucial presupposition: without context, words can mean anything and everything, and therefore mean nothing. It is only through the delimiting influence of context that words, phrases, sentences, and paragraphs are endowed with significance.
Although this concept seems simple and justified enough, it is often forgotten within the field of biblical exegesis. Due to influences as simple as our versification of the biblical text and as complex as the historical/theological developments which have dictated how we teach and interpret the Scriptures, many exegetes (wittingly or unwittingly) ignore context when trying to ascertain the meaning of particular biblical texts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Romans, Distilled and Paraphrased</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-distilled-paraphrased/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 14:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-distilled-paraphrased/</guid>
      <description>The following is an attempt, written in 2012, to distill and paraphrase the main argument/message/story/logic of St. Paul&amp;rsquo;s Epistle to the Romans.
Romans 1:1-17 If you don’t catch anything else from what I’m about to say, remember this:
God is righteous. He is just. He is faithful.
God has proven himself faithful to his promises of restoring the world, working through his faithful Son, the Messiah, to bring about both our faith in and our faithfulness to him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 19:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unity/</guid>
      <description>The more I study the New Testament, I become more convinced that the unity of the Church is of utmost importance to God.
What bothers me is that this has never been taught to me before. All of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned (specifically in my studies on Philippians, Galatians, and now Romans) about the importance of unity for the sake of the Gospel mission and the Kingdom of God have come as somewhat of a shock.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Good News of Christmas</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-good-news-of-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 13:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-good-news-of-christmas/</guid>
      <description>After reading The King Jesus Gospel: The Original Good News Revisited by Scot McKnight, who makes the claim that the gospel is the saving story of Jesus as Messiah, King, and Lord as the completion to the story of Israel, I started to notice some profound gospel messages in the Christmas carols we often sing during this season.
I have found that several of these carols go much deeper (much more biblical) than the personal salvation &amp;ldquo;gospel&amp;rdquo; of sin-management that we often preach and sing about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Church and State</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/church_and_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 12:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/church_and_state/</guid>
      <description>(Note: for a more recent piece on the relationship between Church and State, see my essay: &amp;quot; Improvising Church and State.&amp;quot;)
I just read an article by Kevin DeYoung at The Gospel Coalition: &amp;ldquo;Thinking Theologically About Memorial Day&amp;rdquo;. Listen to his intro:
This post probably has something to make everyone unhappy. But here goes.
With Memorial Day on Monday (in the U.S.) and, no doubt, a number of patriotic services scheduled for this Sunday, I want to offer a few theses on patriotism and the church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Bible Says About Poverty: The Book of Proverbs</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bible-poverty-proverbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 23:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bible-poverty-proverbs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Poverty and Wealth In contrast to the affluence of mainstream American culture, poverty is a harsh and painful reality. It can be found in abundance in the urban centers of this country, and in countless other places around the globe.
Modern day slavery “more cruel than any beast of prey” (Wright 2005, 136), it traps human beings created in the image of God in a lifestyle of hunger, sickness, anger, and darkness.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
