<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Theology on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theology on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 16:45:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/theology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taking Scripture and Women’s Ordination Seriously: A Response to Blake Johnson and Lee Nelson</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: Thank you to the Rev. Dr. Emily McGowin for writing this rejoinder to &lt;a href=&#34;http://theopolisinstitute.com/sacramental-representation-and-the-created-order/&#34;&gt;Fr. Blake Johnson’s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/&#34;&gt;Fr. Lee Nelson’s&lt;/a&gt; responses to &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/&#34;&gt;her original blog post&lt;/a&gt; about the&lt;/em&gt; in persona Christi &lt;em&gt;argument against women’s ordination. While we invite this conversation (about McGowin’s original blog post) to continue in our comments section and elsewhere—and we plan to publish more about women’s ordination in the future—we will not be adding surrejoinder blog posts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Editor’s Note: Thank you to the Rev. Dr. Emily McGowin for writing this rejoinder to <a href="http://theopolisinstitute.com/sacramental-representation-and-the-created-order/">Fr. Blake Johnson’s</a> and <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/">Fr. Lee Nelson’s</a> responses to <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/">her original blog post</a> about the</em> in persona Christi <em>argument against women’s ordination. While we invite this conversation (about McGowin’s original blog post) to continue in our comments section and elsewhere—and we plan to publish more about women’s ordination in the future—we will not be adding surrejoinder blog posts.</em></p>
<hr>
<p>I am grateful to <a href="http://theopolisinstitute.com/sacramental-representation-and-the-created-order/">Fr. Blake Johnson</a> and <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/">Fr. Lee Nelson</a> for their responses to my previous blog post, <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/">“If Women Can Be Saved, Then Women Can Be Priests.”</a></p>
<p>I begin with a point of clarification: My piece was intentionally narrow. I offered a critique of the <em>in persona Christi</em> argument against women’s ordination to the priesthood. I was not offering a full argument for women’s ordination. It seems some confusion has resulted from those who assume I was doing the latter rather than the former.</p>
<p>With that in mind, I am glad to see Johnson and Nelson have broadened the discussion on this subject. They help to demonstrate that the conclusion one draws regarding women in the priesthood depends not only upon the christological issue I raised initially, but also a variety of other weighty matters, including biblical interpretation, how one draws upon the sources of the tradition, and more.</p>
<h2 id="beginning-with-scripture">Beginning with Scripture</h2>
<p>While both authors raise a variety of issues worthy of engagement, I want to begin with biblical interpretation (something Nelson faults me for not doing enough of). Since both Johnson and Nelson root their arguments in a particular reading of Genesis 2, I’ll focus my attention there. In what follows, I am drawing, in part, upon conversations with my Wheaton College colleague, <a href="http://www.wheaton.edu/academics/faculty/aubrey-buster/">Dr. Aubrey Buster</a>.</p>
<h3 id="genesis-2">Genesis 2</h3>
<h4 id="first-in-genesis-22122-the-hebrew-word-tsela-does-not-mean-rib-as-nelson-suggests">First, in Genesis 2:21–22, the Hebrew word <em>tsela’</em> does not mean “rib” as Nelson suggests.</h4>
<p>It is translated “rib” by some Bible translations today, but that translation is not demonstrative of the best scholarship on the subject.</p>
<p>According to <a href="http://www.logos.com/product/5226/hebrew-and-aramaic-lexicon-of-the-old-testament"><em>HALOT</em></a>, the current standard Hebrew lexicon, there is no other occurrence in the Hebrew Bible where <em>tsela’</em> means “rib”. In every other case, it is translated “side” (see p. 1030). The Septuagint translates the Hebrew with the Greek word <em>pleura</em>, which also means “side.” Even in cognate languages where it is used for animal or human anatomy, it refers to the side of the chest.</p>
<h4 id="why-is-this-important">Why is this important?</h4>
<p>Because the scriptures say Eve is constructed out of Adam’s <em>side.</em> Eve is derivative in the sense of being taken from Adam (like Adam was taken from the earth), but decidedly <em>not</em> derivative in the sense of subordinate to Adam; she is his <em>side,</em> one half of a whole. The theological point of Genesis 2 is not to emphasize the <em>hierarchical</em> <em>difference</em> between Adam and Eve, whether in terms of ontology, function, or roles, but their <em>similarity</em>. Put simply, Adam and Eve are made of the same stuff. Eve is not an alien creature. She is Adam’s side—his own flesh and bone—which Dr. John Walton calls Adam’s “ontological equal” (see <em><a href="http://amzn.to/2NXWq9N">The Lost World of Adam and Eve</a></em>, p. 110).</p>
<p>Interpreters of Genesis note that chapters 1 and 2 appear to be intentionally subversive of the creation stories and cosmologies of the nations surrounding the people of Israel. The same holds true in the creation of woman. It was quite common in the cultures of the ANE to view women as creatures of inferior ontology in comparison to men. (Not just the ANE, of course, but in Greek thought, too, where the supposed inferior ontology of women becomes more institutionalized.) The biblical narrative is, in Walton’s words, “operating in the same room of discourse” as the ANE, but “Genesis has rearranged all the furniture”. The author is offering a subversive, countercultural perspective: one that affirms the full humanity and God-ordained status of women side-by-side with men.</p>
<h4 id="second-a-close-reading-of-the-text-shows-that-the-task-for-which-eve-is-created-is-the-same-task-for-which-the-man-is-created">Second, a close reading of the text shows that the task for which Eve is created is the <em>same</em> task for which the man is created.</h4>
<p>Johnson rightly notes that God gives to the man a task, namely to “keep and to guard” the garden (v. 15), which parallels the temple service of the Levites (see Num. 3:8-9). And it is in the context of <em>this task</em> that God says it is not good for him to be alone (v. 18).</p>
<p>That is to say, is it not good for Adam to do his keeping and guarding work alone. Instead, he must have an <em>ezer kenegdo</em> (v. 18): an “ally (one who aids someone in accomplishing a task) of the same kind.” What is this ally-ship for, but for the task for which the man was created? Eve will be the one who helps him in accomplishing the task given him by God.</p>
<p>Others have written about the significance of <em>ezer</em> in Gen. 2:18, so I won’t duplicate their work here. I’ll simply point out that the word <em>ezer</em> occurs 21 times in the Bible: it is used twice to describe the woman in Gen. 2, sixteen times to describe God, and three times to describe an army aiding in battle.</p>
<p>For example,</p>
<ul>
<li>in Exod. 18:4: “…the name of the other, Eliezer (for he said, “The God of my father was my <em>help</em>, and delivered me from the sword of Pharaoh”).</li>
<li>In Deut. 33:26: “There is none like God, O Jeshurun, who rides through the heavens to your <em>help</em>, through the skies in his majesty.”</li>
<li>And Ps. 33:20: “Our soul waits for the Lord; he is our <em>help</em> and our shield.”</li>
</ul>
<p>The word <em>ezer</em> is never used to refer to aid in procreation and there is certainly never any sense of subordination in its usage (especially since it is used so often to speak of God himself!). In most contexts, <em>ezer</em> is referring to something related to the military, hence the translation of “ally” offered above.</p>
<p>Furthermore, in Gen. 2 there is no reference in the creation of woman to her function as “life-giver,” or any procreative purposes whatsoever until after the fall (Gen. 3:20). The only task that is given the man and the woman in the passage regarding the purposes for which they are created is the mandate to keep and to guard the garden, and to obey the command of the Lord (Gen. 2:15-17).</p>
<p>(Now, the creation narrative of Gen. 1 does indeed contain a reference to procreation. In that context, though, man and woman are created simultaneously in the image of God and blessed <em>as a pair</em>, just as the animals are blessed, to “be fruitful and multiply” [Gen. 1:28]. Fruitfulness and reproduction are not unique to humankind, but part of the plant and animal world in which they exist. What the text emphasizes, rather, is the dominion that God grants to the humans [“subdue it” in v. 28]. Furthermore, there is no sense in Gen. 1 that fruitfulness and multiplication are functions given to women exclusively; it is something the human couple <em>shares</em>.)</p>
<h4 id="finally-in-contrast-to-nelsons-translation-adam-is-certainly-not-tasked-with-serving-as-a-gardener">Finally, in contrast to Nelson’s translation, Adam is certainly not tasked with serving as a “gardener.”</h4>
<p>As Johnson points out, because of its parallel to Num. 3:8 and other references to the temple, what’s being spoken of here is keeping and guarding the <em>the place where God’s presence dwells</em>.</p>
<p>This is priestly language describing a priestly vocation. And, once again, it is something Adam is not meant to do alone. It is precisely the work of preserving sacred space that Adam is unable to accomplish without Eve. In the vocation of tending to the place where God’s presence dwells, Eve is Adam’s “ally of the same kind” (<em>ezer kenegdo).</em></p>
<h4 id="now-in-fairness-to-johnson-and-nelson-they-are-not-doing-a-strictly-grammatical-and-historical-reading-of-gen-2">Now, in fairness to Johnson and Nelson, they are not doing a strictly grammatical and historical reading of Gen. 2.</h4>
<p>Instead, they are employing a typological reading, one clearly inspired, in my estimation, by <a href="http://www.usccb.org/issues-and-action/marriage-and-family/natural-family-planning/catholic-teaching/theology-of-the-body.cfm">Pope John Paul II’s “Theology of the Body</a>.”</p>
<p>To be clear, I have no problem with typological readings of Scripture in general. But, I do have a problem when a typological reading imposes something that is alien to, or directly at odds with, the most natural and straightforward interpretation of the sacred text.</p>
<p>And this, I believe, is one of those instances. Those of us committed to the authority of Scripture must, at the very least, allow Scripture to speak for itself before assigning to it typological meanings that go beyond the intent of the original author.</p>
<h4 id="before-moving-on-and-along-the-same-lines-i-want-to-offer-a-word-of-caution-to-those-inclined-to-agree-with-nelsons-interpretation-of-gen-2-and-the-theology-of-the-body-as-a-whole">Before moving on, and along the same lines, I want to offer a word of caution to those inclined to agree with Nelson’s interpretation of Gen. 2 and the “Theology of the Body” as a whole.</h4>
<p>The notion that, as Nelson says, “sexual difference serves to show the relation between God and creation,” with men imaging God (father, gardener, giver) and women imaging creation (life-giver, mother, receiver) has deep conceptual resonance with the <em>pagan</em> cosmology of the Ancient Near East.</p>
<p>In fact, it is this kind of Canaanite cosmology, which closely linked human sexuality and the deity, that the creation narratives of Genesis 1-2 are expressly denying.</p>
<p>In their desire to find a unified essentialist theology of gender in the scriptures, I fear many are extrapolating the analogies of Christ and the church, Yahweh and Israel, husband and wife, in ways that are deeply harmful—both for our theology proper and our theological anthropology.</p>
<p>I therefore encourage my sisters and brothers to think more critically about these kinds of claims and to consider carefully whether their conclusions are, indeed, in continuity with the scriptures and the great tradition of the Christian church.</p>
<h3 id="there-are-many-more-points-of-interpretive-disagreement-i-could-cite-between-nelsons-and-johnsons-responses-but-i-find-myself-constrained-by-time-and-space">There are many more points of interpretive disagreement I could cite between Nelson’s and Johnson’s responses, but I find myself constrained by time and space.</h3>
<p>Regarding the conclusions we draw from the Pauline corpus, like 1 Tim. 2:11-16, 1 Cor. 11:1-16; and 1 Cor. 14:34-35, I’ll simply say this: Nelson demonstrates precisely the kind of argumentation that Johnson rightly warns against—treating these texts simply as “knockdown verse[s]” against women’s ordination to the priesthood, rather than engaging carefully with St. Paul’s reasoning in its immediate and canonical context.</p>
<p>For instance, what does Paul mean about forbidding women to teach men (1 Tim. 2:12) when he assumes elsewhere that they will, in fact, do so? And, when they do, Paul says they should do so with their heads covered (1 Cor. 11:2-16) and in good order (1 Cor. 14:1-33)?</p>
<p>Whatever we are to make of this, it is by no means simple and straightforward. We should not insult our interlocutors by suggesting that it is.</p>
<h2 id="i-want-to-be-very-clear-about-my-position-i-do-not-support-the-ordination-of-women-to-the-priesthood-despite-the-bible-i-support-it-because-of-the-bible">I want to be very clear about my position: I do not support the ordination of women to the priesthood <em>despite</em> the Bible; I support it <em>because</em> of the Bible.</h2>
<p>And I am by no means alone in this. I encourage those who argue against women’s ordination to the priesthood to engage the works of a great many respected and orthodox biblical scholars whose research on this subject directly refutes many, if not all, of the interpretive points Nelson and Johnson raise:</p>
<ul>
<li>Craig Keener (the new president of the Evangelical Theological Society),</li>
<li>Scot McKnight,</li>
<li>Ben Witherington III,</li>
<li>Nijay Gupta,</li>
<li>Cynthia Long Westfall,</li>
<li>Lucy Peppiatt,</li>
<li>N.T. Wright,</li>
<li>Gordon Fee,</li>
<li>Richard Bauckham,</li>
<li>I. Howard Marshall,</li>
<li>and Anthony Thiselton, among many others.</li>
</ul>
<p>In my view, Scripture does not, in fact, define narrowly what men and women are ontologically, nor does it demarcate women’s and men’s functions based solely on their gender. Such notions have to be read into the text.</p>
<p>Instead, the scriptures provide an overarching vision for women and men as different, distinct, and mutually submissive partners in the Kingdom of God. This was God’s intention from the beginning and it is a partnership restored in the reign of God inaugurated by Jesus Christ. And this new creation is something the church gets to embody as an outpost of the Kingdom within this fallen world until our Lord returns.</p>
<h2 id="other-questionsissues">Other Questions/Issues</h2>
<p>As I said at the beginning, the interpretation of Scripture is not the only area within which we must adjudicate the question of women’s ordination to the priesthood.</p>
<p>For the sake of clarity, I think it will be helpful to acknowledge some of the many questions raised by Johnson’s and Nelson’s responses:</p>
<h3 id="on-the-subject-of-scripture-and-its-interpretation">On the subject of Scripture and its interpretation:</h3>
<ul>
<li>What does the narrative of Scripture have to say about the meaning of being created male and female? Does Scripture indeed teach discrete roles or functions in the world and Christ’s church based on gender?</li>
<li>Does the canon speak with one voice on the subject of women and women’s “roles”? Or is there discernible development/movement within the canon?</li>
<li>More specifically, is the New Covenant best understood as continuous or discontinuous with the Old Covenant in regard to ecclesial leadership; namely, the priesthood?</li>
<li>How are we to interpret the passages in the letters of St. Paul, which seem to restrict women in some instances (1 Tim. 2:11-15; 1 Cor. 11:1-16; 1 Cor. 14:34-35), while freeing them and assuming their leadership in other instances (1 Cor. 12:1-31; 1 Cor. 14:1-33; Gal. 3:28; Rom. 16:1-16; Phil. 4:2-3)? What is the best way to interpret these passages so as to make sense of all of the evidence in the canon?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="on-the-subject-of-the-tradition">On the subject of the tradition:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Does the great tradition of Christianity speak with one voice on the subject of women in leadership, particularly, sacramental leadership? If not, what do we make of dissenting voices or practices within the tradition?</li>
<li>What do we make of <a href="http://www.palgrave.com/gp/book/9783030111106">recent findings</a> that suggest that significantly more expanded roles for women were operative in the earliest days of the church? Does this have any impact on our perspective on and interpretation of the tradition?</li>
<li>Does tradition need to be interpreted within its own contexts? Or are the voices of the tradition permitted to speak without regard to their own social and cultural norms (particularly in regard to their views of women)?</li>
<li>Along similar lines, are the conclusions of the early church fathers regarding women and women’s roles normative for Christians today? If so, why? And how so?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="on-the-subject-of-the-anglican-communions-relationship-to-other-catholic-bodies">On the subject of the Anglican Communion’s relationship to other catholic bodies:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Are Anglicans mainly Protestant or mainly Catholic, or something else entirely? And what impact does that have on our theological method and church practice?</li>
<li>Are the traditions of the Roman Catholic Church and Orthodox Church on the matter of women in the priesthood normative for the Anglican Communion?</li>
<li>More specifically, are the teachings of Pope John Paul II, particularly his “Theology of the Body,” which are often brought to bear on this issue, to be understood as normative for Anglicans today?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="on-the-subject-of-theological-method">On the subject of theological method:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Are arguments from natural law, upon which much of the “Theology of the Body” is based, appropriate within the Anglican theological tradition?</li>
<li>Is our conception of natural law context-free? Or, are our notions of what is “natural” in some way shaped by our social and cultural context—not to mention our fallenness and the fallenness of our world?</li>
<li>Should our biblical exegesis be constrained by the perspective of the church fathers? Or, is there room for <em>ecclesia semper reformanda</em> (“the church always being reformed”) within Anglican theological method?</li>
<li>Does the apparent work of the Holy Spirit in setting apart and empowering women for priestly ministry today—not just in the West, but in regions all over the world—have something to contribute to the discussion? Certainly, experience alone cannot be normative within the Anglican tradition, but can it be permitted a seat at the theological “table”?</li>
</ul>
<p>I could go on, but I’ll stop here.</p>
<h2 id="the-point-is-this-johnson-nelson-and-i-disagree-on-the-matter-of-womens-ordination-to-the-priesthood-not-because-i-do-not-take-the-authority-of-scripture-seriously-i-most-certainly-do-but-because-we-have-different-answers-to-a-number-of-vitally-important-questions">The point is this: Johnson, Nelson, and I disagree on the matter of women’s ordination to the priesthood, not because I do not take the authority of Scripture seriously (I most certainly do), but because we have different answers to a number of vitally important questions.</h2>
<p>For instance, I do not accept the premise that Nelson’s version of gender essentialism is taught by Scripture, nor do I find the church fathers teaching the same.</p>
<p>As I tell my students, every text has to be interpreted. Whether we’re talking about the tradition or the scriptures, “nature” or the church fathers, all these “texts” must be interpreted. And since the Anglican tradition does not have a Magisterium like the Roman Catholic Church’s, which can declare an issue definitively settled for all time (i.e., <a href="http://w2.vatican.va/content/john-paul-ii/en/apost_letters/1994/documents/hf_jp-ii_apl_19940522_ordinatio-sacerdotalis.html">John Paul II’s apostolic letter, <em>Ordinatio Sacerdotalis</em></a>), Anglicans must engage in the hard work of interpretation ever mindful of the fact that people of goodwill are going to disagree.</p>
<p>Moreover, this list of questions also makes clear that, because of the interplay of so many weighty matters (i.e., biblical exegesis and hermeneutics, historical and systematic theology, liturgical and sacramental theology, biology, sociology, and culture), the question of gender and its implications is probably one of the most complicated and challenging subjects facing the church today. This conversation is going to continue—as it should. And I hope we can continue to do so with humility and charity befitting sisters and brothers in Christ.</p>
<p>In some ways, it would be easier if we still lived in a time when <a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-the-argument-from-tradition-is-not-the-traditional-argument/">women were assumed to be physically, intellectually, emotionally, and spiritually inferior to men. Then, the argument would be moot, as it was for many years of the church’s history</a>. Obviously, inferior persons should not serve as priests in Christ’s church.</p>
<p>But we now know with certainty that women are <em>not</em> inherently inferior to men. Though essentially distinct in important ways—ways we are just beginning to understand—church leaders, biblical scholars, and theologians must consider carefully what these distinctions <em>mean.</em></p>
<p>Despite claims to the contrary, the meaning of gender difference is not, in fact, clear and obvious, and neither is the question of what impact that meaning should have on the structure of Christ’s body, the church.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>(Want to learn more about women’s ordination debates within Anglicanism? <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/">Start with these resources</a>.)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Women Can Be Saved, Then Women Can Be Priests: A Critique of the &#39;in persona Christi&#39; Argument Against Women&#39;s Ordination</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 05:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/if-women-can-be-saved-then-women-can-be-priests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Pastor does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After reading this piece, please see &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/&#34;&gt;Lee Nelson’s response&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicancompass.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/&#34;&gt;Emily McGowin’s rejoinder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-connection-between-christology-and-soteriology&#34;&gt;The connection between christology and soteriology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cornerstone of orthodox Christian theology is summed up in the phrase “what is not assumed is not healed”. The phrase is echoed by many early church fathers, but it is credited to St. Gregory of Nazianzus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Editor’s Note: The piece below represents the opinion of the author. Anglican Pastor does not take a site-wide position for or against women’s ordination. We do, however, require both clarity and charity. We ask that your responses to it do so as well.</em></p>
<p><em>After reading this piece, please see <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/the-problem-with-making-a-patristic-argument-for-the-ordination-of-women-a-response-to-emily-mcgowin/">Lee Nelson’s response</a> and <a href="http://anglicancompass.com/taking-scripture-and-womens-ordination-seriously-a-response-to-blake-johnson-and-lee-nelson/">Emily McGowin’s rejoinder</a>.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-connection-between-christology-and-soteriology">The connection between christology and soteriology</h2>
<p>A cornerstone of orthodox Christian theology is summed up in the phrase “what is not assumed is not healed”. The phrase is echoed by many early church fathers, but it is credited to St. Gregory of Nazianzus.</p>
<p>I teach this principle to undergraduates in my theology classes every semester when we are discussing the development of classical christology (the doctrine of Christ). And my students usually grasp the significance of this principle quite easily.</p>
<p>As the early church fathers sought to make sense of the revelation of God in Jesus Christ, they recognized that if Christ were not fully human—human in every way as we are, yet without sin—then Christ could not redeem humanity.</p>
<p>Thus, Jesus Christ had to have:</p>
<ul>
<li>a real human body,</li>
<li>a real human mind,</li>
<li>real human emotions, and</li>
<li>a real human soul.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the words of St. Gregory of Nazianzus:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“For that which he has not assumed he has not healed; but that which is united to his Godhead is also saved. If only half Adam fell, then that which Christ assumes and saves may be half also; but if the whole of his nature fell, it must be united to the whole nature of him that was begotten, and so be saved as a whole” (Epistle 101, 32).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In this way, christology and soteriology (the doctrine of salvation) are intimately connected. To rescue us from the dominion of Sin, Evil, and Death, the Word, the Second Person of the Trinity, had to become like us.</p>
<p>As the divine Word, he could descend into the darkest depths of human sin and suffering without being overcome by them. And, as the Word-made-flesh, he could ascend to the heights of heaven following his resurrection—and bring us, now reconciled and united with God, along with him.</p>
<h2 id="implications">Implications</h2>
<p>If “what is not assumed is not healed” is a crucial, non-negotiable aspect of orthodox Christianity, then we do well to consider carefully its implications.</p>
<p>For example, if the flesh that the Word assumed in Jesus Christ was ethnically Jewish, does that mean Jesus cannot save Gentiles?</p>
<p>The church has consistently answered: No, of course not. In the logic of “what is not assumed is not healed,” what matters in the incarnation is Jesus’ <em>humanness</em>, not his Jewishness.</p>
<p>(To be clear, Jesus’ Jewishness is crucial to his person and work. Without recognizing that Jesus was a first-century Jew, and all the religious, social, and cultural implications that entails, one cannot fully understand Jesus and what he has done on our behalf. But what I’m exploring here is the logic at work in orthodox reasoning about christology and soteriology.)</p>
<p>Indeed, it is precisely in the particularities of Jesus Christ’s person that he can save all people. The particularity of the incarnation is the pathway to the universality of salvation. “[H]e had to be made like them, fully human in every way, in order that he might become a merciful and faithful high priest in service to God, and that he might make atonement for the sins of the people” and “not only for ours but also for the sins of the whole world” (Heb. 2:17; 1 Jn. 2:2).</p>
<p>As Beth Felker Jones says in her book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Practicing-Christian-Doctrine-Introduction-Theologically/dp/0801049334/ref=as_li_ss_tl?keywords=Practicing+Christian+Doctrine&amp;pd_rd_i=0801049334&amp;pd_rd_r=01c428a0-07cc-4048-8894-9d6ce2c96457&amp;pd_rd_w=P9xKu&amp;pd_rd_wg=KXfEi&amp;pf_rd_p=39e7c2a0-69e1-4a3f-8d8f-4c4ee1aefdb5&amp;pf_rd_r=66AKMKQNSQTGPJWF63JS&amp;psc=1&amp;qid=1569494218&amp;s=gateway&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=anglicanpasto-20&amp;linkId=6d704c46c306131181f6420e60ccefbf&amp;language=en_US"><em>Practicing Christian Doctrine</em></a>, “Jesus does not come among us as a generic human being; he comes as we do, with particulars.” The truth is, there is no such thing as a generic human being. So, in order to be human, the Word had to become a particular human being, with ethnicity, culture, language, sex, gender, and more.</p>
<p>What, then, of Jesus’ maleness? Can a male Christ save women?</p>
<p>Yes, orthodox theologians reply. Yes, of course he can.</p>
<p>Why? Because in assuming the flesh and blood, soul and spirit, of a particular human being, the Word has assumed the flesh and blood, soul and spirit of <em>all</em> human beings—including women.</p>
<p>(It is worth observing that, according to orthodox Christian teaching, the human nature of Jesus Christ was formed in the womb of the Virgin Mary, without the contribution of male “flesh” whatsoever. The Word-made-flesh receives his human flesh from a woman. I am grateful to my colleague, Rev. Dr. Amy Peeler, for bringing this to my attention.)</p>
<p>Again, what matters for salvation is Jesus’ <em>humanness</em>, not Jesus’ maleness.</p>
<h2 id="now-what-does-all-this-have-to-do-with-womens-ordination">Now, what does all this have to do with women’s ordination?</h2>
<p>Quite a lot, actually.</p>
<p>Many arguments are proffered against women’s ordination, some biblical, some theological, some historical, some even biological and psychological. Of course, there is far more to the arguments for and against women’s ordination than this short piece is able to address.</p>
<p>For now, due to space constraints, I choose to focus on one argument against women’s ordination that I find particularly theologically problematic: The assertion that women cannot represent Christ in the celebration of the Eucharist; the claim that women cannot act <em>in persona Christi</em> (“in the person of Christ”).</p>
<p>The argument, in short, goes something like this: Because women have female bodies and Jesus Christ has a male body, women cannot serve as a sacramental sign of Christ in the Eucharist.</p>
<p>To be more specific, women cannot act <em>in persona Christi</em> because their female bodies do not correspond to the body of the male Christ. In this view, female priests are not just <em>not allowed</em>; female priests are <em>false signifiers</em>. In their female persons, female priests lie, as it were, about the male person of Jesus Christ, who is presiding sacramentally at the altar.</p>
<p>And, as a result, women must not represent Christ at the Eucharistic feast.</p>
<p>Today, very often, though not always, this perspective is linked to a form gender essentialism gleaned from Pope John Paul II’s “<a href="http://amzn.to/2lXRIO3">theology of the body</a>” and his recent popularizer, <a href="http://amzn.to/2mV9kdy">Christopher West</a>.</p>
<p>In the theology of the body, male and female are seen as ontologically distinct, two parts of the one whole of the <em>imago Dei.</em> This “natural” gender division then serves as the foundation for structured gender roles.</p>
<p>When it comes to the function of the priesthood, then, the male sacramentally represents Christ while the female sacramentally represents the Church. Within this perspective, to have a woman priest is to usurp and upend a fundamental ontological reality of the world God has made.</p>
<p>But this brings us back to our christological and soteriological principle: “what is not assumed is not healed”. If women qua women are fundamentally incapable—and, according to some Christians, even <em>ontologically</em> incapable—of representing the male Jesus Christ in their female persons, then that calls into question whether their female persons can be redeemed by the male Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>But, of course, we know that isn’t the case.</p>
<p>All human beings—Jew and Greek, male and female, slave and free—are saved through the Incarnation of the Word (the life, death, resurrection and ascension of Jesus Christ).</p>
<p>The particularities of Jesus’ person—a poor, Jewish, male, unmarried, 30-something adult living in first-century, Roman-occupied Israel—are the means by which <em>all</em> human persons are redeemed. And, by becoming one with Christ in our baptism, all become partakers of his Royal Priesthood.</p>
<p>If that’s the case, then all persons are potentially capable of serving as sacramental signs of their Savior.</p>
<h2 id="responding-to-an-objection-arent-redemption-and-sacramental-representation-different">Responding to an objection: Aren’t redemption and sacramental representation different?</h2>
<p>But, some might object: “Jesus, though male, can redeem women. But women can’t sacramentally represent Jesus because redemption and sacramental representation are two different things.”</p>
<p>I would respond: On what basis does the concept of sacramental representation rest?</p>
<p>Many things could be addressed on this front, but I’ll specify only a few.</p>
<h3 id="first-the-idea-of-sacramentality-is-rooted-in-part-in-the-analogy-of-being">First, the idea of sacramentality is rooted, in part, in the analogy of being.</h3>
<p>An analogy does not require a pure one-to-one correspondence—indeed, in Christian theology it specifies the opposite. Between creature and Creator there are similarities, but never such that the dissimilarities are not always greater. Thus, all analogies between God and human beings are inadequate. They are able to speak some real truth, but always fall short in the end.</p>
<p>Similarly, the sacramental representation of the priest will always fall short of pure representation because it is based on analogy.</p>
<h3 id="second-sacramental-representation-means-the-priest-functions-not-as-christ-but-as-an-icon-of-christ">Second, sacramental representation means the priest functions not <em>as Christ</em>, but as an <em>icon</em> of Christ.</h3>
<p>As William Witt has argued, priests are jars of clay, pointing away from him- or herself and pointing to Christ the High Priest, particularly as they share in his suffering (2 Cor. 4:5-10).</p>
<p>What is central is not physical similarity to the male body of Christ, but the priest’s participation in the pattern of Christ, the Suffering Servant. Insofar as the priest demonstrates this participation, the priest serves as a sacramental representation.</p>
<h3 id="finally-if-the-sacramental-validity-of-the-priesthood-is-based-in-significant-part-upon-the-sexed-and-gendered-body-of-the-priest-that-is-a-male-body-to-match-the-male-christ-then-we-find-ourselves-in-a-bit-of-a-bind">Finally, if the sacramental validity of the priesthood is based in significant part upon the sexed and gendered body of the priest (that is, a male body to match the male Christ), then we find ourselves in a bit of a bind.</h3>
<p>As Sarah Coakley (among others) has shown, in the course of the Eucharistic service, the priest not only acts <em>in persona Christi</em>, but also <em>in persona Ecclesiae</em>, which, in the imagery of Eph. 5:22, is gendered female.</p>
<p>If a woman cannot act <em>in persona Christi</em> because her female body does not match the male body of Christ, then how will a man act <em>in persona Ecclesiae</em> when his male body does not match the female Church?</p>
<p>The answer, of course, is that they can; because the priestly body functions sacramentally, or analogically.</p>
<h3 id="no-matter-which-priestly-body-is-the-subject-of-scrutiny-all-bodies-inevitably-fall-short-of-a-pure-one-to-one-correspondence-between-the-sexed-and-gendered-body-of-human-beings-and-the-bride-and-bridegroom-they-are-meant-to-represent">No matter which priestly body is the subject of scrutiny, all bodies inevitably fall short of a pure one-to-one correspondence between the sexed and gendered body of human beings and the Bride and Bridegroom they are meant to represent.</h3>
<p>And that brings us back to the principle of analogy. No human body exactly, literally, univocally corresponds to our Great High Priest, Jesus Christ. But, they do not have to. They need only serve as analogues, which is, in fact, core to what sacrament means in the first place.</p>
<p>Let us return then to Gregory’s great insight, “what is not assumed is not healed,” and put my overall point as plainly as possible:</p>
<h2 id="conclusion-if-christ-in-his-male-body-saves-women-through-their-shared-humanity-then-women-through-their-shared-humanity-with-christ-can-represent-christ-at-the-altar">Conclusion: If Christ in his male body saves women through their shared humanity, then women, through their shared humanity with Christ, can represent Christ at the altar.</h2>
<p>If they cannot—if, in their female bodies, women are incapable of serving as sacramental signs of the male Savior, Jesus Christ—then women’s salvation is in jeopardy, as is the salvation of all who differ from Christ in their embodied particulars.</p>
<p>The good news of “what is not assumed is not healed” is that this jeopardy is decidedly <em>not</em> the case. The Word-made-flesh has made provision in his life, death, resurrection, and ascension for the salvation of all humankind. As Gregory of Nazianzus insisted: “[God] has assumed humanity for our salvation … that by one and the same person, who was perfect man and also God, the entire humanity fallen through sin might be created anew” (Epistle 101, 34).</p>
<p>Do women demonstrate bodily differences from the God-man, Jesus Christ? Yes, of course they do.</p>
<p>But it is by virtue of those very distinctions that women offer a powerful sacramental sign of our Great High Priest and the new creation he has inaugurated in his body. And we who feast at Eucharistic tables presided over by women priests get to see glimpses of this new creation every Sunday.</p>
<h2 id="postscript-further-reading">Postscript: Further Reading</h2>
<p>The argument offered here is inspired, in part, by the following resources. I recommend them to you for further reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>Thomas F. Torrance, <a href="http://amzn.to/2mVXCiM"><em>Royal Priesthood: A Theology of Ordained Ministry</em></a>, 2nd Edition (London: T &amp; T Clark, 2003).</li>
<li>Sarah Coakley, “<a href="http://www.anglicantheologicalreview.org/read/issue/13/">The Woman at the Altar: Cosmological Disturbance or Gender Subversion?</a>” <em>Anglican Theological Review</em>, 86.1 (2004): 75-93.</li>
<li>William G. Witt, “Concerning Women’s Ordination: Women’s Ordination and the Priesthood of Christ”, accessed September 12, 2019: <a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-and-the-priesthood-of-christ/">http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-and-the-priesthood-of-christ/</a>.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/adam_jones/27713547834">Featured image by Adam Jones via Flickr</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/want-to-learn-more-about-womens-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/">Want to learn more about women’s ordination debates within Anglicanism? Check out these resources.</a></p>
<p><a href="http://anglicancompass.com/write-for-anglican-pastor/">Want to write for Anglican Pastor? Check out our writing guidelines.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
