<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Racism on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/racism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Racism on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 06:51:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/racism/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Help! I’m looking for the best Christian resources on the Bible, social justice, racism, Critical Race Theory, and Marxism</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 17:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/help-im-looking-for-the-best-christian-resources-on-the-bible-social-justice-racism-critical-race-theory-and-marxism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Help me out. I’m looking for the best, clearest, and most charitable explanations of the following three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the biblical and theological reasons for caring about social justice and systemic racism,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the unfair ways in which some have used accusations of Critical Race Theory (CRT) and Cultural Marxism to sideline legitimate Christian concerns about social justice and systemic racism, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the legitimate Christian critiques of CRT and Marxism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that there are plenty of resources out there that address each of the three items above!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Help me out. I’m looking for the best, clearest, and most charitable explanations of the following three things:</p>
<ol>
<li>the biblical and theological reasons for caring about social justice and systemic racism,</li>
<li>the unfair ways in which some have used accusations of Critical Race Theory (CRT) and Cultural Marxism to sideline legitimate Christian concerns about social justice and systemic racism, and</li>
<li>the legitimate Christian critiques of CRT and Marxism.</li>
</ol>
<p>Now, I <em>know</em> that there are plenty of resources out there that address each of the three items above!</p>
<p>I’m specifically looking for the resources that are the <em>easiest to understand</em> for someone who has little (or no) biblical, theological, or philosophical training. I’m thinking something that you could easily share with friends and relatives who have legitimate questions.</p>
<p>I’m also specifically looking for resources that address 2 or 3 of the items above, not just 1.</p>
<p>Do such resources already exist?</p>
<p>If not, should we start a Kickstarter to create a “Crash Course”-style YouTube video that addresses all three points above??</p>
<h2 id="my-current-shortlist-of-helpful-resources">My current shortlist of helpful resources</h2>
<p>To provide some grist for the mill, the following resources don’t address all three of my points above, but they <em>are</em> really good and they’re on my current short list of recommended resources for family and friends:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AGUwcs9qJXY">Phil Vischer’s video on “Race in America”</a> (he’s the creator of VeggieTales and the voice of Bob the Tomato)</li>
<li><a href="https://ntwrightpage.com/2020/06/14/undermining-racism-complete-text/">N.T. Wright’s talk on “Undermining Racism”</a> (scroll to the bottom for a video of the talk)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/kelly.hamren.7/posts/10156935647256923">Kelly Hamren’s “Reflections from a Christian scholar on Social Justice, Critical Race Theory, Marxism, and Biblical Ethics”</a> (Facebook essay)</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who really cares about the Trinity in 2020?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 13:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-in-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://friendsofthesavior.org/sermons/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-josh-steele/&#34;&gt;To listen to the audio of this sermon as it was preached on June 6, 2020, click here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians believe that there is one God in three persons—Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, as my daughter Eva put it recently after seeing a picture in her book, “Father, Son, and Bird.” We’re working on that…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We Christians have been taught that the Trinity is important. No one wants to be a heretic. Trinity, good. Modalism, bad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>(<a href="https://friendsofthesavior.org/sermons/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-josh-steele/">To listen to the audio of this sermon as it was preached on June 6, 2020, click here.</a>)</em></p>
<p>Christians believe that there is one God in three persons—Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.</p>
<p>Or, as my daughter Eva put it recently after seeing a picture in her book, “Father, Son, and Bird.” We’re working on that…</p>
<p>We Christians have been taught that the Trinity is important. No one wants to be a heretic. Trinity, good. Modalism, bad.</p>
<p>But, quite frankly, who cares about the Trinity right now in 2020?</p>
<p>What difference does divine mathematics make when the world is on fire? When Black people are dying?</p>
<p>Don’t we Christians have more important things to worry about?</p>
<p>I’m tempted to just sit in silence and then skip to the creed. It sure wouldn’t be the worst Trinity sermon!</p>
<p>But friends, though I readily confess</p>
<ul>
<li>my inadequacy,</li>
<li>my anger, and</li>
<li>the inadequacy of my anger,</li>
</ul>
<p>it falls to me, a young white priest, to preach the gospel on Trinity Saturday 2020.</p>
<p>So, preach I will.</p>
<h2 id="the-trinity-and-the-bible">The Trinity and the Bible</h2>
<p>But please, bear with me! My sermon has changed a lot in recent days.</p>
<p>Originally, the whole thing was going to be about how the Trinity is not an abstract list of thoughts be thunk about God.</p>
<p>Instead, the Trinity is how the Church reads the Bible.</p>
<p>And let me just say a little bit more about that, because I think it’s really important.</p>
<p>The Church developed the doctrine of the Trinity in order to make sense of the Bible as the single story of how the one true God</p>
<ul>
<li>creates the world,</li>
<li>refuses to let it fall into nothingness due to sin,</li>
<li>redeems it through Jesus Christ and</li>
<li>brings it to perfection through the Holy Spirit.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="without-the-doctrine-of-the-trinity">Without the Doctrine of the Trinity…</h2>
<p>Without the doctrine of the Trinity, the Bible falls apart into <em>fragments</em>.</p>
<p>What do we do with YHWH?</p>
<p>With God’s Spirit?</p>
<p>With God’s Son, Jesus Christ?</p>
<p>Are these <em>three</em> different gods?</p>
<p>Is just <em>one</em> of them god?</p>
<p>Are <em>none</em> of them god, but just <em>masks</em> that God wears?</p>
<p>Without the doctrine of the Trinity, at best, we’re either</p>
<ul>
<li>polytheists, who worship more than one god</li>
<li>idolaters, who worship things that God made</li>
<li>or we’re completely unsure of who the true God really is.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="with-the-doctrine-of-the-trinity">With the doctrine of the Trinity…</h2>
<p><em>With</em> the doctrine of the Trinity, however, we can trust that God is who he has revealed himself to be in Scripture and in the life of the Church—Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.</p>
<p>This is God’s <em>proper name</em>.</p>
<p>With the doctrine of the Trinity, we can trust, especially in difficult times, that we worship the same God who called the world into existence and order out of nothing.</p>
<p>We worship the same God</p>
<ul>
<li>who rescued his people from slavery in Egypt.</li>
<li>who brought his people back from exile by going into exile for them at the cross.</li>
<li>who raised Jesus Christ from the grave.</li>
<li>who exalted Jesus to his right hand, where he now sits enthroned over the universe.</li>
<li>who poured out his Holy Spirit at Pentecost, and like <em>that</em>, can break down linguistic, social, and racial barriers.</li>
</ul>
<p>The doctrine of the Trinity reminds us that we worship the same God who, since Pentecost, has equipped and empowered his Church in every generation—through <em>persecutions</em>, <em>plagues</em>, and <em>prejudices</em>— to</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything” that Jesus commanded.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="so-yes-i-think-we-should-care-about-the-doctrine-of-the-trinity-especially-in-2020">So, yes, I think we <em>should</em> care about the doctrine of the Trinity, especially in 2020.</h2>
<p>Because some Christians, especially some white Christians, seem to have forgotten that all human beings are created in the image of the Triune God.</p>
<p>All human beings are therefore worthy of <em>dignity</em>, <em>respect</em>, and <em>self-sacrifice for their well-being</em>.</p>
<p>We’re supposed to extend God’s rule and reign throughout the world as good stewards, instead of exploiting creation and other human beings for our own gain.</p>
<p>We should care about the Trinity in 2020, because some of us seem to have forgotten that the Triune God is always and everywhere in control, so we don’t need to be driven by <em>fear</em>.</p>
<p>Some of us seem to have forgotten that Jesus has “all authority in heaven and on earth,” so we don’t need to curry favor with tyrants or Trumps in order to accomplish our Great Commission.</p>
<p>We Christians should care about the Trinity in 2020 because we are image-bearers of the Triune God, commissioned to make disciples of Jesus Christ in all the diverse people groups of the world.</p>
<h2 id="now-lets-just-take-a-moment-and-ask-ourselves-how-is-that-going">Now, let’s just take a moment and ask ourselves: How is that going?</h2>
<p>Let judgment begin with the household of God!</p>
<p>How much of the chaos around us is due to a failure of the Church to make obedient disciples of Jesus Christ?</p>
<p>After all, Jesus didn’t commission us to make disciples of Fox News, or MSNBC, or even NPR!</p>
<p>Jesus didn’t command us to baptize our greed, our nationalism, or our racism in the unholy water of civil religion.</p>
<p>Jesus didn’t tell us that we only had to obey certain things that he said.</p>
<ul>
<li>He didn’t say it was OK for liberals to ignore his sexual ethic.</li>
<li>And he didn’t say it was OK for conservatives to ignore his social ethic.</li>
</ul>
<p>Instead, speaking with the full authority of the Triune God, Jesus told us to</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, and teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now, obviously, I don’t think the church has ever completely failed to live out her mission, or else there wouldn’t be a church today to preach to!</p>
<p>But, brothers and sisters, as we rightly lament the current state of things, I think we need to ask ourselves if the church has failed to make disciples.</p>
<p>Disciples of Jesus are people who</p>
<ul>
<li>look,</li>
<li>think, and</li>
<li>act like Jesus.</li>
</ul>
<p>Do we look, think, and act like Jesus?</p>
<p>Or do we think that Jesus looks, thinks, and acts like us?</p>
<h2 id="now-let-me-take-a-deep-breath-here-and-say-that-ive-been-preaching-at-a-much-broader-target-in-this-sermon-than-just-church-of-the-savior-in-wheaton-il">Now, let me take a deep breath here and say that I’ve been preaching at a much broader target in this sermon than just Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL!</h2>
<p>I thank God for how he has blessed our church with godly leaders and laypeople who are willing to consider the gospel’s implications for all of life.</p>
<p>I wouldn’t call our local church a nationalist church or a racist church, and I thank God for that.</p>
<h2 id="nevertheless-its-not-enough-to-congratulate-ourselves-that-were-not-as-bad-as-other-churches">Nevertheless, it’s not enough to congratulate ourselves that we’re not as bad as other churches.</h2>
<p>There is always room for growth!</p>
<p>How, then, should we live?</p>
<p>Well, SO MUCH could be said, but here’s what I think we need to focus on.</p>
<h2 id="as-image-bearers-of-the-triune-god-in-2020-we-need-to-ask-ourselves-what-it-would-look-like-to-be-and-make-disciples-of-jesus-who-take-a-stand-for-biblical-justice-against-the-systemic-sin-of-racism">As image-bearers of the Triune God in 2020, we need to ask ourselves what it would look like to be and make disciples of Jesus who take a stand for biblical justice against the systemic sin of racism.</h2>
<p>I don’t have all the answers, but I do have 3 suggestions.</p>
<h3 id="first-we-need-to-read-the-bible">First, we need to read the Bible.</h3>
<p>We need to be so thoroughly familiar with the Bible that we can explain our biblical and theological reasons for taking a stand against the systemic sin of racism.</p>
<p>Let it be known that, as Christians, we are not against racism because we’re trying to impress our liberal friends!</p>
<p>We are against racism because we’ve read our Bibles and recognized that the Triune God is against racism!</p>
<p>At minimum, the doctrine of the Trinity reminds us that God’s oneness has never meant sameness.</p>
<p>When we read the narrative of Scripture, it becomes clear that God is not colorblind, and neither should we be as we make disciples of all the <em>ethne</em>, all the people groups of the world.</p>
<p>We have an opportunity to preach the gospel of Jesus Christ to a world that desperately needs hope! Let’s not waste that opportunity.</p>
<h3 id="second-we-christians-especially-we-white-anglican-christians-need-to-familiarize-ourselves-with-the-history-of-racism-the-united-states-of-america">Second, we Christians, ESPECIALLY we white Anglican Christians, need to familiarize ourselves with the history of racism the United States of America.</h3>
<p>We can’t understand the current state of things if we are ignorant of America’s racist history and white Anglican Christians’ complicity in it.</p>
<p>Frankly, I do not know enough about this myself, so, in addition to reading our Bibles, I invite you to join me in reading books like Jemar Tisby’s <em>The Color of Compromise</em> and Ibram X. Kendi’s <em>Stamped from the Beginning</em>.</p>
<p>We also all need to read Esau McCaulley’s <em>Reading While Black</em> when it comes out in a few months!</p>
<h3 id="third-we-need-to-take-action">Third, we need to take action.</h3>
<p>Reading our Bibles and learning more about the history of racism in America are good starts. But they’re not enough.</p>
<ul>
<li>We need to listen and learn from the example of the Black Church about what it looks like to take a biblical stand against injustice.</li>
<li>We need to develop diverse relationships.</li>
<li>We white Christians need to listen to people of color, without expecting them to solve all of our problems for us.</li>
<li>We need to raise up leaders of color within the church.</li>
<li>We need to give money to leaders of color and the ministries that they lead.</li>
<li>We need to let our bishops know that we want the Anglican Church in North America to look more like the North America we’re called to serve.</li>
<li>We need to speak up and call out racism even when it’s costly to do so and especially when it’s coming from an elected or an ordained leader.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="now-is-anyone-else-feeling-overwhelmed">Now, is anyone else feeling overwhelmed?</h2>
<p>I mean, does our church, does <em>the</em> church, have the strength to fulfill the Great Commission when things have gone so horribly wrong?</p>
<p>No, she doesn’t. And she never has.</p>
<p>But perhaps you’ve noticed that I’ve not yet quoted the last part of the Great Commission.</p>
<p>We need to hear it, though, because it’s the most important part.</p>
<h3 id="jesus-said-and-surely-i-am-with-you-always-to-the-very-end-of-the-age">Jesus said: “And surely I am with you always, to the very end of the age.”</h3>
<p>Without that promise, the Great Commission is an unbearable burden, an impossible command.</p>
<p>But <em>with</em> that promise, the Great Commission is good news, even in 2020.</p>
<p>It might not feel like it some days, but the end of the age has not yet arrived.</p>
<p>Jesus didn’t promise to be with us</p>
<ul>
<li>until COVID-19 forced us to meet online,</li>
<li>until George Floyd and countless others were murdered, or</li>
<li>until the President profaned the Word of God for a photo op.</li>
</ul>
<p>No, Jesus promised to be with us until the END.</p>
<p>Until “God’s dwelling place is now among the people, and he will dwell with them. They will be his people”—his people from every tribe and tongue and nation!—“and God himself will be with them and be their God. ‘He will wipe every tear”—every tear-gassed tear!—from their eyes. There will be no more death’ or mourning or crying or pain, for the old order of things has passed away.”</p>
<p>Friends, this is why we should care about the Trinity!</p>
<p>If Christ is with us, then the Triune God is with us.</p>
<p>And if the Triune God is with us, then we can make disciples and not be afraid, no matter how bad things get!</p>
<p>For no one, nothing, not even the gates of Hell will prevail against Christ’s Church.</p>
<p>Amen. Amen. Amen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Books, Movies, and Podcasts about Race for White Christians like Me</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/top-3-books-movies-and-podcasts-about-race-for-white-christians-like-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/top-3-books-movies-and-podcasts-about-race-for-white-christians-like-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are PLENTY of resource recommendations out there for those interested in learning more about racism and anti-racism (just Google “best X (books, movies, podcasts, etc.) on racism,” “antiracist reading list,” etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I’m worried that, especially for people who are not used to working their way through lengthy reading lists, getting so many recommendations at once will lead to nothing due to the paradox of choice. I’d much rather recommend a single book that someone will actually read than 100 books they won’t!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are PLENTY of resource recommendations out there for those interested in learning more about racism and anti-racism (just Google “best X (books, movies, podcasts, etc.) on racism,” “antiracist reading list,” etc.).</p>
<p>However, I’m worried that, especially for people who are not used to working their way through lengthy reading lists, getting so many recommendations at once will lead to nothing due to the paradox of choice. I’d much rather recommend a single book that someone will actually read than 100 books they won’t!</p>
<p>With that in mind, here is the reading, viewing, and listening shortlist that I am starting with. I’ve been biblically and theologically opposed to racism for awhile now, but I was convicted by the Rev. Canon Dr. Esau McCaulley recently when he said, like a good professor, that “we can tell when you haven’t done the reading.” I’ve done a <em>bit</em> of the reading (mainly <a href="https://amzn.to/2zULBBn"><em>The Christian Imagination: Theology and the Origins of Race</em></a> by Willie James Jennings, <a href="https://amzn.to/3eUpvxz"><em>A Black Theology of Liberation</em></a> by James Cone, and <a href="https://amzn.to/2XyMloK"><em>How to be an Antiracist</em></a> by Ibram X. Kendi), but not nearly enough.</p>
<p>So, if you’re looking for a place to start, I recommend the following as a beginning. Within each category, take a brief look at all 3 and then start with the 1 that interests you the most.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3dFpxck"><em>The Color of Compromise: The Truth about the American Church’s Complicity in Racism</em></a> by Jemar Tisby (Also, if you have Amazon Prime, there’s a <a href="https://amzn.to/2Mu7tpI">free “Color of Compromise” video teaching series by Jemar Tisby</a>)</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2A8Lylg"> <em>White Fragility: Why It’s So Hard for White People to Talk About Racism</em> </a>by Robin DiAngelo</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2XyMloK"><em>How to be an Antiracist</em></a> by Ibram X. Kendi (I’ve listened to this on Audible, but I need to revisit it, along with Kendi’s <a href="https://amzn.to/2UfR3Wh"> <em>Stamped from the Beginning: The Definitive History of Racist Ideas in America</em></a>)</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2ACOTZT">Just Mercy</a> (Amazon)</li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3eRePQj">I Am Not Your Negro</a> (Amazon)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80091741">13th</a> (Netflix)</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="podcasts">Podcasts</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.sceneonradio.org/seeing-white/">Seeing White</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/codeswitch/">Code Switch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.truthstable.com/podcast">Truth’s Table</a></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Fellow ACNA Clergy: On Anti-Racism and a More Diverse and Just Anglicanism</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: As is our policy with &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; Anglican Compass content, we ask that you &lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com/republishing-guidelines/&#34;&gt;please submit a request before republishing content&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://adoc.church/a-letter-concerning-the-death-of-george-floyd-and-so-many-others/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;recently wrote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care. Whether you’re ACNA clergy, a layperson, or a Christian leader outside the ACNA, we invite your consideration of the following and your &lt;a href=&#34;#sign&#34;&gt;signature&lt;/a&gt; in support.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>NOTE</strong>: As is our policy with <em>all</em> Anglican Compass content, we ask that you <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/republishing-guidelines/">please submit a request before republishing content</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who</em> <a href="https://adoc.church/a-letter-concerning-the-death-of-george-floyd-and-so-many-others/"><em>recently wrote</em></a> <em>in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care. Whether you’re ACNA clergy, a layperson, or a Christian leader outside the ACNA, we invite your consideration of the following and your <a href="#sign">signature</a> in support.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="our-context">Our Context</h2>
<p>Our province, The Anglican Church in North America (ACNA), was born as part of a global movement that features diverse leadership and reflects the churches and people of global Anglicanism. It is a manifestation of the universal power and eschatological <em>telos</em> of the Gospel of Jesus: “from every nation, from all tribes and peoples and languages, standing before the throne and before the Lamb” (Rev. 7:9).</p>
<p>Currently, the American population is about 38% non-white. By many projections, over the next 20 years, it will be increasingly composed of ethnic minorities. Our province, however, is far from representative of this emerging reality. The mission on our doorstep is clear: to reach North America, in all of its ethnic diversity, “with the transforming love of Jesus Christ.” We have the opportunity to proclaim the Gospel “to the whole creation” (Mark 16:15) and to be Jesus’ witnesses “to the ends of the earth” (Acts 1:8). We are called to reflect the ethnic diversity of the global movement of which we are a part, as well as the diverse locales in which we are present.</p>
<p>In order to more fully embody our Gospel witness, we must support, encourage, and empower the leadership of brothers and sisters of color in the ACNA to create more hospitable and welcoming spaces for people of color. This includes Black, Latino/a, Native, Asian, and other people groups. We must listen and respond to these voices in our midst and collectively seek to understand and address the historic and ongoing ways in which people of color continue to struggle under various expressions of injustice.</p>
<p>We see and grieve the racism and discrimination that exists and has a deep cultural and structural influence in our society, in our communities, and in our churches. The recent tragedies of Ahmaud Arbery, Breonna Taylor, and George Floyd are simply the latest in a long line of harrowing examples of these deeply embedded systemic realities. We see and grieve that our brothers and sisters of color, including many in our own dioceses and parishes, have been and continue to be profoundly affected by these realities.</p>
<p>Against this backdrop, we offer the following confessions and make the following commitments.</p>
<h2 id="confessions">Confessions</h2>
<p>We confess that we have failed to see, understand, and address the expressions of racism, both personal and systemic, that plague our society, communities, and churches.</p>
<p>We confess our slowness to listen to the dismay and discouragement of our brothers and sisters of color, especially those in our own province, and have neglected to cultivate hospitable spaces for them to flourish.</p>
<p>We confess that our ignorance, complacency, and silence have undermined our fidelity to the Great Commandment to love God and love our neighbor (Matt. 22:36-40), which fundamentally calls us into disciplines of anti-racism.</p>
<h2 id="commitments">Commitments</h2>
<p>We commit to listening to, learning from, and supporting leaders of color in their witness to our province.</p>
<p>We commit to partnering with these friends, and with organizations like</p>
<ul>
<li>the<a href="https://anglicanmultiethnic.org/"> Anglican Multiethnic Network (AMEN)</a>,</li>
<li><a href="https://www.caminemos-juntos.com/">Caminemos Juntos</a>,</li>
<li><a href="http://www.ammic.ca/">Asian &amp; Multicultural Ministries in Canada</a>, and</li>
<li>the<a href="http://etnn.org/"> Every Tribe and Nation Network</a></li>
</ul>
<p>that are working to promote, support, and invest in a more diverse and just Anglicanism.</p>
<p>And, in all of our different capacities and platforms, in our churches and in the world, we commit ourselves to investing in the work of anti-racism—in our catechesis, discipleship, preaching, ministry, advocacy, and reform.</p>
<p><em>(Editor’s note: You should also check out <a href="https://www.anglicanjusticeandmercy.org/home">the work being done by The Matthew 25 Initiative</a>.)</em></p>
<h2 id="the-road-ahead">The Road Ahead</h2>
<p>We are encouraged by the leaders, including the Archbishop, who have spoken out about the recent injustices, and we know that there are places within the province where there is movement toward realizing this vision of a multi-ethnic church, one that is unhindered by racism in all its forms, that can reach the entirety of North America.</p>
<p>However, there is significant work yet to be done. We hope that others will join us in our intentional commitment to partnering with leaders of color and the provincial organizations listed above in order to cultivate a diverse and just Anglicanism in North America.</p>
<p>We are a group of clergy committed to the ACNA and its mission. <a href="#sign">If you would like either to join us in these confessions and commitments or signal your affirmation of such work, we invite you to add your name to this letter.</a></p>
<p>Our ultimate goal, however, is not just signatures, but a collective public commitment towards diversity and justice for the sake of the gospel and our Kingdom witness.</p>
<p><em>Almighty God, you created us in your own image: Grant us grace to contend fearlessly against evil and to make no peace with oppression; and help us to use our freedom rightly in the establishment of justice in our communities and among the nations, to the glory of your holy Name; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and for ever. Amen.</em></p>
<p>Sincerely in Christ,</p>
<h2 id="authors">Authors</h2>
<p>Rev. Ryan Boettcher<br>
<em>Associate Clergy,</em> <a href="https://www.rezaustin.com/"><em>Resurrection Anglican South Austin</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Dr. Shawn McCain<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.rezaustin.com/"><em>Resurrection Anglican South Austin</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Seth Richardson<br>
<a href="https://www.teloscollective.com/"><em>The Telos Collective</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Dr. J.R. Rozko<br>
<em>National Director,</em> <a href="https://www.missioalliance.org/"><em>Missio Alliance</em></a> <em>&amp; Co-Lead Pastor,</em> <a href="http://www.firstchurchcanton.com/"><em>First Church of the Resurrection</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Ben Sternke<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.thetableindy.org/"><em>The Table Indianapolis</em></a> <em>&amp; Co-Founder,</em> <a href="https://gravityleadership.com/"><em>Gravity Leadership</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Matt Tebbe<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.thetableindy.org/"><em>The Table Indianapolis</em> </a><em>&amp; Co-Founder,</em> <a href="https://gravityleadership.com/"><em>Gravity Leadership</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Erik Willits<br>
<em>Host of</em> <a href="https://www.teloscollective.com/podcast/"><em>The Intersection Podcast</em></a> <em>Special Projects,</em> <a href="https://www.c4so.org/"><em>Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</em></a></p>
<h2 id="initial-signatories-click-here-or-scroll-down-to-signsign">Initial Signatories (<a href="#sign">Click Here or Scroll Down to Sign</a>)</h2>
<p>Rev. Canon Dr. Dan Alger<br>
<em>Provincial Canon for Church Planting,</em> <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/index.php/main/Staff_Directory/"><em>Anglican Church in North America</em></a><br>
<em>Director,</em> <a href="https://www.always-forward.com/"><em>Always Forward Church Planting Initiative</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Gary Ball<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="http://www.redeemerasheville.com/"><em>Redeemer Asheville</em></a><em>, NC</em></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Taylor Bodoh<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.incarnationtallahassee.org/"><em>Incarnation, Tallahassee</em></a><br>
<em>Canon for Church Planting,</em> <a href="http://www.gulfatlanticdiocese.org/"><em>Gulf Atlantic Diocese</em></a><br>
<em>Leader in the</em> <a href="https://anglicanmultiethnic.org/"><em>Anglican Multiethnic Network (AMEN)</em></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Seth Cain<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://villageanglican.church/">The Village Anglican, Greenville</a></em><br>
</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Dan Claire<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://rezchurch.org/">The Church of the Resurrection, Washington, D.C.</a></em></span></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Greg Goebel<br>
<em>Editor-in-chief,</em> <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/"><em>Anglican Compass</em></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. David Martin Hanke<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://restorationarlington.org/">Restoration Anglican, Arlington</a></em><br>
</span></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Alan Hawkins<br>
<em>Chief Operating Officer,</em> <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/index.php/main/Staff_Directory/"><em>Anglican Church in North America</em></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Thomas Hinson<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://adventdc.org/">Advent Anglican, Washington, D.C.</a></em></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Hannah King<br>
<em>Associate Rector, <a href="https://villageanglican.church/">The Village Anglican, Greenville</a></em></span></p>
<p>Rev. Michael King<br>
<em>Associate Rector, <a href="https://villageanglican.church/">The Village Anglican, Greenville</a></em></p>
<p>Very Rev. Canon Dr. Kris McDaniel<br>
<em>Senior Pastor,</em> <a href="https://atltrinity.org/"><em>Trinity Anglican, Atlanta</em></a> <em>Canon for Church Development (Planting and Adoptions),</em> <a href="https://www.c4so.org/our-team/"><em>Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Dr. Emily McGowin<br>
<em>Associate Lecturer of Theology,</em> <a href="https://www.wheaton.edu/academics/faculty/emily-mcgowin/"><em>Wheaton College</em></a><br>
<em>Canon,</em> <a href="https://www.c4so.org/our-team/"><em>The Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Ron McGowin<br>
<em>Interim Rector,</em> <a href="http://www.holycross-anglican.org/"><em>Holy Cross Anglican Church, Lake Villa, IL</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Lee Nelson<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.christchurchwaco.org/"><em>Christ Church, Waco</em></a></p>
<p>Very Rev. Rob Patterson<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://redeemeranglican.com/">Redeemer Anglican, Santa Cruz</a> Regional Dean, Northern California, <a href="https://www.c4so.org/">Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</a></em></p>
<p>Rev. Marty Reardon<br>
<em>Westside Worship Pastor,</em> <a href="https://westside.atltrinity.org/"><em>Trinity Anglican, Atlanta</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Erik Rogers<br>
<em>Assisting Clergy, <a href="https://www.rezaustin.com/">Resurrection Anglican South Austin</a></em></p>
<p>Rev. Canon David Roseberry<br>
<em>Publisher,</em> <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/"><em>Anglican Compass</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Joshua Steele<br>
<em>Managing Editor,</em> <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/"><em>Anglican Compass</em></a></p>
<p>Very Rev. Cliff Warner<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://christchurchofaustin.org/"><em>Christ Church, Austin</em></a></p>
<p>Christine Warner<br>
<em>Director,</em><a href="https://www.anglicanjusticeandmercy.org/"> <em>Matthew 25 Initiative</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Tish Harrison Warren<br>
<em>Author,</em> <a href="https://amzn.to/2TTk7CT"><em>Liturgy of the Ordinary</em></a><br>
<em>Writer-in-Residence,</em> <a href="https://www.ascensionpittsburgh.org/our-leadership/"><em>Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Dr. Jonathan Warren Pagán<br>
<em>Associate Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.ascensionpittsburgh.org/our-leadership/"><em>Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Janna Ziegler<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://resurrectionla.org/"><em>Church of the Resurrection, Los Angeles</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Jon Ziegler<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://resurrectionla.org/"><em>Church of the Resurrection, Los Angeles</em></a></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="sign-the-letter">Sign the Letter</h2>
<p><em>If you’re ACNA clergy, please use the first form. We’d also love for laypeople and Christian leaders outside of the ACNA to indicate their support. If you’re <strong>not ACNA clergy</strong>, please use the <strong>second</strong> form (scroll down).</em></p>
<p><em>(<strong>NOTE</strong>: Don’t worry if you don’t see your name appear below right away. There might be a bit of a lag. No need to submit twice.)</em></p>
<p>[emailpetition id=”2″]</p>
<h3 id="all-other-supporters">All Other Supporters</h3>
<p>[emailpetition id=”3″]</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="signatures">Signatures</h2>
<h3 id="acna-clergy">ACNA Clergy</h3>
<div class="wp-block-file">[ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter\_2022-08-15](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter_2022-08-15.csv)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter_2022-08-15.csv)</div>\[signaturelist id=”2″\]
<h3 id="all-other-supporters-1">All Other Supporters</h3>
<div class="wp-block-file">[Not-ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter-Here\_2022-08-15](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Not-ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter-Here_2022-08-15.csv)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Not-ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter-Here_2022-08-15.csv)</div>\[signaturelist id=”3″\]]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
