<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 06:51:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/technology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Online Scams: A Simple Guide for Non-Tech-Savvy Internet Users</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 21:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/avoiding-online-scams-a-simple-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-internet-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online scams can touch anyone’s life. They don’t discriminate based on how tech-savvy you are or how often you use the internet. We’ve all heard stories—maybe from a friend, a family member, or even in the news—of someone getting tricked online, often with distressing consequences. It serves as a stark reminder of the darker side of our digital world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why it’s crucial for every one of us to understand online scams—how they operate, how to identify them, and most importantly, how to avoid becoming a victim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Online scams can touch anyone’s life. They don’t discriminate based on how tech-savvy you are or how often you use the internet. We’ve all heard stories—maybe from a friend, a family member, or even in the news—of someone getting tricked online, often with distressing consequences. It serves as a stark reminder of the darker side of our digital world.</p>
<p>This is why it’s crucial for every one of us to understand online scams—how they operate, how to identify them, and most importantly, how to avoid becoming a victim.</p>
<p>In this guide, I’ll demystify the most common types of online scams and equip you with practical knowledge to stay safe. Regardless of whether you’re a digital native or just someone who occasionally checks emails or shops online, this guide will offer valuable insights to help protect you and your loved ones.</p>
<p>Let’s begin this important journey to digital safety.</p>
<h2 id="understanding-online-scams">Understanding Online Scams</h2>
<p>In the broadest sense, an online scam is a fraudulent scheme performed by a dishonest individual, group, or company in an attempt to obtain money or something else of value from unsuspecting internet users. They can happen virtually anywhere online, from your email inbox to social media platforms, online marketplaces, and even dating sites.</p>
<p>Here are a few common types of online scams that you might encounter:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Phishing Scams:</strong> Perhaps the most common type of online scam, phishing occurs when a scammer attempts to trick you into giving out your personal information. They might send you an email that appears to be from a legitimate company asking you to login to your account, and when you do, they capture your username and password.</li>
<li><strong>Lottery Scams:</strong> These scams operate by telling you that you’ve won a huge amount of money in a lottery or sweepstakes that you never even entered. To receive your “winnings,” however, you’ll be asked to pay a fee or provide your banking information.</li>
<li><strong>Tech Support Scams:</strong> Scammers posing as tech support personnel from a well-known company claim to have detected issues with your computer. They’ll attempt to gain remote access to your machine, potentially stealing data or installing harmful software.</li>
</ol>
<p>These are just a few examples (for more examples and advice, <a href="https://usa.kaspersky.com/resource-center/threats/top-scams-how-to-avoid-becoming-a-victim">checkout this piece from Kaspersky</a>). Scams can come in many forms, and scammers are always evolving their tactics. However, understanding these common types of scams is the first step toward protecting yourself.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-identify-online-scams">How to Identify Online Scams</h2>
<p>While online scams can take various forms and evolve over time, there are certain red flags you can look out for to help you identify potential scams:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Unsolicited Contact:</strong> Be wary if you receive unexpected emails, messages, or calls from people or organizations you don’t know, especially if they’re asking for personal or financial information.</li>
<li><strong>Too Good To Be True:</strong> If an offer seems too good to be true—like a huge lottery win from a contest you never entered—it probably is. Scammers often lure their victims with promises of large financial gains.</li>
<li><strong>Pressure Tactics:</strong> Many scammers try to create a sense of urgency to pressure you into making quick decisions without giving you time to think or verify the information.</li>
<li><strong>Requests for Sensitive Information:</strong> Legitimate companies will rarely, if ever, ask for your personal or financial information through email or text message.</li>
<li><strong>Grammar and Spelling Mistakes:</strong> While not always the case, many scam messages contain poor grammar and spelling. This can be a telltale sign of a scam, as legitimate companies typically proofread their communications carefully.</li>
</ol>
<p>Here’s an example: Imagine you receive an email that looks like it’s from your bank. The email states there’s been suspicious activity on your account and you need to confirm your details immediately or your account will be closed.</p>
<p>But there’s something off about the email—the bank’s logo looks a bit blurry, there are a couple of typos, and they’ve addressed you as ‘Valued Customer’ instead of your name. All of these signs point to a potential phishing scam.</p>
<p>By recognizing these signs, you can better protect yourself from falling victim to online scams.</p>
<p>(Learn more about <a href="https://www.mcafee.com/learn/how-to-recognize-an-online-scammer/">how to recognize an online scammer here from McAfee</a>.)</p>
<h2 id="how-to-protect-yourself-from-online-scams">How to Protect Yourself from Online Scams</h2>
<p>Knowing how to identify potential scams is only part of the solution. Here are some practical steps to protect yourself from becoming a victim:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Secure Your Devices:</strong> Ensure that all your devices are protected with the latest security software, web browsers, and operating systems. Regular updates can help protect against the latest threats.</li>
<li><strong>Be Cautious with Links and Attachments:</strong> Do not click on links or download attachments from unknown sources. They could lead to malicious websites or install malware on your device.</li>
<li><strong>Use Strong, Unique Passwords:</strong> Use complex passwords and change them regularly. Consider using a password manager to help keep track of your passwords. (I LOVE, use, and <a href="https://1password.com/">highly recommend 1Password. Check them out!</a>)</li>
<li><strong>Enable Two-Factor Authentication:</strong> Where possible, enable two-factor authentication for your online accounts. This adds an extra layer of security by requiring a second form of identification beyond just your password.</li>
<li><strong>Verify Before Sharing:</strong> Don’t share personal or financial information unless you’ve verified the person or organization requesting it. If you receive an unexpected request, contact the company directly using a phone number or website you know is legitimate.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Informed:</strong> Scams evolve constantly. Staying informed about the latest scam tactics can help you stay one step ahead.</li>
</ol>
<p>Remember, online safety is a continuous process. By adopting these practices, you can browse the internet more confidently and securely.</p>
<p>(Want more advice on how to protect yourself? Read <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-au/topic/protect-yourself-from-online-scams-and-attacks-0109ae3f-fe61-4262-8dce-2ee3cd43bac7">this piece from Microsoft</a>.)</p>
<h2 id="what-to-do-if-youre-a-victim-of-an-online-scam">What to Do if You’re a Victim of an Online Scam</h2>
<p>If you suspect you’ve become a victim of an online scam, it’s essential to take action promptly to minimize potential damage. Here’s what you should do:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Report the Scam:</strong> Depending on the nature of the scam, you can report it to your local law enforcement agency, your bank (if money was taken from your account), or an appropriate online platform. In the US, you can also report scams to the Federal Trade Commission through their website.</li>
<li><strong>Secure Your Accounts:</strong> If the scam involved any of your online accounts, change your passwords immediately. If you used the same password on any other accounts, change those as well.</li>
<li><strong>Monitor Your Accounts:</strong> Keep an eye on your bank accounts, credit cards, and other financial accounts for any suspicious activity.</li>
<li><strong>Contact a Credit Reporting Agency:</strong> If the scam involved your personal identity or financial information, contact one of the credit reporting agencies to place a fraud alert on your name.</li>
<li><strong>Seek Support:</strong> It can be distressing to be a victim of an online scam. Reach out to your friends, family, or professional counselors to help manage any stress or anxiety.</li>
</ol>
<p>Being a victim of an online scam can feel overwhelming, but by taking these steps, you can work to mitigate the effects and prevent future scams.</p>
<p>(The Federal Trade Commission has some good advice about <a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/articles/what-do-if-you-were-scammed">what to do if you were scammed</a>.)</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>In the digital age, online scams are an unfortunate reality that we must all be prepared to face. Yet, with understanding and vigilance, you can significantly reduce your risk of becoming a victim.</p>
<ul>
<li>Remember to stay skeptical of unsolicited contact, especially if it promises vast rewards or pressures you into fast action.</li>
<li>Take the time to verify information before acting on it.</li>
<li>Maintain strong, unique passwords and use two-factor authentication wherever possible.</li>
<li>Protect your devices with updated security software, and be cautious when clicking on links or downloading attachments.</li>
</ul>
<p>Being scammed can feel violating and disheartening. It’s important to remember that if you are scammed, it’s not your fault. The individuals perpetrating these scams are the ones to blame. If you’ve been scammed, don’t hesitate to report it and take steps to protect yourself from further harm.</p>
<p>By spreading awareness and sharing information about online scams, we can all contribute to making the internet a safer place. Feel free to share this post with anyone who might benefit from it. Stay safe out there!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask Me Anything: Software Engineering Questions from a Coding Bootcamp Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 14:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/ask-me-anything-software-engineering-questions-from-a-coding-bootcamp-student/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m posting my answers to these software engineering questions here, just in case anyone else finds them helpful! (Also, it gives me another link to share when I get asked these kinds of questions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-you-become-interested-in-software-engineering&#34;&gt;How did you become interested in software engineering?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a bit about &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/&#34;&gt;my coding bootcamp journey&lt;/a&gt; in a previous post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my interest in software engineering is/was related to the particular path my journey took. That is, while studying Bible/religion/theology, I always knew that “bi-vocational ministry” (ministering in a church setting while also making money from another profession) was on the table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m posting my answers to these software engineering questions here, just in case anyone else finds them helpful! (Also, it gives me another link to share when I get asked these kinds of questions.)</p>
<h2 id="how-did-you-become-interested-in-software-engineering">How did you become interested in software engineering?</h2>
<p>I wrote a bit about <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/my-coding-bootcamp-journey-how-a-pastor-became-a-programmer/">my coding bootcamp journey</a> in a previous post.</p>
<p>Part of my interest in software engineering is/was related to the particular path my journey took. That is, while studying Bible/religion/theology, I always knew that “bi-vocational ministry” (ministering in a church setting while also making money from another profession) was on the table.</p>
<p>Whenever I thought about “careers that might be a good fit for bi-vocational ministry,” software engineering, web development, etc. were on the short-list. You don’t need a specific degree. You can make good money. You can work remotely. It’s not an especially emotionally draining profession (like, say, counseling, therapy, or chaplaincy). The list goes on.</p>
<p>As it turns out, I’m now “just” a full-time software engineer. I’m not having to balance things with working in a church setting. But it’s nice to know that I could have that flexibility in the future, if I wanted to.</p>
<p>And, in addition to all the ministry-related reasons that software engineering was on my radar screen, I really love <strong>learning things and solving problems</strong>. And that’s what I get to do each day as a software engineer!</p>
<p>I was born in 1991, so computers and the internet have always been a part of my life. I was always curious about how digital tools worked behind the scenes. After years of dabbling and tinkering in the shallow end of the internet, as it were, I was eager to take the plunge into the deep end of computer programming.</p>
<h2 id="what-does-a-typical-work-dayweek-look-like-for-you">What does a typical work day/week look like for you?</h2>
<p>Most days, I work from home. My company has an office here in Pittsburgh, but I’m not required to go in.</p>
<p>I’m expected to be available/contactable (via Microsoft Teams) from 8am-5pm Eastern. And there are various meetings I have to attend each day/week:</p>
<ul>
<li>daily squad standup at 10am,</li>
<li>weekly 1:1 with manager,</li>
<li>weekly “town hall” meeting,</li>
<li>weekly “tech sync-up” chat with other devs on my squad,</li>
<li>bi-weekly sprint planning and retrospective meetings, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>Outside of the meetings and general availability, however, I’m pretty free to get my work done when/as I wish.</p>
<p>Now, I usually get all my work done between 8am and 5pm anyway! But if I have to step out for a bit for a doctor’s appointment, to drop-off/pick-up kids, to run a few errands, etc., I can always put in the time needed to get my work done outside of business hours.</p>
<h2 id="what-do-you-like-mostleast-about-your-work-specifically-or-this-career-in-general">What do you like most/least about your work specifically or this career in general?</h2>
<p>I LOVE how my work requires me to continuously learn things and solve problems.</p>
<p>Sure, my work isn’t as “tangible” as, say, building a house. But, especially when compared with my previous work/studies in religion and theology, building software feels a lot more concrete!</p>
<p>Fixing a bug, getting tests to pass, building a feature and seeing it work for customers…all of these things are very satisfying to me.</p>
<p>However, the main downside is related: software engineering can feel very overwhelming because you’ll never know everything–or even almost everything–about the field. In addition to acquiring basic knowledge of programming, one of the main skills I’ve had to learn is <strong>how to keep making progress even when the task at hand feels confusing and overwhelming</strong>.</p>
<p>It’s taken some getting used to, going from being one of the well-informed “experts” when it comes to church, Bible, theology, etc., to being a complete n00b at software engineering!</p>
<p>But, even though the feeling of “I have no idea how to do that” is the main source of stress in my work these days, re-framing it as “I get to learn something new” is what keeps the work exciting!</p>
<h2 id="in-your-opinion-what-skillsabilitiespersonal-attributes-are-essential-to-success-in-this-field">In your opinion, what skills/abilities/personal attributes are essential to success in this field?</h2>
<p>You’ve got to be curious. A lifelong learner. Which, importantly, doesn’t just mean “I enjoy <em>knowing</em> a lot of things,” but also “I’m comfortable with the uncomfortable parts of learning something new.”</p>
<p>Are you OK with realizing that you don’t know something? Or does that totally paralyze you?</p>
<p>When you realize that you don’t know something, is your first instinct to go learn more about it and figure things out? Or do you tend to avoid that area of uncertainty?</p>
<p>Furthermore, what about when you don’t know what you don’t know? How do you respond?</p>
<h2 id="can-you-tell-me-about-the-hiring-process-you-went-through-either-for-your-current-job-or-others-you-have-applied-for">Can you tell me about the hiring process you went through? Either for your current job or others you have applied for.</h2>
<p>One of the reasons I chose my coding bootcamp, Tech Elevator, was that they included a pretty robust job-search component to the bootcamp. As a part of this, they set us up with a handful (I think I had 5) of brief (15-minute) “matchmaking” interviews.</p>
<p>Tech Elevator develops relationships with tech companies, usually with a focus on companies that have a footprint nearby one of Tech Elevator’s campuses.</p>
<p>So, in my case, one of the matchmaking interviews I was assigned was with Proofpoint.</p>
<p>To be honest, I hadn’t heard of Proofpoint before the bootcamp. And, once I discovered that it’s a large cybersecurity company, I was SUPER intimated. In fact, I straight-up told that to the two developers who did my first interview: “Look, Proofpoint sounds amazing, but I don’t know if I’m cut out to work for a cybersecurity company with just a 14-week bootcamp under my belt!”</p>
<p>Those devs reassured me that, even though Proofpoint’s a cybersecurity company, that I was not applying for a cybersecurity expert role, but for a junior developer role. That calmed my nerves a bit!</p>
<p>After my matchmaking interview, which went quite well (and, unlike my other matchmaking interviews, was quite technically focused…getting a sense of what I had and had not learned at the bootcamp), I made it to a 3-part second interview. 3 back-to-back interviews (Zoom calls, in my case) with 3 different groups of 2 Proofpoint interviewers each. I spoke with a technical product manager, a QA manager, two mid-level devs, and two senior-level devs.</p>
<p>Only the 3rd sub-interview was the dreaded “technical interview.” A mid-level and a senior dev asked me to whiteboard maybe 2 different problems. (As they taught me in the bootcamp, I went into as much detail as possible while solving the technical problem(s), so we didn’t cover all that many different topics.)</p>
<p>The devs were quick to reassure me that I was not being judged on coding syntax, but rather on problem-solving approach. I could either code in the language I was most comfortable with or write pseudocode.</p>
<p>I was quick to say that, in the real world, I would approach a problem by googling to see if a ready-made solution (in this case, for string manipulation) existed. I even mentioned the library/tool that I thought could do what I was being asked to do.</p>
<p>And, looking back on the experience, that’s completely true. The coding problem(s) I was asked to do in the technical interview was NOTHING LIKE what I do each day as a software dev. I would never ever spend so much time trying to put together a string manipulation solution from scratch unless I had already exhausted other options.</p>
<p>But, hey, there are only so many different ways you can test someone’s problem-solving skills. At least my interviewers clearly understood (and told me) that this was obviously a very artificial situation.</p>
<p>Anyway, it didn’t go <em>perfectly</em> (at least not in my opinion), but I was able to come up with a workable solution to the problem and, more importantly, thoroughly talk through my thinking as I went. I felt very well-prepared by the bootcamp for my interviews.</p>
<p>BUT, I will say that, outside of my other matchmaking interviews, it was quite difficult to get my foot in the door for an interview for other positions. There were plenty of jobs I applied for that I either never heard back from or received a pretty quick rejection.</p>
<p>This makes sense to me because, without any industry experience or a Computer Science degree on my resume, why would the average tech company give me a second look? For all I knew, my resume was getting filtered out by an algorithm before a human even looked at it!</p>
<p>Again, that’s one of the reasons why I chose Tech Elevator, and it paid off. They developed a relationship with companies to get students initial interviews. And they trained us, as people who were pivoting into tech from a variety of other backgrounds, how to pitch ourselves and compellingly describe what we brought to the table.</p>
<h2 id="what-steps-would-you-recommend-i-take-to-prepare-to-enter-the-field">What steps would you recommend I take to prepare to enter the field?</h2>
<p><a href="https://austinkleon.com/keepgoing/">Keep going</a>. <a href="https://austinkleon.com/show-your-work/">Show your work</a>. <a href="https://austinkleon.com/steal/">Steal like an artist</a> (programmer).</p>
<p>Read those books above. Read <a href="https://nostarch.com/missing-readme">The Missing README</a>. Read the books recommended in The Missing README. Keep reading! (Need to learn how to read better? Read <a href="https://amzn.to/3T0K28W">How to Read a Book</a>. Seriously. It’s golden.)</p>
<p>Keep making friends and making things until someone notices you and you get a job! Then, keep making friends and making things!</p>
<p>Learn <a href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/smart-questions.html">how to ask questions the smart way</a>.</p>
<p>Keep learning. Your “to-learn” list should never ever be empty.</p>
<p>Don’t know what to learn next? Let your immediate problems be your guide. If you’ve got a job, learn what you need to learn to close your next ticket. If you don’t have a job (yet), learn what you need to learn to better align with job descriptions.</p>
<p>Need a bigger-picture overview of things to learn and be familiar with? I LOVE the <a href="https://roadmap.sh/">“Developer Roadmaps” over at roadmaps.sh</a>.</p>
<p>Need to get your sh*t together, life-wise? Check out these books below. Start with whichever book piques your interest the most!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3kXIK21">The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3ZVE63w">First Things First</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3ZAavga">How to Win Friends and Influence People</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3JrUOC7">The Happiness Trap</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3ZUsFJi">Getting Things Done</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3ZxFUzD">The Practicing Stoic</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3kYhikz">Atomic Habits</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3LaFpHn">The Personal MBA</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/3ZBcGzU">Super Thinking</a></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>I hope that helps! Do you have more questions for me? Let me know in the comments! Or use the <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/contact/">contact form on my website</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
