<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>bible on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tag/bible/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bible on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 17:46:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tag/bible/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Barth, the Bible, and &#34;What we ought to do&#34;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-the-bible-and-what-we-ought-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 17:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-the-bible-and-what-we-ought-to-do/</guid>
      <description>Came across this Barth quote in Church Dogmatics II/2 this morning. I really like it, because it&amp;rsquo;s a good reminder that Barth valued the Bible. His distinction between the Bible as witness to the Word of God and Jesus Christ as the Word of God did not cause him to abandon the Scriptural witness.
It is as well to remind ourselves, at the conclusion of this analysis, that the question: What ought we to do?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A List of Karl Barth&#39;s Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</guid>
      <description>To make this list, I&amp;rsquo;ve used the data available in the Digital Karl Barth Library. I&amp;rsquo;ve just taken the tables of contents in the sermon volumes of Barth&amp;rsquo;s collected works and put them all in one place.
The only way to display the dates correctly in Markdown is to write these up as code blocks, as I&amp;rsquo;ve done below.
Predigten 1913 (GA I.8) 1. und 5. Januar (Neujahr): Prediger 1,9 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the relationship between biblical and systematic/dogmatic theology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 15:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</guid>
      <description>This is the question we&amp;rsquo;re considering this week in our doctoral seminar on biblical and theological integration. Two of us are theologians and the other four are bible scholars. Should be interesting!
(Note: we&amp;rsquo;ll have to save the difference(s) between systematic, historical, and dogmatic theology for another post!)
Here are the articles we were assigned to read for this week:
D.A. Carson, “Systematic Theology and Biblical Theology” in the New Dictionary of Biblical Theology, pp.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s the Elevator Pitch for my Dissertation Proposal: &#34;Scriptural, but Not Religious&#34;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 21:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, I defend the proposal for my dissertation. For now, the dissertation is tentatively titled: &amp;ldquo;Scriptural, but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion.&amp;rdquo;
Here&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;elevator pitch&amp;rdquo; for the dissertation. Feedback appreciated.
Scriptural, but Not Religious: Barth, Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion My project traces its origins to a single classroom discussion question in the Spring of 2015. The question was this: &amp;ldquo;In what ways is Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s understanding of religion similar to, and different from, that of Barth?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Questions to Ask When You Study the Bible (Plus a Worksheet!)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 15:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/</guid>
      <description>The Problem: Studying the Bible can Quickly Feel Overwhelming Right? Even with helpful books out there like How to Read the Bible for All Its Worth(that&amp;rsquo;s an affiliate link, by the way, meaning that I get a small commission at no cost to you if you end up buying the book), there are still so many potential questions to ask of any biblical text when we study it.
How are we supposed to keep questions of authorship, genre, meaning, application, etc.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
