<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity and Time Management on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/productivity-and-time-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity and Time Management on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:41:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/productivity-and-time-management/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Know Thyself: Unveiling Your Unique Strengths and Personality Traits</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/know-thyself-unveiling-your-unique-strengths-and-personality-traits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/know-thyself-unveiling-your-unique-strengths-and-personality-traits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the quest for personal and professional growth, understanding our unique strengths and personality traits can be incredibly enlightening. Today, I want to share my insights from various personality paradigms and how they shape my approach to work and life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cliftonstrengths-harnessing-core-talents&#34;&gt;CliftonStrengths: Harnessing Core Talents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CliftonStrengths assessment has been instrumental in identifying my core talents. Here are my top five strengths:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Input&lt;/strong&gt;: I have an insatiable curiosity and a constant desire to collect information. This strength fuels my drive to learn and gather knowledge from diverse sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intellection&lt;/strong&gt;: My love for deep thinking and intellectual discussions is a hallmark of this strength. It allows me to explore complex ideas and engage in thoughtful analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learner&lt;/strong&gt;: The process of learning excites me. Whether it’s acquiring new skills or understanding new concepts, I thrive in environments that offer continuous growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ideation&lt;/strong&gt;: Creativity and innovation are my playgrounds. I enjoy brainstorming and generating new ideas, which often leads to novel solutions and approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytical&lt;/strong&gt;: I have a keen ability to dissect problems and examine them from different angles. This strength helps me make informed decisions based on solid data and evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on CliftonStrengths, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gallup.com/cliftonstrengths/en/home.aspx&#34;&gt;Gallup’s CliftonStrengths&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the quest for personal and professional growth, understanding our unique strengths and personality traits can be incredibly enlightening. Today, I want to share my insights from various personality paradigms and how they shape my approach to work and life.</p>
<h2 id="cliftonstrengths-harnessing-core-talents">CliftonStrengths: Harnessing Core Talents</h2>
<p>The CliftonStrengths assessment has been instrumental in identifying my core talents. Here are my top five strengths:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Input</strong>: I have an insatiable curiosity and a constant desire to collect information. This strength fuels my drive to learn and gather knowledge from diverse sources.</li>
<li><strong>Intellection</strong>: My love for deep thinking and intellectual discussions is a hallmark of this strength. It allows me to explore complex ideas and engage in thoughtful analysis.</li>
<li><strong>Learner</strong>: The process of learning excites me. Whether it’s acquiring new skills or understanding new concepts, I thrive in environments that offer continuous growth.</li>
<li><strong>Ideation</strong>: Creativity and innovation are my playgrounds. I enjoy brainstorming and generating new ideas, which often leads to novel solutions and approaches.</li>
<li><strong>Analytical</strong>: I have a keen ability to dissect problems and examine them from different angles. This strength helps me make informed decisions based on solid data and evidence.</li>
</ol>
<p>For more on CliftonStrengths, check out <a href="https://www.gallup.com/cliftonstrengths/en/home.aspx">Gallup’s CliftonStrengths</a>.</p>
<h2 id="disc-the-analyst">DISC: The Analyst</h2>
<p>In the DISC personality framework, I fall under the ‘C’ category, which stands for Conscientiousness. As an Analyst, I am detail-oriented, systematic, and value accuracy and precision. This aligns well with my Analytical strength from CliftonStrengths, as both emphasize a methodical approach to problem-solving.</p>
<p>Learn more about the DISC personality types at <a href="https://www.discprofile.com/what-is-disc">DISC Personality Testing</a>.</p>
<h2 id="mbti-the-intj-architect">MBTI: The INTJ Architect</h2>
<p>The Myers-Briggs Type Indicator (MBTI) describes me as an INTJ, also known as the Architect or Strategist. This personality type is characterized by a strong sense of independence, strategic thinking, and an ability to see the big picture while planning meticulously. INTJs are known for their rationality and logic, which complements my Analytical and Intellection strengths.</p>
<p>Dive deeper into the INTJ personality at <a href="https://www.16personalities.com/intj-personality">16 Personalities</a>.</p>
<h2 id="enneagram-the-idealist">Enneagram: The Idealist</h2>
<p>According to the Enneagram of Personality, I am a Type 1, the Idealist. This type is driven by a desire for integrity and a strong sense of purpose. Idealists strive for excellence and often advocate for change to improve systems and processes. This aligns with my Ideation and Learner strengths, as I constantly seek to innovate and improve.</p>
<p>Explore the Enneagram types at <a href="https://www.enneagraminstitute.com/">The Enneagram Institute</a>.</p>
<h2 id="integrating-strengths-and-personality">Integrating Strengths and Personality</h2>
<p>Understanding these paradigms helps me navigate my personal and professional life more effectively. Here’s how I integrate these insights:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Professional Growth</strong>: By leveraging my strengths, I can focus on roles and projects that align with my talents. For instance, my Analytical and Intellection strengths are invaluable in complex problem-solving scenarios.</li>
<li><strong>Collaboration</strong>: Understanding my DISC and MBTI types allows me to communicate and collaborate more effectively with others, appreciating diverse perspectives and working styles.</li>
<li><strong>Continuous Learning</strong>: My Learner and Input strengths drive my passion for lifelong learning, ensuring that I stay updated and adaptable in a constantly evolving field.</li>
<li><strong>Innovation</strong>: With Ideation as a core strength, I can contribute creative solutions and foster an environment of innovation within my team.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="helpful-questions-to-discover-your-personality-strengths">Helpful Questions to Discover Your Personality Strengths</h2>
<ol>
<li>What activities make me feel most energized and engaged?</li>
<li>How do I approach problem-solving in both personal and professional contexts?</li>
<li>What types of tasks do I naturally excel at and enjoy?</li>
<li>How do I prefer to receive and process information?</li>
<li>What are my key motivators and values in my work and personal life?</li>
<li>How do I handle challenges and setbacks?</li>
<li>What feedback have I received from others about my strengths and areas for improvement?</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Embracing our strengths and understanding our personality traits is a powerful tool for personal and professional development. By recognizing and nurturing these aspects, we can unlock our full potential and achieve greater success and fulfillment.</p>
<p>For those interested in embarking on their own journey of self-discovery, I highly recommend exploring these personality assessments and reflecting on how their insights can enhance your life and career.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="references">References</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.gallup.com/cliftonstrengths/en/home.aspx">Gallup’s CliftonStrengths</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.discprofile.com/what-is-disc">DISC Personality Testing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.16personalities.com/intj-personality">16 Personalities</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.enneagraminstitute.com/">The Enneagram Institute</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Feel free to share your own experiences and insights in the comments below!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Lessons: 32 Things I&#39;ve Learned So Far</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/life-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/life-lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are 32 things I’ve learned from life, so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are not your thoughts. There is a “you” behind and above your inner voice/monologue/dialogue. Pay attention to what you pay attention to. Think about what you think about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We always only have the present moment. Focusing too much on the future leads to anxiety. Focusing too much on the past leads to depression. Wherever you are, be fully there, now! (Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/400hFeH&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Power of Now&lt;/em&gt; by Eckhart Tolle&lt;/a&gt; [affiliate link here and throughout] for more on this.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s OK not to be OK. Feeling anxious, depressed, angry, etc. is fine. However, avoid the trap of feeling anxious about how anxious you feel, feeling depressed about how depressed you feel, etc. (Learned this from &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/404talb&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Happiness Trap&lt;/em&gt; by Russ Harris&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you never make mistakes, you’re not learning/growing as well as you could be. Perfectionism is a deadly prison. Break free with “good enough” and “always learning.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are stronger than you think you are. You are weaker than you think you are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask more questions. Ask better questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is not a thing among things. There is an “infinite qualitative difference” between God and everything that is not God, everything that exists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jesus of Nazareth is the living Lord of all. ___ is not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beware of overconfidence in what the Bible (or any other sacred text, for that matter) “clearly”does or does not say.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is devoted to the poor and powerless. Those who speak and act on God’s behalf should speak and act &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; the poor and powerless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To do better with people, ask them questions about themselves. (Read the classic &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3QlSsrR&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/em&gt; by Dale Carnegie&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can’t out-exercise your appetite forever. &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/4018XfY&#34;&gt;Eat food. Mostly plants. Not too much.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get enough sleep. You probably don’t get enough sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lift heavy things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go outside. Take a walk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a Roth IRA. Invest consistently in low-cost mutual funds or lifecycle funds as soon as you can. (Learned this from &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/48Uc65D&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Will Teach You to Be Rich&lt;/em&gt; by Ramit Sethi&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading is a superpower. You can learn from as many other lives and lifetimes as you want. &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/46YrOdW&#34;&gt;Learn how to read&lt;/a&gt;. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/46Dgm7J&#34;&gt;learn how to learn.&lt;/a&gt; Then, learn whatever you want!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always read with a pen or pencil in your hand. If you really want to learn from a book, buy a physical copy and annotate the heck out of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You always have to earn and keep your audience’s attention. Before/while communicating, ask yourself “Why should they care? What’s in it for them?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humans are incredibly good at misunderstanding each other. Before/while communicating, ask yourself “How might I be misunderstood? How might I be misunderstanding others?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that you and your loved ones are all going to die. What do you want to be known for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eulogize people BEFORE they die.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone should go to therapy for at least a few months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Slow is smooth. Smooth is fast.” Feeling nervous/stressed/angry/etc.? SLOW DOWN, especially if you’re in front of other people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courage is a choice, not a feeling. No matter how nervous you are, you can always ACT courageously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone is trying to figure it out as they go along. Do you often feel like an imposter? Join the club!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Act like you’ve been here before. Act like you’ve done this before. Act calm, comfortable, and confident, if for no other reason than to help the people around you feel calm, comfortable, and confident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leadership is service. Leadership is the willingness to make a decision for the good of the group even when it’s awkward or uncomfortable to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on what you can control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journal. What do you really want? What are you afraid of? What’s the most important thing you need to get done today? Get a notebook and write it down!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In many domains, 80% of the outcomes/effects come from 20% of the inputs/causes. Find the “vital few” things that have outsized impacts, both positive and negative, on your life. Double-down on what’s helping you. Get rid of what’s hurting you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use smoked paprika. You’re welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here are 32 things I’ve learned from life, so far.</p>
<ol>
<li>You are not your thoughts. There is a “you” behind and above your inner voice/monologue/dialogue. Pay attention to what you pay attention to. Think about what you think about.</li>
<li>We always only have the present moment. Focusing too much on the future leads to anxiety. Focusing too much on the past leads to depression. Wherever you are, be fully there, now! (Read <a href="https://amzn.to/400hFeH"><em>The Power of Now</em> by Eckhart Tolle</a> [affiliate link here and throughout] for more on this.)</li>
<li>It’s OK not to be OK. Feeling anxious, depressed, angry, etc. is fine. However, avoid the trap of feeling anxious about how anxious you feel, feeling depressed about how depressed you feel, etc. (Learned this from <a href="https://amzn.to/404talb"><em>The Happiness Trap</em> by Russ Harris</a>.)</li>
<li>If you never make mistakes, you’re not learning/growing as well as you could be. Perfectionism is a deadly prison. Break free with “good enough” and “always learning.”</li>
<li>You are stronger than you think you are. You are weaker than you think you are.</li>
<li>Ask more questions. Ask better questions.</li>
<li>God is not a thing among things. There is an “infinite qualitative difference” between God and everything that is not God, everything that exists.</li>
<li>Jesus of Nazareth is the living Lord of all. ___ is not.</li>
<li>Beware of overconfidence in what the Bible (or any other sacred text, for that matter) “clearly”does or does not say.</li>
<li>God is devoted to the poor and powerless. Those who speak and act on God’s behalf should speak and act <em>for</em> the poor and powerless.</li>
<li>To do better with people, ask them questions about themselves. (Read the classic <a href="https://amzn.to/3QlSsrR"><em>How to Win Friends and Influence People</em> by Dale Carnegie</a>.)</li>
<li>You can’t out-exercise your appetite forever. <a href="https://amzn.to/4018XfY">Eat food. Mostly plants. Not too much.</a></li>
<li>Get enough sleep. You probably don’t get enough sleep.</li>
<li>Lift heavy things.</li>
<li>Go outside. Take a walk.</li>
<li>Open a Roth IRA. Invest consistently in low-cost mutual funds or lifecycle funds as soon as you can. (Learned this from <a href="https://amzn.to/48Uc65D"><em>I Will Teach You to Be Rich</em> by Ramit Sethi</a>.)</li>
<li>Reading is a superpower. You can learn from as many other lives and lifetimes as you want. <a href="https://amzn.to/46YrOdW">Learn how to read</a>. Then <a href="https://amzn.to/46Dgm7J">learn how to learn.</a> Then, learn whatever you want!</li>
<li>Always read with a pen or pencil in your hand. If you really want to learn from a book, buy a physical copy and annotate the heck out of it.</li>
<li>You always have to earn and keep your audience’s attention. Before/while communicating, ask yourself “Why should they care? What’s in it for them?”</li>
<li>Humans are incredibly good at misunderstanding each other. Before/while communicating, ask yourself “How might I be misunderstood? How might I be misunderstanding others?”</li>
<li>Remember that you and your loved ones are all going to die. What do you want to be known for?</li>
<li>Eulogize people BEFORE they die.</li>
<li>Everyone should go to therapy for at least a few months.</li>
<li>“Slow is smooth. Smooth is fast.” Feeling nervous/stressed/angry/etc.? SLOW DOWN, especially if you’re in front of other people.</li>
<li>Courage is a choice, not a feeling. No matter how nervous you are, you can always ACT courageously.</li>
<li>Everyone is trying to figure it out as they go along. Do you often feel like an imposter? Join the club!</li>
<li>Act like you’ve been here before. Act like you’ve done this before. Act calm, comfortable, and confident, if for no other reason than to help the people around you feel calm, comfortable, and confident.</li>
<li>Leadership is service. Leadership is the willingness to make a decision for the good of the group even when it’s awkward or uncomfortable to do so.</li>
<li>Focus on what you can control.</li>
<li>Journal. What do you really want? What are you afraid of? What’s the most important thing you need to get done today? Get a notebook and write it down!</li>
<li>In many domains, 80% of the outcomes/effects come from 20% of the inputs/causes. Find the “vital few” things that have outsized impacts, both positive and negative, on your life. Double-down on what’s helping you. Get rid of what’s hurting you.</li>
<li>Use smoked paprika. You’re welcome.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master the Art of Interpersonal Relationships with &#34;How to Win Friends and Influence People&#34;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/master-the-art-of-interpersonal-relationships-with-how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 12:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/master-the-art-of-interpersonal-relationships-with-how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dale Carnegie’s timeless classic, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3K0VcaM&#34;&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, has been a bestseller for decades, offering insights and advice on improving interpersonal relationships. The book’s practical principles have helped millions of readers excel in their personal and professional lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’ll summarize the key points from Carnegie’s work and provide you with a solid foundation to start mastering your own relationships. If you find these ideas helpful and compelling, I highly recommend reading the entire book!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dale Carnegie’s timeless classic, <em><a href="https://amzn.to/3K0VcaM">How to Win Friends and Influence People</a></em>, has been a bestseller for decades, offering insights and advice on improving interpersonal relationships. The book’s practical principles have helped millions of readers excel in their personal and professional lives.</p>
<p>In this blog post, I’ll summarize the key points from Carnegie’s work and provide you with a solid foundation to start mastering your own relationships. If you find these ideas helpful and compelling, I highly recommend reading the entire book!</p>
<h2 id="key-principles-from-how-to-win-friends-and-influence-peoplehttpsamznto3k0vcam">Key Principles from <em><a href="https://amzn.to/3K0VcaM">How to Win Friends and Influence People</a></em></h2>
<h3 id="be-genuinely-interested-in-others">Be genuinely interested in others</h3>
<p>Showing sincere interest in people makes them feel valued and appreciated. Ask questions, listen actively, and show empathy to create meaningful connections.</p>
<h3 id="smile-and-be-friendly">Smile and be friendly</h3>
<p>A warm smile and friendly demeanor create a positive atmosphere and make it easier for people to open up and trust you. Your body language and tone of voice matter just as much as your words.</p>
<h3 id="remember-and-use-peoples-names">Remember and use people’s names</h3>
<p>Using someone’s name in conversation shows that you respect and value them. It also helps to build rapport and strengthen relationships.</p>
<h3 id="be-a-good-listener">Be a good listener</h3>
<p>Active listening is a critical skill for building relationships. Encourage others to talk about themselves and their interests, and listen intently. This helps to create a strong bond and demonstrate that you genuinely care.</p>
<h3 id="talk-in-terms-of-the-other-persons-interests">Talk in terms of the other person’s interests</h3>
<p>Discuss topics that are important and interesting to the other person. This demonstrates that you’re attentive to their needs and helps to create a positive, engaging conversation.</p>
<h3 id="make-others-feel-important-and-do-it-sincerely">Make others feel important, and do it sincerely</h3>
<p>Everyone wants to feel important and appreciated. Offer genuine praise and compliments, acknowledge others’ achievements, and express gratitude for their efforts.</p>
<h3 id="avoid-arguments-and-criticism">Avoid arguments and criticism</h3>
<p>Arguing and criticizing others can damage relationships. Instead, focus on understanding the other person’s perspective and finding common ground.</p>
<h3 id="admit-when-youre-wrong">Admit when you’re wrong</h3>
<p>Be humble and open to admitting your mistakes. Apologizing when necessary demonstrates your integrity and earns the respect of others.</p>
<h3 id="be-genuinely-interested-in-other-peoples-opinions">Be genuinely interested in other people’s opinions</h3>
<p>Show respect for others’ opinions, even if you don’t agree with them. Encourage open dialogue and create an environment where everyone feels comfortable sharing their thoughts.</p>
<h3 id="encourage-others-to-share-their-achievements">Encourage others to share their achievements</h3>
<p>Celebrate the successes of others and encourage them to share their accomplishments. This fosters a supportive, positive environment and helps to strengthen relationships.</p>
<h2 id="reading-recommendations">Reading Recommendations</h2>
<p>If you found <em><a href="https://amzn.to/3K0VcaM">How to Win Friends and Influence People</a></em> valuable, here are some other books that can further improve your interpersonal skills:</p>
<ol>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/40m8SCU">The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</a></em> by Stephen R. Covey. This self-help classic focuses on developing habits to achieve personal and professional success, emphasizing the importance of effective communication and empathic listening.</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3ndc2un">Emotional Intelligence 2.0</a></em> by Travis Bradberry and Jean Greaves. This book delves into the importance of emotional intelligence and offers strategies to improve self-awareness, self-management, social awareness, and relationship management.</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3K0ZIpH">The Charisma Myth</a></em> by Olivia Fox Cabane. Learn how to develop your charisma and become more influential, persuasive, and inspiring in your personal and professional relationships.</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/42xJX0V">Never Split the Difference</a></em> by Chris Voss. Written by a former FBI negotiator, this book provides valuable insights and techniques for mastering the art of negotiation in any situation.</li>
<li><em><a href="https://amzn.to/3z2kI9i">Influence: The Psychology of Persuasion</a></em> by Robert B. Cialdini. Explore the psychological principles behind persuasion and learn how to ethically influence others to achieve your goals.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Dale Carnegie’s <em><a href="https://amzn.to/3K0VcaM">How to Win Friends and Influence People</a></em> provides timeless wisdom and valuable insights into the art of building strong interpersonal relationships. By applying these principles in your daily life, you can enhance your personal and professional connections and create a more positive, supportive environment around you.</p>
<p>I highly recommend reading the entire book to fully grasp the depth and nuances of Carnegie’s teachings. Furthermore, consider exploring the additional reading recommendations listed above to continue developing your communication, emotional intelligence, and persuasion skills. Remember, the key to success in any area of life often lies in the strength of your relationships with others!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Useful Websites: My Favorite Online Resources</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/most-useful-websites-my-favorite-online-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 19:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/most-useful-websites-my-favorite-online-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;general--thinking&#34;&gt;General / Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Untools: &lt;a href=&#34;https://untools.co/&#34;&gt;https://untools.co/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Clear: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/&#34;&gt;https://jamesclear.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Farnam Street: &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/&#34;&gt;https://fs.blog/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your Logical Fallacy Is: &lt;a href=&#34;https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/&#34;&gt;https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your Bias Is: &lt;a href=&#34;https://yourbias.is/&#34;&gt;https://yourbias.is/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fitness--health&#34;&gt;Fitness / Health&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Darebee: &lt;a href=&#34;https://darebee.com/&#34;&gt;https://darebee.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading--writing&#34;&gt;Reading / Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QuillBot: &lt;a href=&#34;https://quillbot.com/&#34;&gt;https://quillbot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12ft Ladder: &lt;a href=&#34;https://12ft.io/&#34;&gt;https://12ft.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Library: &lt;a href=&#34;https://openlibrary.org/&#34;&gt;https://openlibrary.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PDF24 Tools: &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.pdf24.org/en/&#34;&gt;https://tools.pdf24.org/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsplash: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/&#34;&gt;https://unsplash.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Noun Project: &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenounproject.com/&#34;&gt;https://thenounproject.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-development&#34;&gt;Software Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stack Overflow: &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/&#34;&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;O’Reilly: &lt;a href=&#34;https://learning.oreilly.com/&#34;&gt;https://learning.oreilly.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;roadmap.sh: &lt;a href=&#34;https://roadmap.sh/&#34;&gt;https://roadmap.sh/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cheat.sh: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cheat.sh/&#34;&gt;https://cheat.sh/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevHints.io: &lt;a href=&#34;https://devhints.io/&#34;&gt;https://devhints.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn X in Y minutes: &lt;a href=&#34;https://learnxinyminutes.com/&#34;&gt;https://learnxinyminutes.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baeldung (for Java/Spring): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baeldung.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.baeldung.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would you add to this list? Let me know!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="general--thinking">General / Thinking</h2>
<ul>
<li>Untools: <a href="https://untools.co/">https://untools.co/</a></li>
<li>James Clear: <a href="https://jamesclear.com/">https://jamesclear.com/</a></li>
<li>Farnam Street: <a href="https://fs.blog/">https://fs.blog/</a></li>
<li>Your Logical Fallacy Is: <a href="https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/">https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/</a></li>
<li>Your Bias Is: <a href="https://yourbias.is/">https://yourbias.is/</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="fitness--health">Fitness / Health</h2>
<ul>
<li>Darebee: <a href="https://darebee.com/">https://darebee.com/</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="reading--writing">Reading / Writing</h2>
<ul>
<li>QuillBot: <a href="https://quillbot.com/">https://quillbot.com/</a></li>
<li>12ft Ladder: <a href="https://12ft.io/">https://12ft.io/</a></li>
<li>Open Library: <a href="https://openlibrary.org/">https://openlibrary.org/</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="design">Design</h2>
<ul>
<li>PDF24 Tools: <a href="https://tools.pdf24.org/en/">https://tools.pdf24.org/en/</a></li>
<li>Unsplash: <a href="https://unsplash.com/">https://unsplash.com/</a></li>
<li>The Noun Project: <a href="https://thenounproject.com/">https://thenounproject.com/</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="software-development">Software Development</h2>
<ul>
<li>Stack Overflow: <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/">https://stackoverflow.com/</a></li>
<li>O’Reilly: <a href="https://learning.oreilly.com/">https://learning.oreilly.com/</a></li>
<li>roadmap.sh: <a href="https://roadmap.sh/">https://roadmap.sh/</a></li>
<li>cheat.sh: <a href="https://cheat.sh/">https://cheat.sh/</a></li>
<li>DevHints.io: <a href="https://devhints.io/">https://devhints.io/</a></li>
<li>Learn X in Y minutes: <a href="https://learnxinyminutes.com/">https://learnxinyminutes.com/</a></li>
<li>Baeldung (for Java/Spring): <a href="https://www.baeldung.com/">https://www.baeldung.com/</a></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>What would you add to this list? Let me know!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s time for another social media fast!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-for-another-social-media-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 15:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/its-time-for-another-social-media-fast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After listening to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blinkist.com/en/books/deep-work-en&#34;&gt;the Blinkist summary of Cal Newport’s &lt;em&gt;Deep Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (I’ve read the book, this was just for a refresher), I’m convinced that it’s time for another 30-day fast from Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I’ll still keep &lt;a href=&#34;https://micro.blog/joshuapsteele&#34;&gt;my micro.blog up and running&lt;/a&gt;, but between &lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com&#34;&gt;running Anglican Compass&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/&#34;&gt;sprinting for some last-ditch clarity on my increasingly frustrating dissertation&lt;/a&gt;, I need all the extra bandwidth I can get!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to get in touch for some reason, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/contact/&#34;&gt;use the contact form on my website&lt;/a&gt;. You can also &lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/joshuapsteele&#34;&gt;sign up for my very occasional email newsletter here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After listening to <a href="https://www.blinkist.com/en/books/deep-work-en">the Blinkist summary of Cal Newport’s <em>Deep Work</em></a> (I’ve read the book, this was just for a refresher), I’m convinced that it’s time for another 30-day fast from Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram.</p>
<p>I think I’ll still keep <a href="https://micro.blog/joshuapsteele">my micro.blog up and running</a>, but between <a href="https://anglicancompass.com">running Anglican Compass</a> and <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/the-phd-plan-or-the-lack-thereof/">sprinting for some last-ditch clarity on my increasingly frustrating dissertation</a>, I need all the extra bandwidth I can get!</p>
<p>If you need to get in touch for some reason, please <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/contact/">use the contact form on my website</a>. You can also <a href="https://buttondown.email/joshuapsteele">sign up for my very occasional email newsletter here</a>.</p>
<p>One last thing: If you haven’t read <a href="https://www.calnewport.com/books/deep-work/">Cal Newport’s <em>Deep Work</em></a> yet, you should do so ASAP!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>They Say, I Say Writing Templates</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 17:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/they-say-i-say-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOURCE: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3eOMlXF&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;They Say / I Say: The Moves that Matter in Academic Writing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 4th edition (affiliate link). Perhaps the most helpful and practical book on academic writing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disagreeing-without-being-disagreeable&#34;&gt;Disagreeing Without Being Disagreeable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I understand the impulse to A, my own view is B.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I agree with X that Y, I cannot accept her overall conclusion that Z.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While X argues Y, and I argue Z, in a way we’re both right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-template-of-templates&#34;&gt;The Template Of Templates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent discussions of A, a controversial issue has been whether B. On the one hand, some argue that C. From this perspective, D. On the other hand, however, others argue that E. In the words of F, one of this view’s main proponents, “G.” According to this view, H. In sum, then, the issue is whether I or J.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SOURCE: <a href="https://amzn.to/3eOMlXF"><em>They Say / I Say: The Moves that Matter in Academic Writing</em></a>, 4th edition (affiliate link). Perhaps the most helpful and practical book on academic writing!</p>
<h2 id="disagreeing-without-being-disagreeable">Disagreeing Without Being Disagreeable</h2>
<ul>
<li>While I understand the impulse to A, my own view is B.</li>
<li>While I agree with X that Y, I cannot accept her overall conclusion that Z.</li>
<li>While X argues Y, and I argue Z, in a way we’re both right.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-template-of-templates">The Template Of Templates</h2>
<p>In recent discussions of A, a controversial issue has been whether B. On the one hand, some argue that C. From this perspective, D. On the other hand, however, others argue that E. In the words of F, one of this view’s main proponents, “G.” According to this view, H. In sum, then, the issue is whether I or J.</p>
<p>My own view is that K. Though I concede that L, I still maintain that M. For example, N. Although some might object that O, I would reply that P. The issue is important because Q.</p>
<h2 id="introducing-what-they-say">Introducing What “They Say”</h2>
<ul>
<li>A number of have recently suggested that X.</li>
<li>It has become common today to dismiss X.</li>
<li>In their recent work, A and B have offered harsh critiques of C for D.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-standard-views">Introducing “Standard Views”</h2>
<ul>
<li>Americans today tend to believe that X.</li>
<li>Conventional wisdom has it that X.</li>
<li>Common sense seems to dictate that X.</li>
<li>The standard way of thinking about topic X has it that Y.</li>
<li>It is often said that X.</li>
<li>My whole life I have heard it said that X.</li>
<li>You would think that X.</li>
<li>Many people assume that X.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="making-what-they-say-something-you-say">Making What “They Say” Something You Say</h2>
<ul>
<li>I’ve always believed that X.</li>
<li>When I was a child, I used to think that X.</li>
<li>Although I should know better by now, I cannot help thinking that X.</li>
<li>At the same time that I believe X, I also believe Y.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-something-implied-or-assumed">Introducing Something Implied Or Assumed</h2>
<ul>
<li>Although none of them have ever said so directly, my teachers have often given me the impression that X.</li>
<li>One implication of X’s treatment of Y is that Z.</li>
<li>Although X does not say so directly, she apparently assumes that Y.</li>
<li>While they rarely admit as much, X often take for granted that Y.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-an-ongoing-debate">Introducing An Ongoing Debate</h2>
<ul>
<li>In discussions of X, one controversial issue has been A. On the one hand, B argues C. On the other hand, D contends E. Others even maintain F. My own view is G.</li>
<li>When it comes to the topic of X, most of us will readily agree that A. Where this agreement usually ends, however, is on the question of B. Whereas some are convinced that C, others maintain that D.</li>
<li>In conclusion, then, as I suggested earlier, defenders of X can’t have it both ways. Their assertion that Y is contradicted by their claim that Z.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="capturing-authorial-action">Capturing Authorial Action</h2>
<ul>
<li>X acknowledges that .</li>
<li>X agrees that .</li>
<li>X argues that .</li>
<li>X believes that .</li>
<li>X celebrates the fact that .</li>
<li>X claims that .</li>
<li>X complains that .</li>
<li>X concedes that .</li>
<li>X demonstrates that .</li>
<li>X denies/does not deny that .</li>
<li>X deplores the tendency to .</li>
<li>X emphasizes that .</li>
<li>X insists that .</li>
<li>X observes that .</li>
<li>X questions whether .</li>
<li>X refutes the claim that .</li>
<li>X reminds us that .</li>
<li>X reports that .</li>
<li>X suggests that .</li>
<li>X urges us to .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-quotations">Introducing Quotations</h2>
<ul>
<li>X states, “ .”</li>
<li>As the prominent philosopher X puts it, “ .”</li>
<li>According to X, “ .”</li>
<li>X himself writes, “ .”</li>
<li>In her book, , X maintains that “ ”</li>
<li>Writing in the journal , X complains that “ .”</li>
<li>In X’s view, “ .”</li>
<li>X agrees when she writes, “ .”</li>
<li>X disagrees when he writes, “ .”</li>
<li>X complicates matters further when he writes, “ .”</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="explaining-quotations">Explaining Quotations</h2>
<ul>
<li>Basically, X is saying .</li>
<li>In other words, X believes .</li>
<li>In making this comment, X urges us to .</li>
<li>X is corroborating the age-old adage that .</li>
<li>X’s point is that .</li>
<li>The essence of X’s argument is that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="disagreeing-with-reasons">Disagreeing, With Reasons</h2>
<ul>
<li>I think X is mistaken because she overlooks .</li>
<li>X’s claim that rests upon the questionable assumption that .</li>
<li>I disagree with X’s view that because, as recent research has shown, .</li>
<li>X contradicts herself / can’t have it both ways. On the one hand, she argues . On the other hand, she also says .</li>
<li>By focusing on , X overlooks the deeper problem of .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="agreeingwith-a-difference">Agreeing—With A Difference</h2>
<ul>
<li>I agree that because my experience confirms it.</li>
<li>X surely is right about because, as she may not be aware, recent studies have shown that .</li>
<li>X’s theory of is extremely useful because it sheds insight on the difficult problem of .</li>
<li>Those unfamiliar with this school of thought may be interested to know that it basically boils down to .</li>
<li>I agree that , a point that needs emphasizing since so many people believe .</li>
<li>If group X is right that , as I think they are, then we need to reassess the popular assumption that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="agreeing-and-disagreeing-simultaneously">Agreeing And Disagreeing Simultaneously</h2>
<ul>
<li>Although I agree with X up to a point, I cannot accept his overall conclusion that .</li>
<li>Although I disagree with much that X says, I fully endorse his final conclusion that .</li>
<li>Though I concede that , I still insist that .</li>
<li>Whereas X provides ample evidence that , Y and Z’s research on and convinces me that instead.</li>
<li>X is right that , but she seems on more dubious ground when she claims that .</li>
<li>While X is probably wrong when she claims that , she is right that .</li>
<li>I’m of two minds about X’s claim that . On the one hand, I agree that . On the other hand, I’m not sure if .</li>
<li>My feelings on the issue are mixed. I do support X’s position that , but I find Y’s argument about and Z’s research on to be equally persuasive.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="signaling-who-is-saying-what">Signaling Who Is Saying What</h2>
<ul>
<li>X argues .</li>
<li>According to both X and Y, .</li>
<li>Politicians , X argues, should .</li>
<li>Most athletes will tell you that .</li>
<li>My own view, however, is that .</li>
<li>I agree, as X may not realize, that .</li>
<li>But are real and, arguably, the most significant factor in .</li>
<li>But X is wrong that .</li>
<li>However, it is simply not true that .</li>
<li>Indeed, it is highly likely that .</li>
<li>X’s assertion that does not fit the facts.</li>
<li>X is right that .</li>
<li>X is wrong that .</li>
<li>X is both right and wrong that .</li>
<li>Yet a sober analysis of the matter reveals .</li>
<li>Nevertheless, new research shows .</li>
<li>Anyone familiar with should agree that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="embedding-voice-markers">Embedding Voice Markers</h2>
<ul>
<li>X overlooks what I consider an important point about .</li>
<li>My own view is that what X insists is a is in fact a .</li>
<li>I wholeheartedly endorse what X calls .</li>
<li>These conclusions, which X discusses in , add weight to the argument that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="entertaining-objections">Entertaining Objections</h2>
<ul>
<li>At this point I would like to raise some objections that have been inspired by the skeptic in me. She feels that I have been ignoring . “ ,” she says to me, “ .”</li>
<li>Yet some readers may challenge the view that .</li>
<li>Of course, many will probably disagree with this assertion that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="naming-your-naysayers">Naming Your Naysayers</h2>
<ul>
<li>Here many would probably object that .</li>
<li>But would certainly take issue with the argument that .</li>
<li>, of course, may want to question whether .</li>
<li>Nevertheless, both followers and critics of will probably argue that .</li>
<li>Although not all think alike, some of them will probably dispute my claim that .</li>
<li>are so diverse in their views that it’s hard to generalize about them, but some are likely to object on the grounds that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-objections-informally">Introducing Objections Informally</h2>
<ul>
<li>But is my proposal realistic? What are the chances of its actually being adopted?</li>
<li>Yet is it always true that ? Is it always the case, as I have been suggesting, that ?</li>
<li>However, does the evidence I’ve cited prove conclusively that ?</li>
<li>“Impossible,” some will say. “You must be reading the research selectively.”</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="making-concessions-while-still-standing-your-ground">Making Concessions While Still Standing Your Ground</h2>
<ul>
<li>Although I grant that , I still maintain that .</li>
<li>Proponents of X are right to argue that . But they exaggerate when they claim that .</li>
<li>While it is true that , it does not necessarily follow that .</li>
<li>On the one hand, I agree with X that . But on the other hand, I still insist that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="indicating-who-cares">Indicating Who Cares</h2>
<ul>
<li>used to think . But recently [or within the past few decades] suggests that .</li>
<li>These findings challenge the work of earlier researchers, who tended to assume that .</li>
<li>Recent studies like these shed new light on , which previous studies had not addressed.</li>
<li>Researchers have long assumed that . For instance, one eminent scholar of cell biology, , assumed in , her seminal work on cell structures and functions, that fat cells . As herself put it, “ ” (2012). Another leading scientist, , argued that fat cells “ ” (2011). Ultimately, when it came to the nature of fat, the basic assumption was that .</li>
<li>But a new body of research shows that fat cells are far more complex and that .</li>
<li>If sports enthusiasts stopped to think about it, many of them might simply assume that the most successful athletes . However, new research shows .</li>
<li>These findings challenge neoliberals’ common assumptions that .</li>
<li>At first glance, teenagers appear to . But on closer inspection .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="establishing-why-your-claims-matter">Establishing Why Your Claims Matter</h2>
<ul>
<li>X matters / is important because .</li>
<li>Although X may seem trivial, it is in fact crucial in terms of today’s concern over .</li>
<li>Ultimately, what is at stake here is .</li>
<li>These findings have important consequences for the broader domain of .</li>
<li>My discussion of X is in fact addressing the larger matter of .</li>
<li>These conclusions / This discovery will have significant applications in as well as in .</li>
<li>Although X may seem of concern to only a small group of , it should in fact concern anyone who cares about .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="commonly-used-transitions">Commonly Used Transitions</h2>
<h3 id="addition">Addition</h3>
<ul>
<li>also</li>
<li>and</li>
<li>besides</li>
<li>furthermore</li>
<li>in addition</li>
<li>in fact</li>
<li>indeed</li>
<li>moreover</li>
<li>so too</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="elaboration">Elaboration</h3>
<ul>
<li>actually</li>
<li>by extension</li>
<li>in other words</li>
<li>in short</li>
<li>that is</li>
<li>to put it another way</li>
<li>to put it bluntly</li>
<li>to put it succinctly</li>
<li>ultimately</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="example">Example</h3>
<ul>
<li>after all</li>
<li>as an illustration</li>
<li>consider</li>
<li>for example</li>
<li>for instance</li>
<li>specifically</li>
<li>to take a case in point</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="cause-and-effect">Cause and Effect</h3>
<ul>
<li>accordingly</li>
<li>as a result</li>
<li>consequently</li>
<li>hence</li>
<li>it follows, then</li>
<li>since</li>
<li>so</li>
<li>then</li>
<li>therefore</li>
<li>thus</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="comparison">Comparison</h3>
<ul>
<li>along the same lines</li>
<li>in the same way</li>
<li>likewise</li>
<li>similarly</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="contrast">Contrast</h3>
<ul>
<li>although</li>
<li>but</li>
<li>by contrast</li>
<li>conversely</li>
<li>despite</li>
<li>even though</li>
<li>however</li>
<li>in contrast</li>
<li>nevertheless</li>
<li>nonetheless</li>
<li>on the contrary</li>
<li>on the other hand</li>
<li>regardless</li>
<li>whereas</li>
<li>while</li>
<li>yet</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="concession">Concession</h3>
<ul>
<li>admittedly</li>
<li>although it is true that</li>
<li>granted</li>
<li>I concede that</li>
<li>naturally</li>
<li>of course</li>
<li>to be sure</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<ul>
<li>as a result</li>
<li>consequently</li>
<li>hence</li>
<li>in conclusion, then</li>
<li>in short</li>
<li>in sum, then</li>
<li>it follows, then</li>
<li>so</li>
<li>the upshot of all this is that</li>
<li>therefore</li>
<li>thus</li>
<li>to sum up</li>
<li>to summarize</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="translation-recipes">Translation Recipes</h2>
<ul>
<li>Scholar X argues, “ .” In other words, .</li>
<li>Essentially, X argues .</li>
<li>X’s point, succinctly put, is that .</li>
<li>Plainly put, .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="adding-metacommentary">Adding Metacommentary</h2>
<ul>
<li>In other words, .</li>
<li>What really means by this is .</li>
<li>Ultimately, my goal is to demonstrate that .</li>
<li>My point is not , but .</li>
<li>To put it another way, .</li>
<li>In sum, then, .</li>
<li>My conclusion, then, is that, .</li>
<li>In short, .</li>
<li>What is more important, .</li>
<li>Incidentally, .</li>
<li>By the way, .</li>
<li>Chapter 2 explores , while Chapter 3 examines .</li>
<li>Having just argued that , let us now turn our attention to .</li>
<li>Although some readers may object that , I would answer that .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="linking-to-what-they-say">Linking To What “They Say”</h2>
<ul>
<li>As X mentions in this article, “ .”</li>
<li>In making this comment, X warns that .</li>
<li>Economists often assume ; however, new research by X suggests .</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-gaps-in-the-existing-research">Introducing Gaps In The Existing Research</h2>
<ul>
<li>Studies of X have indicated . It is not clear, however, that this conclusion applies to .</li>
<li>often take for granted that . Few have investigated this assumption, however.</li>
<li>X’s work tells us a great deal about . Can this work be generalized to ?</li>
<li>Our understanding of remains incomplete because previous work has not examined .</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balderdash! 12 Suggestions for Overcoming Writer’s Block (From Andrew T. Le Peau’s “Write Better”)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 13:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/balderdash-12-suggestions-for-overcoming-writers-block-from-andrew-t-le-peaus-write-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writer’s block sucks. I’m currently facing it with regard to &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/&#34;&gt;my dissertation&lt;/a&gt; and I’ve decided to hit pause on research and writing until I regain access to my library carrell at Wheaton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I’ve come across some helpful advice on overcoming writer’s block in Andrew T. Le Peau’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ZuTZC3&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Writer Better: A Lifelong Editor on Craft, Art, and Spirituality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; with helpful and practical advice on writing, rewriting, publishing, etc. To whet your appetite, I’d like to share some of Le Peau’s tips for conquering writer’s block. These all come from chapter 7, pages. 72–80.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Writer’s block sucks. I’m currently facing it with regard to <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/">my dissertation</a> and I’ve decided to hit pause on research and writing until I regain access to my library carrell at Wheaton.</p>
<p>Thankfully, I’ve come across some helpful advice on overcoming writer’s block in Andrew T. Le Peau’s <a href="https://amzn.to/2ZuTZC3"><em>Writer Better: A Lifelong Editor on Craft, Art, and Spirituality</em></a> (affiliate link).</p>
<p>The book is <em>filled</em> with helpful and practical advice on writing, rewriting, publishing, etc. To whet your appetite, I’d like to share some of Le Peau’s tips for conquering writer’s block. These all come from chapter 7, pages. 72–80.</p>
<ol>
<li>Read lots of stuff. Fill up the tank!</li>
<li>Keep an idea file. Gather tidbits whenever and wherever you can.</li>
<li>Take notes on anything and everything.</li>
<li>Copy the greats. Literally. Take out a classic passage and start copying it down verbatim.</li>
<li>Get some rest. Do something different than you normally do.</li>
<li>Play Balderdash. It’s good practice for coming up with words on the spot without overthinking.</li>
<li>Don’t judge yourself just yet. First, write as a “Madman.” Anything goes! Then, go over what you’ve written as an “Architect.” Then, as a “Carpenter.” Finally, as a “Judge.”</li>
<li>Hit pause, especially if writer’s block is due to a life event.</li>
<li>If you are an extrovert, try talking things out with a friend. Then, if the friend is willing to stick around, try writing while they’re still there! (This might have to be adapted via Zoom these days.)</li>
<li>If you’re a detail person, then research the crap out of your topic. Just set a deadline for yourself so you don’t research forever!</li>
<li>If you can’t land the plane, find an accountability partner (“who is not a peer,” Le Peau specifies. “It needs to be someone you respect and will listen to, who has some authority in your life” pg. 79) and set a deadline.</li>
<li>Remember that writing is difficult! You shouldn’t expect good writing to come easy.</li>
</ol>
<p>Again, I really need to take Le Peau’s advice when I get back to working on my dissertation after the stay-at-home order is lifted in Illinois! If you find any of these suggestions helpful, or if you work with words in any way, I highly recommend that you read Le Peau’s <a href="https://amzn.to/2ZuTZC3"><em>Write Better</em></a>! You should also check out his blog at <a href="https://andyunedited.com/">https://andyunedited.com/</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helpful Writing Templates</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/helpful-writing-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 14:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/helpful-writing-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following templates come from &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/33TJdor&#34;&gt;They Say / I Say: The Moves That Matter in Academic Writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-what-they-say&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing What They Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A number of $$$ have recently suggested that $$$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has become common today to dismiss $$$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In their recent work, Y and Z have offered harsh critiques of Dr. X for $$$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-standard-views&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing Standard Views&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;American today tend to believe that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conventional wisdom has it that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common sense seems to dictate that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The standard way of thinking about topic X has it that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is often said that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My whole life I have heard it said that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You would think that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many people assumed that $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making What They Say Something You Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The following templates come from <em><a href="https://amzn.to/33TJdor">They Say / I Say: The Moves That Matter in Academic Writing</a></em>.</p>
<h2 id="introducing-what-they-say"><strong>Introducing What They Say</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>A number of $$$ have recently suggested that $$$.</li>
<li>It has become common today to dismiss $$$.</li>
<li>In their recent work, Y and Z have offered harsh critiques of Dr. X for $$$.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-standard-views"><strong>Introducing Standard Views</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>American today tend to believe that $$$</li>
<li>Conventional wisdom has it that $$$</li>
<li>Common sense seems to dictate that $$$</li>
<li>The standard way of thinking about topic X has it that $$$</li>
<li>It is often said that $$$</li>
<li>My whole life I have heard it said that $$$</li>
<li>You would think that $$$</li>
<li>Many people assumed that $$$</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Making What They Say Something You Say</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I’ve always believed that $$$</li>
<li>When I was a child, I used to think that $$$</li>
<li>Although I should know better by now, I cannot help thinking that $$$</li>
<li>At the same time that I believe $$$, I also believe $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-something-implied-or-assumed"><strong>Introducing Something Implied or Assumed</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Although none of them have ever said so directly, my teachers have often given me the impression that $$$</li>
<li>One implication of X’s treatment of $$$ is that $$$</li>
<li>Although X does not say so directly, she apparently assumes that $$$</li>
<li>While they rarely admit as much, $$$ often take for granted that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-an-ongoing-debate"><strong>Introducing an Ongoing Debate</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>In discussions of X, one controversial issue has been $$$. On the other hand, $$$ argues $$$. On the other hand, $$$ contends $$$. Others even maintain $$$. My own view is $$$.</li>
<li>When it comes to the topic of $$$, most of us will readily agree that $$$. Where this agreement usually ends, however, is on the question of $$$. Whereas some are convinced that $$$, others maintain that $$$.</li>
<li>In conclusion, then, defenders of $$$ can’t have it both ways. Their assertion that $$$ is contradicted by their claim that $$$.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="capturing-authorial-action"><strong>Capturing Authorial Action</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X <strong>acknowledges</strong> that $$$.</li>
<li>X <strong>agrees</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>argues</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>believes</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>denies</strong> / does <strong>not</strong> deny that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>claims</strong> that</li>
<li>X <strong>complains</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>conceded</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>demonstrates</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>deplores</strong> the tendency to $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>celebrates</strong> the fact that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>emphasizes</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>insists</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>observes</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>questions</strong> whether $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>refutes</strong> the claim that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>reminds</strong> us that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>suggests</strong> that $$$</li>
<li>X <strong>urges</strong> us to $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-quotations"><strong>Introducing Quotations</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X <strong>states</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
<li>As the prominent philosopher X <strong>puts</strong> it, “$$$.”</li>
<li><strong>According</strong> to X, “$$$.”</li>
<li>X himself <strong>writes</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
<li>In her book, $$$, X <strong>maintains</strong> that “$$$.”</li>
<li><strong>Writing</strong> in the journal $$$, X <strong>complains</strong> that “$$$.”</li>
<li><strong>In X’s view</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
<li>X <strong>agrees/disagrees</strong> when she <strong>writes</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
<li>X <strong>complicates matters further</strong> when he <strong>writes</strong>, “$$$.”</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="explaining-quotations"><strong>Explaining Quotations</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Basically, X is saying $$$.</li>
<li>In other words, X believes $$$.</li>
<li>In making this comment, X argues that $$$.</li>
<li>X is insisting that $$$</li>
<li>X’s point is that $$$</li>
<li>The essence of X’s argument is that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="disagreeing-with-reasons"><strong>Disagreeing, with Reasons</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>I think X is mistaken because she overlooks $$$</li>
<li>X’s claim that $$$ rests upon the questionable assumption that $$$.</li>
<li>I disagree with X’s view that $$$ because, as recent research has show, $$$</li>
<li>X contradicts herself /can’t have it both ways. On the one hand, she argues $$$, but on the other hand, she also says $$$</li>
<li>By focusing on $$$, X overlooks the deeper problem of $$$</li>
<li>X claims $$$, but we don’t need X to tell us that. Anyone familiar with $$$ has long know that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="agreeing-with-a-difference"><strong>Agreeing, with a Difference</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>I agree that $$$ because my experience confirms it.</li>
<li>X surely is right about $$$ because, as she may not be aware, recent studies have shown that $$$.</li>
<li>X’s theory of $$$ is extremely useful because it sheds insight on the difficult problem of $$$</li>
<li>I agree that $$$, a point that needs emphasizing since so many people believe $$$</li>
<li>Those unfamiliar with this school of thought may be interested to know that it basically boils down to $$$</li>
<li>If group X is right that $$$, as I think they are, then we need to reassess the popular assumption that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="agreeing-and-disagreeing-simultaneously"><strong>Agreeing and Disagreeing Simultaneously</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Although I agree with X up to a point, I cannot accept his overall conclusion that $$$</li>
<li>Although I disagree with much that X says, I fully endorse his final conclusion that $$$</li>
<li>Though I concede that $$$, I still insist that $$$</li>
<li>Whereas X provides ample evidence that $$$, Y and Z’s research on $$$ and $$$ convinces me that $$$ instead.</li>
<li>X is right that $$$, but she seems on more dubious ground when she claims that $$$</li>
<li>While X is probably wrong when she claims that $$$, she is right that $$$</li>
<li>I’m of two minds about X’s claim that $$$. On the one hand, I agree that $$$. On the other hand, I’m not sure if $$$</li>
<li>My feelings on the issue are mixed. I do support X’s positions that $$$, but I find Y’s argument about $$$ and Z’s research on $$$ to be equally persuasive.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="signaling-who-is-saying-what"><strong>Signaling Who Is Saying What</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X argues $$$</li>
<li>According to both X and Y, $$$</li>
<li>Politicians $$$, X argues, should $$$</li>
<li>Most athletes will tell you that $$$</li>
<li>My own view, however, is that $$$</li>
<li>I agree, as X may not realize, that $$$, but $$$ are real and, arguably, the most significant factor in $$$</li>
<li>However X is wrong that $$$</li>
<li>However, it is simply not true that $$$</li>
<li>Indeed, it is highly likely that $$$</li>
<li>Nonetheless, the view that $$$ does not fit all the facts.</li>
<li>X is right that $$$</li>
<li>X is wrong that</li>
<li>X is both right and wrong that $$$</li>
<li>A sober analysis of the matter reveals $$$</li>
<li>Nevertheless, new research shows $$$</li>
<li>Anyone familiar with $$$ should see that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="embedding-voice-markers"><strong>Embedding Voice Markers</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X overlooks what I consider an important point about $$$</li>
<li>My own view is that what X insists is a $$$ is in fact a $$$</li>
<li>I wholeheartedly endorse what X calls $$$</li>
<li>These conclusions, which X discusses in $$$, add weight to the argument that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="entertaining-objections"><strong>Entertaining Objections</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>At this point, I would like to raise some objections that have been inspired by the skeptic in me. She feels that I have been ignoring $$$., “$$$,” she says to me, “$$$.”</li>
<li>Thus far some readers may challenge the view that $$$. After all, many believe $$$. Indeed, my own argument that $$$ seems to ignore $$$ and $$$</li>
<li>Of course, many will probably disagree with the assertion that $$$</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Naming Your Nay Sayers</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Here many $$$ would probably object that $$$</li>
<li>However/But $$$ would certainly take issue with the argument that $$$</li>
<li>$$$, of course, may want to question whether/dispute my claim that $$$</li>
<li>Nevertheless, both followers and critics of $$$ will probably argue that $$$</li>
<li>Although not all $$$ think alike, some of them will probably dispute my claim that $$$</li>
<li>$$$ are so diverse in their views that it’s hard to generalize about them, but some are likely to object on the grounds that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="introducing-objections-informally"><strong>Introducing Objections Informally</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>However/But is my proposal realistic? What are the chances of its actually being adopted?</li>
<li>Yet is it always true that $$$? Is it always the case, as I have been suggesting, that $$$?</li>
<li>However, does the evidence cited prove conclusively that $$$?</li>
<li>“Impossible,” some will say. “You must be reading the research selectively.”</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="making-concessions-while-still-standing-your-ground"><strong>Making Concessions while Still Standing Your Ground</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Although I grant that $$$, I still maintain that $$$</li>
<li>Proponents of X are right to argue that $$$. But they exaggerate when they claim that $$$</li>
<li>While it is true that $$$, it does not necessarily follow that $$$</li>
<li>On the one hand, I agree with X that $$$. But on the other hand, I still insist that $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="indicating-who-cares"><strong>Indicating Who Cares</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>$$$ used to think $$$, but recently (or within the past few decades) $$$ suggests that $$$</li>
<li>What his new research does, then, is correct the mistaken impression, held by many earlier researchers, that $$$</li>
<li>These findings challenge the work of earlier researchers, who tended to assume that $$$</li>
<li>Recent studies like these shed new light on $$$, which previous studies had not addressed.</li>
<li>Researchers have long assumed that $$$. For instance, one eminent scholar of cell biology, $$$ assumed in $$$, her seminal work on cell structures and functions, that fate cells $$$. As $$$ herself put it, “$$$.” Another leading scientist, $$$, argued that fat cells “$$$.” Ultimately, when it came to the nature of fat, the basic assumption was that $$$. But a new body of research shows that fat cells are far more complex and that $$$</li>
<li>If sports enthusiasts stopped to think about it, any of them might simply assume that the most successful athletes $$$. However, new research shows $$$.</li>
<li>These findings challenge $$$’s common assumptions that $$$</li>
<li>At first glance, teenagers appear to $$$, but on closer inspection $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="establishing-why-your-claims-matter"><strong>Establishing Why Your Claims Matter</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>X matters/is important because $$$</li>
<li>Although X may seem trivial, it is in fact crucial in terms of today’s concern over $$$</li>
<li>Ultimately, what is at stake here is $$$</li>
<li>These findings have important consequences for the broader domain of $$$</li>
<li>My discussion of X is in fact addressing the larger matter of $$$</li>
<li>These conclusions / This discovery will have significant application in $$$ as well as in $$$</li>
<li>Although X may seem of concern to only a small group of $$$, it should in fact concern anyone who cares about $$$</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="adding-meta-commentary"><strong>Adding Meta-commentary</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>In other words, $$$</li>
<li>What $$$ really means by this is $$$</li>
<li>My point is $$$</li>
<li>Essentially, I am arguing that $$$</li>
<li>My point is not that we should $$$, but that we should $$$</li>
<li>What $$$ really means is $$$</li>
<li>In other words, $$$</li>
<li>To put it another way, $$$</li>
<li>In sum, then, $$$</li>
<li>My conclusion, then is that, $$$</li>
<li>In short, $$$</li>
<li>What is more important, $$$</li>
<li>Incidentally, $$$</li>
<li>By the way, $$$</li>
<li>Chapter two explores $$$, while Chapter three examines $$$</li>
<li>Having just argued that $$$, let us now turn our attention to $$$.</li>
<li>Although some readers may object that $$$, I would answer that $$$.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="commonly-used-transitions"><strong>Commonly Used Transitions</strong></h2>
<h3 id="cause-and-effect"><strong>Cause and Effect</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Accordingly</li>
<li>As a result</li>
<li>Consequently</li>
<li>Hence</li>
<li>It follows, then</li>
<li>Since</li>
<li>So</li>
<li>Then</li>
<li>Therefore</li>
<li>Thus</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="conclusion"><strong>Conclusion</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>As a result</li>
<li>Consequently</li>
<li>Hence</li>
<li>In conclusion, then</li>
<li>In short</li>
<li>In sum, then</li>
<li>It follows, then</li>
<li>So</li>
<li>The upshot of all this is that</li>
<li>Therefore</li>
<li>Thus</li>
<li>To sum up</li>
<li>To summarize</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="comparison"><strong>Comparison</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Along the same line</li>
<li>In the same way</li>
<li>Likewise</li>
<li>Similarly</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="contrast"><strong>Contrast</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Although</li>
<li>But</li>
<li>By contrast</li>
<li>Conversely</li>
<li>Despite the fact that</li>
<li>Even though</li>
<li>However</li>
<li>In contrast</li>
<li>Nevertheless</li>
<li>Nonetheless</li>
<li>On the contrary</li>
<li>On the other hand</li>
<li>Regardless</li>
<li>Whereas</li>
<li>While</li>
<li>Yet</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="addition"><strong>Addition</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Also</li>
<li>And</li>
<li>Besides</li>
<li>Furthermore</li>
<li>In addition</li>
<li>In fact</li>
<li>Indeed</li>
<li>Moreover</li>
<li>So too</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="concession"><strong>Concession</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Admittedly</li>
<li>Although it is true that</li>
<li>Granted</li>
<li>I concede that</li>
<li>Of course</li>
<li>Naturally</li>
<li>To be sure</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="example"><strong>Example</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>After all</li>
<li>As an illustration</li>
<li>Consider</li>
<li>For example</li>
<li>For instance</li>
<li>Specifically</li>
<li>To take/taking a case in point</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="elaboration"><strong>Elaboration</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>Actually</li>
<li>By extension</li>
<li>In short</li>
<li>That is</li>
<li>In other words</li>
<li>To put it another way</li>
<li>To put it bluntly</li>
<li>To put it succinctly</li>
<li>Ultimately</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me achieve my home gym dream</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-achieve-my-home-gym-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 18:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-achieve-my-home-gym-dream/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to put together a basic home gym in our basement apartment. Mainly, I’m interested in doing squats for now. Then, I’ll expand to deadlifts and benchpress. Our ceilings are too low for overhead presses, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I just ordered the Valor Fitness BD-9 squat rack from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still need a decent Olympic bar and Olympic plates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m trying to put together a basic home gym in our basement apartment. Mainly, I’m interested in doing squats for now. Then, I’ll expand to deadlifts and benchpress. Our ceilings are too low for overhead presses, however.</p>
<p>Anyways, I just ordered the Valor Fitness BD-9 squat rack from Amazon.</p>
<p>I still need a decent Olympic bar and Olympic plates.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Rapoport&#39;s Rules for Better Conversations and Disagreements</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 17:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/use-rapoports-rules-for-better-conversations-and-disagreements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading Walter Sinnott-Armstrong’s excellent book, &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2BNTlTq&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Think Again: How to Reason and Argue&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In it (on pages 25–26), I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Rapoport%27s_Rules&#34;&gt;“Rapoport’s Rules.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First formulated by mathematical psychologist Anatol Rapoport and discussed by Daniel Dennett (&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2NmrH4m&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 31–35), here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1: You should attempt to re-express your target’s position so clearly, vividly, and fairly that your target says, “Thanks, I wish I’d thought of putting it that way.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m reading Walter Sinnott-Armstrong’s excellent book, <a href="https://amzn.to/2BNTlTq"><em>Think Again: How to Reason and Argue</em></a>.</p>
<p>In it (on pages 25–26), I came across <a href="https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Rapoport%27s_Rules">“Rapoport’s Rules.”</a></p>
<p>First formulated by mathematical psychologist Anatol Rapoport and discussed by Daniel Dennett (<a href="https://amzn.to/2NmrH4m"><em>Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking</em></a>, 31–35), here they are:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>1: You should attempt to re-express your target’s position so clearly, vividly, and fairly that your target says, “Thanks, I wish I’d thought of putting it that way.”</p>
<p>2: You should list any points of agreement (especially if they are not matters of general or widespread agreement).</p>
<p>3: You should mention anything you have learned from your target.</p>
<p>4: Only then are you permitted to say so much as a word of rebuttal or criticism.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>How would our conversations—everything from family dinner to classroom discussions to church business meetings—look different if we put these rules into practice?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What blogs are you reading?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m using the RSS readers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inoreader.com/&#34;&gt;Inoreader&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://reederapp.com/&#34;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe to the following blogs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ayjay.org&#34;&gt;Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog&#34;&gt;Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://seths.blog&#34;&gt;Seth’s Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://calnewport.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Study Hacks – Decoding Patterns of Success – Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com&#34;&gt;James Clear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bakadesuyo.com&#34;&gt;Barking Up The Wrong Tree – How to be awesome at life.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://appademic.tech&#34;&gt;The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcsweeneys.net&#34;&gt;McSweeney’s Internet Tendency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com&#34;&gt;Lifehacker – Do everything better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you reading?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Right now, I’m using the RSS readers <a href="https://www.inoreader.com/">Inoreader</a> and <a href="http://reederapp.com/">Reeder</a> to subscribe to the following blogs:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://blog.ayjay.org">Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fs.blog">Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://seths.blog">Seth’s Blog</a></li>
<li><a href="http://calnewport.com/blog/">Study Hacks – Decoding Patterns of Success – Cal Newport</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jamesclear.com">James Clear</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bakadesuyo.com">Barking Up The Wrong Tree – How to be awesome at life.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://appademic.tech">The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.mcsweeneys.net">McSweeney’s Internet Tendency</a></li>
<li><a href="https://lifehacker.com">Lifehacker – Do everything better</a></li>
</ul>
<p>What are you reading?</p>
<p>If you haven’t given RSS readers a try, then <a href="https://feedly.com/">Feedly</a> is a good first RSS reader to try.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me StickK to my writing habit</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need to finish &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/&#34;&gt;this dissertation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I’ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it’s been a bear to get back on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I need to finish <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/">this dissertation</a>.</p>
<p>To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.</p>
<p>Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I’ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it’s been a bear to get back on!</p>
<p>So, I’ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.</p>
<p>If I don’t write 500 words related to my dissertation every day, StickK will donate $35 dollars every week I fail to the NRA.</p>
<p><em>(I do not like the NRA.)</em></p>
<p>I’m giving this a try for 8 weeks. If it works well, I’ll continue the commitment via StickK!</p>
<p>If you’d like to support me and keep track of my progress on StickK, you can do so by clicking <a href="https://stik.to/r2N">here</a>.</p>
<p>If you have a habit you’d like to stick to, give StickK a try!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a fantastic wooden pencil (Mitsubishi 9850)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to give a quick shout-out to this fantastic pencil: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2QcXI2B&#34;&gt;the Mitsubishi 9850&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Mitsubishi-Pencil-pencil-hardness-K9850HB/dp/B001BKZVWU/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;linkCode=li3&amp;amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;linkId=e6e38efe0138c6a5bb4092270163728e&amp;amp;language=en_US&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B001BKZVWU&amp;amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;language=en_US&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=joshuapsteele-20&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;l=li3&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B001BKZVWU&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s cheap, writes well, erases well, and looks great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on wooden pencils, read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-wooden-pencils/pt/633&#34;&gt;this JetPens guide to the best wooden pencils&lt;/a&gt;. And, while you’re at it, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-pencil-sharpeners/pt/710&#34;&gt;JetPens’ recommendations for the best pencil sharpeners&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just wanted to give a quick shout-out to this fantastic pencil: <a href="https://amzn.to/2QcXI2B">the Mitsubishi 9850</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mitsubishi-Pencil-pencil-hardness-K9850HB/dp/B001BKZVWU/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=e6e38efe0138c6a5bb4092270163728e&amp;language=en_US"><img loading="lazy" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B001BKZVWU&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;language=en_US" alt=""  />
</a><img loading="lazy" src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=joshuapsteele-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B001BKZVWU" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>It’s cheap, writes well, erases well, and looks great!</p>
<p>For more on wooden pencils, read <a href="https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-wooden-pencils/pt/633">this JetPens guide to the best wooden pencils</a>. And, while you’re at it, check out <a href="https://www.jetpens.com/blog/the-best-pencil-sharpeners/pt/710">JetPens’ recommendations for the best pencil sharpeners</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s the Template I Use to Take Notes on Books I Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 19:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed from &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2M5AHsy&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/em&gt;, by Mortimer J. Adler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bibliographic-data&#34;&gt;BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author(s):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor(s):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translator(s):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Title and subtitle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Title and subtitle of any larger work that contains the source:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volume:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;URL and date accessed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publisher:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;interpretation&#34;&gt;INTERPRETATION:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of Book (Practical or theoretical?):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subject Matter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems Attempted to Solve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary (What is the book about as a whole?):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outline of Source:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Terms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Propositions/Arguments (What is being said in detail, and how?):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Developed from <a href="https://amzn.to/2M5AHsy"><em>How to Read a Book</em>, by Mortimer J. Adler</a>.</p>
<h1 id="bibliographic-data">BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA:</h1>
<p>Author(s):</p>
<p>Editor(s):</p>
<p>Translator(s):</p>
<p>Title and subtitle:</p>
<p>Title and subtitle of any larger work that contains the source:</p>
<p>Pages:</p>
<p>Volume:</p>
<p>Issue:</p>
<p>Edition:</p>
<p>URL and date accessed:</p>
<p>Publisher:</p>
<p>Place:</p>
<p>Date:</p>
<h1 id="interpretation">INTERPRETATION:</h1>
<p>Kind of Book (Practical or theoretical?):</p>
<p>Subject Matter:</p>
<p>Problems Attempted to Solve:</p>
<p>Summary (What is the book about as a whole?):</p>
<p>Outline of Source:</p>
<p>Key Terms:</p>
<p>Key Propositions/Arguments (What is being said in detail, and how?):</p>
<h1 id="critique">CRITIQUE:</h1>
<p>Is the book true, in whole or part?:</p>
<p>Problems Solved:</p>
<p>Problems Not Solved:</p>
<p>Author is uninformed:</p>
<p>Author is misinformed:</p>
<p>Author is illogical:</p>
<p>Author is incomplete:</p>
<p>What of it? (Why) is it important to know these things?:</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/&#34;&gt;I catalogued a bunch of different takes on Jordan Peterson, before giving my own take&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since that post, two other pieces about Jordan Peterson have been written that I’d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;jordan-peterson-custodian-of-the-patriarchy-by-nellie-bowles-new-york-times&#34;&gt;“Jordan Peterson, Custodian of the Patriarchy,” by Nellie Bowles (New York Times)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/18/style/jordan-peterson-12-rules-for-life.html&#34;&gt;Nellie Bowles writes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Peterson, 55, a University of Toronto psychology professor turned YouTube philosopher turned mystical father figure, has emerged as an influential thought leader. The messages he delivers range from hoary self-help empowerment talk (clean your room, stand up straight) to the more retrograde and political (a society run as a patriarchy makes sense and stems mostly from men’s competence; the notion of white privilege is a farce). He is the stately looking, pedigreed voice for a group of culture warriors who are working diligently to undermine mainstream and liberal efforts to promote equality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Previously, <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/">I catalogued a bunch of different takes on Jordan Peterson, before giving my own take</a>.</p>
<p>Since that post, two other pieces about Jordan Peterson have been written that I’d like to share.</p>
<h1 id="jordan-peterson-custodian-of-the-patriarchy-by-nellie-bowles-new-york-times">“Jordan Peterson, Custodian of the Patriarchy,” by Nellie Bowles (New York Times)</h1>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/18/style/jordan-peterson-12-rules-for-life.html">Nellie Bowles writes</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mr. Peterson, 55, a University of Toronto psychology professor turned YouTube philosopher turned mystical father figure, has emerged as an influential thought leader. The messages he delivers range from hoary self-help empowerment talk (clean your room, stand up straight) to the more retrograde and political (a society run as a patriarchy makes sense and stems mostly from men’s competence; the notion of white privilege is a farce). He is the stately looking, pedigreed voice for a group of culture warriors who are working diligently to undermine mainstream and liberal efforts to promote equality.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Later in the piece, she continues:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“He was angry at God because women were rejecting him,” Mr. Peterson says of the Toronto killer. “The cure for that is enforced monogamy. That’s actually why monogamy emerges.”</p>
<p>Mr. Peterson does not pause when he says this. Enforced monogamy is, to him, simply a rational solution. Otherwise women will all only go for the most high-status men, he explains, and that couldn’t make either gender happy in the end.</p>
<p>“Half the men fail,” he says, meaning that they don’t procreate. “And no one cares about the men who fail.”</p>
<p>I laugh, because it is absurd.</p>
<p>“You’re laughing about them,” he says, giving me a disappointed look. “That’s because you’re female.”</p>
<p>But aside from interventions that would redistribute sex, Mr. Peterson is staunchly against what he calls “equality of outcomes,” or efforts to equalize society. He usually calls them pathological or evil.</p>
<p>He agrees that this is inconsistent. But preventing hordes of single men from violence, he believes, is necessary for the stability of society. Enforced monogamy helps neutralize that.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>OK, here is a perfect example of how easy it is to misunderstand Peterson. When he says “enforced monogamy,” he’s using a technical anthropological term, one that has to do with social norms, and not enforcing monogamy by assigning sexual partners through the use of state (or other) power/violence.</p>
<p><a href="https://jordanbpeterson.com/media/on-the-new-york-times-and-enforced-monogamy/">Peterson himself has attempted to clarify this since the NYT piece</a>, writing:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>So, let’s summarize. Men get frustrated when they are not competitive in the sexual marketplace (note: the fact that they DO get frustrated does not mean that they SHOULD get frustrated. Pointing out the existence of something is not the same as justifying its existence). Frustrated men tend to become dangerous, particularly if they are young. The dangerousness of frustrated young men (even if that frustration stems from their own incompetence) has to be regulated socially. The manifold social conventions tilting most societies toward monogamy constitute such regulation.</p>
<p>That’s all.</p>
<p>No recommendation of police-state assignation of woman to man (or, for that matter, man to woman).</p>
<p>No arbitrary dealing out of damsels to incels.</p>
<p>Nothing scandalous (all innuendo and suggestive editing to the contrary)</p>
<p>Just the plain, bare, common-sense facts: socially-enforced monogamous conventions decrease male violence. In addition (and not trivially) they also help provide mothers with comparatively reliable male partners, and increase the probability that stable, father-intact homes will exist for children.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now, of course, you can still disagree with Peterson’s take here. However, it seems unfair to make it sound like he thinks women should be assigned to men against their wishes.</p>
<h1 id="the-shocking-truth-about-jordan-peterson-by-wesley-yang-tablet">“The Shocking Truth About Jordan Peterson,” by Wesley Yang (Tablet)</h1>
<p>This piece by Wesley Yang is currently my favorite take on Jordan Peterson, because it offers such a nuanced critique.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.tabletmag.com/jewish-news-and-politics/262280/jordan-peterson">Wesley Yang writes</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>There is something uneasily poised at the border of grandiosity and grandeur, heroism and quixotism, about Peterson that makes him appealing to undergraduates at the same time as it makes him a target-rich environment for haughty intellectuals and snarky journalists. There are literally tens of thousands of graduate students and ex-graduate students who know more about the intricacies of postmodern thought than Jordan Peterson does. Peterson’s tweeted and blogged responses to the Times piece are indicative of a person with virtually no sense of how he will be regarded by those who do not share his private system of reference. Why don’t you recognize that I’m not speaking of actual men and women but the symbolic Masculine and Feminine in Jungian archetypal thinking? Why don’t you know that “Enforced Monogamy” is an anthropological term? You won’t understand anything about Jordan Peterson until you realize that his confusion on these questions is entirely sincere.</p>
<p>So what does Peterson actually believe? He has consistently defended the moral position that the “individual is sovereign over the group,” a unique feature of Anglo-American political theory and practice that holds that citizens hold their rights against the state rather than through it, which is inscribed into our founding documents, and helps to account for the remarkable capacity of societies built around its doctrines to accommodate high levels of diversity while remaining democratic. The underlying sovereignty of individuals forces state power to operate against a hard constraint that limits coercion, and gives individuals the means by which to push back.</p>
<p>This position is not a “centrist” position between the poles of alt-right and the identity politics of the left, but a distinct position orthogonal to both. It rejects group identity as the foundation of politics in favor of strengthening the individual as a bulwark against what Peterson calls “ideological possession”—the temptation to subordinate the various ends of life into a contest for group dominance. Peterson sees the emergence of identity politics on both the right and left as a single phenomenon, with each pole feeding the growth of the other, as individuals lost amidst the chaos of contemporary life turn to ideologies providing simple solutions to complex questions, a corresponding set of friends—and a corresponding set of enemies. How anyone who has spent a single afternoon on Twitter can doubt that these polarizing group psychological dynamics exist—and explain the growth of political extremism at a time of relative prosperity—is frankly perplexing to me.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So, on the one hand, Peterson should be held responsible for some of his rhetoric, and he should take a bit more care to ensure that he’s being correctly understood by his various audiences. On the other hand, Peterson’s views are quite MODERATE. He is not the radical right-wing ideologue that many people make him out to be.</p>
<h1 id="whats-your-take-on-jordan-peterson">What’s YOUR take on Jordan Peterson?</h1>
<p>Let me know in the comments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Four Tendencies: 4 Ways You Can Play to Your Personality Strengths</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 18:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In both my personal and coaching conversations recently, Gretchen Rubin’s personality framework called “The Four Tendencies” has really seemed to resonate with people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I thought I would take a few minutes to share it with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;gretchen-rubin-explains-the-four-tendencies&#34;&gt;Gretchen Rubin Explains the Four Tendencies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, here’s a six-minute video of Gretchen herself explaining the Four Tendencies and their relevance to changing one’s habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LIgvEOVT9OE&#34; width=&#34;560&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-do-you-respond-to-inner-expectations-and-outer-expectations&#34;&gt;How do you respond to INNER EXPECTATIONS and OUTER EXPECTATIONS?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the key question that drives the framework. Here are the possible answers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In both my personal and coaching conversations recently, Gretchen Rubin’s personality framework called “The Four Tendencies” has really seemed to resonate with people.</p>
<p>So, I thought I would take a few minutes to share it with you.</p>
<h1 id="gretchen-rubin-explains-the-four-tendencies">Gretchen Rubin Explains the Four Tendencies</h1>
<p>First, here’s a six-minute video of Gretchen herself explaining the Four Tendencies and their relevance to changing one’s habits.</p>
<iframe allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LIgvEOVT9OE" width="560"></iframe>
<h1 id="how-do-you-respond-to-inner-expectations-and-outer-expectations">How do you respond to INNER EXPECTATIONS and OUTER EXPECTATIONS?</h1>
<p>This is the key question that drives the framework. Here are the possible answers.</p>
<h2 id="if-you-readily-meet-both-inner-and-outer-expectations-youre-an-upholder">If you READILY MEET BOTH INNER AND OUTER EXPECTATIONS, you’re an “UPHOLDER”</h2>
<p>Here’s Gretchen Rubin specifically talking about Upholders, her own tendency.</p>
<iframe allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jym9X6ijjio" width="560"></iframe>
<h2 id="if-you-readily-meet-inner-expectations-and-resist-outer-expectations-youre-a-questioner">If you READILY MEET INNER EXPECTATIONS and RESIST OUTER EXPECTATIONS, you’re a “QUESTIONER”</h2>
<p>This is what I am. Questioners basically turn all expectations into <em>inner</em> expectations!</p>
<p>Here’s Gretchen talking about Questioners.</p>
<iframe allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oOQGgbfx9ns" width="560"></iframe>
<h2 id="if-you-readily-meet-outer-expectations-and-resist-inner-expectations-youre-an-obliger">If you READILY MEET OUTER EXPECTATIONS and RESIST INNER EXPECTATIONS, you’re an “OBLIGER”</h2>
<p>Here’s Gretchen talking about Obligers.</p>
<iframe allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CUU99WhRu5Q" width="560"></iframe>
<h2 id="if-you-resist-both-inner-and-outer-expectations-youre-a-rebel">If you RESIST BOTH INNER AND OUTER EXPECTATIONS, you’re a “REBEL”</h2>
<p>Here’s Gretchen talking about Rebels.</p>
<iframe allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jli-sW5LP-Q" width="560"></iframe>
<h1 id="so-which-tendency-are-you-if-youre-not-sure-take-this-free-quiz">So, which tendency are you? If you’re not sure, take this free quiz!</h1>
<p>Gretchen Rubin has provided a free quiz to tell you which one of the four tendencies you are. In just a few minutes, you can be well on your way to benefiting from Rubin’s framework. <a href="https://www.surveygizmo.com/s3/4232520/gretchenrubinfourtendenciesquiz">Click here to take the quiz!</a></p>
<h1 id="heres-why-i-love-this-personality-framework">Here’s why I love this personality framework</h1>
<p>At first glance, it might seem like the BEST tendency is the Upholder and the WORST tendency is the Rebel.</p>
<p>However, while it might be easier in many circumstances for Upholders to change their habits, <strong>each of the four tendencies have their own strengths and weaknesses</strong>.</p>
<p>So, for example, if you’re an Obliger, you’re much better off playing to the strengths of that tendency than trying to move heaven and earth to change yourself into an Upholder!</p>
<p>Yes, be aware of your weaknesses. But play to your personality strengths!</p>
<p>Here are <a href="https://gretchenrubin.com/2017/07/want-to-change-an-important-habit/">Gretchen Rubin’s suggested habit-change strategies for each of the four tendencies</a>.</p>
<h1 id="if-youre-interested-in-learning-more-about-the-four-tendencies-check-out-gretchen-rubins-book">If you’re interested in learning more about the Four Tendencies, check out Gretchen Rubin’s book!</h1>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=B01MU23P0N&asins=B01MU23P0N&linkId=0445100c6ccc7d61cff3c3011a57e9a9&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width:120px;height:240px;"></iframe>
<p>You can also check out these <a href="https://gretchenrubin.com/resources/">free Four Tendencies resources from Gretchen Rubin’s website</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Note: some of the links in this post are <strong>affiliate links</strong>. This means that, if you click on the link and make a purchase, then, at no extra cost to you, I receive a small commission. I only ever recommend resources that I know will benefit my readers! If you’re interested in these resources, buying them through the affiliate links is a way that you can support my work!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hate Running? Try Rucking Instead</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 16:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(DISCLAIMER: You are, of course, more than welcome to try rucking, even if you also love running.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rucking-gt-running&#34;&gt;Rucking &amp;gt; Running&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; time to “fall in love” with running. It did not take me nearly as long to fall &lt;em&gt;out&lt;/em&gt; of love with running!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, even though I’ve long enjoyed &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/&#34;&gt;doing kettlebell swings&lt;/a&gt; and doing &lt;a href=&#34;https://stronglifts.com/5x5/&#34;&gt;the 5×5 weight-lifing workout&lt;/a&gt;, I did begin to miss the benefits of cardio training.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>(DISCLAIMER: You are, of course, more than welcome to try rucking, even if you also love running.)</em></p>
<h1 id="rucking-gt-running">Rucking &gt; Running</h1>
<p>It took me a <em>long</em> time to “fall in love” with running. It did not take me nearly as long to fall <em>out</em> of love with running!</p>
<p>And yet, even though I’ve long enjoyed <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/">doing kettlebell swings</a> and doing <a href="https://stronglifts.com/5x5/">the 5×5 weight-lifing workout</a>, I did begin to miss the benefits of cardio training.</p>
<p>Enter <em>rucking</em>.</p>
<p>I first heard about <em>rucking</em>—carrying a weighted pack on your back—as a form of personal fitness over at <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/articles/the-benefits-of-rucking/">The Art of Manliness</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Rucking is simple. So simple, it’s stupid.<br>
Get a backpack.<br>
Put some weight in said backpack.<br>
Put on the backpack.<br>
Start walking.<br>
That’s it.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="want-to-get-started-heres-how-to-ruck-on-a-budget">Want to Get Started? Here’s How to Ruck on a Budget</h1>
<p>To get started with rucking, I first used my old backpack and a couple dumbbells. This worked fine, but I didn’t like how the dumbbells dug into my lower back.</p>
<p>So, I did some research about rucking on a budget, and I found <a href="http://www.mettleforger.com/how-to-ruck-on-a-budget/">this very helpful blogpost: “How to: Ruck on a Budget.”</a> There’s also <a href="https://www.thesimpledollar.com/a-guide-to-rucking-my-favorite-low-cost-frugal-exercise-activity/">this piece at The Simple Dollar: A Guide to Rucking, My Favorite Low-Cost Exercise Activity.</a></p>
<p>Nevertheless, I picked different gear. Here’s my current rucking setup:</p>
<h2 id="backpack-la-police-gear-3-day-backpack-20">Backpack: LA Police Gear 3 Day Backpack 2.0</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/IMG_4031.jpg" alt="IMG 4031"  title="IMG_4031.JPG"  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/IMG_4032.jpg" alt="IMG 4032"  title="IMG_4032.JPG"  />
</p>
<p>This backpack has held up great for me so far. I use it regularly for rucking, and also <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/dangerous-beauty-phoenix-grand-canyon-trip-2018/">took it with me out to the Grand Canyon, where it performed admirably</a>. I love that it includes a waist and chest strap, as well as a convenient opening for a hydration pack.</p>
<p>You can <a href="https://lapolicegear.com/diplomat-3-day-backpack1.html">buy this pack from LA Police Gear directly</a>, or <a href="https://amzn.to/2JsKE2C">it’s also available on Amazon</a>.</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=B01MZ9PXQV&asins=B01MZ9PXQV&linkId=f58dc2f8674cb1e39f2e9d26837723f8&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width:120px;height:240px;"></iframe>
<h2 id="hydration-pack-source-outdoor-widepac-hydration-system-reservoir-with-helix-bite-valve-2-liter">Hydration Pack: Source Outdoor Widepac Hydration System Reservoir with Helix Bite Valve, 2-Liter</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/IMG_4036.jpg" alt="IMG 4036"  title="IMG_4036.JPG"  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/IMG_4037.jpg" alt="IMG 4037"  title="IMG_4037.JPG"  />
</p>
<p>I sweat a <em>lot</em>, so I figured that it would be nice to have a reliable hydration pack to take with me while rucking.</p>
<p>So far, this 2-liter hydration pack from Source has NOT disappointed me!</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=B004QMDS1G&asins=B004QMDS1G&linkId=f286494baa9002d10bd5a95fd78ff03d&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width:120px;height:240px;"></iframe>
<h2 id="weight-bricks-and-duct-tape">Weight: Bricks and Duct Tape</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/IMG_4033.jpg" alt="IMG 4033"  title="IMG_4033.JPG"  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/IMG_4034.jpg" alt="IMG 4034"  title="IMG_4034.JPG"  />
</p>
<p>I believe that the bricks I currently use came from Home Depot. I could be mistaken, but I think that I have 6 of <a href="https://www.homedepot.com/p/Holland-7-75-in-x-4-in-x-1-75-in-River-Red-Concrete-Paver-22051EA/100619492">these Holland 7.75 in. x 4 in. x 1.75 in. River Red Concrete Paver</a> bricks. Currently, they’re listed for $0.58 each.</p>
<p>As for duct tape, I’m pretty sure I used good ol’ fashioned Duck Brand duct tape.</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=B0006HX2MK&asins=B0006HX2MK&linkId=24bcb61af9da3e015fc7748a328df51a&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width:120px;height:240px;"></iframe>
<p>I also used some <a href="https://www.walmart.com/browse/office/bubble-wrap/1229749_2696828_1478303_5636662">bubble wrap that I picked up at Walmart</a>.</p>
<p>Here’s <a href="http://news.goruck.com/event-news/wrapping-bricks-explained/">a helpful guide to wrapping bricks from GoRuck</a>.</p>
<h2 id="to-position-the-bricks-2-foam-yoga-blocksbricks">To Position the Bricks: 2 Foam Yoga Blocks/Bricks</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/IMG_4035.jpg" alt="IMG 4035"  title="IMG_4035.JPG"  />
</p>
<p>I don’t think this is necessary, but I went out and bought <a href="https://www.walmart.com/ip/YOGA-BLOCK-BLUE/54193774">two foam yoga blocks/bricks from Walmart</a> in order to position the bricks a bit higher in the backpack.</p>
<p>You could also go with these from Amazon. Just make sure that the yoga blocks are big enough to support the stack of bricks you end up using (or whatever other weights you end up using).</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=B01MDMDDFH&asins=B01MDMDDFH&linkId=3ce9cfdcbd606c7e10f09cae0dfdb5d4&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width:120px;height:240px;"></iframe>
<hr>
<h1 id="want-to-learn-more-about-rucking">Want to Learn More About Rucking?</h1>
<p>To learn more about rucking, I highly recommend <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/articles/the-benefits-of-rucking/">this Art of Manliness blogpost, “Cardio for the Man Who Hates Cardio: The Benefits of Rucking,”</a> as well as <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/articles/podcast-314-building-better-citizens-rucking/">this Art of Manliness podcast episode about rucking, “Podcast #314: Building Better Citizens Through Rucking.”</a></p>
<p>Also, check out <a href="https://www.goruck.com/what-is-rucking/">this great resource from GoRuck, “What is Rucking?,”</a> which features the following video:</p>
<iframe allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LqoyqYxGTW0" width="560"></iframe>
<h1 id="got-questions-about-rucking-ask-them-in-the-comments-below">Got Questions About Rucking? Ask Them in the Comments Below!</h1>
<hr>
<p><em>Note: some of the links in this post above are <strong>affiliate links</strong>. This means that, if you click on the link and make a purchase, then, at no extra cost to you, I receive a small commission. I only ever recommend resources that I know will benefit my readers! If you’re interested in these resources, buying them through the affiliate links is a way that you can support my work!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to make of Jordan Peterson? Some takes, then my own.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: Read my post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/&#34;&gt;“Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I remember correctly, I first heard of and listened to Jordan Peterson on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2017/08/31/podcast-335-using-power-myths-live-flourishing-life/&#34;&gt;an episode of The Art of Manliness podcast&lt;/a&gt;. (Or perhaps it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/06/12-rules-for-life-jordan-peterson-interview/&#34;&gt;this episode&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;however-i-could-be-mistaken-because-petersons-been-popping-up-in-conversation-all-over-the-place-in-my-circles&#34;&gt;However, I could be mistaken, because Peterson’s been popping up in conversation all over the place in my circles.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blog posts, podcast episodes, conversations with friends – Peterson has been popping up everywhere, so it seems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>UPDATE: Read my post, <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/">“Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson.”</a></em></p>
<p>If I remember correctly, I first heard of and listened to Jordan Peterson on <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/2017/08/31/podcast-335-using-power-myths-live-flourishing-life/">an episode of The Art of Manliness podcast</a>. (Or perhaps it was <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/06/12-rules-for-life-jordan-peterson-interview/">this episode</a>.)</p>
<h1 id="however-i-could-be-mistaken-because-petersons-been-popping-up-in-conversation-all-over-the-place-in-my-circles">However, I could be mistaken, because Peterson’s been popping up in conversation all over the place in my circles.</h1>
<p>Blog posts, podcast episodes, conversations with friends – Peterson has been popping up everywhere, so it seems.</p>
<h2 id="gerald-mcdermotts-take">Gerald McDermott’s Take</h2>
<p>My <a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/northamptonseminar/2018/02/03/biblical-wisdom-secular-psychologist/">old seminary professor, Gerald McDermott</a>, has blogged about Peterson’s new book, “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/12-Rules-Life-Antidote-Chaos/dp/0345816021/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1522244418&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=12+rules+for+life&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=joshuapsteele-20&amp;linkId=3dbfc723801c4d44e8f654a5e7da752c">12 Rules for Life: an Antidote to Chaos</a>,” saying:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It is a good book, blunt and inspiring.</p>
<p>We live in a time when so many young (and not so young) people feel lost, unsure of how they should approach their lives, or life in general. Mr. Peterson talks about the attitudes that will help find the path. It is not a politically correct or officially approved path, but it is an intensely practical and yet heightened one: This life you’re living has meaning.</p>
</blockquote>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=0345816021&asins=0345816021&linkId=798f148b4266de5cd4854d35961356ee&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width: 120px; height: 240px;"></iframe>
<h2 id="scot-mcknights-blogs-patrick-mitchells-take">Scot McKnight’s Blog’s (Patrick Mitchell’s) Take</h2>
<p>Furthermore, <a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/jesuscreed/2018/01/29/jordan-petersons-12-rules/">Scot McKnight blogged (or rather, published a guest post by Patrick Mitchell) about Peterson’s 12 Rules</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is he saying?</p>
<p>This is a big question because, as he says himself, he talks a lot, often too much and often at speed. He also covers a lot of ground from psychology, to philosophy, to men and women, to the Bible, to politics, to the world of work and freedom of speech. What follows is a snap-shot, drawn from listening to Peterson over the last year.</p>
<p>And the fact that what he is saying is now seen as ‘provocative’ or ‘radical’ or ‘patriarchal’ or ‘extreme’ says more about a contemporary culture of relativism and victimhood than it does about Peterson. Finding out more about his ‘reputation’, I have had to keep asking myself, ‘am I missing something?’. ‘Is this guy a member of some secret right-wing network?’ For I can’t see the evidence in his academic lectures, written material or YouTube videos.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The rest of the post is <a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/jesuscreed/2018/01/29/jordan-petersons-12-rules/">a pretty detailed look at various aspects of Peterson’s thought</a>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-infamous-channel-4-interview">The Infamous Channel 4 Interview</h2>
<p>Both of those blogs mention Peterson’s now infamous Channel 4 interview where Cathy Newman adopts some pretty aggressive and apparently unfair interviewing tactics (listen for “so you’re saying…,” followed by caricatures of Peterson’s claims):</p>
<iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aMcjxSThD54?rel=0" width="560"></iframe>
<hr>
<h1 id="other-takes-on-peterson">Other Takes on Peterson</h1>
<hr>
<p>First, here are a couple explicitly “theological” takes:</p>
<h2 id="first-things-jordan-peterson-unlikely-guru-matthew-schmitz">First Things: “Jordan Peterson, Unlikely Guru” (Matthew Schmitz)</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.firstthings.com/article/2018/04/jordan-peterson-unlikely-guru">Schmitz’s entire piece</a> is worth reading, but here was the kicker, in my opinion:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What critics and fans alike miss is just how unlikely a guru Peterson is. Though he brims with sympathy for the confused, he is uncertain about where they should go. He advocates for rules but is vague on who should set them. He believes in the importance of religion, but he doesn’t quite have one.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Schmitz concludes the piece with:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Young men look to Peterson for answers, but he is still turning the kaleidoscope, searching for pattern and form. Earlier this year, an interviewer for VICE asked him, “Who is your target audience, who are you trying to reach?” With eyes downcast he said, “Partly me.”</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="think-theology-peterson-driscoll-and-the-millenial-man-matthew-hosier">Think Theology: “Peterson, Driscoll, and the Millenial Man” (Matthew Hosier)</h2>
<p><a href="http://thinktheology.co.uk/blog/article/peterson_driscoll_the_millennial_man">Mathew Hosier, at Think Theology, confesses that some of Peterson’s talk of personal responsibility reminds him of Mark Driscoll</a>. Nevertheless, he admits that he thinks Peterson is different than Driscoll:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Whatever the rights and wrongs of what happened at Mars Hill, it is undeniable that Driscoll’s genius was connecting with and motivating young men. They responded in their droves to his yelling at them to take responsibility for themselves and others. He painted a picture of the possible that was more compelling for many Millennials than the needs-based, rights-oriented culture in which they had been raised.</p>
<p>Peterson has observed how his lectures attract a surprisingly large number of young men too. Peterson is a very different character from Driscoll, but his challenge to young men to ‘pick up the heaviest rock you can and carry it’ is strikingly similar. Many Millennial young men seem confused about what it is to be a man and something leaps in them when another man tells them what they can do about it: shoulder a load, take some responsibility, clean your room and make life better for you and for those around you.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p>Other, less (explicitly) theological takes on Peterson abound:</p>
<h2 id="the-atlantic-why-cant-people-hear-what-jordan-peterson-is-saying-connor-friesdorf">The Atlantic: “Why Can’t People Hear What Jordan Peterson is saying?” (Connor Friesdorf)</h2>
<p>Focusing on the Channel 4 interview, Friesdorf concludes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>…this is neither an endorsement nor a condemnation of Peterson’s views. It is an argument that the effects of the approach used in this interview are pernicious.</p>
<p>For one, those who credulously accept the interviewer’s characterizations will emerge with the impression that a prominent academic holds troubling views that, in fact, he does not actually believe or advocate. Some will feel needlessly troubled. And distorted impressions of what figures like Peterson mean by the words that they speak can only exacerbate overall polarization between their followers and others, and sap their critics of credibility to push back where they are wrong.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="vox-jordan-peterson-explained-zack-beauchamp">Vox: “Jordan Peterson, Explained” (Zack Beauchamp)</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2018/3/26/17144166/jordan-peterson-12-rules-for-life">Zack Beauchamp has a long write-up on Jordan Peterson in Vox magazine</a>, which concludes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But Peterson has inextricably intertwined his self-help approach with a kind of reactionary politics that validates white, straight, and cisgender men at the expense of everyone else. He gives them a sense of purpose by, in part, tearing other people down — by insisting that the world can and should revolve around them and their problems.</p>
<p>This painful contrast is on display later in that very interview, in which he explicitly argues that concern for sexism is to blame for the plight of the West’s young men.</p>
<p>“We’re so stupid. We’re alienating young men. We’re telling them that they’re patriarchal oppressors and denizens of rape culture,” he says. “It’s awful. It’s so destructive. It’s so unnecessary. And it’s so sad.”</p>
<p>The empathy that he displays for men and boys in his BBC interview and 12 Rules for Life is touching. The problem is that he can’t seem to extend it to anyone else.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>NOTE: From what I know of Peterson, Beauchamp’s take strikes me as unfair. Peterson himself isn’t trying to validate “white, straight, and cisgender men at the expense of everyone else</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-new-york-times-the-jordan-peterson-moment-david-brooks">The New York Times: “The Jordan Peterson Moment” (David Brooks)</h2>
<p>In my opinion, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/25/opinion/jordan-peterson-moment.html">David Brooks hits the nail on the head here</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Much of Peterson’s advice sounds to me like vague exhortatory banality. Like Hobbes and Nietzsche before him, he seems to imagine an overly brutalistic universe, nearly without benevolence, beauty, attachment and love. His recipe for self-improvement is solitary, nonrelational, unemotional. I’d say the lives of young men can be improved more through loving attachment than through Peterson’s joyless and graceless calls to self-sacrifice.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, I wouldn’t exactly call Peterson’s calls to self-sacrifice “joyless and graceless.”</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-new-yorker-jordan-petersons-gospel-of-masculinity-kelefa-sanneh">The New Yorker: “Jordan Peterson’s Gospel of Masculinity” (Kelefa Sanneh)</h2>
<p>Similarly, I think that <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/03/05/jordan-petersons-gospel-of-masculinity">Kelefa Sanneh hits the nail on the head here</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Peterson sometimes asks audiences to view him as an alternative to political excesses on both sides. During an interview on BBC Radio 5, he said, “I’ve had thousands of letters from people who were tempted by the blandishments of the radical right, who’ve moved towards the reasonable center as a consequence of watching my videos.” But he typically sees liberals, or leftists, or “postmodernists,” as aggressors—which leads him, rather ironically, to frame some of those on the “radical right” as victims. Many of his political stances are built on this type of inversion. Postmodernists, he says, are obsessed with the idea of oppression, and, by waging war on oppressors real and imagined, they become oppressors themselves. Liberals, he says, are always talking about the importance of compassion—and yet “there’s nothing more horrible for children, and developing people, than an excess of compassion.” (This horror, he says, is embodied in the figure of the “Freudian devouring mother”; as an example, he cites Ursula, the sea witch from “The Little Mermaid.”) The danger, it seems, is that those who want to improve Western society may end up destroying it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Alright, time for some thoughts of my own.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="my-current-take-on-jordan-peterson">My Current Take on Jordan Peterson</h1>
<h2 id="first-hes-definitely-on-to-something">First, he’s definitely on to something.</h2>
<p>There’s no denying it, Jordan Peterson is striking a chord. And, I believe, that’s at least partially due to the fact that he’s RIGHT.</p>
<p>Despite the existence of structural sins and systems of oppression, it simply will not do to blame the world for all of one’s problems. At some point, we must take responsibility for our own lives.</p>
<p>I believe that the Christian doctrine of the imago Dei — of humans being created in the image of God — can theologically underwrite Peterson’s emphasis on responsibility. We humans have been created by God and given stewardship over the earth (see Genesis 1-2). Perhaps, despite the effects of the Fall (see Genesis 3), we have more control over our lives than we might realize.</p>
<p>Furthermore, there’s plenty of content in biblical Wisdom Literature (see Proverbs and Ecclesiastes, especially) to support what Peterson is saying about how to live your life in a way that fights back against the chaos of the world.</p>
<h2 id="and-yet-his-individualism-worries-me">And yet, his individualism worries me.</h2>
<p>Sure, we’re created in the imago Dei, and that means we have control and responsibility for our lives.</p>
<p>And yet, humans are communal creatures. So, if we overemphasize <em>individual</em> responsibility, we might end up underemphasizing the ways in which we are responsible for one another, including — and especially — the oppressed and the outcasts.</p>
<p>Now, Peterson is prone to claim that any talk of systemic oppression these days is due to the Radical Left, but I don’t buy his over-generalizations on that count. The Bible seems to bear witness to the existence of structural sin, and Christians must take systems of oppression into account as they discern how to follow Jesus.</p>
<p>Granted, Peterson isn’t simply saying “it’s every man for himself, forget about the losers.” He’s much more nuanced than that.</p>
<p>But still, I find his views of the world — at least as expressed in 12 Rules for Life — to be more individualistic than the account I see in Christian Scripture.</p>
<h2 id="furthermore-he-seems-to-fall-into-the-very-trap-he-attempts-to-avoid-victimhood">Furthermore, he seems to fall into the very trap he attempts to avoid: victimhood.</h2>
<p>Peterson is trying to provide an alternative, a middle way, to the Radical Left and the Radical Right. However, some of his rhetoric about the Radical Left — justified though it may be in certain circumstances, given what appear to be widespread mischaracterizations of his thought! — sometimes seem to fall into the very trap of “victimhood” that he encourages his audience to avoid.</p>
<p>It goes something like this: Peterson claims that it’s the Radical Left that’s oppressing people — specifically, men — by insisting that people are either oppressors or the oppressed.</p>
<p>Again, Peterson’s not flat-footed or unnuanced about this, but in some of his less-careful moments, he seems to fall into what he’s labeling as the Radical Left’s trap by painting himself and his audience as victims of a Radical Leftist conspiracy theory.</p>
<p>Then again, perhaps that’s because Peterson’s been the target of quite a few misinterpretations and attacks. Maybe he gets some grace to have certain less-careful moments, as it were.</p>
<p>And yet, if he’s <em>really</em> going to provide a middle way between Right and Left ideologies, he needs to avoid the victim/oppressed rhetoric consistently.</p>
<h2 id="finally-he-plays-fast-and-loose-with-divine-revelation-and-religious-traditions">Finally, he plays fast and loose with divine revelation and religious traditions.</h2>
<p>I think it’s great that Peterson has respect for religion and religious narratives.</p>
<p>And yet, I think it’s pretty awful that Peterson feels free to float lightly above all religious narratives and basically craft a Petersonian “meta-religion” of his own out of the bits and pieces of religious narratives that he finds most useful and compelling.</p>
<p>Sure, sometimes his theological interpretation of biblical texts seems pretty thought-provoking, excellent, and faithful to the Christian tradition. However, at other times I find myself bracing at the idiosyncrasies of his interpretations — not to mention the ease with which he pulls in building blocks from various traditions to craft his own narrative. It makes me wonder if adherents of other religious traditions would feel a similar unease when their narratives are used in such a construction project.</p>
<p>By respecting all/most religious traditions, Peterson may very well end up respecting no particular religious tradition. As a Christian theologian, I find that troublesome.</p>
<h2 id="hes-worth-reading">He’s worth reading.</h2>
<p>After listening to the book on Audible, I bought myself a physical copy of 12 Rules for Life.</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=0345816021&asins=0345816021&linkId=798f148b4266de5cd4854d35961356ee&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width: 120px; height: 240px;"></iframe>
<p>I plan to read the book again and discuss it with friends. It’s currently the top non-fiction book on Amazon for good reason: it’s thought-provoking and it will get you thinking deeper about how to live your life in this world.</p>
<p>Those Amazon links above are affiliate links. It’s a no-extra-cost way to support my writing. If you click the link and buy something, I get a small commission.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="if-you-do-end-up-reading-or-listening-to-peterson-let-me-know-what-you-think">If you do end up reading or listening to Peterson, let me know what you think!</h1>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do More Better: Tim Challies&#39; Excellent Little Book on Personal Productivity Could Change Your Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tim Challies begins his book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2ufosG4&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do More Better: A Practical Guide to Productivity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with a bold claim: “I believe this book can improve your life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after reading the book, which is just 120 pages long including endnotes!, I believe that Challies makes good on his claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=1941114172&amp;asins=1941114172&amp;linkId=61476ee8a72a820b76e43d746b704020&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as explicitly Christian approaches to personal productivity go, Challies’ &lt;em&gt;Do More Better&lt;/em&gt; stands alongside &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2uf5r6A&#34;&gt;Matt Perman’s &lt;em&gt;What’s Best Next: How the Gospel Transforms the Way You Get Things Done&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While Perman’s book is fantastic and thorough, Challies’ book has the advantage of being MUCH shorter (120 pages vs. 383 pages).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tim Challies begins his book, <a href="http://amzn.to/2ufosG4"><em>Do More Better: A Practical Guide to Productivity</em></a> with a bold claim: “I believe this book can improve your life.”</p>
<p>However, after reading the book, which is just 120 pages long including endnotes!, I believe that Challies makes good on his claim.</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=1941114172&asins=1941114172&linkId=61476ee8a72a820b76e43d746b704020&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width:120px;height:240px;"></iframe>
<p>As far as explicitly Christian approaches to personal productivity go, Challies’ <em>Do More Better</em> stands alongside <a href="http://amzn.to/2uf5r6A">Matt Perman’s <em>What’s Best Next: How the Gospel Transforms the Way You Get Things Done</em></a>. While Perman’s book is fantastic and thorough, Challies’ book has the advantage of being MUCH shorter (120 pages vs. 383 pages).</p>
<h3 id="put-simply-as-far-as-bang-for-the-buck-or-bang-for-the-page-do-more-better-is-the-best-reading-recommendation-i-can-make-if-youd-like-to-learn-more-about-a-christian-approach-to-personal-productivity">Put simply, as far as bang-for-the-buck (or bang-for-the-page), <em>Do More Better</em> is the best reading recommendation I can make if you’d like to learn more about a Christian approach to personal productivity.</h3>
<hr>
<h1 id="do-more-better-an-overview"><em>Do More Better</em>, An Overview</h1>
<h2 id="know-your-purpose">Know Your Purpose</h2>
<p><strong>Chapter one, Know Your Purpose</strong>, is devoted to the maxim that, <strong>as a Christian, your purpose is to glorify God by doing good to others.</strong></p>
<h2 id="answer-the-call">Answer the Call</h2>
<p>In <strong>chapter two, Answer the Call</strong>, Challies discusses the “Producitivity Thieves” of Laziness, Busyness, “BusyLazy,” and Thorns &amp; Thistles. He also places personal productivity in its proper context in the Christian life, rightly stating that:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“God calls you to productivity, but he calls you to the right kind of productivity. He calls you to be productive for his sake, not your own. While this book will emphasize tools and systems and other important elements of productivity, nothing is more important than your own holiness and your own godliness. No amount of organization and time management will compensate for a lack of Christian character, not when it comes to this great calling of glory through good — bringing glory to God by doing good to others” (25).</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="define-your-responsibilities">Define Your Responsibilities</h2>
<p>In <strong>chapter three, Define Your Responsibilities</strong>, Challies walks us through the process of defining and listing the various <strong>areas of responsibility</strong> in our lives (Personal, Family, Church, School, Work, Social, etc.), as well as our <strong>roles</strong> within those various areas of responsibility. Defining and listing both of these things provides the map/framework for what follows.</p>
<h2 id="state-your-mission">State Your Mission</h2>
<p>In <strong>chapter four, State Your Mission</strong>, Challies covers the process of developing mission/purpose statements for each of the Areas of Responsibility from chapter three. This completes the “audit” of one’s life, before moving on to the <strong>tools of productivity in chapter five</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="select-your-tools">Select Your Tools</h2>
<p>This is where things get really practical.</p>
<p>According to Challies, everyone needs the following three tools:</p>
<ul>
<li>A Task Management Tool (he recommends <a href="https://todoist.com/">ToDoist</a>, which I also use)</li>
<li>A Scheduling Tool (he recommends <a href="https://calendar.google.com/">Google Calendar</a>, which I also use)</li>
<li>An Information Tool (he recommends <a href="https://evernote.com/">Evernote</a>, which I also use)</li>
</ul>
<p>He also introduces the extremely important productivity principle: <strong>a home for everything, and like goes with like.</strong></p>
<h2 id="collect-your-tasks-plan-your-calendar-and-gather-your-information">Collect Your Tasks, Plan Your Calendar, and Gather Your Information</h2>
<p>In <strong>chapter six, Collect Your Tasks</strong>, Challies walks us through the process of setting up and beginning to use ToDoist. <strong>Chapter seven, Plan Your Calendar</strong>, is devoted to setting up and using Google Calendar. <strong>Chapter eight, Gather Your Information</strong>, is (you guessed it) devoted to setting up and using Evernote.</p>
<p>These three chapters are insanely helpful if you’re not already familiar with these three powerful tools!</p>
<h2 id="live-the-system">Live the System</h2>
<p>In <strong>chapter nine, Live the System</strong>, Challies covers how the three productivity tools work together in a cohesive personal productivity system on a daily level. This chapter contains a bunch of helpful information on how to prioritize and structure your day.</p>
<h2 id="maintain-it-consistently">Maintain it Consistently</h2>
<p><strong>Chapter ten, Maintain It Consistently</strong>, expands the horizon of focus to the weekly level. Challies walks us through the important process of the Weekly Review, focusing on the power of checklists and how we can “serve and surprise” in each of our areas of responsibilities and roles.</p>
<h2 id="bonus-material">Bonus Material</h2>
<p>As a <strong>bonus</strong>, <em>Do More Better</em> ends with <strong>6 Tips for Doing More Better with Email</strong> and <strong>20 Tips to Increase Your Productivity</strong>. My favorite tip from this section of the book is “6. Create a Not-To-Do-List”!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Create a note within Evernote that will contain a not-to-do-list. Make this a list of bad productivity habits you are trying to break, and go over this list each week during your weekly review. My not-to-do-list includes ‘Do not dring coffee after 2 p.m.,’ ‘Do not leave email open all day,’ and ‘Do not agree to meethings that have no agenda or no end-time’ (116-17).”</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 id="again-i-know-of-no-better-briefer-christian-approach-to-personal-productivity-than-do-more-better">Again, I know of no better, briefer Christian approach to personal productivity than <em>Do More Better</em></h2>
<p>If you’re looking for a personal productivity system of your own, in order to do more for the glory of God and the good of others, pick up Challies’ book today!</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=1941114172&asins=1941114172&linkId=61476ee8a72a820b76e43d746b704020&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width:120px;height:240px;"></iframe>
<hr>
<h2 id="want-to-read-more-about-productivity">Want to read more about productivity?</h2>
<p>If you’re currently a student, especially in high school or college, check out <a href="http://amzn.to/2uccsVV">Challies’ student edition of <em>Do More Better</em></a>:</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=1941114466&asins=1941114466&linkId=9f8e9fa77d5655fcc916247c84ffebf0&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width:120px;height:240px;"></iframe>
<p>Otherwise, if you’d like an even deeper dive into a Christian approach to productivity, the best book I know of is <a href="http://amzn.to/2uf5r6A">Matt Perman’s <em>What’s Best Next: How the Gospel Transforms the Way You Get Things Done</em></a>:</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ss&ref=as_ss_li_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=0310533988&asins=0310533988&linkId=0d72c8e86dce16547132ded926f625c6&show_border=true&link_opens_in_new_window=true" style="width:120px;height:240px;"></iframe>
<hr>
<p><em>Note: some links above are Amazon affiliate links. This means that, if you click the link and make a purchase, then (at no extra cost to you) I receive a small commission. However, I only ever recommend products that I think will benefit my readers!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Need to Develop a Writing Habit. Do You?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because good writing = good thinking, I believe that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; could benefit from developing the habit of regular writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, because I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am a Ph.D. student about to begin work on his dissertation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit a blog (&lt;a href=&#34;http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/&#34;&gt;Rookie Anglican&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write this personal blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need to develop the habit of regular writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until now, I’ve largely relied upon writing in fits and starts, when the Muse descends, as it were.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Because good writing = good thinking, I believe that <em>everyone</em> could benefit from developing the habit of regular writing.</p>
<p>However, because I</p>
<ul>
<li>Am a Ph.D. student about to begin work on his dissertation</li>
<li>Edit a blog (<a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/">Rookie Anglican</a>)</li>
<li>Write this personal blog</li>
</ul>
<p>I <em>really</em> need to develop the habit of regular writing.</p>
<p>Up until now, I’ve largely relied upon writing in fits and starts, when the Muse descends, as it were.</p>
<p>This, however, is not good enough (as Stephen Pressfield forcefully says in his book, <a href="http://amzn.to/2DDHfu7"><em>The War of Art: Break Through the Blocks and Win Your Inner Creative Battles</em></a>). It won’t get my dissertation written, nor will it help me stay on top of two different blogs!</p>
<p>What’s the solution? A regular writing habit, day in and day out.</p>
<h1 id="how-to-developchange-a-habit">How to develop/change a habit</h1>
<p>There are plenty of guides out there on the internet about the process of habit formation. Here are a few:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://jamesclear.com/habits">The Habits Guide: How to Build Good Habits and Break Bad Ones </a>[James Clear]</li>
<li><a href="https://www.npr.org/2012/03/05/147192599/habits-how-they-form-and-how-to-break-them">Habits: How They Form and How to Break Them</a> [NPR]</li>
<li><a href="https://zenhabits.net/habitses/">The Four Habits that Form Habits</a> [Zen Habits]</li>
</ul>
<p>Furthermore, there are two excellent books on habit formation that I highly recommend:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2HHVT5Z"><em>The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business</em></a> by Charles Duhigg</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2pnd5Xz"><em>Better than Before: What I Learned About Making and Breaking Habits–to Sleep More, Quit Sugar, Procrastinate Less, and Generally Build a Happier Life</em></a> by Gretchen Rubin</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="habit--trigger--behavior--reward">Habit = Trigger + Behavior + Reward</h2>
<p>If you look through those resources, you’ll notice a particular model that appears again and again. A habit boils down to three things (this version of the framework mainly comes from Charles Duhigg’s <a href="http://amzn.to/2pkxfBO"><em>The Power of Habit</em></a><em>.</em> You can read the appendix of the book for free <a href="http://charlesduhigg.com/how-habits-work/">here</a>.) :</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>TRIGGER</strong>: The cue or reminder that prompts the behavior. Frequently, cues involve
<ul>
<li>Time</li>
<li>Location</li>
<li>People (who are you with?)</li>
<li>Preceding Action (what did you just do?)</li>
<li>Emotion</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>BEHAVIOR</strong>: The behavior itself, whether something good for you, like writing 500 words every day, or something bad for you, like smoking a pack of cigarettes.</li>
<li><strong>REWARD</strong>: The benefit you get from the behavior.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="to-change-an-old-habit-taken-from-this-helpful-flowcharthttpcharlesduhiggcomwp-contentuploads201404flowchart-how-to-change-a-habitpdf-from-charles-duhigg">To change an old habit (taken from <a href="http://charlesduhigg.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Flowchart-How-to-Change-a-Habit.pdf">this helpful flowchart</a> from Charles Duhigg):</h2>
<ul>
<li>Isolate the consistent TRIGGER. When you feel the craving to do the thing you’re trying to stop doing, ask yourself:
<ul>
<li>What time is it?</li>
<li>Where are you?</li>
<li>Who else is around?</li>
<li>What did you just do?</li>
<li>What emotion are you feeling?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Isolate the consistent REWARD. What benefit/craving is this habit providing/satisfying? Come up with an idea and test the theory by substituting different rewards until you find something that makes the craving goes away. This is what you’re really craving as a result of the behavior.</li>
<li>Insert a new BEHAVIOR between the trigger and the reward.
<ul>
<li>Choose a new activity that is triggered by the old trigger and provides the old reward.</li>
<li>Write this commitment down in the following form: “When [TRIGGER occurs], I will [do the new BEHAVIOR], because it provides me with [the REWARD].”</li>
<li>Follow through on your plan!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="to-develop-a-new-habit-taken-from-this-helpful-flowcharthttpcharlesduhiggcomwp-contentuploads201404flowchart-how-to-create-a-habitpdf-from-charles-duhigg">To develop a new habit (taken from <a href="http://charlesduhigg.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Flowchart-How-to-Create-a-Habit.pdf">this helpful flowchart</a> from Charles Duhigg):</h2>
<ul>
<li>Come up with a TRIGGER:
<ul>
<li>Time?</li>
<li>Location?</li>
<li>People around?</li>
<li>Immediately preceding action?</li>
<li>Emotion?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Come up with a REWARD for after the behavior:
<ul>
<li>Make sure you actually enjoy it!</li>
<li>Make sure that you crave this reward when exposed to the trigger from the previous step!</li>
<li>Ideally, you will eventually desire the habit for its intrinsic reward. That’s what you’re shooting for.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Insert the BEHAVIOR into a routine:
<ul>
<li>Write it down in the following form: “When [TRIGGER occurs], I will [perform desired BEHAVIOR], because it provides me with [the REWARD].”</li>
<li>Follow through on your plan!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="how-to-develop-a-writing-habit-my-example">How to develop a writing habit: my example</h1>
<p>In theory, it’s pretty simple, actually. We just need to take the previous outline, for how to develop a new habit, and apply it to the specific behavior of writing consistently. 500 words a day is a great goal, and it’s the one I’ll be using.</p>
<p>First, however, we need a TRIGGER. For me, the trigger I’m going to try out for the next few days is “When I arrive at the library in the morning, before doing anything else…”</p>
<p>The REWARD I’m going to experiment with is: “…I will go for a 20-minute walk outside.”</p>
<p>Put together, my commitment looks like: “When I arrive at the library in the morning, before doing anything else, I will write 500 words, because then I get to go for a 20-minute walk outside.”</p>
<h1 id="what-about-you-what-will-your-writing-habit-look-like">What about you? What will your writing habit look like?</h1>
<p>Would you like to create a writing habit?</p>
<p>If so, what’s your trigger going to be?</p>
<p>What’s your reward going to be?</p>
<p>What’s your writing behavior going to look like? How often will you write? How many words?</p>
<h1 id="get-specific-let-me-know-what-youre-planning-in-the-comments-below"><strong>Get specific! Let me know what you’re planning in the comments below!</strong></h1>
<hr>
<p><em>Note: some of the links above are Amazon affiliate links. This means that, if you click the link and make a purchase on Amazon, I receive a small commission (at no extra cost to you). I only ever recommend things I think that my readers will find helpful.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting back on the &#34;Getting Things Done&#34; Productivity Bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 22:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting Things Done (“GTD” for short) is a wildly popular personal productivity system invented and popularized by David Allen. However, as &lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com/getting-things-done-ten-years-in-1795707084&#34;&gt;Nicole Dieker at Lifehacker pointed out in 2017&lt;/a&gt;, “You don’t hear a lot of people talk about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; productivity system anymore.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that’s a shame, because it’s a very effective system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first tried Getting Things Done after reading “&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2tMiX1w&#34;&gt;What’s Best Nex&lt;/a&gt;t” by Matt Perman, and then reading “&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2HvNJxv&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt;” by David Allen (in its newly revised 2015 edition) shortly thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Getting Things Done (“GTD” for short) is a wildly popular personal productivity system invented and popularized by David Allen. However, as <a href="https://lifehacker.com/getting-things-done-ten-years-in-1795707084">Nicole Dieker at Lifehacker pointed out in 2017</a>, “You don’t hear a lot of people talk about the <a href="http://gettingthingsdone.com/"><em>Getting Things Done</em></a> productivity system anymore.”</p>
<p>I think that’s a shame, because it’s a very effective system.</p>
<p>I first tried Getting Things Done after reading “<a href="http://amzn.to/2tMiX1w">What’s Best Nex</a>t” by Matt Perman, and then reading “<a href="http://amzn.to/2HvNJxv">Getting Things Done</a>” by David Allen (in its newly revised 2015 edition) shortly thereafter.</p>
<p>At its core, GTD revolves around the following idea from David Allen:</p>
<h3 id="your-mind-is-for-having-ideas-not-holding-them">“Your mind is for having ideas, not holding them.”</h3>
<p>What’s that mean? Well, your brain does a much better job of coming up with random things than with keeping track of them. Therefore, if you don’t have a system in place for reliably and comprehensively keeping track of all the random “open loops” your brain comes up with throughout the day, you will use up a lot of your mental bandwidth trying to keep track of all those things, instead of moving forward on them.</p>
<p>Enter the GTD system. It’s designed to solve the problem of keeping track of the “open loops” your brain comes up with, whether “I need to buy milk” or “I need to revamp my blog.”</p>
<h1 id="the-pillars-of-gtd">The “Pillars” of GTD</h1>
<ol>
<li><strong>Capture</strong>. Think on paper. Get stuff out of your head and into a list.</li>
<li><strong>Clarify</strong>. Decide whether or not each item on your list is an action, a project, something to delete, defer, or delegate, etc. Check out this <a href="https://gettingthingsdone.com/pdfs/tt_workflow_chart.pdf">GTD Workflow Chart</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Organize</strong>. As you clarify, put things into different “buckets” – Action Lists, Project Lists, Someday/Maybe Lists, Waiting For Lists, Reference Materials, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Review</strong>. Look at your buckets!! Daily and weekly.</li>
<li><strong>Engage</strong>. You know, get. stuff. done.</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="getting-back-on-the-gtd-bandwagon">Getting Back on the GTD Bandwagon</h1>
<p>Unfortunately, after following GTD for a few years, I “fell off the bandwagon.” I started to get sloppy with my practices of capturing and clarifying my “open loops,” so I started to spend more of my time worrying about what I had to get done that I was forgetting about, instead of reviewing my “Next Action” lists and getting things done, GTD-style.</p>
<p>So, just this past week, I decided to get back on the GTD bandwagon. I’ve got a Ph.D. dissertation to write and a baby on the way, after all! There’s no time to spend all day worrying about the things I’m forgetting! 🙂</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="my-gtd-tools">My GTD Tools</h1>
<h2 id="todoisthttpssupporttodoistcomhcen-usarticles203799792-getting-things-done-gtd-with-todoist"><a href="https://support.todoist.com/hc/en-us/articles/203799792-Getting-Things-Done-GTD-with-Todoist">ToDoist</a></h2>
<p>ToDoist is a fantastic task manager. I use it to keep track of my personal tasks and projects.</p>
<h2 id="google-calendarhttpscalendargooglecom"><a href="https://calendar.google.com/">Google Calendar</a></h2>
<p>I use Google Calendar as my…calendar. Pretty straightforward. 🙂</p>
<h2 id="gmailhttpsmailgooglecom"><a href="https://mail.google.com/">Gmail</a></h2>
<p>I use Gmail for email communication. In addition to folders created automatically by <a href="https://unroll.me/">Unroll.Me</a> and <a href="https://www.boomeranggmail.com/">Boomerang</a> (two FANTASTIC things to use in conjunction with Gmail), I have three simple folders:</p>
<ul>
<li>@ACTION_SUPPORT</li>
<li>@KEEP</li>
<li>@WAITING_FOR_SUPPORT</li>
</ul>
<p>If I receive an email that requires action from me, I place it in the @ACTION_SUPPORT folder and create a task in ToDoist reminding me to do the action.</p>
<p>If I receive an email that doesn’t contain an action, but that I want to keep for reference purposes, I either click “Archive” in GMail, or I move it to the “@KEEP” folder.</p>
<p>If I have an email that I can’t take the next action on, but that I’m waiting for someone to take an action before I can move forward, I create a task in ToDoist reminding me to follow up on this, and I move the email to the @WAITING_FOR_SUPPORT folder.</p>
<h2 id="evernotehttpsevernotecom"><a href="https://evernote.com/">Evernote</a></h2>
<p>Evernote is basically my second brain and reference file system. Everything from old receipts to class notes is in there.</p>
<h3 id="leuchtturm1917-medium-size-hardcover-a5-notebook--dotted-gridhttpamznto2fg5ccu"><a href="http://amzn.to/2FG5Ccu">Leuchtturm1917 Medium Size Hardcover A5 Notebook – Dotted Grid</a></h3>
<p>This is my favorite notebook and tool for “capturing” ideas, projects, actions, etc.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="some-good-overviews-of-gtd">Some Good Overviews of GTD</h1>
<p>The best overview of the GTD system is the aforementioned book, “<a href="http://amzn.to/2FC6IWz">Getting Things Done</a>.”</p>
<p>However, there are also some very helpful free overviews of the GTD system out there.</p>
<h3 id="how-to-hack-your-to-do-list">How to Hack Your To-Do List</h3>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xduzwk04l2E?start=1&feature=oembed" title="How To Hack Your To-Do List" width="750"></iframe>
<h3 id="watch-and-listen-to-david-allen-himself-summarize-gtd">Watch and Listen to David Allen Himself Summarize GTD</h3>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pvjOhLV3V6c?feature=oembed" title="Overview of Getting Things Done | lynda.com" width="750"></iframe>
<h3 id="productivity-101-a-primer-to-the-getting-things-done-gtd-philosophyhttpslifehackercomproductivity-101-a-primer-to-the-getting-things-done-1551880955-lifehacker"><a href="https://lifehacker.com/productivity-101-a-primer-to-the-getting-things-done-1551880955">Productivity 101: A Primer to the Getting Things Done (GTD) Philosophy</a> [LifeHacker]</h3>
<div class="row"><div class="col-md-8 col-md-offset-2 col-xs-12 text-center">### [GTD in 15 minutes – A Pragmatic Guide to Getting Things Done](https://hamberg.no/gtd/) \[Hamberg.no\]
<h3 id="getting-things-done-gtd-by-david-allen--animated-book-summary-and-review">Getting Things Done (GTD) by David Allen – Animated Book Summary And Review</h3>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gCswMsONkwY?feature=oembed" title="Getting Things Done (GTD) by David Allen - Animated Book Summary And Review" width="750"></iframe>
</div></div># Want to try GTD?
<p>Again, the best place to start is with the book, “<a href="http://amzn.to/2FC6IWz">Getting Things Done</a>,” by David Allen.</p>
<p>However, I’m also happy to answer any of your GTD questions! Please ask them in the comments below!</p>
<hr>
<p>Note: Some links above are <strong>affiliate links</strong>. This means that, if you click on the link and make a purchase, then (at no extra cost to you) I earn a small commission. I only recommend things I think would be useful to my readers!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This One Simple Trick Helps Me Read Faster as a Ph.D. Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 06:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading is the closest thing that human beings have to a superpower. We can learn, from other minds, from other times, just by looking at symbols on a screen or a page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I mean, come on. Who has enough time to read? I don’t know about you, but I’ve got a stack of books a mile high that I’d like to work my way through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, there’s a bunch of good advice out there about &lt;strong&gt;finding more time to read&lt;/strong&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fs.blog/2013/09/finding-time-to-read/&#34;&gt;this post from Farnam Street&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/26/how-to-read-more-books/&#34;&gt;this post from The Art of Manliness&lt;/a&gt;). In fact, finding more time to read is one of the main reasons why you should learn the basics of personal productivity and time management (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/category/productivity-and-time-management/&#34;&gt;my posts about productivity and time management&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reading is the closest thing that human beings have to a superpower. We can learn, from other minds, from other times, just by looking at symbols on a screen or a page.</p>
<p>But, I mean, come on. Who has enough time to read? I don’t know about you, but I’ve got a stack of books a mile high that I’d like to work my way through.</p>
<p>Now, there’s a bunch of good advice out there about <strong>finding more time to read</strong> (see <a href="https://www.fs.blog/2013/09/finding-time-to-read/">this post from Farnam Street</a> and <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/26/how-to-read-more-books/">this post from The Art of Manliness</a>). In fact, finding more time to read is one of the main reasons why you should learn the basics of personal productivity and time management (see <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/category/productivity-and-time-management/">my posts about productivity and time management</a>).</p>
<p>However, even if you manage to find more time to read, it can be very helpful to <strong>improve your reading speed</strong>.</p>
<p>As a Ph.D. student, this is something that I’ve tried to get better at in recent months. I’d like to share my top tip/trick. Here it is:</p>
<h2 id="use-a-penpencilfinger-as-a-pacer-when-you-read">Use a Pen/Pencil/Finger as a Pacer When You Read</h2>
<p>That’s right. Whenever I read these days, I’m using <em>something</em> as a pacer, tracing under each line of text as I read it. (I’m usually also standing and pacing around to avoid falling asleep!)</p>
<p>It might seem stupidly simple tip, but it’s crazy how much using something – whether a pen, pencil, or just your finger – as a pacer can help you read faster. It cuts down on the number of times your eye bounces around on the page, and it enables you to read exactly as quickly as you’d like to – you can slow down or speed up at will.</p>
<p>I first considered using a pacer while reading after reading Tim Ferriss’s wildly popular blog post, <a href="https://tim.blog/2009/07/30/speed-reading-and-accelerated-learning/">“Scientific Speed Reading: How to Read 300% Faster in 20 Minutes”</a>. I encourage you to give that post a read if you’re interested.</p>
<p>Or, if you’d rather watch a video of Tim teaching his technique, check this one out:</p>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZwEquW_Yij0?feature=oembed" title="How to Speed Read | Tim Ferriss" width="750"></iframe>
<p>Anyways, I hope this simple tip helps you to read faster when you want to! Give it a try and let me know what you think.</p>
<h2 id="got-any-reading-tips-youd-like-to-share-post-them-in-the-comments-below">Got any reading tips you’d like to share? Post them in the comments below!</h2>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go to Sleep and Have Some Kids: What the Bible (Psalm 127) Says about Productivity</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 12:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-productivity-in-psalm-127&#34;&gt;Personal Productivity in Psalm 127&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Psalm 127. Not because it makes me feel great, necessarily, but because it hits me like a ton of bricks whenever I read it (like I did last night, during evening prayer).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the Psalm opens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ps-127-1&#34;&gt;Unless the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; builds the house,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;indent-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;indent-1-breaks&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ps-127-1&#34;&gt;the builders labor in vain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;text Ps-127-1&#34;&gt;Unless the &lt;span class=&#34;small-caps&#34;&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; watches over the city,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;indent-1&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;indent-1-breaks&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;text Ps-127-1&#34;&gt;the guards stand watch in vain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but it’s easy for me to think that my success or lack thereof completely depends on me and the intensity of my efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="personal-productivity-in-psalm-127">Personal Productivity in Psalm 127</h2>
<p>I love Psalm 127. Not because it makes me feel great, necessarily, but because it hits me like a ton of bricks whenever I read it (like I did last night, during evening prayer).</p>
<p>Here’s how the Psalm opens:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="text Ps-127-1">Unless the <span class="small-caps">Lord</span> builds the house,</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Ps-127-1">the builders labor in vain.</span></span><br>
<span class="text Ps-127-1">Unless the <span class="small-caps">Lord</span> watches over the city,</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Ps-127-1">the guards stand watch in vain.</span></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I don’t know about you, but it’s easy for me to think that my success or lack thereof completely depends on me and the intensity of my efforts.</p>
<p>Not true! It doesn’t matter how hard you work. If the Lord is not behind it and in favor of it, you’ll be laboring in vain.</p>
<p>Now, of course, this Psalm doesn’t undo the Bible other admonitions to work diligently, lest you fall into poverty (see my post about <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/20110210proverbs-topical-study-poverty/">Poverty in the book of Proverbs</a>).</p>
<p>However, it does have implications for when we go to bed!</p>
<h2 id="go-to-sleep">Go to Sleep</h2>
<p>Verse 2 reads:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="text Ps-127-2" id="en-NIV-16124">In vain you rise early</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Ps-127-2">and stay up late,</span></span><br>
<span class="text Ps-127-2">toiling for food to eat—</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Ps-127-2">for he grants sleep to those he loves.</span></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thankfully, personal productivity advice these days has come around to recognizing the vital importance of sleep for your health.</p>
<p>However, I don’t know about you, but I often feel the nagging temptation that, if only I could squeeze a few extra hours out of the day, I could turn things around. To be perfectly honest, this is one of the reasons why I try to get up early (~5:00am) most mornings.</p>
<p>There’s nothing inherently wrong with getting up early in the morning. After all, Jesus himself did so, in order to pray (see Mark 1:35).</p>
<p>However, if you’re staying up late and getting up early in order to toil away because you think your work and success depends only on your efforts, then this Psalm encourages you to go to bed. Get some sleep. Learn to receive each day, along with exactly as much time as it contains, as a gift from God.</p>
<h2 id="have-some-kids">Have Some Kids</h2>
<p>The second part of the Psalm hits close to home as well! (See my previous post: <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/3-confessions-expectant-father/">3 Confessions of an Expectant Father</a>.)</p>
<p>Verses 3-5 read:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="text Ps-127-3" id="en-NIV-16125">Children are a heritage from the <span class="small-caps">Lord</span>,</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Ps-127-3">offspring a reward from him.</span></span><br>
<span class="text Ps-127-4" id="en-NIV-16126">Like arrows in the hands of a warrior</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Ps-127-4">are children born in one’s youth.</span></span><br>
<span class="text Ps-127-5" id="en-NIV-16127">Blessed is the man</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Ps-127-5">whose quiver is full of them.</span></span><br>
<span class="text Ps-127-5">They will not be put to shame</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Ps-127-5">when they contend with their opponents in court.</span></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>DISCLAIMER: I don’t have space here to address the complicated issue of infertility or other things that get in the way of having children. Just know that these verses don’t negate the fact that God loves and draws near to people going through such things in their times of pain.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, these verses also teach an important truth: children are a blessing from God.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong, I love kids. And, <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/3-confessions-expectant-father/">as I’ve said in my previous post, I’m excited to be a dad</a>!</p>
<p>And yet, I think that I’m going to need this Psalm as a frequent reminder in the days and years ahead! Personal productivity advice has come around to the idea of sleep being important, but I don’t know if there’s broad consensus on children always being considered a blessing! If you ask many people, <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/the-happiness-doctor/201709/does-having-children-make-us-happy">the jury is still out on whether or not having children makes you happier</a> – much less more productive!!</p>
<h2 id="reminders-of-our-finitude">Reminders of Our Finitude</h2>
<p>So, I think this Psalm is a countercultural reminder that both sleep and children are good gifts from God.</p>
<p>They are BOTH reminders that we are finite creatures who cannot accomplish everything (or even <em>anything</em> meaningful) on our own. Instead, even though we are called to make the best use of our time, we are to receive each day as a gift from God – recognizing that, without his constant provision and sustenance, we would perish.</p>
<p>So, take heart! Go to bed a little earlier tonight! Everything doesn’t depend on you.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="how-would-your-sleep-habits-andor-your-plans-for-the-future-change-if-you-took-psalm-127-to-heart">How would your sleep habits and/or your plans for the future change if you took Psalm 127 to heart?</h2>
<p>Let me know in the comments below!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Pray Before You Read and Write: A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 09:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to share with you the following prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study, based on &lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.preces-latinae.org/thesaurus/Varia/CreatorIneff.html&#34;&gt;Oratio S. Thomae Aquinatis ante studium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, which Thomas Aquinas would pray before studying, writing, or preaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We prayed it responsively before class (Patristic and Medieval History and Doctrine) with Dr. Piotr Malysz at Beeson Divinity School, and I’ve since turned back to this prayer often!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study&#34;&gt;A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O God, Creator of all that is, From the treasures of Your wisdom, You have arrayed the universe with marvelous order, And now govern with skill and might. You are the true fount of light and wisdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I want to share with you the following prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study, based on <u><em><strong><a href="http://www.preces-latinae.org/thesaurus/Varia/CreatorIneff.html">Oratio S. Thomae Aquinatis ante studium</a></strong></em></u>, which Thomas Aquinas would pray before studying, writing, or preaching.</p>
<p>We prayed it responsively before class (Patristic and Medieval History and Doctrine) with Dr. Piotr Malysz at Beeson Divinity School, and I’ve since turned back to this prayer often!</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="a-prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study">A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study</h1>
<p><strong>O God, Creator of all that is, From the treasures of Your wisdom, You have arrayed the universe with marvelous order, And now govern with skill and might. You are the true fount of light and wisdom.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Pour forth a ray of Your brightness Into the darkened places of our minds; Disperse from our souls the twofold darkness into which we were born: Sin and ignorance.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Grant to each of us: Deftness of hand, Keenness of mind, Skill in learning, Subtlety to interpret, And eloquence in speech.</strong></p>
<p><strong>And since you have given us the privilege to share in the loving, healing, reconciling mission of Your Son Jesus Christ, our Lord, in this age and wherever we are,</strong></p>
<p><strong>May your Spirit make us wise; May your Spirit guide us; May your Spirit renew us; May your Spirit strengthen us.</strong></p>
<p><strong>So that we will be Strong in faith, Discerning in proclamation, Courageous in witness, Persistent in good deeds.</strong></p>
<p><strong>May You guide the beginning of our work, Direct its progress, And bring it to completion. You who bring all that is good to its proper end, Now prosper the work of our hands. Through Jesus Christ our Lord,</strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Amen</em>.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Books Every Christian Should Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 03:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OK, OK. I get it. Claiming that every Christian should read these 5 books is a bold claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, honestly, I think that these reading recommendations stand up to the scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wracking my brain trying to come up with just the top 5 books that a busy Christian should read if she wants to learn the essentials about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Productivity and Time Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bible Study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, I think I’ve arrived at a pretty good shortlist if I do say so myself. If you &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/understand-remember-read-4-questions-ask-reading-book/&#34;&gt;read and understand&lt;/a&gt; these 5 books, you’ll be well on your way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OK, OK. I get it. Claiming that every Christian should read these 5 books is a bold claim.</p>
<p>But, honestly, I think that these reading recommendations stand up to the scrutiny.</p>
<p>I’ve been wracking my brain trying to come up with just the top 5 books that a busy Christian should read if she wants to learn the essentials about:</p>
<ul>
<li>Productivity and Time Management</li>
<li>Bible Study</li>
<li>Theology</li>
</ul>
<p>And, I think I’ve arrived at a pretty good shortlist if I do say so myself. If you <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/understand-remember-read-4-questions-ask-reading-book/">read and understand</a> these 5 books, you’ll be well on your way.</p>
<p>Please note that all links to books below are Amazon Affiliate links. That means that, if you buy the product after clicking on the link, I’ll receive a little bit of money in exchange. It helps me keep the lights on. You’re more than welcome, of course, to go to Amazon.com and search for the books, in which case I will not get a commission.</p>
<p>Bottom line: Even if I don’t get paid, I believe that these books are helpful and I think you should read them!</p>
<h1 id="5-books-every-christian-should-read">5 Books Every Christian Should Read</h1>
<h3 id="1-a-study-bible">1. A Study Bible</h3>
<p>That’s right, a study Bible is my single top recommendation for a Christian’s personal library. That’s because a good study Bible will combine the resources of an entire library into a single volume to help you better understand Scripture as you read it. There are, of course, a TON of study Bibles out there. My personal favorite is <strong><a href="http://amzn.to/2DX8phs">The ESV Study Bible</a></strong>.</p>
<p>If the ESV Study Bible doesn’t look like what you need, consider <strong><a href="http://amzn.to/2G1ysEJ">The CEB Study Bible</a></strong>.</p>
<h3 id="2-gordon-d-fee-and-douglas-stuart-how-to-read-the-bible-for-all-its-worthhttpamznto2g0rupp-fourth-edition">2. Gordon D. Fee and Douglas Stuart, <strong><a href="http://amzn.to/2G0rUpP">How to Read the Bible for All Its Worth</a></strong> (Fourth Edition)</h3>
<p>Although most study Bibles will contain short guides on how to read and study the Bible, Fee and Stuart’s book (now in its fourth edition) is somewhat of an industry standard in teaching people how to interpret Scripture. They will take you through:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Need to Interpret the Bible</li>
<li>The Basics of Bible Translation(s) and How to Pick One</li>
<li>How to Study Various Bible Genres:
<ul>
<li>Epistles</li>
<li>Old Testament Narratives</li>
<li>Acts</li>
<li>Gospels</li>
<li>Parables</li>
<li>Law(s)</li>
<li>Prophets</li>
<li>Psalms</li>
<li>Wisdom Literature</li>
<li>Revelation</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Plus, Fee and Stuart include an appendix about how to evaluate and use Bible commentaries! This book will set you up for a lifetime of Bible study. <a href="http://amzn.to/2BF6CKQ">Take up and read!</a></p>
<h3 id="3-bruce-shelley-church-history-in-plain-languagehttpamznto2dxu128-fourth-edition">3. Bruce Shelley, <strong><a href="http://amzn.to/2DxU128">Church History in Plain Language</a></strong> (Fourth Edition)</h3>
<p>As Shelley notes in the prologue to this volume, “Many Christians today suffer from historical amnesia. The time between the apostles and their own day is one giant blank. That is hardly what God had in mind” (xi). Shelley wrote this book to address this problem.</p>
<p>Now, in seminary, I had to take a “History &amp; Doctrine” sequence of 4 courses that covered the Patristic era through 20th-century Church history and theology. It was amazing, but who’s got that kind of time, right?! So, I asked around, including some of my former college and seminary theology profs, searching for the best, accessible, single-volume overview of the history of the Christian Church.</p>
<p>This book received the most votes by far. And I can see why.</p>
<p>Shelley’s book (also now in its fourth edition, which is a good sign!) manages to cover from the time of Jesus to the present day in approximately 500 pages. Yes, it’s a long book, but there’s a lot to cover! If you read this book, you’ll go through:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Age of Jesus and the Apostles (6BC – AD 70)</li>
<li>The Age of Catholic Christianity (70-312)</li>
<li>The Age of the Christian Roman Empire (312-590)</li>
<li>The Christian Middle Ages (590-1517)</li>
<li>The Age of the Reformation (1517-1648)</li>
<li>The Age of Reason and Revival (1648-1789)</li>
<li>The Age of Progress (1789-1914)</li>
<li>The Age of Ideologies (1914-1989)</li>
<li>The Age of Global Expansion and Relocation (1900 — )</li>
</ul>
<p>Again, I know of no better place to start to learn about the history of the Church if you’re crunched for time. Again: <a href="http://amzn.to/2GuNK4W">take up and read</a>!</p>
<h3 id="4-thomas-oden-classic-christianity-a-systematic-theologyhttpamznto2npexxa">4. Thomas Oden, <strong><a href="http://amzn.to/2npeXxa">Classic Christianity: A Systematic Theology</a></strong></h3>
<p>OK, so we’ve covered (1) The Bible, (2) how to read it, and (3) Church history. Now it’s time for the best, accessible, single-volume introduction to Christian theology.</p>
<p>This was harder to narrow down. After all, there are plenty of introductions to theology and systematic (think “a comprehensive system”) theologies out there. What makes one better than any of the others?</p>
<p>Well, as far as I know, Oden’s book is different than any other systematic theology out there because he gives you a “consensus view of the Christian faith.” That is, instead of giving you <em>his</em> particular take on Christian theology, he’s attempting to give you the Christian theology upon which there was widespread agreement throughout the first 15 or so centuries of Church history.</p>
<p>The inside cover of the book claims that it “provides the best synthesis of the whole history of Christian thought.” Even though that’s a bold claim, I’m inclined to believe it, based upon the systematic theologies I’ve encountered in my academic research.</p>
<p><a href="http://amzn.to/2BF1GWu">I strongly recommend you buy and read Oden</a>, obviously. However, if, for some reason, Oden seems too long or expensive, check out Alister McGrath’s <a href="http://amzn.to/2EpfFmn">Theology: The Basics</a> or Daniel Migliore’s <a href="http://amzn.to/2FvyuUm">Faith Seeking Understanding: An Introduction to Christian Theology (Third Edition)</a>.</p>
<h3 id="5-matthew-perman-whats-best-next-span-classa-size-large-idproducttitlehow-the-gospel-transforms-the-way-you-get-things-donespanhttpamznto2dnczma">5. Matthew Perman, <a href="http://amzn.to/2DNCzma"><strong>What’s Best Next:</strong> <span class="a-size-large" id="productTitle"><strong>How the Gospel Transforms the Way You Get Things Done</strong></span></a></h3>
<p>OK, last book of my top 5! And it’s a good one. In fact, this is the single best book on productivity and time management for Christians that I know of. It got me started on my kick of reading productivity books for the past few years, and I trust that it will help you create more margin in your life to pursue purpose and meaning.</p>
<p>Perman begins the book with an argument for why we need a uniquely Christian view of productivity. From there, he covers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Making God Supreme in Our Productivity</li>
<li>Gospel-Driven Productivity: A New Way to Look at Getting Things Done</li>
<li>D.A.R.E.
<ul>
<li>Define: Know What’s Most Important</li>
<li>Architect: Create a Flexible Structure</li>
<li>Reduce: Free Up Your Time for What’s Most Important</li>
<li>Execute: Do What’s Most Important</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Living This Out</li>
</ul>
<p>This is a profoundly useful and useable book! As a productivity guru, Perman naturally ends each chapter with what he calls “The Box” – a summary section containing the core point and core passage of the chapter, further resources, and suggestions for immediate application.</p>
<p>There’s also a 500 word summary of the book at the end, followed by a helpful topical index and suggestions for further reading – including some of the “classic” works in productivity and time management which, if you’re like me, you’ll want to track down!</p>
<p>If you want to become more productive and manage your time better for the glory of Jesus Christ, <a href="http://amzn.to/2DOtMjQ">buy and read Perman’s book</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An 80/20 Approach to the Christian Life: 2 Reasons Why Christians Should Care About the Pareto Principle</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 12:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you want to live a more meaningful and purposeful Christian life, but you feel like it’s hard enough just to get everything done on your to-do list each day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m right there with you! That’s why I’ve made “&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/category/productivity-and-time-management/&#34;&gt;Get Your Act Together (Productivity and Time Management)&lt;/a&gt;” the first of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/start-here/&#34;&gt;Steps to Find Purpose and Meaning in Life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I think I’ve found something that can help. I’d like to introduce you to the “&lt;strong&gt;Pareto Principle&lt;/strong&gt;,” also known as “&lt;strong&gt;the 80/20 Rule&lt;/strong&gt;,” the “law of the vital few,” or the “principle of factor sparsity,” if you want to get all technical about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you want to live a more meaningful and purposeful Christian life, but you feel like it’s hard enough just to get everything done on your to-do list each day?</p>
<p>I’m right there with you! That’s why I’ve made “<a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/category/productivity-and-time-management/">Get Your Act Together (Productivity and Time Management)</a>” the first of my <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/start-here/">Steps to Find Purpose and Meaning in Life</a>.</p>
<p>Thankfully, I think I’ve found something that can help. I’d like to introduce you to the “<strong>Pareto Principle</strong>,” also known as “<strong>the 80/20 Rule</strong>,” the “law of the vital few,” or the “principle of factor sparsity,” if you want to get all technical about it.</p>
<h3 id="put-as-simply-as-possible-the-8020-rule-says-this-80-of-effects-come-from-20-of-causes">Put as simply as possible, the 80/20 rule says this: 80% of effects come from 20% of causes.</h3>
<p>Take a moment to think about this, and it becomes obvious that the 80/20 principle is at play all over the place.</p>
<p>Have you ever heard someone say that 80% of the money/work in a church comes from just 20% of the congregation? 80% of sales come from 20% of clients? As long as you don’t get hung up on exact percentages and allow the principle to be a ballpark estimator/lens, you can see the Pareto Principle at work in several different areas of life, from agriculture to economics.</p>
<p>Here’s a helpful video if you’d like to learn more about the 80/20 Rule:</p>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V28B_xOJzK4?start=51&feature=oembed" title="How to Instantly Be More Productive – The 80/20 Principle by Richard Koch" width="750"></iframe>
<h3 id="performing-an-8020-analysis--determining-which-20-of-things-are-responsible-for-80-of-the-results">Performing an “80/20 Analysis” = Determining which 20% of things are responsible for 80% of the results.</h3>
<p>This works both positively and negatively. Right? 20% of the people you spend time with are responsible for 80% of the positive emotions and experiences. But 20% of the people you spend time with are also responsible for 80% of the negative emotions in your life.</p>
<p>20% of the things you spend your time doing are responsible for 80% of the outcomes – both positively and negatively.</p>
<p>This means that you can make some pretty drastic changes in your life by zeroing in on the correct 20%! Eliminating the bad 20% and focusing on increasing the good 20% can quickly turn your life around.</p>
<p>Doing an 80/20 analysis in various areas of your life can save you a bunch of time, because you’re maximizing your efforts by prioritizing the changes you make.</p>
<p>The 80/20 Rule is, therefore, understandably a pretty popular concept. (Google “80/20 Rule” and you’ll see what I mean!) If you’d like to learn more about it, consider picking up Richard Koch’s classic book, <a href="http://amzn.to/2BEFj3k">The 80/20 Principle: The Secret to Achieving More with Less</a>. (Heads up: that’s an affiliate link. If you end up buying that book, I earn a small commission, at no extra cost to you.)</p>
<p>However, I’m convinced that there are two reasons why Christians in particular should care about the 80/20 Principle.</p>
<h1 id="2-reasons-why-christians-should-care-about-the-8020-pareto-principle">2 Reasons Why Christians Should Care about the 80/20 Pareto Principle</h1>
<h2 id="1-it-could-be-deadly-to-your-christian-life">1. It could be deadly to your Christian life.</h2>
<p>That’s right, I think that, if it’s misused, the Pareto Principle can be deadly for your walk with God.</p>
<p>Here’s the thing, if you allow “the world” to calibrate your 80/20 analysis, then you will end up frequently overlooking the things that God cares about — the things that God wants YOU to care about.</p>
<p>Do you think that loving your enemies, caring for the poor, turning the other cheek, and loving the unlovely are going to show up at the top of your 80/20 analysis if you’re not allowing your head and your heart to be shaped by the gospel – by the Good Story of God? I don’t think so.</p>
<p>So, Christians should care about the 80/20 Rule because, if we use it incorrectly, it might end up making us less effective for the Kingdom of God.</p>
<h2 id="2-it-could-change-your-christian-life-for-the-better">2. It could change your Christian life for the better.</h2>
<p>However, just because a principle can be misused doesn’t mean you should use it!</p>
<p>(Also, technically, the Pareto Principle is at work, even if you’re not choosing to capitalize on it! So, there’s no sense in ignoring it!)</p>
<p>As long as we allow our perspectives to be shaped by the Gospel, Christians can profitably use the 80/20 Principle to become more effective, healthy, and whole for the Kingdom of God. There’s no reason not to use this tool.</p>
<h1 id="performing-an-8020-analysis-on-your-christian-life">Performing an 80/20 Analysis on Your Christian Life</h1>
<p>Take advantage of the Pareto Principle by applying it to your walk with God. Think about it with me:</p>
<h3 id="what-20-of-people-things-and-habits-are-drawing-you-80-farther-away-from-god">What 20% of People, Things, and Habits are Drawing You 80% Farther Away from God?</h3>
<p>What people/places/things/actions are responsible for the vast majority of your spiritual decline?</p>
<p>Is it your phone? Social media? Pornography? An old friend who is clearly influencing you more in a negative direction than you’re influencing them in a positive direction?</p>
<p>You need to prioritize your time, your efforts, and your prayers to <strong>decreasing</strong> these things. Even taking just one of these “worst offenders” out of your life could make a huge difference.</p>
<h3 id="what-20-of-people-things-and-habits-are-drawing-you-80-closer-to-god">What 20% of People, Things, and Habits are Drawing You 80% Closer to God?</h3>
<p>What people/places/things/actions are responsible for the vast majority of your spiritual growth?</p>
<p>Is it going to church regularly? Getting up early to read your Bible and pray? Finding and spending time with a trusted spiritual mentor?</p>
<p>You need to prioritize your time, your efforts, and your prayers to <strong>increasing</strong> these things. Doing so will have an outsized impact on your spiritual life.</p>
<h3 id="remember-you-cant-do-this-alone">Remember, YOU Can’t Do This Alone</h3>
<p>No, of course, we can’t “fix ourselves” on our own!</p>
<p>We desperately need the life-transforming ministry of the Holy Spirit to make these kinds of changes in our lives. And God doesn’t love us based on how well we do an 80/20 analysis (praise God!).</p>
<p>But still, it helps to have a clearer idea of where to focus in terms of having a closer relationship with God and others. And I believe that the 80/20 Rule can help us get more clarity.</p>
<h1 id="coming-soon-an-8020-approach-to-productivity-time-management-bible-study-and-theology">Coming Soon: An 80/20 Approach to Productivity, Time Management, Bible Study, and Theology</h1>
<p>There’s another reason why I’m bringing up the 80/20 Rule. This principle will guide my future posts about</p>
<ul>
<li>Productivity</li>
<li>Time Management</li>
<li>Bible Study</li>
<li>Theology</li>
</ul>
<p>Why? Because I’m not convinced that anyone needs to learn 100% or even 80% about these topics before they move forward. Attempting to do so will frequently lead to paralysis and indecision, instead of growth.</p>
<p>Instead, it pays off to begin with the most effective 20% of the information in each topic area. And that’s what I’m going to focus on in the weeks ahead.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="got-questions">Got Questions?</h3>
<p>I’d love to help you brainstorm how the 80/20 Principle could make a difference in your Christian life. Feel free to leave any questions, comments, or concerns in the comment section below!</p>
<p>Finally, if you’ve enjoyed this content, would you please share it with at least one other person who could benefit from it? Thanks!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principles: 10 Imperatives for the Good Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 16:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why write out a list of principles?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one thing, it’s my birthday. And, although I’m only in my twenties, I’m feeling a bit reflective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For another, I’ve just been given a copy of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2yQpytf&#34;&gt;Principles: Life and Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2yQpytf&#34;&gt; by Ray Dalio&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Dalio (ix),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principles are fundamental truths that serve as the foundations for behavior that gets you what you want out of life. They can be aplied again and again in similar situations to help you achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why write out a list of principles?</p>
<p>For one thing, it’s my birthday. And, although I’m only in my twenties, I’m feeling a bit reflective.</p>
<p>For another, I’ve just been given a copy of <em><a href="http://amzn.to/2yQpytf">Principles: Life and Work</a></em><a href="http://amzn.to/2yQpytf"> by Ray Dalio</a> (affiliate link).</p>
<p>According to Dalio (ix),</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Principles are fundamental truths that serve as the foundations for behavior that gets you what you want out of life. They can be aplied again and again in similar situations to help you achieve your goals.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With that in mind, here are 10 principles I’ve developed so far. I’ve followed Dalio’s lead in casting my principles as imperatives. No, I don’t always do an excellent job at these. But they’re worth striving for.</p>
<p>No, this is not an exhaustive list. And no, I don’t always do an excellent job at these. But they’re worth striving for.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="1-go-to-church-word-amp-sacraments">1. Go to Church: Word &amp; Sacraments</h1>
<p>This principle, and the following one, are purposefully at the top of the list. Why? Because they will place you in a context where your desires, your view of reality, and therefore your principles will be formed in the right direction.</p>
<p>So, go to a church where you can hear the Word of God preached and where you can partake of the Sacraments.</p>
<h2 id="further-reading">Further Reading:</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2kWJkgq"><em>For the Life of the World: Sacraments and Orthodoxy</em> by Alexander Schmemann</a> (affiliate link, as well as all book links below)</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2yuxbo2"><em>Liturgical Theology: The Church as Worshiping Community</em> by Simon Chan</a></li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2x2UQbM"><em>The Church: A Theological and Historical Account</em> by Gerald Bray</a></li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2yuJeSj"><em>Exploring Ecclesiology: An Evangelical and Ecumenical Introduction</em> by Brad Harper and Paul Louis Metzger</a></li>
</ul>
<h1 id="2-do-the-daily-office-morning-and-evening-prayer">2. Do the Daily Office: Morning and Evening Prayer</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/dailyofficebooklet/">Rookie Anglican’s Daily Office Booklet</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.missionstclare.com/english/">The Daily Office from Mission St. Clare</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thetrinitymission.org/">The Daily Office from The Trinity Mission</a></li>
</ul>
<p>NOTE: I realize that a WHOLE LOT MORE could be said with/underneath these first two “principles.” As an overarching principle, <em><strong>“Become More Like Jesus Christ in All I Think, Feel, Say, and Do,”</strong></em> is quite good. In fact, I’d consider most of the rest of this blog to be relevant in that respect.</p>
<p>However, I’m going to devote the next eight principles to various pragmatic concerns, such as productivity, physical fitness, and financial well-being.</p>
<h1 id="3-think-on-paper-keep-a-journal-and-to-do-lists">3. Think on Paper: Keep a Journal and To-Do Lists</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://tim.blog/2015/01/15/morning-pages/">What My Morning Journal Looks Like</a> – Tim Ferriss</li>
<li><a href="http://bulletjournal.com/">Bullet Journal</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.intelligentchange.com/products/the-five-minute-journal">Five-Minute Journal</a></li>
<li><a href="http://juliacameronlive.com/basic-tools/morning-pages/">Morning Pages</a></li>
</ul>
<h1 id="4-read-more-amp-take-notes">4. Read More &amp; Take Notes</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2yuCZ0M"><em>How to Read a Book: The Classic Guide to Intelligent Reading</em></a> by Mortimer J. Adler</li>
<li><a href="https://tim.blog/2009/07/30/speed-reading-and-accelerated-learning/">Scientific Speed Reading: How to Read 300% Faster in 20 Minutes</a> – Tim Ferriss</li>
<li><a href="https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/2013/11/taking-notes-while-reading/">The Top 3 Most Effective Ways to Take Notes While Reading</a> – Farnam Street Blog</li>
<li><a href="http://calnewport.com/blog/2014/10/23/deep-habits-create-an-idea-index/">Deep Habits: Create an Idea Index</a> – Cal Newport</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="5-ask-morebetter-questions">5. Ask More/Better Questions</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2yPWaDy"><em>A More Beautiful Question: The Power of Inquiry to Spark Breakthrough Ideas</em></a> by Warren Berger</li>
<li><a href="https://tim.blog/2016/12/07/testing-the-impossible-17-questions-that-changed-my-life/">Testing The “Impossible”: 17 Questions That Changed My Life</a> – Tim Ferriss</li>
<li><em><a href="http://amzn.to/2zvFSwv">The Coaching Habit: Say Less, Ask More &amp; Change the Way You Lead Forever</a></em> by Michael Bungay Stanier</li>
<li><a href="https://tim.blog/2016/10/06/the-art-and-science-of-learning-anything-faster/">The Art and Science of Learning Anything Faster</a> – Tim Ferriss</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="6-sit-less-amp-move-heavier-objects">6. Sit Less &amp; Move Heavier Objects</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2016/12/13/staying-fit-with-no-gym-in-sight/">Staying Fit With No Gym in Sight</a> – Mr. Money Mustache</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2zvvwg8"><em>Starting Strength: Basic Barbell Training</em></a> by Mark Rippetoe</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2zvvwg8">Stronglifts 5×5: The Simplest, Most Effective Workout to Build Muscle, Gain Strength and Get Ripped</a></li>
</ul>
<h1 id="7-eat-less-sugar-amp-more-vegetables">7. Eat Less Sugar &amp; More Vegetables</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/@erinfrey/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-slow-carb-diet-a67062761d92">Everything You Need to Know About the Slow-Carb Diet</a> – Medium</li>
<li><em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Defense-Food-Michael-Pollan/dp/1594133328">In Defense of Food</a></em> by Michael Pollan (also a <a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80097071">documentary</a> [available on Netflix], which is worth watching!!)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.webmd.com/food-recipes/news/20090323/7-rules-for-eating#1">7 Rules for Eating</a> – WebMD</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="8-turn-off-the-tv-and-the-notifications-on-your-phone">8. Turn off the TV and the Notifications on Your Phone</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.becomingminimalist.com/ten-reasons-to-watch-less-television/">10 Reasons to Watch Less Television</a> – Becoming Minimalist</li>
<li><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/turn-off-your-push-notifications/">Turn Off Your Push Notifications. All of Them.</a> – WIRED</li>
<li><em><a href="http://amzn.to/2yukPvS">Bored and Brilliant: How Spacing Out Can Unlock Your Most Productive and Creative Self</a></em> by Manoush Zomorodi</li>
<li><em><a href="http://amzn.to/2xNkN3u">Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World</a></em> by Cal Newport</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2013/10/01/the-low-information-diet/">The Low Information Diet</a> – Mr. Money Mustache</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="9-getstay-out-of-debt">9. Get/Stay out of Debt</h1>
<ul>
<li><em><a href="http://amzn.to/2yuPmtG">The Total Money Makeover: A Proven Plan for Financial Fitness</a></em> by Dave Ramsey</li>
<li><em><a href="http://amzn.to/2zg4DvR">Dave Ramsey’s Complete Guide to Money</a></em> by Dave Ramsey</li>
<li><em><a href="http://amzn.to/2zg5FYL">I Will Teach You to Be Rich</a></em> by Ramit Sethi</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="10-invest-a-401k-and-ira-in-index-funds-or-lifecycle-funds">10. Invest a 401K and IRA in Index Funds or Lifecycle Funds</h1>
<ul>
<li>(See books from #9 above)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.investopedia.com/articles/retirement/08/401k-info.asp">The Basics of a 401(k) Retirement Plan</a> – Investopedia</li>
<li><a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/i/ira.asp?adtest=rira-layout-bttn-bsln">Individual Retirement Account – IRA</a> – Investopedia</li>
<li><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/nextavenue/2016/09/28/how-to-start-investing-in-index-funds/#459949875400">How to Start Investing in Index Funds</a> – Forbes</li>
<li><a href="https://www.fool.com/knowledge-center/what-is-a-lifecycle-fund.aspx">What is a Lifecycle Fund?</a> – The Motley Fool</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>What principles would you add to this list? Let us know in the comments!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts You Should Listen To</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 15:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;podcasts-an-introduction&#34;&gt;Podcasts: An Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although podcasts (think “iPod” + “broadcast”) have been around for over a decade, we’re living in a bit of a golden age – or a least a Rennaissance – of the medium. For the uninitiated, here’s a nice video about what podcasts are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oerm5Q&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oerm5Q&lt;/a&gt;_9u2A&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, podcasts are one of my very favorite ways to consume information about a wide variety of topics. Sure, gun to my head, I’ll choose books over podcasts as a way to learn. However, unlike books (or videos), you can easily listen to podcasts while doing other things – whether folding laundry, washing dishes, or going for a run/walk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="podcasts-an-introduction">Podcasts: An Introduction</h1>
<p>Although podcasts (think “iPod” + “broadcast”) have been around for over a decade, we’re living in a bit of a golden age – or a least a Rennaissance – of the medium. For the uninitiated, here’s a nice video about what podcasts are:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oerm5Q">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oerm5Q</a>_9u2A</p>
<p>Currently, podcasts are one of my very favorite ways to consume information about a wide variety of topics. Sure, gun to my head, I’ll choose books over podcasts as a way to learn. However, unlike books (or videos), you can easily listen to podcasts while doing other things – whether folding laundry, washing dishes, or going for a run/walk.</p>
<p>(Note: as I mentioned in <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tools">my list of favorite tools and apps</a>, <a href="https://overcast.fm/">Overcast</a> is my current favorite podcast player. Although, there are plenty of other worthy podcast players/managers to check out!)</p>
<p>There are no shortage of podcasts, or lists of best podcasts, for that matter. However, here are my current favorites.</p>
<h1 id="my-favorite-podcasts">My Favorite Podcasts:</h1>
<h2 id="up-first-nprhttpwwwnprorgpodcasts510318up-first"><a href="http://www.npr.org/podcasts/510318/up-first">Up First (NPR)</a></h2>
<p>This is the first podcast I listen to every weekday while making coffee. I love that it’s short (˜10 minutes) and that it provides some snapshots of important news stories that day. In addition to Up First, I frequently listen to NPR newscasts via their <a href="http://one.npr.org/">NPR One app</a>, which is worth checking out!</p>
<h2 id="the-art-of-manlinesshttpwwwartofmanlinesscompodcast"><a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com/podcast/">The Art of Manliness</a></h2>
<p>Sure, the egalitarian in me wishes there were a show out there called “The Art of Humanity” – about how to be a <em>Mensch.</em> However, in the meantime, Brett McKay has a solid podcast going about “reviving the lost art of manliness.” I enjoy the podcast (and t<a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com/">he Art of Manliness website</a>) because it includes so many helpful how-to guides – for everything from weightlifting to men’s fashion.</p>
<h2 id="word-amp-tablehttpswordandtablesimplecastfm"><a href="https://wordandtable.simplecast.fm/">Word &amp; Table</a></h2>
<p>I created <a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/rookieanglican/">Rookie Anglican</a> as a way of making Anglicanism more accessible. This podcast, Word &amp; Table, has much the same mission, although it’s focus is not just on Anglicanism, but rather on the rich Christian tradition of liturgical worship. As I wrote about the podcast <a href="http://anglicanpastor.com/listen-to-the-word-table-podcast-to-learn-more-about-liturgical-and-sacramental-christian-worship/">over at Rookie Anglican</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>According to their <a href="https://wordandtable.simplecast.fm/">website</a>, Word &amp; Table “is a weekly podcast about liturgy, sacrament, and the great tradition of Christian worship and why it is vital in our world today.”</p>
<p>The podcast was started back in October 2016, and it’s hosted by <a href="http://www.greenhousemovement.com/team/alex-wilgus/">Alex Wilgus</a> and Fr. <a href="http://www.churchrez.org/staff/profile/stephengauthier">Stephen Gauthier</a>, the Canon Theologian for the Anglican Church in North America’s Diocese of the Upper Midwest.</p>
<p>You can subscribe to the podcast via <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/word-table/id1161203280?mt=2">iTunes</a>, listen to episodes via the <a href="https://wordandtable.simplecast.fm/">Word &amp; Table website</a>, or simply search for “Word and Table” in your podcast player/manager of choice.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you’ve got questions about anything related to the Christian tradition, check out the Word &amp; Table podcast to see if they have an episode on the topic!</p>
<h2 id="the-tim-ferriss-showhttpstimblogpodcast"><a href="https://tim.blog/podcast/">The Tim Ferriss Show</a></h2>
<p>I’ve become somewhat of a Tim Ferriss junkie in the past two years. In addition to this podcast – which features long-form interviews with “top performers,” in which Tim distils tips, tricks, habits, and practices for the common person – Ferriss’ books are well worth checking out (Affiliate LInks: <a href="http://amzn.to/2uTWui7">The 4-Hour Workweek</a>; The <a href="http://amzn.to/2uxKdxq">4-Hour Body</a>; The <a href="http://amzn.to/2h0dtJT">4-Hour Chef</a>; <a href="http://amzn.to/2h0dwp3">Tools of Titans</a>) . He’s great at teaching <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meta_learning">metalearning</a></em> – how to learn how to learn!</p>
<p>(Note: Tim Ferriss is how I found out about <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/2016/05/25/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/">kettlebells</a> – one of my <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tools">favorite tools</a> for personal fitness.)</p>
<h2 id="coffee-break-germanhttpsradiolinguacomcoffeebreakgerman"><a href="https://radiolingua.com/coffeebreakgerman/">Coffee Break German</a></h2>
<p>Sure, Coffee Break German hasn’t taught me the kind of German that I’ll need for my Ph.D. German translation exam. However, it is a very informative introduction to basic/conversational German. It makes a wonderful companion to Duolingo for language learning! Radio Lingua Network offers <a href="https://radiolingua.com/">a whole suite of “Coffee Break” languages</a>, including French, Spanish, Italian, German, and Chinese!</p>
<h2 id="this-american-lifehttpswwwthisamericanlifeorg"><a href="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/">This American Life</a></h2>
<p>In my opinion, no podcast beats This American Life in terms of the quality and variety of storytelling. It’s well worth your time, in addition to the “spinoff” shows <a href="https://serialpodcast.org/">Serial</a> and <a href="https://stownpodcast.org/">S-Town</a>.</p>
<h1 id="honorable-mentions">Honorable Mentions:</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://theartofcharm.com/podcast/">The Art of Charm</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.always-forward.com/category/podcast/">Always Forward</a>: Anglican Church Planting</li>
<li><a href="http://www.preachingtoday.com/media/podcast/">Monday Morning Preacher</a></li>
<li>Malcolm Gladwell’s <a href="http://revisionisthistory.com/">Revisionist History</a></li>
<li><a href="http://optimallivingdaily.com/">Optimal Living Daily</a></li>
</ul>
<p>So tell me, what are <em><strong>your</strong></em> favorite podcasts?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is The Well-Equipped Christian Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 23:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had a problem finding a reliable resource for recommendations?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain Google searches are a piece of cake, but the “best resources for ______” ones can be hit-or-miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t even get me started on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_fatigue&#34;&gt;decision fatigue&lt;/a&gt;. As a serial over-thinker, I start to hate myself a little bit after reading through the upteenth list of “5 Best ____s.” It makes it so hard to make a decision! Then, when you pick something, you end up doubting your decision. Not fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever had a problem finding a reliable resource for recommendations?</p>
<p>I have.</p>
<p>Certain Google searches are a piece of cake, but the “best resources for ______” ones can be hit-or-miss.</p>
<p>And don’t even get me started on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_fatigue">decision fatigue</a>. As a serial over-thinker, I start to hate myself a little bit after reading through the upteenth list of “5 Best ____s.” It makes it so hard to make a decision! Then, when you pick something, you end up doubting your decision. Not fun.</p>
<p>I’m sure these dynamics apply to a bunch of different things in life. However, while serving as a Youth Minister in seminary, I realized that finding reliable Christian recommendations and resources can be very difficult.</p>
<p>Sure, it’s not for lack of content out there! When it comes to Christianity, everyone has an opinion – and usually an associated reading list!</p>
<p>But how do you know that the book or blog-post that you find isn’t from some crazy yahoo with nothing more than a computer and a Bible?</p>
<p>Furthermore, if you’re a Christian and your looking for recommendations and resources in some <em>other</em> area, how do you know that what you find is worthwhile?</p>
<p>I mean, sure, <em>everything</em> should be read with a critical eye. But is that latest book or blog-post about mindfulness, parenting, self-help, or productivity helpful and useful for Christians? Or will it require quite a bit of theological critique and analysis before it’s helpful without being potentially harmful?</p>
<p>Google is great, and getting better at many things. But – at least for right now – it’s a pretty crappy theologian!</p>
<h1 id="idea-the-well-equipped-christian">Idea: The Well-Equipped Christian</h1>
<p>With all this in mind, I have an idea: <em><strong>The Well-Equipped Christian</strong></em> (or a similar title) – a website that’s a one-stop shop for Christians looking for reliable recommendations and resources.</p>
<p>Now, to be clear, I’m not claiming to BE the well-equipped Christian! I am not the be-all-end-all source of reliable Christian information.</p>
<p>However, I am a Christian with a seminary education. I’m pursuing a PhD in theology, and I have a heart for the Church.</p>
<p>I want to devote my life and ministry to helping to produce as many “well-equipped Christians” as possible. And I absolutely <strong>love</strong> giving practical recommendations – specifically in the areas of Bible study, theology, productivity, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meta_learning">meta-learning</a>.</p>
<p>There are a lot of great resources out there. Resources that Christians can benefit from to have healthy <strong>minds</strong>, <strong>bodies</strong>, and <strong>souls</strong> as they advance God’s Kingdom in their daily lives.</p>
<p>I want to connect you to those resources.</p>
<h1 id="i-need-your-help">I Need Your Help</h1>
<p>Are you wiling to help me figure out whether or not this is a good idea? If so, great! <strong>I’d love to hear your answers to the following questions:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>What is the biggest problem that you’ve faced in finding reliable recommendations and resources?</strong> Not just for specifically Christian resources (although that’s great if you want to focus on that), but also for resources in general.</li>
<li><strong>When you talk to your friends about finding reliable recommendations and resources, what kinds of things do you say?</strong> Any specific feelings or complaints?</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally, please share this post with anyone you think would be willing to give me their input! Thank you so much!</p>
<p>~Josh</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Ridiculously Helpful Markdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 14:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been dragging my heels on learning Markdown for awhile now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know, Markdown is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightweight_markup_language&#34; title=&#34;Lightweight markup language&#34;&gt;lightweight markup language&lt;/a&gt; with plain text formatting syntax designed so that it can be converted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML&#34; title=&#34;HTML&#34;&gt;HTML&lt;/a&gt; and many other formats using a tool by the same name.&lt;sup class=&#34;reference&#34; id=&#34;cite_ref-8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown#cite_note-8&#34;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Markdown is often used to format &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/README&#34; title=&#34;README&#34;&gt;readme files&lt;/a&gt;, for writing messages in online discussion forums, and to create &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formatted_text&#34; title=&#34;Formatted text&#34;&gt;rich text&lt;/a&gt; using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plain_text&#34; title=&#34;Plain text&#34;&gt;plain text&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_editor&#34; title=&#34;Text editor&#34;&gt;editor&lt;/a&gt;. [Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been dragging my heels on learning Markdown for awhile now.</p>
<p>If you don’t know, Markdown is:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightweight_markup_language" title="Lightweight markup language">lightweight markup language</a> with plain text formatting syntax designed so that it can be converted to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML" title="HTML">HTML</a> and many other formats using a tool by the same name.<sup class="reference" id="cite_ref-8"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown#cite_note-8">[8]</a></sup> Markdown is often used to format <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/README" title="README">readme files</a>, for writing messages in online discussion forums, and to create <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formatted_text" title="Formatted text">rich text</a> using a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plain_text" title="Plain text">plain text</a> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_editor" title="Text editor">editor</a>. [Source: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">Wikipedia</a>]</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That is, get the benefits of HTML and/or rich text, without [as steep of] a learning curve!</p>
<p>To make things even easier, I suggest starting with this <a href="http://www.markdowntutorial.com/">Markdown</a><a href="http://www.markdowntutorial.com/"> Tutorial</a>. Should this tutorial prove too basic, it even links to other, more in-depth guides at the end!</p>
<p>I plan to start implementing Markdown in my workflow for this blog, and also for <a href="http://www.rookieanglican.com/">Rookie Anglican</a>.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Want To Be Remembered?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you know what the worst thing about &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;death&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not the &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;dying&lt;/span&gt; itself – its the &lt;strong&gt;separation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, we don’t suffer the most from our own deaths (a one-time occurrence), but from suffering the deaths of others (repeatedly). Instead of living relationships, we are left with distant memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sad reality, to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-if-however-we-could-use-death-to-our-own-advantage&#34;&gt;What if, however, we could use death to our own advantage?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced this is the truth behind Ecclesiastes 7:2 –&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you know what the worst thing about <em><strong>death</strong></em> is?</p>
<p>It’s not the <span style="text-decoration: underline;">dying</span> itself – its the <strong>separation</strong>.</p>
<p>That is, we don’t suffer the most from our own deaths (a one-time occurrence), but from suffering the deaths of others (repeatedly). Instead of living relationships, we are left with distant memories.</p>
<p>A sad reality, to be sure.</p>
<h3 id="what-if-however-we-could-use-death-to-our-own-advantage">What if, however, we could use death to our own advantage?</h3>
<p>I’m convinced this is the truth behind Ecclesiastes 7:2 –</p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="text Eccl-7-2" id="en-NIV-17432">It is better to go to a house of mourning</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Eccl-7-2">than to go to a house of feasting,</span></span><br>
<span class="text Eccl-7-2">for death is the destiny of everyone;</span><br>
<span class="indent-1"><span class="indent-1-breaks"> </span><span class="text Eccl-7-2">the living should take this to heart.</span></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now, obviously, simply taking death to heart isn’t enough to defeat our most ancient enemy. For that, we need (and have been given) a <em><strong>resurrection</strong></em>.</p>
<p>But, have you taken your own death to heart? I believe there’s something to be gained by considering how you’d like to be remembered by others after you die.</p>
<h2 id="how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered">How do you want to be remembered:</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<h2 id="by-god">by God?</h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2 id="by-your-spouse">by your spouse?</h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2 id="by-your-children">by your children?</h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2 id="by-your-parents">by your parents?</h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2 id="by-your-family-and-friends">by your family and friends?</h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2 id="by-your-colleagues">by your colleagues?</h2>
</li>
</ul>
<p>For me, I’d like to be remembered:</p>
<ul>
<li>…as God’s faithful servant.</li>
<li>…as my wife’s best friend.</li>
<li>…as my children’s most important teacher.</li>
<li>…as my parents’ legacy.</li>
<li>…as my family and friends’ loyal brother.</li>
<li>…as my colleagues inspiring teammate.</li>
</ul>
<p>…which sounds great, right? But here’s the rub:</p>
<h2 id="what-span-styletext-decoration-underlinechangesspan-do-you-and-i-need-to-make-in-our-lives-to-start-making-those-hypothetical-memories-more-realistic-each-day">What <span style="text-decoration: underline;">changes</span> do you and I need to make in our lives, to start making those hypothetical memories more realistic each day?</h2>
<p>I’d love to hear your thoughts on this in the comments below, as I consider how taking death to heart should impact one’s entire life.</p>
<p>~Josh (<a href="https://twitter.com/joshuapsteele">@joshuapsteele</a>)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Take Seth Godin to Church</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie. My first reaction when I saw the cover of this book? &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0502.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0502-225x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;no-of-course-youre-not-indispensable-what-use-could-this-crap-possibly-be-to-the-church-or-to-me--simultaneously-a-pastor-and-a-pastor-in-training&#34;&gt;No! Of course you’re not indispensable. What use could this crap possibly be to the Church, or to me – simultaneously a pastor and a pastor-in-training.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, however, &lt;strong&gt;I read the book&lt;/strong&gt;. And I suggest you do, too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=1591844096&amp;asins=1591844096&amp;linkId=6dde24820eeb48d4ecb7e52c6696d9b0&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=0066c0&amp;bg_color=ffffff&#34; style=&#34;width: 120px; height: 240px;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;  
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: affiliate link. I get paid if you make a purchase.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sethgodin.com/sg/&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;, bald marketing extraordinaire, is convinced that a paradigm shift has taken place. I’ll quote from his annotated table of contents (which, by the way, I wish all books had):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m not going to lie. My first reaction when I saw the cover of this book? <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0502.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0502-225x300.jpg" alt=""  />
</a></p>
<h5 id="no-of-course-youre-not-indispensable-what-use-could-this-crap-possibly-be-to-the-church-or-to-me--simultaneously-a-pastor-and-a-pastor-in-training">No! Of course you’re not indispensable. What use could this crap possibly be to the Church, or to me – simultaneously a pastor and a pastor-in-training.</h5>
<p>Then, however, <strong>I read the book</strong>. And I suggest you do, too!</p>
<iframe frameborder="0" height="150" loading="lazy" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&OneJS=1&Operation=GetAdHtml&MarketPlace=US&source=ac&ref=tf_til&ad_type=product_link&tracking_id=joshuapsteele-20&marketplace=amazon&region=US&placement=1591844096&asins=1591844096&linkId=6dde24820eeb48d4ecb7e52c6696d9b0&show_border=false&link_opens_in_new_window=true&price_color=333333&title_color=0066c0&bg_color=ffffff" style="width: 120px; height: 240px;" width="300">  
</iframe>
<p><em>(Note: affiliate link. I get paid if you make a purchase.)</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.sethgodin.com/sg/">Seth Godin</a>, bald marketing extraordinaire, is convinced that a paradigm shift has taken place. I’ll quote from his annotated table of contents (which, by the way, I wish all books had):</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We have gone from two teams (management and labor) to a third team, <strong>the linchpins. These are people who own their own means of production, who can make a difference, lead us, and connect us. The death of the factory means that the entire system we have built our lives around is now upside down. This is either a huge opportunity or a giant threat.</strong> Revolutions are frightening because the new benefits sometimes lag behind the old pain. This time, the opportunity is to bring your best self to the marketplace and be rewarded for it (vii).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For the past few generations, we’ve grown used to the implicit deal: If you go to school, learn how to follow instructions, work hard, and show up on time, we’ll take care of you.</p>
<p>But, at least in many sectors, the bargain has fallen apart.</p>
<p>So, Godin advises us to become linchpins in whatever industry we find ourselves. We must treat our work as art, and combine a variety of skills to address complex situations.</p>
<p>We must be able to figure out what to do next, without it being spelled out for us in an instruction manual.</p>
<h2 id="ok-great-but-what-does-this-have-to-do-with-span-styletext-decoration-underlinechurchspan">OK, great. But what does this have to do with <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>CHURCH</strong></span>?</h2>
<h5 id="i-believe-pastors-are-uniquely-situated-to-be-linchpins"><strong>I believe pastors are uniquely situated to be linchpins.</strong></h5>
<p>They are the leaders of a largely volunteer organization. And, Pastoral Epistles notwithstanding, there is no instruction manual (God forbid we treat the Bible like an instruction manual!).</p>
<p>So they must treat their work as art. If they just phone it in and serve their time, they’ll be left with only the people who phone it in and serve their time as church members!</p>
<h5 id="i-believe-christians-are-uniquely-situated-to-be-linchpins-in-their-workplaces"><strong>I believe Christians are uniquely situated to be linchpins in their workplaces.</strong></h5>
<p>I plan to write more about this in future posts, but it’s ridiculous how much of the self-help advice out there these days aligns with the things Christians should be the very best at!</p>
<p>A bunch of Godin’s advice centers around <strong>treating other people as full human beings, and on giving freely without the expectation of debt or compensation</strong> (See chapters “The Powerful Culture of Gifts” and “The Culture of Connection”).</p>
<p>I don’t know about you, but that sounds familiar.</p>
<p>As pastors focus on leading by example – by being linchpins themselves – they could start explicit conversations about the connections between worship on Sunday and work (which should also be worship) on<a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/work"> the other six days</a>.</p>
<h5 id="finally-i-believe-that-each-church-is-uniquely-situated-to-be-a-linchpin-in-its-community">Finally, I believe that each church is uniquely situated to be a linchpin in its community.</h5>
<p>What if churches were known for showing artful, personal, and prodigal love to their communities, without expectation of increased attendance on a Sunday morning?</p>
<p>What if we were seeker-sensitive, without selling out to the “latest” corporate and marketing strategies (which, often enough, rely upon the old paradigm)?</p>
<p>What if, especially in North America, we stopped complaining about “persecution,” and started creatively taking advantage of the situations in which we find ourselves?</p>
<p>I don’t have all the answers to these questions, but I’m convinced they’re worth asking!</p>
<h5 id="godin-is-convinced-that-people-are-starving-for-personal-connection-in-a-world-filled-with-faceless-factories-and-multinational-corporations">Godin is convinced that people are starving for personal connection in a world filled with faceless factories and multinational corporations.</h5>
<h5 id="im-convinced-that-the-church--the-body-of-christ--has-just-the-food-to-feed-those-starving">I’m convinced that the Church – the Body of Christ – has just the food to feed those starving.</h5>
<p>~Josh (<a href="https://twitter.com/joshuapsteele">@joshuapsteele</a>)</p>
<script type="text/javascript">
amzn_assoc_placement = "adunit0";
amzn_assoc_search_bar = "true";
amzn_assoc_tracking_id = "joshuapsteele-20";
amzn_assoc_search_bar_position = "top";
amzn_assoc_ad_mode = "search";
amzn_assoc_ad_type = "smart";
amzn_assoc_marketplace = "amazon";
amzn_assoc_region = "US";
amzn_assoc_title = "More Books by Seth Godin";
amzn_assoc_default_search_phrase = "Seth Godin";
amzn_assoc_default_category = "Books";
amzn_assoc_linkid = "e82ac4d0adeed21f9bf8703b813ac93c";
</script>  
<script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US"></script>
<p><em>(Note: affiliate link. I get paid if you make a purchase.)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are you afraid of?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 20:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m scared. Are you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, as I wrote in my journal this very morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m scared – I’m scared of wasting my life, I’m scared of not being worth anything outside of the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear drives so many aspects of our lives – from how we dress, to how we raise our children, to how we elect our leaders. And, if we’re honest with ourselves, fear can play a large role in what/whom we worship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m scared. Are you?</p>
<p>Specifically, as I wrote in my journal this very morning:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I’m scared – I’m scared of wasting my life, I’m scared of not being worth anything outside of the classroom.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fear drives so many aspects of our lives – from how we dress, to how we raise our children, to how we elect our leaders. And, if we’re honest with ourselves, fear can play a large role in what/whom we worship.</p>
<p>For example, perhaps we worship God out of a fear of going to hell, or a fear of our inherited religion being wrong. We secretly worry that, like Donald Miller’s father accuses him in the movie <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1758575/quotes?item=qt1678309">Blue Like Jazz</a>, we “<em><strong>only believe that stuff ‘cuz [we]’re afraid to hang out with people that don’t</strong></em>.”</p>
<p>Or perhaps we <span style="text-decoration: underline;">don’t</span> worship God – and instead worship a god of our choice/invention – because we’re afraid of the implications of God’s existence.</p>
<p>Now, there is, I’m persuaded, a holy fear. A salutary reverence and awe in the face of the divine.</p>
<p>But that’s not what I’m talking about here, I’m talking about the <em><strong>paralyzing</strong></em> fear – the cold sweat, the white knuckles, the tension headaches.</p>
<p>I’m talking about the same kind of fear as <a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2015/10/the-power-of-fear.html">Seth Godin</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<h3 id="the-power-of-fearhttpsethgodintypepadcomseths_blog201510the-power-of-fearhtml"><a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2015/10/the-power-of-fear.html">The power of fear</a></h3>
<p>Fear will push you to avert your eyes.</p>
<p>Fear will make you think you have nothing to say.</p>
<p>It will create a buzz that makes it impossible to meditate…</p>
<p>or it will create a fog that makes it so you can do nothing but meditate.</p>
<p>Fear seduces us into losing our temper.</p>
<p>and fear belittles us into accepting unfairness.</p>
<p>Fear doesn’t like strangers, people who don’t look or act like us, and most of all, the unknown.</p>
<p>It causes us to carelessly make typos, or obsessively look for them.</p>
<p>Fear pushes us to fit in, so we won’t be noticed, but it also pushes us to rebel and to not be trustworthy, so we won’t be on the hook to produce.</p>
<p>It is subtle enough to trick us into thinking it isn’t pulling the strings, that it doesn’t exist, that it’s not the cause of, “I don’t feel like it.”</p>
<p>When in doubt, look for the fear.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Courage isn’t the absence of fear. It’s knowing how to deal with fear. And, for me, <strong>the first step toward dealing with my fears is frankly admitting them.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I’m scared, because I don’t know what’s next after I graduate from <a href="http://www.beesondivinity.com/">Beeson</a> in December.</li>
<li>I’m scared, because the thing I’ve felt called to for the longest time – getting a PhD in systematic theology – seems like an impractical pipe dream.</li>
<li>I’m scared, because I don’t know if I’ll get into a PhD program. And, if I don’t, I don’t know how I’ll react to not being able to rely upon good grades for self-worth.</li>
</ul>
<p>Thankfully, none of these fears prevent me from being faithful with the day I’ve been given – today. <strong>The greatest failure would be to use fears of the future as an excuse for present faithlessness</strong>.</p>
<h3 id="so-what-are-you-afraid-of-how-are-you-dealing-with-those-fears">So, what are you afraid of? How are you dealing with those fears?</h3>
<h3 id="have-you-admitted-them-to-anyone-if-not-i-challenge-you-to-do-so-today">Have you admitted them to anyone? If not, I challenge you to do so today.</h3>
<p>If you’ve got no one, not even a journal, to listen to your admission, I’m all ears, for what it’s worth.</p>
<p>~Josh (<a href="https://twitter.com/joshuapsteele">@joshuapsteele</a>)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kettlebell Swings: Back Balm for the Sedentary [Seminarian]</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 23:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love books. Books, however, do not like my back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you relate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s not sitting around reading books all day, but I imagine plenty of you out there suffer from back pain/fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me share a time-saving solution I’ve recently found: &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/kettlebells/how-to-do-the-perfect-kettlebell-swing&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;two-handed kettlebell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;swings.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure aria-describedby=&#34;caption-attachment-3810&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34; id=&#34;attachment_3810&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px&#34;&gt;![Our small kettlebell family](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0472-e1464220672909-300x225.jpg)&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34; id=&#34;caption-attachment-3810&#34;&gt;Our small kettlebell family&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can these cannonballs with handles help your back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the kettlebell swing is one of the many exercises out there that activates your &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posterior_chain&#34;&gt;posterior chain&lt;/a&gt; – the muscles along the back of your body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love books. Books, however, do not like my back.</p>
<p>Can you relate?</p>
<p>Maybe it’s not sitting around reading books all day, but I imagine plenty of you out there suffer from back pain/fatigue.</p>
<p>Let me share a time-saving solution I’ve recently found: <a href="http://breakingmuscle.com/kettlebells/how-to-do-the-perfect-kettlebell-swing"><em><strong>two-handed kettlebell</strong></em> </a><em><strong>swings.</strong></em></p>
<figure aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3810" class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_3810" style="width: 300px">![Our small kettlebell family](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_0472-e1464220672909-300x225.jpg)<figcaption class="wp-caption-text" id="caption-attachment-3810">Our small kettlebell family</figcaption></figure>
<p>How can these cannonballs with handles help your back?</p>
<p>Well, the kettlebell swing is one of the many exercises out there that activates your <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Posterior_chain">posterior chain</a> – the muscles along the back of your body.</p>
<p>However, as <a href="http://breakingmuscle.com/kettlebells/the-kettlebell-swing-why-its-the-perfect-exercise">BreakingMuscle.com clarifies</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>for those with lower back issues traditional posterior chain exercises such as deadlifts, good mornings, etc. may exacerbate the condition, while swings may not. For those looking to strengthen the lower back and unable to use these traditional exercises the swing may be just the thing they’re looking for</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thanks to the full-body movement of the swing, <strong>you really don’t need to use a lot of weight to feel a difference</strong>. For example, I’ve been squatting 225 lbs. in maintenance mode recently, and after the first day of kettlebell swings with a 35 lb. kettlebell, my glutes and hamstrings were more sore than they’d been in months!</p>
<p>I’ve been very impressed with the results of <a href="http://rkcblog.dragondoor.com/the-best-and-simplest-one-kettlebell-workout/">a basic kettlebell workout</a>, and it will enable me to get exercise at home during the semester, when going to the gym is more of a stretch.</p>
<p><strong>Would you like to give kettlebell swings a try?</strong></p>
<p><strong>First, learn the proper form</strong> and <span style="text-decoration: underline;">then</span> look for a kettlebell to give it a try.</p>
<p>For the CliffsNotes version, here’s <a href="http://fourhourworkweek.com/2011/01/08/kettlebell-swing/">the Tim Ferriss blogpost on the matter</a>. For a more in-depth approach, BreakingMuscle.com, in addition to their <a href="http://breakingmuscle.com/kettlebells/the-kettlebell-swing-why-its-the-perfect-exercise">article on why the kettlebell swing is such a great exercise</a>, has this piece on <a href="http://breakingmuscle.com/kettlebells/how-to-do-the-perfect-kettlebell-swing">how to do the perfect kettlebell swing</a>.</p>
<p>If you’re more of a visual learner, here’s a helpful instructional video from Eric Moss:</p>
<p><a href="http://https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0_XjJjLc7NE">http://https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0_XjJjLc7NE</a></p>
<p><strong>What weight should you start with?</strong> I began with a 35 lb. (16 kg.). Kettlebells USA has <a href="https://www.kettlebellsusa.com/what-size-kettlebell-should-i-buy-guidelines-for-men-and-women-to-choose-a-starter-kettlebell-weight">one of the best guides on choosing a starting weight</a>, based upon your gender and current fitness level.</p>
<p><strong>What brand of kettlebell should you purchase?</strong> I went with <a href="http://thesweethome.com/reviews/best-kettlebell/">Sweethome’s budget pick</a>: the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00I6CRMP0/">CAP Cast Iron Competition Weight Kettlebell</a>. But, <a href="http://thesweethome.com/reviews/best-kettlebell/">the in-depth review of different brands by Mark Bixby at Sweethome</a> can’t be beat. I like the CAP, but I now agree with his assessment that the grip tears up your hands a bit on one-handed excercises.</p>
<p>Give two-handed kettlebell swings a try! Your back and body will thank you (although, full disclosure, you’ll be sore after the first time).</p>
<p>If you have any comments or questions about kettlebell swings or other methods of easing back pain in the midst of a sedentary lifestyle, please leave them below!</p>
<p>~Josh</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
