<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 14:46:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 14:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/contact-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 14:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/contact-2/</guid>
      <description>About me Minimized simplicity
I love simplicity I am a fashion photographer and blogger, feel free to read the whole story. Whereas a trend often connotes.
Blog Posts I am a fashion photographer and blogger, feel free to read the whole story. Whereas a trend often connotes a very specific aesthetic expression, and often lasting shorter than a season.
Go to blog
Services I am a fashion photographer and blogger, feel free to read the whole story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 19:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/blog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy of Ministry</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/philosophy-of-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 11:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/philosophy-of-ministry/</guid>
      <description>Every Christian is a theologian.
I consider it my life&amp;rsquo;s work to help &amp;ldquo;everyday Christians&amp;rdquo; grow in their knowledge and love of God so that we all can put our gifts to good use by joining with God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive work in the world. In biblical terms, I&amp;rsquo;m called to &amp;ldquo;equip the saints for the work of ministry&amp;rdquo; and to &amp;ldquo;build up the body of Christ&amp;rdquo; (Eph. 4:12).
Now, on the one hand, this means that I’m not supposed to do all the work of ministry myself!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Story</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/my-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 22:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/my-story/</guid>
      <description>(Note: for a much briefer profile of what I&amp;rsquo;m like and what makes me tick as a worker, read this self-assessment.)
From Childhood to College God’s faithfulness to me is linked with his faithfulness to my parents. They both grew up in nominally Roman Catholic homes, and came to relationship with Christ shortly before my birth. When I came along, their church environment was a mixture between conservative Baptist and non-denominational.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, the Bible, and &#34;What we ought to do&#34;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-the-bible-and-what-we-ought-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 17:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-the-bible-and-what-we-ought-to-do/</guid>
      <description>Came across this Barth quote in Church Dogmatics II/2 this morning. I really like it, because it&amp;rsquo;s a good reminder that Barth valued the Bible. His distinction between the Bible as witness to the Word of God and Jesus Christ as the Word of God did not cause him to abandon the Scriptural witness.
It is as well to remind ourselves, at the conclusion of this analysis, that the question: What ought we to do?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth’s Gesamtausgabe (“Complete/Collected Edition”): A List of Works</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-gesamtausgabe-complete-collected-edition-a-list-of-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-gesamtausgabe-complete-collected-edition-a-list-of-works/</guid>
      <description>Note that, as of 2019-01-26, 54 volumes of the Gesamtausgabe have been published.
Unfortunately, only the first 45 of these are available in the Digital Karl Barth Library.
*I&amp;rsquo;ve marked volumes unavailable in the DKBL with an asterisk.
According to the publisher, TVZ:
Seit 1971 sind im Theologischen Verlag Zürich mehr als 50 Bände der Karl Barth-Gesamtausgabe erschienen. In ihr werden Barths Texte kritisch ediert und so präsentiert, dass sie für die wissenschaftliche Beschäftigung, aber auch für einen grösseren Interessentenkreis lesbar und zugänglich werden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A List of Karl Barth&#39;s Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 16:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-list-of-karl-barths-sermons/</guid>
      <description>To make this list, I&amp;rsquo;ve used the data available in the Digital Karl Barth Library. I&amp;rsquo;ve just taken the tables of contents in the sermon volumes of Barth&amp;rsquo;s collected works and put them all in one place.
The only way to display the dates correctly in Markdown is to write these up as code blocks, as I&amp;rsquo;ve done below.
Predigten 1913 (GA I.8) 1. und 5. Januar (Neujahr): Prediger 1,9 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the relationship between biblical and systematic/dogmatic theology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 15:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-the-relationship-between-biblical-and-systematic-dogmatic-theology/</guid>
      <description>This is the question we&amp;rsquo;re considering this week in our doctoral seminar on biblical and theological integration. Two of us are theologians and the other four are bible scholars. Should be interesting!
(Note: we&amp;rsquo;ll have to save the difference(s) between systematic, historical, and dogmatic theology for another post!)
Here are the articles we were assigned to read for this week:
D.A. Carson, “Systematic Theology and Biblical Theology” in the New Dictionary of Biblical Theology, pp.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spirit, Flesh, Restoration, and Sublimation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 18:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/spirit-flesh-restoration-and-sublimation/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s an intriguing passage in Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s Letters and Papers from Prison where he discusses the relationship between &amp;ldquo;spirit&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;flesh,&amp;rdquo; in the context of discussing &amp;ldquo;restoration&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sublimation,&amp;rdquo; in the context of discussing lyrics from certain hymns and songs that were meaningful to him in prison.
Here it is, from a December 19, 1943 (the Fourth Sunday of Advent) letter to Eberhard Bethge:
In recent weeks this line has been running through my head over and over: “Calm your hearts, dear friends; / whatever plagues you, / whatever fails you, / I will restore it all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StickKing to the Slow Carb Diet</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/stickking-to-the-slow-carb-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 02:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/stickking-to-the-slow-carb-diet/</guid>
      <description>Last night, the scale read 192.4. I&amp;rsquo;d really like it to read 180 or less.
So, in lieu of how effective putting money on the line via StickK has been for my daily writing habit these past two weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to put money on the line as motivation to stick to the Slow Carb Diet for a month.
For my writing habit, I&amp;rsquo;ve committed to writing 500 words toward my dissertation every day for 8 weeks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth and Bonhoeffer on Religion&#39;s False God(s)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-religions-false-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 19:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-and-bonhoeffer-on-religions-false-gods/</guid>
      <description>In The Epistle to the Romans, Barth writes the following concerning the false image of God at the heart of religion:
What men on this side resurrection name ‘God’ is most characteristically not God. Their ‘God’ does not redeem his creation, but allows free course to the unrighteousness of men; does not declare himself to be God, but is the complete affirmation of the course of the world and of men as it is.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth&#39;s Reversal on the &#34;Knowledge of Good and Evil&#34;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-reversal-on-the-knowledge-of-good-and-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/karl-barths-reversal-on-the-knowledge-of-good-and-evil/</guid>
      <description>I argue that, although Barth’s interpretation of the Genesis passages changed between The Epistle to the Romans and the Church Dogmatics, his mature readings of Genesis 2–3 still support his overall theological critique of religion as idolatry, the self-justifying positing of false gods.
Specifically, in Romans (240–57, esp. 246–51), Barth interpreted “the knowledge of good and evil” as the divine secret that humans are merely humans.
The prohibition of eating from the tree of knowledge thereby concealed the creator/creature distinction and was meant to enable a direct relationship between God and humans.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I wish these 2 Barth (and Bonhoeffer) books would come out sooner!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-wish-these-2-barth-and-bonhoeffer-books-would-come-out-sooner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 22:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-wish-these-2-barth-and-bonhoeffer-books-would-come-out-sooner/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to reading these two Barth (and Bonhoeffer) books coming out from Baker in 2019:
Freedom under the Word: Karl Barth’s Theological Exegesis. Edited by Ben Rhodes and Martin Westerholm. Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer: Theologians for a Post-Christian World. By Wolf Krötke. Translated by John P. Burgess. Freedom under the Word (May 2019) According to Baker:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer of Confession</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-of-confession/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 20:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-prayer-of-confession/</guid>
      <description>To start off the semester the other day, we prayed this prayer of confession together as a class. The professor didn’t remember where the prayer was from, so I tracked it down online. According to Justin Taylor, it was written by Bob Kauflin.
Holy and righteous God, we confess that like Isaiah, we are a people of unclean lips. But it is not only unclean lips we possess. We are people with unclean hands and unclean hearts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What blogs are you reading?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</guid>
      <description>Right now, I’m using the RSS readers Inoreader and Reeder to subscribe to the following blogs:
Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise. Seth’s Blog Study Hacks - Decoding Patterns of Success - Cal Newport James Clear Barking Up The Wrong Tree - How to be awesome at life. The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds McSweeney’s Internet Tendency Lifehacker - Do everything better What are you reading?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help me StickK to my writing habit</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-me-stickk-to-my-writing-habit/</guid>
      <description>I need to finish this dissertation.
To do so, I need to write regularly. For me, that means writing every day—a minimum of 500 words every day.
Last spring, I did a pretty good job of writing regularly. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen off the wagon for various reasons, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a bear to get back on!
So, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to put some money on the line, using a service called StickK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonhoeffer&#39;s &#34;Definition&#34; of &#34;Religion&#34; in Prison: 15 Facets/Aspects</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bonhoeffers-definition-of-religion-in-prison-15-facets-aspects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 14:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bonhoeffers-definition-of-religion-in-prison-15-facets-aspects/</guid>
      <description>Based upon my own reading of Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s Letters and Papers from Prison [DBWE 8], here is my attempt at a summary list of the facets/aspects of Bonhoeffer’s view of “religion” in prison.
Religion emphasizes inwardness. [DBWE 8:362, 364, 455–57] Religion emphasizes conscience. [DBWE 8:362] Religion is a temporary phenomenon. [DBWE 8:362, 364] Religion is manipulative and exploitative. [DBWE 8:363, 366, 426–27, 450, 455–57] Religion ignores human strength/knowledge/autonomy and instead focuses on human weakness, ignorance, and boundaries/limits/limitations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Christian Theology: A Draft Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 22:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/introduction-to-christian-theology-a-draft-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>As a part of my &amp;ldquo;pedagogical experience&amp;rdquo; at Wheaton College this semester, I was required to draft a syllabus for an introduction to Christian theology. Feel free to let me know what you think in the comments.
Note: the length of this syllabus doesn’t necessarily correspond to the difficulty of this course
Contact Information Email: [REDACTED] Phone: [REDACTED] Office Hours (Buswell Library Carrell): T, W, R, 15:00–17:00. Course Description This course is an introduction to the methods of systematic theology and the major topics within biblical revelation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Karl Barth Software Drama Continues: Inaccurate Page Numbers in Logos</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-karl-barth-software-drama-continues-inaccurate-page-numbers-in-logos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 16:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-karl-barth-software-drama-continues-inaccurate-page-numbers-in-logos/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I wrote about how the Scripture search tool in the Digital Karl Barth Library was broken. Thankfully, it appears to have been fixed (although it still has issues). This means I can search Barth&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Collected Edition&amp;rdquo; (Gesamtausgabe) if needed.
However, I&amp;rsquo;m now having some issues with the copy of Barth&amp;rsquo;s Church Dogmatics I purchased via Logos Bible Software.
Before I complain, let me first say how grateful I am that Logos is MUCH more user-friendly than the Digital Karl Barth Library.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing the Way of the Lord in the Wilderness: Luke 3:1-6</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/preparing-the-way-of-the-lord-in-the-wilderness-luke-31-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 15:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/preparing-the-way-of-the-lord-in-the-wilderness-luke-31-6/</guid>
      <description>I’d like to pray this week’s collect again:
Merciful God, who sent your messengers the prophets to preach repentance and prepare the way for our salvation: Give us grace to heed their warnings and forsake our sins, that we may greet with joy the coming of Jesus Christ our Redeemer; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen.
Introduction It’s been a particularly difficult week here at Church of the Savior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UPDATE: You can now search for Bible citations in the Digital Karl Barth Library again</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/update-you-can-now-search-for-bible-citations-in-the-digital-karl-barth-library-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/update-you-can-now-search-for-bible-citations-in-the-digital-karl-barth-library-again/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote about a problem I found in Alexander Street Press&amp;rsquo; Digital Karl Barth Library: the Scripture citation search function no longer worked!
I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that, though the DKBL is still far from user-friendly, the Bible search works again!
Now we just need some angel investors and programmers to produce a user-friendly version of the Digital Karl Barth Library! :) Any takers?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a fantastic wooden pencil (Mitsubishi 9850)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/this-is-a-fantastic-wooden-pencil-mitsubishi-9850/</guid>
      <description>Just wanted to give a quick shout-out to this fantastic pencil: the Mitsubishi 9850.
It&amp;rsquo;s cheap, writes well, erases well, and looks great!
For more on wooden pencils, read this JetPens guide to the best wooden pencils. And, while you&amp;rsquo;re at it, check out JetPens&amp;rsquo; recommendations for the best pencil sharpeners.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/now/</guid>
      <description>These days, I&amp;rsquo;m:
Living in Toledo, OH (my hometown!) Raising 3 kids with my wife Enjoying my work as a software engineer Trying to lose weight (current weight: 240lbs; goal: 200lbs) Working on home repair, DIY projects (next up: installing a water-powered backup sump pump) Buying too many books (like The Highly Sensitive Person: How to Thrive When the World Overwhelms You) Buying too many tools (like this amazing little &amp;ldquo;Superman&amp;rsquo;s fingernail&amp;rdquo; skin wedge pry bar from Ares) Last updated: 2024-08-06</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s gone wrong with the Digital Karl Barth Library?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-gone-wrong-with-the-digital-karl-barth-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 15:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/whats-gone-wrong-with-the-digital-karl-barth-library/</guid>
      <description>As I slowly make progress on my dissertation (&amp;ldquo;Scriptural but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion&amp;rdquo;), I&amp;rsquo;m longing for the day when:
Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s Gesamtausgabe (Collected Edition) is finished. They are translated into a critical English edition. They are available within the same database/framework as Dietrich Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s Works in English and German (DBWE and DBW). In the meantime, the Digital Karl Barth Library, provided by Alexander Street Press is the best resource out there for searching the text of Barth&amp;rsquo;s works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wish List</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 19:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wishlist/</guid>
      <description>I want…
To be a good husband To be a good father To be a good friend To solve people’s problems To build what people use To write what people read To never stop learning Finances To have control over my time “The ability to do what you want, when you want, with who you want, for as long as you want, is priceless. It is the highest dividend money pays” (Morgan Housel, The Psychology of Money, 83).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justification and Sanctification</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/justification-and-sanctification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 15:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/justification-and-sanctification/</guid>
      <description>For my &amp;ldquo;Pedagogical Experience&amp;rdquo; requirement at Wheaton, I&amp;rsquo;m helping to teach a masters-level Christian Theology course.
Yesterday, I got to teach a lesson on justification and sanctification. A lot to cover in a 95-minute class session!
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in what I covered, here are my slides (in PDF format).
Justification and Sanctification Slides
Download
And here is the handout (Word document).
Justification and Sanctification Handout
Download</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take Up Your Tongue and Follow Jesus</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/take-up-your-tongue-and-follow-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/take-up-your-tongue-and-follow-jesus/</guid>
      <description>This sermon, on Mark 8:27-38 and James 3:1-12, was originally preached on September 16, 2018 at Christ Redeemer Anglican Church in Milwaukee, WI.
Introduction Would you pray with me?
O God, because without you we are not able to please you—especially in what we say!—mercifully grant that your Holy Spirit may in all things direct and rule our hearts, so that the words of our mouths and the meditations of our hearts might be acceptable in your sight, O Lord, our strength and our redeemer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Theologies: A List (Help Me Update!)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/systematic-theologies-a-list-help-me-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/systematic-theologies-a-list-help-me-update/</guid>
      <description>SYSTEMATIC THEOLOGIES: A LIST I put together the following list, using the 10th edition of John Glynn&amp;rsquo;s Commentary and Reference Survey (Kegel, 2007) as a starting point.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be updating this list in the future, but I could use your help. If there&amp;rsquo;s something that needs included, please let me know in the comments!
Systematic Theologies Barth, Karl. Church Dogmatics, 5 vols. In 14 parts. (T&amp;amp;T Clark, [1932–1967] 1936–1969). Bavinck, Herman.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s the Template I Use to Take Notes on Books I Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 19:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-template-i-use-to-take-notes-on-books-i-read/</guid>
      <description>Developed from How to Read a Book, by Mortimer J. Adler.
BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA: Author(s):
Editor(s):
Translator(s):
Title and subtitle:
Title and subtitle of any larger work that contains the source:
Pages:
Volume:
Issue:
Edition:
URL and date accessed:
Publisher:
Place:
Date:
INTERPRETATION: Kind of Book (Practical or theoretical?):
Subject Matter:
Problems Attempted to Solve:
Summary (What is the book about as a whole?):
Outline of Source:
Key Terms:
Key Propositions/Arguments (What is being said in detail, and how?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Reading this Fall</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>This upcoming semester, I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking a seminar on the Doctrine of Creation from my supervisor Marc Cortez. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be doing my &amp;ldquo;pedagogical experience&amp;rdquo; in a Christian Theology course—also with Marc Cortez.
Anyways, in case you&amp;rsquo;re interested, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share what I&amp;rsquo;ll be reading for each course.
Have you read any of these works? If so, what did you think? What will you be reading this semester?
Doctrine of Creation Colin Gunton, The Triune Creator: A Historical and Systematic Study.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Questions to Ask While Reading Theology</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</guid>
      <description>While reading Beth Felker Jones&amp;rsquo; Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically, I came across the following list of extremely helpful questions to ask while reading theology (on page 29).
What are the key Christian teachings being articulated? What is the author&amp;rsquo;s driving concern or main theme? What counts for the author as authoritative (Scripture, tradition, reason, experience&amp;hellip;)? Is the author&amp;rsquo;s theological method implicit or explicit? How does the author deal with the witness of Scripture?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eva Joy Steele: A Birth Story</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/eva-joy-steele-a-birth-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 15:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/eva-joy-steele-a-birth-story/</guid>
      <description>This is a self-indulgently long story. The gist of it is that my wife, Rachel, was unexpectedly induced due to gestational hypertension at 37 weeks, right before we were supposed to head to Pennsylvania for her sister&amp;rsquo;s wedding.
After a lengthy induction and labor, our beautiful daughter, Eva Joy Steele, was born at 5:46am on Friday, July 20, 2018.
If that&amp;rsquo;s all you&amp;rsquo;d like to know, great! If you&amp;rsquo;d like to know more about what went down, keep reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Theologians (Should) Do</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-theologians-should-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 14:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-theologians-should-do/</guid>
      <description>Kevin J. Vanhoozer, affectionately known by some as &amp;ldquo;KJV,&amp;rdquo; has written one of the best, briefest overviews of what theologians (should) do.
The entire piece is filled with gems like the following:
To become a theologian, you must be willing to bear true witness and call out false witnesses, casting down idols and ideologies. That’s the shadow side of theology, but the best part is speaking light and truth in astonished indications of God’s goodness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Attracts People to Anglicanism? Here&#39;s My Take</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 21:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-attracts-people-to-anglicanism-heres-my-take/</guid>
      <description>Based upon my work over at Rookie Anglican, I was asked by The Telos Collective to write a blog post about the different ways that people are coming into Anglicanism. What&amp;rsquo;s drawing them in?
You can read my full post over at the Telos Collective blog, but here&amp;rsquo;s a taste:
Anglican Christianity, precisely because of its weirdness, can remind us that, in the words of Brad Harper and Paul Louis Metzger in Exploring Ecclesiology, “The church is a cultural community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 19:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/two-more-pieces-about-jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I catalogued a bunch of different takes on Jordan Peterson, before giving my own take.
Since that post, two other pieces about Jordan Peterson have been written that I&amp;rsquo;d like to share.
&amp;ldquo;Jordan Peterson, Custodian of the Patriarchy,&amp;rdquo; by Nellie Bowles (New York Times) Nellie Bowles writes
Mr. Peterson, 55, a University of Toronto psychology professor turned YouTube philosopher turned mystical father figure, has emerged as an influential thought leader.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Four Tendencies: 4 Ways You Can Play to Your Personality Strengths</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 18:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-four-tendencies-4-ways-you-can-play-to-your-personality-strengths/</guid>
      <description>In both my personal and coaching conversations recently, Gretchen Rubin&amp;rsquo;s personality framework called &amp;ldquo;The Four Tendencies&amp;rdquo; has really seemed to resonate with people.
So, I thought I would take a few minutes to share it with you.
Gretchen Rubin Explains the Four Tendencies First, here&amp;rsquo;s a six-minute video of Gretchen herself explaining the Four Tendencies and their relevance to changing one&amp;rsquo;s habits.
How do you respond to INNER EXPECTATIONS and OUTER EXPECTATIONS?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hate Running? Try Rucking Instead</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 16:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hate-running-try-rucking-instead/</guid>
      <description>(DISCLAIMER: You are, of course, more than welcome to try rucking, even if you also love running.)
Rucking &amp;gt; Running It took me a long time to &amp;ldquo;fall in love&amp;rdquo; with running. It did not take me nearly as long to fall out of love with running!
And yet, even though I&amp;rsquo;ve long enjoyed doing kettlebell swings and doing the 5x5 weight-lifing workout, I did begin to miss the benefits of cardio training.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s the Elevator Pitch for my Dissertation Proposal: &#34;Scriptural, but Not Religious&#34;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 21:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heres-the-elevator-pitch-for-my-dissertation-proposal-scriptural-but-not-religious/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow, I defend the proposal for my dissertation. For now, the dissertation is tentatively titled: &amp;ldquo;Scriptural, but Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion.&amp;rdquo;
Here&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;elevator pitch&amp;rdquo; for the dissertation. Feedback appreciated.
Scriptural, but Not Religious: Barth, Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion My project traces its origins to a single classroom discussion question in the Spring of 2015. The question was this: &amp;ldquo;In what ways is Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s understanding of religion similar to, and different from, that of Barth?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Grain of the Gospel: Why Christians Should Care about Food Ethics</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grain-of-the-gospel-why-christians-should-care-about-food-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 06:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grain-of-the-gospel-why-christians-should-care-about-food-ethics/</guid>
      <description>The following is a guest post written by my friend and former college roommate, Zak Weston. Zak&amp;rsquo;s been working in the area of food ethics, and I asked him to write up a post about why Christians should care about these issues. It&amp;rsquo;s an area in which I need to make some changes in my own life. He delivered this thought-provoking and challenging piece. I hope you enjoy.
Introduction The three or so decisions you make each day about what to eat are some of the most consequential choices you make in your life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to make of Jordan Peterson? Some takes, then my own.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-to-make-of-jordan-peterson-some-takes-then-my-own/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Read my post, &amp;ldquo;Two More Pieces about Jordan Peterson.&amp;rdquo;
If I remember correctly, I first heard of and listened to Jordan Peterson on an episode of The Art of Manliness podcast. (Or perhaps it was this episode.)
However, I could be mistaken, because Peterson&amp;rsquo;s been popping up in conversation all over the place in my circles. Blog posts, podcast episodes, conversations with friends - Peterson has been popping up everywhere, so it seems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do More Better: Tim Challies&#39; Excellent Little Book on Personal Productivity Could Change Your Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 13:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/do-more-better-tim-challies-excellent-little-book-on-personal-productivity-could-change-your-life/</guid>
      <description>Tim Challies begins his book, Do More Better: A Practical Guide to Productivity with a bold claim: &amp;ldquo;I believe this book can improve your life.&amp;rdquo;
However, after reading the book, which is just 120 pages long including endnotes!, I believe that Challies makes good on his claim.
As far as explicitly Christian approaches to personal productivity go, Challies’ Do More Better stands alongside Matt Perman’s What’s Best Next: How the Gospel Transforms the Way You Get Things Done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Please Don&#39;t Leave Me Alone: On Male Friendships, or the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 18:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/please-dont-leave-me-alone-on-male-friendships-or-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you, like me, consider yourself quite the introvert. Maybe you, like me, have a difficult time walking the tightrope between feeling quickly overwhelmed by interpersonal relationships, on the one hand, and feeling incredibly lonely, on the other hand.
Maybe you, like me, feel these problems acutely as a male (although I’m sure that females are having their own relational struggles as our culture increasingly pressures us all to be “alone together,” looking at our screens instead of looking each other in the eye).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Need to Develop a Writing Habit. Do You?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 14:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/i-need-to-develop-a-writing-habit-do-you/</guid>
      <description>Because good writing = good thinking, I believe that everyone could benefit from developing the habit of regular writing.
However, because I
Am a Ph.D. student about to begin work on his dissertation Edit a blog ( Rookie Anglican) Write this personal blog I really need to develop the habit of regular writing.
Up until now, I’ve largely relied upon writing in fits and starts, when the Muse descends, as it were.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting back on the &#34;Getting Things Done&#34; Productivity Bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 22:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-back-on-the-getting-things-done-productivity-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>Getting Things Done (&amp;ldquo;GTD&amp;rdquo; for short) is a wildly popular personal productivity system invented and popularized by David Allen. However, as Nicole Dieker at Lifehacker pointed out in 2017, &amp;ldquo;You don’t hear a lot of people talk about the Getting Things Done productivity system anymore.&amp;rdquo;
I think that&amp;rsquo;s a shame, because it&amp;rsquo;s a very effective system.
I first tried Getting Things Done after reading &amp;quot; What&amp;rsquo;s Best Nex t&amp;quot; by Matt Perman, and then reading &amp;quot; Getting Things Done&amp;quot; by David Allen (in its newly revised 2015 edition) shortly thereafter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Song is a Beautiful Picture of the Theological Journey</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-truth-is-not-a-cave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 21:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-truth-is-not-a-cave/</guid>
      <description>I was recently privileged to see one of my favorite bands, The Oh Hellos, in concert at the House of Blues in downtown Chicago.
I love all of The Oh Hellos&amp;rsquo; music, but one song, in particular, has remained poignant to me ever since I first heard it. The song is called &amp;ldquo;The Truth is a Cave,&amp;rdquo; and I think it provides a beautiful picture of what I&amp;rsquo;m calling &amp;ldquo;the theological journey&amp;rdquo; - the stages one goes through in one&amp;rsquo;s knowledge of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Beauty: Phoenix &amp; Grand Canyon Trip 2018</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dangerous-beauty-phoenix-grand-canyon-trip-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 14:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/dangerous-beauty-phoenix-grand-canyon-trip-2018/</guid>
      <description>Rachel and I just got back from our very first trip to the Southwest. The main reason for the trip was to visit some good friends of ours, the Smith family, in Phoenix, AZ. Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of the group of us together after church at Living Faith Anglican Church in Tempe, AZ, where my friend Peter Smith is the rector.
The trip was a blast. It was great to catch up with the Smiths and to see their new home and church in Arizona.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This One Simple Trick Helps Me Read Faster as a Ph.D. Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 06:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</guid>
      <description>Reading is the closest thing that human beings have to a superpower. We can learn, from other minds, from other times, just by looking at symbols on a screen or a page.
But, I mean, come on. Who has enough time to read? I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got a stack of books a mile high that I&amp;rsquo;d like to work my way through.
Now, there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of good advice out there about finding more time to read (see this post from Farnam Street and this post from The Art of Manliness).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christian, Do the Daily Office: 5 Things You Can Learn from Morning and Evening Prayer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christian-daily-office-5-things-can-learn-morning-evening-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christian-daily-office-5-things-can-learn-morning-evening-prayer/</guid>
      <description>The Problem: We All Need to Grow, But We&amp;rsquo;re Not Sure How Let&amp;rsquo;s face it: to say the very least, we Christians all have room to grow when it comes to following Jesus. None of us has &amp;ldquo;arrived.&amp;rdquo;
There&amp;rsquo;s always more to learn about who God is, what God has done, and how we can join God&amp;rsquo;s mission to set the world right again. And, even if we know a bunch about those things in the previous sentence, we surely don&amp;rsquo;t always live based on that knowledge!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Reasons Why I&#39;m an Anglican Christian</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 05:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/top-3-reasons-im-anglican-christian/</guid>
      <description>Why am I an Anglican Christian? Here are 3 reasons.
1. Anglicanism as a Refuge from Fundamentalism First, for me, Anglicanism has been a refuge from fundamentalism. Now, to be sure, we do have our own fundamentalists within the Anglican Communion! But, compared to some &amp;ldquo;ingrown enclaves&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced in my Christian upbringing, Anglicanism has been a breath of fresh air. It has been an ecclesiological space for healing as I seek to &amp;quot; not throw the (gospel) baby out with the (fundamentalist) bathwater.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cut the &#34;Positivity&#34; Crap: What Frustrates You?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 17:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cut-positivity-crap-frustrates/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this short, sweet, and to the point: I&amp;rsquo;m looking for problems that I can help solve, so I need you to rant at me in the comments.
That&amp;rsquo;s right, I basically want you to complain to me in the comments section of this post.
What&amp;rsquo;s causing you frustration, angst, or stress these days? What questions are you struggling to find the answers to? What obstacles are in the way of you achieving your goals?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go to Sleep and Have Some Kids: What the Bible (Psalm 127) Says about Productivity</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 12:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/go-sleep-kids-bible-psalm-127-says-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Personal Productivity in Psalm 127 I love Psalm 127. Not because it makes me feel great, necessarily, but because it hits me like a ton of bricks whenever I read it (like I did last night, during evening prayer).
Here&amp;rsquo;s how the Psalm opens:
Unless the Lord builds the house,the builders labor in vain.Unless the Lord watches over the city,the guards stand watch in vain.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy for me to think that my success or lack thereof completely depends on me and the intensity of my efforts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Confessions of an Expectant Father</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/3-confessions-expectant-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 12:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/3-confessions-expectant-father/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re Expecting! In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard the news, my wife Rachel and I are expecting our firstborn child this August! Rachel is currently 16 weeks along, and we won&amp;rsquo;t find out the gender of the baby (whom I am affectionately calling &amp;ldquo;Lump&amp;rdquo;) for another month.
The last few months have been quite busy for us since we found out Rachel is pregnant. She works full-time as a Family Nurse Practitioner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mental Models: A Helpful Model for Theology?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 15:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mental-models-helpful-model-theology/</guid>
      <description>This idea has been bouncing around in my head for a bit. It&amp;rsquo;s not fully-formed by any means, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to get it out there and hear what you think of it.
Here it is: &amp;ldquo;Mental Models&amp;rdquo; could be a helpful model for theology.
What is a &amp;ldquo;mental model&amp;rdquo;? Definition of mental models Put simply, a &amp;ldquo;mental model&amp;rdquo; is a concept used to help explain how the world works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Pray Before You Read and Write: A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 09:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/prayer-of-st-thomas-aquinas-before-study/</guid>
      <description>I want to share with you the following prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study, based on Oratio S. Thomae Aquinatis ante studium, which Thomas Aquinas would pray before studying, writing, or preaching.
We prayed it responsively before class (Patristic and Medieval History and Doctrine) with Dr. Piotr Malysz at Beeson Divinity School, and I’ve since turned back to this prayer often!
A Prayer of St. Thomas Aquinas Before Study O God, Creator of all that is, From the treasures of Your wisdom, You have arrayed the universe with marvelous order, And now govern with skill and might.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Questions to Ask When You Study the Bible (Plus a Worksheet!)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 15:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/</guid>
      <description>The Problem: Studying the Bible can Quickly Feel Overwhelming Right? Even with helpful books out there like How to Read the Bible for All Its Worth(that&amp;rsquo;s an affiliate link, by the way, meaning that I get a small commission at no cost to you if you end up buying the book), there are still so many potential questions to ask of any biblical text when we study it.
How are we supposed to keep questions of authorship, genre, meaning, application, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Books Every Christian Should Read</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 03:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/5-books-every-christian-read/</guid>
      <description>OK, OK. I get it. Claiming that every Christian should read these 5 books is a bold claim.
But, honestly, I think that these reading recommendations stand up to the scrutiny.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been wracking my brain trying to come up with just the top 5 books that a busy Christian should read if she wants to learn the essentials about:
Productivity and Time Management Bible Study Theology And, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve arrived at a pretty good shortlist if I do say so myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An 80/20 Approach to the Christian Life: 2 Reasons Why Christians Should Care About the Pareto Principle</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 12:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/80-20-approach-christian-life-2-reasons-christians-care-pareto-principle/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to live a more meaningful and purposeful Christian life, but you feel like it&amp;rsquo;s hard enough just to get everything done on your to-do list each day?
I&amp;rsquo;m right there with you! That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve made &amp;quot; Get Your Act Together (Productivity and Time Management)&amp;quot; the first of my Steps to Find Purpose and Meaning in Life.
Thankfully, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve found something that can help. I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce you to the &amp;quot; Pareto Principle,&amp;quot; also known as &amp;quot; the 80/20 Rule,&amp;quot; the &amp;ldquo;law of the vital few,&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;principle of factor sparsity,&amp;rdquo; if you want to get all technical about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Tools and Resources</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 01:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>A &amp;ldquo;tool&amp;rdquo; is &amp;ldquo;anything that can make your life better.&amp;rdquo; I love tools, whether physical or digital. And I love books, because they&amp;rsquo;re some of the best tools out there!
Lifestyle Tools Coffee Maker: OXO 9-Cup Coffee Maker Coffee Grinder: Capresso Infinity Conical Burr Grinder Water Bottle: Owala FreeSip, 24oz Previous: Iron Flask, 64oz Fitness Tools Squat Rack: REP Fitness PR-1100 Power Rack Previous: Valor Fitness BD–9 Squat Stands Bench: Amazon Basics Flat Weight Bench Barbell and Weights: Fitness Gear 300lb.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start Here</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/start-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 01:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/start-here/</guid>
      <description>The Problem: Everyone Loves a Good Story, But Few People Live One Absolutely everyone wants to live a meaningful life - to live a good story.
So why do so few of us feel like our lives have purpose?! Instead of a meaningful narrative, life seems like a series of random (at best) or unfortunate (at worst) events.
Yet, we all have a sneaking suspicion that things ought to be different, that there ought to be a greater sense of purpose, direction, and significance out there - something that can shape our chaotic series of events into a meaningful and beautiful story.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/</guid>
      <description>Joshua P. Steele, &amp;ldquo;The Rev. Dev.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m Josh Steele, a pastor-turned-programmer (&amp;ldquo;Rev[erend]&amp;quot;-to-&amp;ldquo;Dev[eloper]&amp;rdquo;) who solves problems with a programmer&amp;rsquo;s eye for detail and a pastor&amp;rsquo;s heart for people.
As a software engineer, I work mainly on backend development in Java for a cybersecurity company. But I&amp;rsquo;m also an ordained Anglican priest (currently resigned from active ministry) with three Bible/theology degrees.
Currently living in Toledo, OH, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a wife, three young children, and an addiction to buying books and tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hermeneutical Implications of Scripture&#39;s Theological Location</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hermeneutical-implications-scriptures-theological-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 15:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hermeneutical-implications-scriptures-theological-location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theological &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermeneutics&#34;&gt;hermeneutics&lt;/a&gt; – human understanding and interpretation in light of the identity and acts of the triune God – faces two problematic questions that, I believe, every biblical and/or theological scholar must be prepared to address. First, should the Bible be read in some special sense as divine revelation, or should we read the Bible like any other text? And second, should biblical and theological studies be one discipline, or two?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what follows, I propose that &lt;strong&gt;we can best account for both (1) the relationship between general and special hermeneutics and (2) the relationship between biblical and theological studies by first attending to Scripture’s theological location regarding its subject matter – the all-encompassing story, to which it bears witness, of how the triune God creates and redeems a people unto fellowship with himself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first section, I will argue that the Scripture plays an authoritative role in the all-encompassing story to which it bears witness. After briefly summarizing the subject matter of Scripture, I will explain Scripture’s role by explaining the relationships between Scripture and (1) God, (2) creation, and (3) God’s people. With respect to God, Scripture is the authoritative and inspired word of the triune God, which God uses to reveal himself and redeem his creatures. With respect to creation, because Scripture’s subject matter is all-encompassing, there is no domain outside of its purview. And with respect to God’s people, Scripture is unavoidably and irreducibly ecclesiological.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we clarify the relationship between Scripture and its subject matter, if the story to which Scripture bears witness is true, then the relationships between (1) special and general hermeneutics and (2) biblical and theological studies become much less problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second section, therefore, I maintain that, because Scripture plays a uniquely authoritative role within its all-encompassing subject matter, theological hermeneutics encompasses both special and general hermeneutics. This has implications for two related hermeneutical triads: the general hermeneutical triad of author, text, and reader, and the special hermeneutical triad of historical, literary, and theological analysis. My approach calls for giving theology pride of place in both triads. That is, the divine author, the Christ-centered text, and the Spirit-led interpretive community of the Church are of primary importance. Nevertheless, due to the historically particular way(s) in which the triune God has revealed himself and redeemed his people, a theological hermeneutic requires attending to the historical and literary particularities of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; authors, texts, and readers – especially to those involved in the interpretation of Holy Scripture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in the third section, I offer an account of biblical and theological studies as a single multifaceted discipline, one that includes both biblical studies and the various theological sub-disciplines of historical, systematic, and pastoral theology. Because Scripture’s subject matter is complex, unified, and irreducibly ecclesiological, biblical and theological studies need each other. This has, I believe, implications for how the contested and contentious fields of biblical theology and the theological interpretation of Scripture ought to relate to each other.  Furthermore, because the Church’s understanding of and participation in Scripture’s subject matter is historically, conceptually, and practically complex, the theological subdisciplines need each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principles: 10 Imperatives for the Good Life</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 16:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/principles-10-imperatives-good-life/</guid>
      <description>Why write out a list of principles?
For one thing, it&amp;rsquo;s my birthday. And, although I&amp;rsquo;m only in my twenties, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a bit reflective.
For another, I&amp;rsquo;ve just been given a copy of Principles: Life and Work by Ray Dalio (affiliate link).
According to Dalio (ix),
Principles are fundamental truths that serve as the foundations for behavior that gets you what you want out of life. They can be aplied again and again in similar situations to help you achieve your goals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testimony: A Faith Story, In Brief</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/testimony-brief/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 07:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/testimony-brief/</guid>
      <description>The following is an attempt to tell my testimony, the story of my Christian faith, in approximately 500 words. It was challenging to do, but also a helpful exercise! I challenge you to write out your own story in approximately 500 words.
Testimony For as long as I can remember, I have known and followed Jesus Christ as my Lord and Savior. However, there has been a lingering problem in our relationship – on my end.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts You Should Listen To</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 15:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-favorite-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Podcasts: An Introduction Although podcasts (think &amp;ldquo;iPod&amp;rdquo; + &amp;ldquo;broadcast&amp;rdquo;) have been around for over a decade, we&amp;rsquo;re living in a bit of a golden age - or a least a Rennaissance - of the medium. For the uninitiated, here&amp;rsquo;s a nice video about what podcasts are:
Currently, podcasts are one of my very favorite ways to consume information about a wide variety of topics. Sure, gun to my head, I&amp;rsquo;ll choose books over podcasts as a way to learn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It is Finished! So, Get to Work! - A Sermon on the Ascension</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20170613it-is-finished-so-get-to-work-an-ascension-sermon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 01:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20170613it-is-finished-so-get-to-work-an-ascension-sermon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following is an &amp;ldquo;It is Finished&amp;rdquo; sermon preached on Ascension Sunday, 2017. You can listen to the sermon here:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goodbyes-suck&#34;&gt;GOODBYES SUCK&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, if there’s one thing I hate, it’s goodbyes. Anyone else here hate goodbyes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and the fact that I hate them so much means I’m not really very good at goodbyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I get awkward and silent. Sometimes I get awkward and really chatty! Heck, sometimes I get awkward and I make poor choices, like the one time when I was getting ready to say goodbye to my family when they dropped me off at college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were looking forward to a final dinner with me, in the school cafeteria, before they left. But I was worried about the awkwardness of saying a tearful goodbye between packed tables and chairs, so I suggested that they just leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s just say that my family wasn’t very happy. And me? Neither was I. I ate my first college meal all alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodbyes suck. And I often suck at goodbyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I telling you this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, for one thing, this is my “goodbye” sermon here at St. Peter’s, and I wanted to give an excuse for this sermon, if it sucks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all seriousness, I do want to thank this congregation for being such a good place for Rachel and me to serve and grow alongside you. Thank you for loving Rachel and me as our brothers and sisters in Christ. We will miss you all very much as we move to Illinois this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I don’t want this goodbye to get TOO awkward, so I’d better keep on preaching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think that goodbyes are bad because they so often leave our stories unfinished.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we humans tend to hate unfinished business. It’s so much better when the story has an end! Sometimes, even a bad ending is better than no ending at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it, if you’re watching an important game on TV – say, Alabama vs. Auburn – would you rather see the ending, even if your team loses, or have the power go out and completely miss the final minutes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stories without endings are frustrating. And that’s why it’s so hard to say goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why Death – the ultimate goodbye, if you will – is so horrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not really an ending, not for those of us who go on living, anyways. Instead, Death leaves our stories hanging, with words left unsaid and promises left unfulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think here of parents in Manchester this week who were forced to say goodbye to their children all too soon, thanks to the suicide bombing. Or the Coptic Christians in Egypt forced to say goodbye to their loved ones too soon, thanks to the bus attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodbyes suck, because they leave our stories unfinished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note: For other sermons, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/sermons/&#34;&gt;my Sermons page&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-the-ascension-does-it-suck&#34;&gt;WHAT ABOUT THE ASCENSION? DOES IT SUCK?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the Ascension of Jesus Christ, then, just another awful goodbye?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lasting Supper - Luke 22:14-30</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 19:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is something special about last meals, isn’t there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to show you a series of photographs. These photographs, except for the last one – which I added, are from &lt;a href=&#34;http://henryhargreaves.com/no-seconds&#34;&gt;a piece called “No Seconds,” and they were put together by Henry Hargreaves&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to belabor the artwork with my commentary, so I’ll give you a few seconds to take each slide in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{ double-space-with-newline }} {{ double-space-with-newline }}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{ double-space-with-newline }} {{ double-space-with-newline }}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t know about you, but those pictures affect me deeply. The whole idea of a criminal’s last meal affects me deeply. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it’s because these last meals combine the familiar with the unfamiliar. They combine the expected and the unexpected. I mean, on one hand, you’ve got comfort food. On the other hand, heinous crimes. The stuff of life right next to life’s untimely end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Jesus of Nazareth was no common criminal, his so-called “Last Supper” with his disciples was a poignant combination of the expected and the unexpected. And when you take a look at the Last Supper, focusing on its unexpected elements, you find out that it’s really a Lasting Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, the Last Supper is not just a one-time event, some two-thousand years ago. Instead, Holy Communion, the Lasting Supper, is an ongoing meal, with profound implications for our past, our future, and our present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-meal&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Meal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let’s look at the original meal itself, the “Last Supper,” as described in our Gospel lesson (Luke 22:14-20).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio (About Me)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 17:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>CV Read my curriculum vitae to learn more about my education and experience.
Workplace Self Assessment To learn more about what I&amp;rsquo;m like as a worker, from the kinds of people I work best with to the transferable skills I bring to the table, read my results from the &amp;ldquo;Flower Petal Exercise&amp;rdquo; in What Color is Your Parachute?
Essays Read a collection of my academic essays.
Sermons Read or listen to an archive of my sermons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is The Well-Equipped Christian Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 23:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/is-the-well-equipped-christian-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever had a problem finding a reliable resource for recommendations?
I have.
Certain Google searches are a piece of cake, but the &amp;ldquo;best resources for ______&amp;rdquo; ones can be hit-or-miss.
And don&amp;rsquo;t even get me started on the decision fatigue. As a serial over-thinker, I start to hate myself a little bit after reading through the upteenth list of &amp;ldquo;5 Best ____s.&amp;rdquo; It makes it so hard to make a decision!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ahead in God&#39;s Upside-Down Kingdom: An Appeal for a Consistently Pro-Life Ethic</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-ahead-in-gods-upside-down-kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 16:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-ahead-in-gods-upside-down-kingdom/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. [ MP3: Getting Ahead in God&amp;rsquo;s Upside-Down Kingdom]
[ PDF Sermon Manuscript: Getting Ahead in God&amp;rsquo;s Upside-Down Kingdom]
Opening Prayer God, our Refuge, I ask that your Holy Spirit would move in our lives, so that we would:
promote your justice embody your steadfast faithful love and humbly obey Your will, even if it costs us our reputations, and even if it costs us our lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Be or Not To Be Religious: A Clarification of Karl Barth&#39;s and Dietrich Bonhoeffer&#39;s Divergence and Convergence Regarding Religion</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/to-be-or-not-to-be-religious-a-clarification-of-karl-barths-and-dietrich-bonhoeffers-divergence-and-convergence-regarding-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 18:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/to-be-or-not-to-be-religious-a-clarification-of-karl-barths-and-dietrich-bonhoeffers-divergence-and-convergence-regarding-religion/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
Christian theologians Karl Barth (1886-1968) and Dietrich Bonhoeffer (1906-1945) inherited a particular understanding of religion. In the broadly post-Kantian milieu, nineteenth-century thinkers such as Friedrich Schleiermacher, Albrecht Ritschl, and Adolf von Harnack defined religion essentially, anthropologically, and subjectively. That is, religion has a particular essence, and is in some manner inalienable from our humanity. The emphasis of this conception is on the experience of the religious subject, instead of the knowledge of religion’s object (let alone its reality).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essays</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/essays/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 21:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/essays/</guid>
      <description>Wheaton College Graduate School (2017 - ) (Here&amp;rsquo;s the elevator pitch for my dissertation proposal: &amp;ldquo;Scriptural, But Not Religious: Karl Barth, Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and a Biblical Critique of Religion.&amp;rdquo;)
The Guilt of Karl Barth: Strengths and Weaknesses of Barth’s Römerbrief Reading of Romans 9:30–10:21 The Tree of Religion: Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer on the Tree of Knowledge in Genesis 2:4–3:24 When will Thy Kingdom Come? The Timing and Agency of the Kingdom of God in the Lord’s Prayer Theological Hermeneutics Essay: The Hermeneutical Implications of Scripture&amp;rsquo;s Theological Location Beeson Divinity School (2013-2016) To Be or Not To Be Religious: A Clarification of Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s and Dietrich Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s Divergence and Convergence Regarding Religion A Crucicentric Credo What Does It Mean To Be Human?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 21:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/cv/</guid>
      <description>(For a brief profile of what I&amp;rsquo;m like and what makes me tick as a worker, read this self-assessment. You can also view my resume on LinkedIn.)
EXPERIENCE Software Engineer II - Proofpoint February 2023 - Present Led the design and development of a major user provisioning integration project, demonstrating leadership and technical skills. Authored scripts for system testing and delivered a technical presentation on the system. Mentored and trained new developers, showcasing leadership and interpersonal skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Disappointing Christmas Homily</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-christmas-homily/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 14:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-christmas-homily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good morning! And Merry Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, let us pray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you make us glad by the yearly festival of the birth of your only Son Jesus Christ: Grant that we, who joyfully receive him as our Redeemer, may with sure confidence behold him when he comes to be our Judge; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, who wonderfully created us in your own image and yet more wonderfully restored us through your Son Jesus Christ: grant that, as he came to share our humanity, so we may share the life of his divinity; who is alive and reigns with you, in the unity of the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, they say that Christmas is the most wonderful time of the year. I’ve even heard it said that it’s the “hap-happiest season of all”!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, can I take a poll real quick?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please raise your hand if you’ve ever had a disappointing Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean a Christmas that didn’t live up to your expectations. You wanted it to be filled with love, happiness, and peace, and instead all you got was stress, anxiety, and loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;have-you-ever-had-a-disappointing-christmas&#34;&gt;Have you ever had a disappointing Christmas?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 Works on Karl Barth &amp; Dietrich Bonhoeffer. Are There Others?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/works-on-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 20:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/works-on-barth-and-bonhoeffer/</guid>
      <description>ABROMEIT, Hans-Jürgen. Das Geheimnis Christi: Dietrich Bonhoeffers erfahrungsbezogene Christologie. Neukirchener Beiträge zur systemaschen Theologie 8. Neukirchen-Vluyn: Neukirchener Verlag, 1991. BEINTKER, Michael. “Kontingenz und Gegenständlichkeit: Zu Bonhoeffers Barth-Kritik in ‘Akt und Sein.’” In Krisis und Gnade: Gesammelte Studien zu Karl Barth, edited by Stefan Holtmann and Peter Zocher, 29–54. Tübingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2013. BENKTSON, Benkt-Erik. Christus Und Die Religion: Der Religionsbegriff Bei Barth, Bonhoeffer Und Tillich. Arbeiten Zur Theologie, II/9. Stuttgart: Calwer, 1967.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christians and Wealth: An Argument for Downward Mobility</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christians-and-wealth-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 01:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/christians-and-wealth-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great news! If you only have a minute to read about wealth, here&amp;rsquo;s my argument in a nutshell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-my-argument&#34;&gt;Outline of My Argument&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Claim: American Christians should reduce their standards of living to what is necessary for human flourishing and give their excess resources beyond this standard to the poor and oppressed.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is the firmest advocate for human flourishing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pursuit of wealth is spiritually dangerous and crippling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our culture’s inclinations toward upward financial mobility go against the message of the New Testament and the life of Christ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;God is revealed in Scripture to have a special concern for the poor and the oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christians will be held accountable for how they treat the poor and the oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objections:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This line of reasoning is advocating asceticism and is unbiblical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christians have every right to keep what they have earned and to do what they wish with their excess funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because the poor are lazy, Christians should not feel pressured to give, in case their generosity is taken advantage of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warrant:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christians want to remain true to Scripture and submit to God’s way of life in order to find satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For more on Christianity, wealth, and poverty, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2011/02/10/20110210proverbs-topical-study-poverty/&#34;&gt;my topical study on what the book of Proverbs has to teach us about poverty&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still interested in reading about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christian_views_on_poverty_and_wealth&#34;&gt;this contentious topic&lt;/a&gt;? Continue below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our current context of wealth and poverty existing side by side in a milieu of materialistic consumerism, the Christian gospel of denying ourselves and making much of God is being abandoned for the American gospel of denying others and making much of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Christians have become content to live a baptized version of the American dream, a hollow faith that is about maximizing your earthly portfolio once your salvation is secured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main contention is that &lt;strong&gt;Christians in the United States should lower their standards of living to what is necessary for human flourishing and give their excess resources beyond this standard to the poor&lt;/strong&gt;. In doing so, they will remain faithful to Scripture and discover a more satisfactory way of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;isnt-that-asceticism&#34;&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t That Asceticism?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, some may claim that I am trying to advocate for a form of asceticism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following Jesus Beyond the Bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-jesus-beyond-the-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 22:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-jesus-beyond-the-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(A chapel message in a Christian school.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things you should know about me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a student at a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; seminary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before that, I went to a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; college.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before that, I went to a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; high school, and a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; middle school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before that, I was home-schooled, and I grew up in a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, also: I’m &lt;strong&gt;the world’s worst sports fan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m serious. The students in my youth group give me a hard time about it. Every week, they’re like, “Josh, did you see the game?!” “Josh, are you going to watch the game?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I’m like, “Game? What game? I don’t even know which sport’s season it is!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World’s. worst. sports fan. I’m telling you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one redeeming quality about my sports fandom is that I’ve stuck with one team through thick and thin: the University of Michigan Wolverines. Go Blue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know that the rivalry between the Wolverines and the Ohio State Buckeyes is but a pale imitation of the rivalry between Alabama and Auburn down here. But up North, this rivalry was and is a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it was really interesting, back when I was in middle school and high school, to observe what would happen each year in November when the Wolverines and the Buckeyes went at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m from Toledo, OH, which is on the border with Michigan, so the fan split was about 50/50 – Wolverines on one side, Buckeyes on the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And each year, on the day after the big game, you could tell who the true fans were…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the people still cheering for the team that &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, &amp; The Theological Critique of Religion: My Reading List This Fall</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-the-theological-critique-of-religion-my-reading-list-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 20:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-bonhoeffer-the-theological-critique-of-religion-my-reading-list-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Read more about my work on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible here.)
This semester &amp;ndash; my final one at Beeson Divinity School -- I&amp;rsquo;m doing a directed study with Piotr Malysz on the topic of &amp;ldquo;Religion&amp;rdquo; in Karl Barth and Dietrich Bonhoeffer.
The impetus for this study was a discussion question in Dr. Malysz’s Spring 2015 20th Century History and Doctrine course. On March 24, our third class period on Dietrich Bonhoeffer, our second question for discussion read as follows:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Ridiculously Helpful Markdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 14:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-ridiculously-helpful-markdown-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been dragging my heels on learning Markdown for awhile now.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know, Markdown is:
lightweight markup language with plain text formatting syntax designed so that it can be converted to HTML and many other formats using a tool by the same name.[8] Markdown is often used to format readme files, for writing messages in online discussion forums, and to create rich text using a plain text editor. [Source: Wikipedia]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Feast of St. James the Apostle: A Homily for Ministers</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-feast-of-st-james-the-apostle-a-homily-for-ministers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 22:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-feast-of-st-james-the-apostle-a-homily-for-ministers/</guid>
      <description>Readings: Psalm 34; Jeremiah 16:14-21; Mark 1:14-20
Like so many other feast days – scheduled, as they are, on the days of the namesakes’ deaths – the feast day of St. James the Apostle is a strong rebuke to our aspirations. To our aspirations as human beings, and especially to our aspirations as ministers of Christ’s Church.
James &amp;amp; John: Fishermen No More? You see, James started off as a mere fisherman.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frustrated with Church? You&#39;re the Problem!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-youre-the-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-youre-the-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I asked you &lt;a href=&#34;http://frustrated&#34;&gt;to join the Church if you, like me, are frustrated with the Church&lt;/a&gt;. The strongest critiques of religion come from within, not without, the Christian community. Plus, your frustrations are likely shared by many others within the Church!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s not enough to point the finger at others from your pew, instead of doing so from the public square. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a good first step, but another one is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;you---and-i---need-to-be-willing-to-take-ownership-for-the-churchs-failures&#34;&gt;You - and I - need to be willing to take ownership for the Church&amp;rsquo;s failures.&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frustrated with Church? Join the Club...</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-join-the-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 17:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-join-the-club/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;and by &amp;ldquo;club&amp;rdquo; I of course mean &amp;ldquo;Church&amp;rdquo;!
What am I getting at? Am I calling the Church a mere &amp;ldquo;club&amp;rdquo;?
No. Although, unfortunately, it often feels that way, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?
A club full of hypocrisy, idolatry, indifference, and platitudes. A club full of power-plays, fear-mongering, and Bible-thumping. A club full of saints too afraid to admit that they are sinners. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;re sick of this &amp;ldquo;club,&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to leave, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t left already.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thank God, I Went to Cedarville</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/thank-god-i-went-to-cedarville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 20:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/thank-god-i-went-to-cedarville/</guid>
      <description>As I prepare for my final semester at Beeson Divinity School, it strikes me just how well I was prepared for my seminary education by my undergraduate professors at Cedarville University.
All things considered, my time at CU exposed me to the riches of biblical and theological studies, and it left me hungry for more.
College gave me a love for Christ&amp;rsquo;s gospel and Christ&amp;rsquo;s Church - which has only increased since I arrived at Beeson.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Want To Be Remembered?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/how-do-you-want-to-be-remembered/</guid>
      <description>Do you know what the worst thing about death is?
It&amp;rsquo;s not the dying itself - its the separation.
That is, we don&amp;rsquo;t suffer the most from our own deaths (a one-time occurrence), but from suffering the deaths of others (repeatedly). Instead of living relationships, we are left with distant memories.
A sad reality, to be sure.
What if, however, we could use death to our own advantage? I&amp;rsquo;m convinced this is the truth behind Ecclesiastes 7:2 -</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Take Seth Godin to Church</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/lets-take-seth-godin-to-church/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not going to lie. My first reaction when I saw the cover of this book? No! Of course you&amp;rsquo;re not indispensable. What use could this crap possibly be to the Church, or to me - simultaneously a pastor and a pastor-in-training. Then, however, I read the book. And I suggest you do, too!
(Note: affiliate link. I get paid if you make a purchase.) Seth Godin, bald marketing extraordinaire, is convinced that a paradigm shift has taken place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are you afraid of?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 20:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-are-you-afraid-of/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m scared. Are you?
Specifically, as I wrote in my journal this very morning:
I&amp;rsquo;m scared - I&amp;rsquo;m scared of wasting my life, I&amp;rsquo;m scared of not being worth anything outside of the classroom.
Fear drives so many aspects of our lives - from how we dress, to how we raise our children, to how we elect our leaders. And, if we&amp;rsquo;re honest with ourselves, fear can play a large role in what/whom we worship.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Reading</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 14:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading/</guid>
      <description>Ah, the joys of summer reading.
What about you? What are you reading? Is there anything I should add to this eclectic assortment?
~Josh ( @joshuapsteele)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kettlebell Swings: Back Balm for the Sedentary [Seminarian]</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 23:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/kettlebell-swings-back-balm-for-the-sedentary-seminarian/</guid>
      <description>I love books. Books, however, do not like my back.
Can you relate?
Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not sitting around reading books all day, but I imagine plenty of you out there suffer from back pain/fatigue.
Let me share a time-saving solution I&amp;rsquo;ve recently found: two-handed kettlebell swings.
How can these cannonballs with handles help your back?
Well, the kettlebell swing is one of the many exercises out there that activates your posterior chain - the muscles along the back of your body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Groom&#39;s Big Day</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grooms-big-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 20:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grooms-big-day/</guid>
      <description>[soundcloud url=&amp;ldquo;https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/256270902&amp;quot; params=&amp;ldquo;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;100%&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;166&amp;rdquo; iframe=&amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; /]
READINGS Ephesians 5:21-33 – Wives and Husbands Psalm 67 – May God Be Gracious to Us and Bless Us Revelation 19:6-10 – The Marriage Supper of the Lamb Matthew 25:1-13 – The Parable of the Ten Virgins HOMILY What makes a great wedding?
Is it the fragrance and color of the flower arrangements? The particular grandeur of the venue?
Is it the number and camaraderie of the guests?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Son of Man, Can Your Bones Live?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/son-of-man-can-your-bones-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 22:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/son-of-man-can-your-bones-live/</guid>
      <description>What would it have been like, on the first Holy Saturday? What would it be like, tonight, if Jesus has been dead for almost 33 hours?
All the hopes and dreams of tonight’s readings – shattered. Blown away by the cold winds of death. Jesus of Nazareth lies in a dark grave, and we, his shell-shocked followers, gather to make some sort of sense of this week’s events – to salvage some sort of hope from this week’s wreckage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Recommendations? Barth&amp;#039;s &amp;#038; Bonhoeffer&amp;#039;s False Gods</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/reading-recommendations-barths-bonhoeffers-false-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 12:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/reading-recommendations-barths-bonhoeffers-false-gods/</guid>
      <description>Hi internet - especially all you Barthians and Bonhoefferians (-ites?) out there.
I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of compiling a reading list, and I could use your suggestions.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my goal: to explore the possible relationship between Barth&amp;rsquo;s critique of the &amp;ldquo;No-God&amp;rdquo;(Nich-Gott) and Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s critique(s) of viewing God as a &amp;ldquo;stopgap&amp;rdquo; (Lückenbüßer) or &amp;ldquo;working hypothesis.&amp;rdquo;
As far as primary sources go, I plan to focus on the Romans commentary, Garrett Green&amp;rsquo;s recent re-translation of CD §17, and Letters and Papers from Prison.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Recent Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/three-recent-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 20:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/three-recent-sermons/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a grueling past few weeks at Beeson. Our Spring Break happens to coincide with Holy Week this year, and it can&amp;rsquo;t come quickly enough!
Part of the hard work has been preparing to preach three sermons for class. However, the opportunity to study and preach God&amp;rsquo;s Word is a joy that outweighs the burdens of preparation!
I have preached twice in the past month on Psalm 32. First, I delivered a sermon (&amp;ldquo;The Refreshment of Forgiveness&amp;rdquo;) designed for the Fourth Sunday in Lent, Year C, for Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sermon: The Challenge of Christmas Light</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sermon-the-challenge-of-christmas-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 20:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sermon-the-challenge-of-christmas-light/</guid>
      <description>There are better preachers out there. So, if you&amp;rsquo;re short on time, go and listen to them! However, if you&amp;rsquo;ve got 26 minutes to spare, I offer &amp;ldquo;The Challenge of Christmas Light&amp;rdquo; to you, and would love to hear your feedback.
I preached this sermon on December 27, 2015 at St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Anglican Church in Mountain Brook, AL, as we celebrated the Feast of St. John the Apostle and Evangelist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvising Church &amp; State: Overaccepting as a Synthesis of Anglican and Anabaptist Approaches</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/improvising-church-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/improvising-church-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-accepting-blocking-and-status&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION: ACCEPTING, BLOCKING, AND STATUS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the church’s perspective, is the state a promising offer, or a threatening one? At the risk of breathtaking oversimplification, Anglicans have tended to adopt the former perspective, leading to accommodation, and Anabaptists the latter, resulting in separation. &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Following Samuel Wells in his theological appropriation of terms from theatrical improvisation, the Anglican tradition has tended to respond to the promising &lt;em&gt;offers&lt;/em&gt; (invitations to respond) of the state by &lt;em&gt;accepting&lt;/em&gt; – maintaining the premise(s) of the state’s action(s). &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; The historical legacy of the Church of England has given Anglicanism, as Anderson notes, an “inheritance of a strong loyalty to the state and a conservatism that has led the church to promote the status quo more often than it agitates for reform.” &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn3&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; This inheritance from the established Church of England has coincided with a dual tendency to adopt a high &lt;em&gt;status&lt;/em&gt; (a strategy for getting one’s way), in terms of relative privilege and political optimism, and a low status, in terms of frequent subservience in church-state relations. &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn4&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For a[n attempted] summary of the Christian faith, see my essay: &amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/theology-outline/&#34;&gt;Theology in Outline: What do I Believe?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the Anabaptist tradition has tended to respond to the threatening offers of the state by &lt;em&gt;blocking&lt;/em&gt; – undermining the premise(s) of the state’s action(s). &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn5&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; For many contemporary Anabaptists, as Joireman summarizes, “[T]he state has the function of ordering the social world, and the church should be the visible witness of believers, the primary affiliation of Christians, and separate from the state.” &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn6&#34;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Passively, blocking the state can be “a choice to shut oneself away and keep oneself unsullied by the world.” &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn7&#34;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; Most often, drawing upon their sixteenth-century inheritance of facing persecution from Catholics and Protestants alike, Anabaptists have adopted a low status as somewhat of a fringe movement. Actively, however, blocking can be “a choice to take up arms,” as seen during the (admittedly rare) example of high status Anabaptist opposition during the Münster Rebellion of 1534. &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn8&#34;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;questioning-givens&#34;&gt;QUESTIONING GIVENS&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theology in Outline: What Do I Believe?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theology-outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/theology-outline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theology is confusing enough, much more so when you attempt to summarize it all in a single essay! Nevertheless, such was my assignment in seminary in 2015. Here are the results.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“At the centre of Christian faith is the history of Christ.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;At the centre of the history of Christ is his passion and his death on the cross.”&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;~ Jürgen Moltmann&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;theology-in-outline-an-attempted-summary-of-the-christian-faith&#34;&gt;Theology in Outline: A[n Attempted] Summary of the Christian Faith&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that, during the prefecture of Pontius Pilate, God died on a Roman cross. &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; We also believe that, the third day thereafter, Jesus of Nazareth – the same person who had been crucified – rose again from the dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can these things be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can the immortal, transcendent, omnipotent One come to a weak, immanent end?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can a dead human leave his grave, living?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, we face a crucial choice between:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the posited “God” of metaphysical theism and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the revealed God of the Christian faith. &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn3&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should we choose the &lt;em&gt;former&lt;/em&gt;, our Christ, canon, and confession are irreducibly &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;docetic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; – the true “God” is aloof, and merely play-acting, at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, should we choose the &lt;em&gt;latter&lt;/em&gt;, God is irreducibly, ineluctably Triune – Father, Son, and Holy Spirit. We believe, we &lt;strong&gt;trust&lt;/strong&gt; that the Triune God is who God has revealed Godself to be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 10:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/portfolio/sermons/</guid>
      <description>( Click here to view all posts that have been categorized as sermons on my blog.)
Why Haven&amp;rsquo;t You Torn the Sky Open Yet? Your browser does not support the audio element. Isaiah 64. November 28, 2020 (First Sunday of Advent). Preached at Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL (via Zoom).
Who Really Cares about the Trinity? Matthew 28:16-20. June 6, 2020. Preached at Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL (via Zoom).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faithful Faith in a Faithful God: Romans 1.1-17</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/faithful-faith-in-a-faithful-god-romans-1-1-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 08:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/faithful-faith-in-a-faithful-god-romans-1-1-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=invos5n6zts[/embed]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-introduction-the-prodigal-son-part-2&#34;&gt;I. Introduction: The Prodigal Son, Part 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a relief, to get out of that house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordinarily, Jude would have scoffed at his father’s request to purchase farming equipment from the next city – a three-day journey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ever since Ethan, that rascal (you might even say that &lt;em&gt;prodigal&lt;/em&gt;) brother of his, had returned, Jude could not stand to be in either man’s presence for long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he relished the chance to forget about his family tension on this farming errand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now he was almost home, and the painful thoughts came rushing back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dad has &lt;em&gt;changed&lt;/em&gt;. Perhaps it was early-onset dementia that caused him to forget the blessed closeness of our years together, alone, when I was not just the firstborn, but the only son. Sure, I had never been perfect, but I thought that my father was finally proud of me. That, after years of hard lessons learned, I had become the man he wanted me to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then Ethan threw it all away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Prodigal Son, Part 2: Introduction to Romans</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-prodigal-son-part-2-introduction-to-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 01:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-prodigal-son-part-2-introduction-to-romans/</guid>
      <description>What a relief, to get out of that house.
Ordinarily, Jude would have scoffed at his father’s request to purchase farming equipment from the next city – a three-day journey! But ever since Ethan, that rascal (you might even say that prodigal) brother of his, had returned, Jude could not stand to be in either man’s presence for long.
So he relished the chance to forget about his family tension on this farming errand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: Mark 8.11-21</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-8-11-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-8-11-21/</guid>
      <description>A homily on Mark 8:11-21 (ESV):
The Pharisees came and began to argue with him, seeking from him a sign from heaven to test him.And he sighed deeply in his spirit and said, “Why does this generation seek a sign? Truly, I say to you, no sign will be given to this generation.”And he left them, got into the boat again, and went to the other side.Now they had forgotten to bring bread, and they had only one loaf with them in the boat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: Mark 1.29-45</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-1-29-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 22:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-1-29-45/</guid>
      <description>A homily on Mark 1:29-45 (ESV):
And immediately he left the synagogue and entered the house of Simon and Andrew, with James and John.Now Simon&amp;rsquo;s mother-in-law lay ill with a fever, and immediately they told him about her.And he came and took her by the hand and lifted her up, and the fever left her, and she began to serve them.That evening at sundown they brought to him all who were sick or oppressed by demons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: James 2.1-13</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-james-2-1-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 21:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-james-2-1-13/</guid>
      <description>A homily on James 2.1-13 (ESV):
&amp;ldquo;My brothers, show no partiality as you hold the faith in our Lord Jesus Christ,the Lord of glory.For if a man wearing a gold ring and fine clothing comes into your assembly, and a poor man in shabby clothing also comes in,and if you pay attention to the one who wears the fine clothing and say, “You sit here in a good place,” while you say to the poor man, “You stand over there,” or, “Sit down at my feet,”have you not then made distinctions among yourselves and become judges with evil thoughts?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus is Not Just &amp;quot;One of Us&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/jesus-is-not-just-one-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 21:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/jesus-is-not-just-one-of-us/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: The audio of the following sermon, preached on July 05, 2015 at St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Anglican Church in Mountain Brook, Alabama, can be found here. (I began with a bit of a mic issue. Ignore the garbled first 10 seconds or so!)
---
Introduction The &amp;ldquo;hometown,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;home court&amp;rdquo; advantage is a very real occurrence in many areas of life. Familiar fans and supportive surroundings help us humans to perform better at many tasks, from singing to sports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentecost: Songs and Scripture</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pentecost-songs-and-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 15:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pentecost-songs-and-scripture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://homebrewedchristianity.com/2015/05/18/pentecost-the-arrival-of-the-spirit-and-the-lectiocast/&#34;&gt;the first episode&lt;/a&gt; of the excellent new podcast, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jrdkirk.com/2015/05/14/lectiocast-a-lectionary-commentary-podcast/&#34;&gt;LectioCast&lt;/a&gt;, helped to orient my thoughts toward &lt;a href=&#34;http://lectionary.library.vanderbilt.edu/&#34;&gt;tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s readings&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.christiantoday.com/article/nine.key.things.to.know.about.pentecost/54344.htm&#34;&gt;Pentecost Sunday&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve reproduced the first lesson, psalm, second lesson, and Gospel reading below, but I&amp;rsquo;d also like to call your attention to three powerful songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;song-1-dry-bones-by-gungor&#34;&gt;Song #1: &amp;ldquo;Dry Bones&amp;rdquo; by Gungor&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first song is &amp;ldquo;Dry Bones&amp;rdquo; by Gungor. Read the Ezekiel passage and psalm below, and give it a listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ioMRzpmnl7U[/embed]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-lesson-ezekiel-371-14net-bible&#34;&gt;First Lesson: Ezekiel 37:1-14 (NET Bible)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-valley-of-dry-bones&#34;&gt;The Valley of Dry Bones&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be human?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-does-it-mean-to-be-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 22:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-does-it-mean-to-be-human/</guid>
      <description>What Does It Mean to Be Human? A clue to the answer lies in the asking of the question, for this act presupposes both a [human] subject and object in a dialectic of self-transcendence.
As Robert Jenson notes, “in asking this question, we somehow take up a vantage outside ourselves to make ourselves our own objects, get beyond ourselves to look back at ourselves.”1 The mystery of human existence is “that I am the subject of the object I am and the object of the subject I am.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disunity in the Church? Absurd!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/disunity-in-the-church-absurd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 09:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/disunity-in-the-church-absurd/</guid>
      <description>Presented at Southeast ETS 2015.
DISUNITY AS ECCLESIOLOGICAL IMPOSSIBILITY:A BARTHIAN ANALOGY
Joshua P. Steele
INTRODUCTION Just as sin is ontological impossibility, disunity is ecclesiological impossibility. The tension between the undeniable reality of sin and Karl Barth’s theological definition of sin as an impossible possibility parallels the tension between the obvious reality of a fractured church1 and the theological definition of the church as the one body of the one Christ. Two excerpts from the Barthian corpus legitimize this connection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hope of the Holy Innocents</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-hope-of-the-holy-innocents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-hope-of-the-holy-innocents/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. (PDF: The Hope of the Holy Innocents)
Today is December 28 (2014) – just the third day since Christmas – a commemoration of what is often called “ The Slaughter of the Innocents,” the killing of the baby boys of Bethlehem by King Herod.
The Church’s regard for this day as a feast day is quite early, going back to at least the fifth century.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Brokenhearted God</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-brokenhearted-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-brokenhearted-god/</guid>
      <description>Not to take away from the undeniably biblical teaching that God is almighty, but sometimes I think we lose sight of God&amp;rsquo;s love for his image-bearers when we emphasize certain &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; portraits of God at the expense of (instead of alongside of) other &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; portraits found in Scripture. (I put &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; in quotes because perhaps our definitions of strength and weakness therefore need to change!)
It might make some of us uncomfortable to read about God portrayed as a jilted lover or a frustrated mother, but those portraits just might be desperately needed in a time when so many people turn away from God because they can&amp;rsquo;t understand how he can possibly be the good Lord of a world so broken and dying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Uncle, Timothy Steele</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20150424my-uncle-timothy-steele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20150424my-uncle-timothy-steele/</guid>
      <description>(This post is about my late uncle, Timothy Steele. It&amp;rsquo;s long, and I swear toward the end. Sorry.)
&amp;ldquo;It is better to go to a funeral than a feast. For death is the destiny of every person, and the living should take this to heart. Sorrow is better than laughter, because sober reflection is good for the heart.&amp;rdquo; (Ecclesiastes 7:2-3)
Timothy Steele The juxtaposition is staggering. The funeral of the man I most associate with laughter and joy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Give Thanks!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/give-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/give-thanks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not the most thankful person.
However, I am a follower of Jesus, and one of the lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning this semester is that praise, thanksgiving, and gratitude are closely intertwined. Worship should involve the public proclamation of who God is and what He has done &amp;ndash; including specific, personal declarations of thanksgiving for God&amp;rsquo;s grace and good gifts.
If, like me, you have a hard time cultivating this worshipful practice of gratitude, then allow me to suggest the following prayers from the Book of Common Prayer to help get us started.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #1, Stones into Bread</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread/</guid>
      <description>Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations isperenniallyinspiring, but particularly poignant during this season of Lent.
What does it mean for Christ to be the Perfect Penitent? And how should this influence our own repentance?
The following series of quotations comes from a lengthy small-print section in CD IV/1, 259-73 (§ 59 The Obedience of the Son of God; 2. The Judge Judged in Our Place). There Barth walks through the three wilderness temptations before masterfully connecting them to Christ&amp;rsquo;s experience in the Garden of Gethsemane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presenting on Karl Barth at 2015 Southeastern ETS</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/presenting-on-barth-at-2015-southeastern-ets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/presenting-on-barth-at-2015-southeastern-ets/</guid>
      <description>I just received the news today that my student paper submission for the 2015 Southeast Regional Meeting of the Evangelical Theological Society has been accepted!
My theme lately has been to write on Karl Barth and the unity of the Church. At last year&amp;rsquo;s Regional ETS (hosted by my seminary, Beeson Divinity School), I presented an edited version of my undergraduate thesis: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof: Atonement, Ecclesiology, and the Unity of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #2, Christendom&amp;#039;s Cost -- Worship Satan</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-2-christendoms-cost-worship-satan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-2-christendoms-cost-worship-satan/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I posted the beginning of Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations. He does a masterful job of explaining how Christ was tempted, not to violate the Law or commit a moral infraction, but to abandon his role as the obedient, Perfect Penitent. Put differently, Barth clarifies that Jesus&amp;rsquo; sinlessness is not a vague moral perfection, but rather obedience and repentance.
Christ&amp;rsquo;s first temptation was to turn stones into bread, thereby using divine power as a &amp;ldquo;technical instrument&amp;rdquo; to save and maintain his own life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #3, The Leap of False Faith</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-3-the-leap-of-false-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-3-the-leap-of-false-faith/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reproducing Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s magnificent exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations in Church Dogmatics IV/1.
It is a particularly appropriate discussion for this season of Lent, for Jesus was not tempted to break the Law or commit a moral infraction. Instead, he was tempted to abandon his role as the Perfect Penitent. For Barth, if Christ had capitulated to any of the temptations, he would have abandoned God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive mission. Jesus Christ had to persist in penitence in order to be &amp;quot; the Judge Judged in Our Place&amp;quot; (Barth&amp;rsquo;s most concise description of the atonement proper).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who am I to be a theologian?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-am-i-to-be-a-theologian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-am-i-to-be-a-theologian/</guid>
      <description>For my 20th Century History &amp;amp; Doctrine course at Beeson Divinity School, I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading through Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s Evangelical Theology: An Introduction. If you&amp;rsquo;re involved in the life and ministry of the Church in any respect, I strongly recommend that you buy and read this book!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a particularly challenging portion from the chapter on &amp;ldquo;Wonder,&amp;rdquo; beginning on page 71. I wish the language were gender-inclusive, but Karl&amp;rsquo;s words still ring true:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHITE NOISE, BHOPAL, AND THE HYPERREAL FEAR OF DEATH</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/white-noise-bhopal-and-the-hyperreal-fear-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 08:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/white-noise-bhopal-and-the-hyperreal-fear-of-death/</guid>
      <description>The following essay deals with the theme of the fear of death in White Noise, the novel by Don DeLillo (affiliate link).
It is better to go to a funeral than a feast. For death is the destiny of every person, and the living should take this to heart. [1]
Don DeLillo’s White Noise, “a paradigm of postmodern literature,”[2] yields the kind of cognitive dissonance that makes you wonder whether the author simply missed the mark, or if you are only confused because you suffer from the postmodern condition which DeLillo adroitly analyzes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Sermon: Our Help</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-sermon-our-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 14:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-sermon-our-help/</guid>
      <description>Hey internet: I was recently given the chance to preach at my church, St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Anglican, on the Second Sunday of Lent. The sermon audio is now online. If you&amp;rsquo;ve got 23 minutes to spare, give it a listen!
First, here are the passages:
Psalm 121 Genesis 12:1-4 Romans 4:1-5, 13-17 John 3:1-17 Then, make sure to ignore my two seconds of speech from 16:35-16:37 in the audio, I departed from my notes &amp;ndash; which ended at &amp;ldquo;Nicodemus then fades from the narrative,&amp;rdquo; (which he does in the passage at hand) &amp;ndash; and said that Nicodemus apparently never gets it and never shows up again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 2014 Regional ETS Paper: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 09:01:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-2014-regional-ets-paper-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, here&amp;rsquo;s the latest version of the Regional ETS paper I will present today at 5:00pm at Beeson Divinity School, room S009.
If you&amp;rsquo;re able to attend the presentation, that&amp;rsquo;s great! If not, feel free to give my paper a read and get back to me with any questions, comments, or suggestions. Atonement theology and the unity of the Church are two things about which I am very passionate, and intend to devote further study to these areas in the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ok, Maybe a Bit More on Cedarville...</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ok-maybe-a-bit-more-on-cedarville/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 11:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/ok-maybe-a-bit-more-on-cedarville/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ll notice that the previous post on Cedarville ends with a link to the Course Schedule:
&amp;ldquo;Class Limited to Women&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; I know, ludicrous. Especially considering Joy Fagan&amp;rsquo;s previous track record of making the first class, Scriptural Interpretation of Gender Issues (or SIGI), a truly excellent course by all accounts from former students, male and female.
Equally ludicrous? The textbook choices! Are you ready for what CU students will be reading to form an even-handed perspective of what the Bible has to say on gender?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerning Romans</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/concerning-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 11:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/concerning-romans/</guid>
      <description>Well, judging by my blog stats for the past 48 hours &amp;ndash; as compared with the past few months &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;d get many more views on this post if it concerned the chaos at Cedarville University!
However, my schedule and blood pressure won&amp;rsquo;t allow me to devote any more time to my shameful alma mater at the moment. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a presentation at the 2014 Southeast Regional Meeting of ETS tomorrow (see my previous post, and come to my presentation at 5:00pm in room S009!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cedarville...</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 17:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-2/</guid>
      <description>I wish I could say I was proud of my alma mater&amp;hellip;
Despite my Lenten Facebook fast, I was made aware of the following post by my friend Marlena Graves. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it, just in case anyone is considering Cedarville as a choice for college. I&amp;rsquo;d still strongly recommend you attend another institution, where you can trust the administration. My previous thoughts on these matters still stand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peru 2014!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/peru-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 17:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/peru-2014/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that Rachel and I will be completing my required Cross Cultural Ministry Practicum for Beeson Divinity School along with our good friends Kyle, Rebekah, and baby Luke DeBoer in Lima, Peru this summer!
Our goal is to assist the Stone families (Dave &amp;amp; Evelyn; Jonathan &amp;amp; Angela) in their various local ministries, including:
Seminario Teológico Bautista (Seminary) Luz del Camino Iglesia (Church) Vida Nueva Centro Prenatal (Pregnancy Center) The goal of Beeson&amp;rsquo;s required Cross Cultural Ministry Practicum is to &amp;quot; expose students to issues related to cross-cultural ministry through first-hand experience in a cross-cultural ministry setting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Regional ETS Presentation: Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 15:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-regional-ets-presentation-reconciliation-and-the-lack-thereof/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re in the Birmingham area from March 21-22, 2014, and you&amp;rsquo;re interested in evangelical theology, please consider attending the Evangelical Theological Society&amp;rsquo;s Southeastern Regional Meeting at Beeson Divinity School! This year&amp;rsquo;s theme is &amp;ldquo;the theological interpretation of Scripture,&amp;rdquo; and the plenary speaker is Wheaton&amp;rsquo;s Daniel J. Treier (incidentally, Dr. Treier and I are both alumni of Cedarville&amp;hellip;go figure).
Furthermore, if you&amp;rsquo;re free from 5:00-5:30pm on Friday, March 21, consider swinging by room S009 to hear me present &amp;ldquo;Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof: Atonement, Ecclesiology, and the Unity of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Translation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-perfect-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 09:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-perfect-translation/</guid>
      <description>Over the break between semesters at Beeson Divinity School, I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing Bruce Waltke&amp;rsquo;s The Dance Between God and Humanity: Reading the Bible Today as the People of God and Philip Goodwin&amp;rsquo;s Translating the English Bible: From Relevance to Deconstruction for Liverpool Hope University&amp;rsquo;s Theological Book Review.
I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished the latter, and hope to write my review in the next day or two. However, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share the following quotes on Deconstructive Literalism and The Perfect Translation, because I find the concepts intriguing as a student of Eugene Nida&amp;rsquo;s dynamic or functional equivalence (when it comes to both NT Greek and modern Spanish), and a newcomer to relevance theory, which Goodwin uses to provide a way forward in the shadow of the KJV tradition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Epistle to Philemon: Analysis and Application</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-epistle-to-philemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-epistle-to-philemon/</guid>
      <description>As the briefest member of the Pauline corpus, the epistle to Philemon is a letter of recommendation for the sake of reconciliation in which the apostle Paul brings the gospel truth of mutual participation in the body of Christ to bear on an estranged relationship – making a delicate request of his friend Philemon to receive back a certain Onesimus into full fellowship as a brother in Christ. [1]Comprehension of the passage’s contemporaneous Greco-Roman epistolary landscape facilitates a knowledgeable analysis of its constituent parts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Friday Book Recommendation: The Economy of Desire</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/black-friday-book-recommendation-the-economy-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 16:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/black-friday-book-recommendation-the-economy-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>Black Friday proves that the progress of (post)modernity has failed to eradicate the ills of idolatry. Lest we denizens of the &amp;ldquo;highly-developed&amp;rdquo; world think that we have left the primitive vestiges of wood, rock, and gold idolatry behind, our shopping patterns (and indeed our shopping identities as consumers) should remind us of our consumerism&amp;rsquo;s dark side -- a lethal one.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve put in &amp;ldquo;Reconciliation and the Lack Thereof&amp;rdquo;:
&amp;ldquo;Although physical idols may not be as universally common today as they once were, invisible idols are as prevalent as ever, especially within the context of Western materialism, where money, possessions, influence, and power are the modern-day Baal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silence and Violence</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/silence-and-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 18:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/silence-and-violence/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;] Silent Cross by Margot Krebs Neale[/caption]
&amp;ldquo;Violence is not human destiny because the God of peace is the beginning and the end of human history&amp;hellip;
&amp;ldquo;Granted, pushing the stone of peace up the steep hill of violence &amp;hellip; is hard. It is easier, however, than carrying one&amp;rsquo;s own cross in the footsteps of the crucified Messiah. This is what Jesus Christ asks Christians to do. Assured of God&amp;rsquo;s justice and undergirded by God&amp;rsquo;s presence, they are to break the cycle of violence by refusing to be caught in the automatism of revenge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Holy Trinity: What Is It? (Why) Is It Important?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/holy-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 21:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/holy-trinity/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: The Holy Trinity One God. Three persons. The Holy Trinity.The orthodox paradox of this Christian confession confounds many, due to its apparent contradictions, abstractions, and absence from Scripture. From Arius to Augustine and beyond, trinitarian debates have raged even among those who agree that God exists, that the Bible is true, and that it is therefore worthwhile to consider what the Bible says because it reveals the existent God. Although the best discussions of the Trinity begin with an acknowledgment of its inscrutable mystery which eludes the grasp of human reason&amp;rsquo;s highest reach, a sober analysis of the doctrine&amp;rsquo;s canonical presence and historical outworking may help to answer the charges that the Trinity is a nonsensical, unbiblical abstraction worthy of abandonment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 2: Quare Fremuerunt Gentes? (Why Do the Nations Rage?)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/psalm-2-quare-fremuerunt-gentes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 22:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/psalm-2-quare-fremuerunt-gentes/</guid>
      <description>(Here&amp;rsquo;s my paper on Psalm 2, submitted to Dr. M. Sydney Park in partial fulfillment of my Biblical Interpretation course here at Beeson Divinity School. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t consider this the best thing I&amp;rsquo;ve ever written, I&amp;rsquo;d love for you to check this piece out and let me know what you think, because no matter the limitations of the assignment, there&amp;rsquo;s always room for improvement. Plus, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have space to talk about all the issues whirring around in my head while writing this paper, and your constructive feedback might very well help me take my next intellectual steps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miroslav Volf on Divine Violence</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/volf-on-divine-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 08:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/volf-on-divine-violence/</guid>
      <description>A couple relevant excerpts (given recent posts) from &amp;ldquo;Violence and Peace,&amp;rdquo; the final chapter of Miroslav Volf&amp;rsquo;s Exclusion and Embrace(my emphasis added in bold; paragraph breaks added where noted):
&amp;ldquo;God will judge, not because God gives people what they deserve, but because some people refuse to receive what no one deserves; if evildoers experience God&amp;rsquo;s terror, it will not be because they have done evil, but because they have resisted to the end the powerful lure of the open arms of the crucified Messiah.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Down With the Pacifists!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/down-with-the-pacifists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 20:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/down-with-the-pacifists/</guid>
      <description>The past week has been a great one for slipshod attacks on pacifism. First, from First Things (Stephen H. Webb) on October 15 &amp;mdash;- &amp;ldquo;John Howard Yoder and the Violent Power of Pacifism&amp;rdquo; (emphasis added below):
&amp;ldquo;Nevertheless, pacifists, at least the ones I know, can be very enthusiastic about the rightness of their cause. Since there is no rational justification for pacifism, defenders typically turn their rhetoric against their critics by casting them as stooges of the status quo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scripture: What The Bible Is And Why It Matters</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2013 13:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-scripture/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION: THE NATURE OF SCRIPTURE As the illocutionary act which testifies to the Son of God 1 as the ultimate redemptive and revelatory locution of the the triune God, Scripture is used by the Spirit of God to accomplish the perlocutionary end of redemption of, in, and through the people of God. 2[Ahem, in order to understand my first paragraph, you must first be familiar with the basics of Speech Act Theory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>King Jesus&amp;#039; Kingdom Gospel</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 13:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/king-jesus-kingdom-gospel/</guid>
      <description>I highly encourage the following:
1. Read Scot McKnight&amp;rsquo;s The King Jesus Gospel.
2. Check out Tim Gombis&amp;rsquo; insightful series of posts on The Gospel of the Kingdom, pt. 1, 2, and 3.
Gombis hits the nail on the head here:
Over the last several months, I’ve had several conversations about how the Gospels’ language about “the gospel” should shape how Christians conceive of the gospel. Whereas the New Testament mainly envisions a broader announcement of a larger reality, many evangelicals associate “the gospel” with a brief presentation, or information about the mechanics of an individual transaction that can secure divine forgiveness and the establishment of a personal relationship with God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alabama Update</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20130719alabama-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 09:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20130719alabama-update/</guid>
      <description>Rachel and I are in the middle of our second month of calling Birmingham, Alabama &amp;ldquo;home.&amp;rdquo;
While we could both do with a little less humidity (!), we&amp;rsquo;re enjoying ourselves and our surroundings down here in Alabama.
What&amp;rsquo;s Happening in Birmingham, AL: I don&amp;rsquo;t start my M.Div. coursework at Beeson Divinity School until late August, but I&amp;rsquo;ve already started working at Beeson&amp;rsquo;s Media Center (follow our nascent Twitter account here). It&amp;rsquo;s an incredibly convenient on-campus job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Requiescas in Pace, Mi Avia</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/requiescas-in-pace-mi-avia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 17:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/requiescas-in-pace-mi-avia/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Depart, O Christian soul, out of this world;
In the Name of God the Father Almighty who created you;
In the Name of Jesus Christ who redeemed you;
In the Name of the Holy Spirit who sanctifies you.
May your rest be this day in peace,
and your dwelling place in the Paradise of God.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inductive Bible Study in 7 Steps: &#34;Scripture, Handle With Care,&#34; by Amy Chase Ashley</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/inductive-bible-study-7-steps-amy-chase-ashley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/inductive-bible-study-7-steps-amy-chase-ashley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Update (April 2017): I&amp;rsquo;ve gone back to update/clean-up the formatting in this wonderful June 2013 guest post on the basics of inductive Bible study from my friend &lt;strong&gt;Amy Elizabeth Chase Ashley,&lt;/strong&gt; one of the most gifted students of Scripture with whom I&amp;rsquo;ve been privileged to study. She blogs at &lt;a href=&#34;https://amyechase.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;https://amyechase.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;jeremiah-2911&#34;&gt;Jeremiah 29:11&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I accepted the invitation to speak at my parents’ church, I immediately started thinking about what message I would deliver.  I decided to give a message on something that is very important to me after my four years at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cedarville.edu/&#34;&gt;Cedarville&lt;/a&gt; and something I am very passionate about.  I hope it will be engaging; I hope it will make you think; and I hope it will bring glory to God.  If I can accomplish those three things, I will be satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Scripture I chose is Jeremiah 29:11 and I’m guessing that most Christians could recite the verse from memory.  If not, once you read it, you’ll probably remember or recognize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“’For I know the plans I have for you,’ declares the Lord, ‘plans to prosper you and not to harm you, plans to give you a hope and a future.’”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a familiar verse for a lot of Christians.  My question today is whether it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might seem like a strange question, but I think you’ll understand what I mean soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why is this verse so familiar to us?  Well, it’s used a lot.  Are you nervous about future uncertainties?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11&lt;/em&gt;.  Are you starting a new job? &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;  Graduating from high school or college?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;  That teenage girl had her boyfriend break up with her?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;  Car trouble that makes you late to work?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;  Lost your lucky pencil?  &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you’re catching my sarcasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://rlv.zcache.com/jeremiah_29_11_i_know_the_plans_bible_verse_denim_keychain-r143db7130dbe4fb3a239db30a4aeef88_x7j3z_8byvr_512.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;
And maybe you think I’m exaggerating.  But I did a Google search for Jeremiah 29:11 and you can buy folders, clocks, plaques, keychains, mugs, pictures, bumper stickers, aprons, tote bags, iPhone cases, tshirts, pillows, bracelets, and even playing cards that have this verse on them.  It might be rivaling the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Psalm%2023&amp;amp;version=NET&#34;&gt;23rd Psalm&lt;/a&gt; after all that.   And I know for a fact that it can be found on countless greeting cards whether they be sympathy, graduation, engagement, or congratulatory cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/this-is-not-a-bag-of-trail-mix-you-cant-just-pick-out-the-p.png&#34; alt=&#34;- this is not a bag of trail mix you cant just pick out the p&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a meme on the internet the other day.  It was an image of the Bible, and the text said: “This is not a bag of trail mix.  You can’t just pick out the pieces you like and ignore the rest.”  I’m afraid that the widespread use of Jeremiah 29:11 demonstrates a bigger problem: we really are guilty of treating the Bible like a bag of trail mix.  Jeremiah 29:11 is an M&amp;amp;M that we pull out time and time again while we ignore all the peanuts and raisins and cashews and granola all around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christians claim to have a high view of Scripture—that is, we say that the Bible is the authoritative, divinely inspired Word of God.  We are quick to use it to tell the world what they’re doing wrong whether that be gay marriage or murder or how to raise children.  We say that we live by what the Bible says, but I’m afraid that we’re often guilty of not even knowing what the Bible says.  For me, the widespread use of Jeremiah 29:11 proves this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate, does anyone know what Jeremiah 29:10 says?  No, because it’s a peanut.  Jeremiah 29:12?  Sorry, I don’t like raisins.  But I am feeling uncertain about this new job/relationship/house/baby/friend/responsibility/accomplishment/etc., so I like to be told that God has good plans for me.  I like to imagine him saying, “I know the plans I have for you…”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heads up! Guest post on the way.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heads-up-guest-post-on-the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 13:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/heads-up-guest-post-on-the-way/</guid>
      <description>Great news! The first ever guest post on this blog is coming soon from my good friend Amy Chase, an incoming student this Fall at Asbury Theological Seminary.
Her post? A sermon titled &amp;quot; Jeremiah 29:11, Scripture: Handle with Care.&amp;quot;
Stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Un)Righteous Anger? - Yoda, Jonah, Nahum, and Us</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unrighteous-anger-yoda-jonah-nahum-and-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 21:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unrighteous-anger-yoda-jonah-nahum-and-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(TEXTS: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Jonah%203:5-10;%204:1-11;%20Nahum%201:1-8&amp;amp;version=NET&#34;&gt;Jonah 3:5-10; 4:1-11; Nahum 1:1-8&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/fear-leaeds-to-anger-yoda-quote-from-star-wars.jpg?w=590&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great green theologian of old claimed that anger is based on fear, that it leads to hatred, and results in suffering. And while I do not wish to disregard the wisdom of a long time ago in a galaxy far, far away, I would like to take a closer look at anger as discussed in Scripture, and to consider what makes certain instances of anger righteous or unrighteous, legitimate or illegitimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a question that has been on my mind throughout my final year at Cedarville University. After hearing of a few rumblings at the end of my Junior year, I left for the summer and got myself married. When my feet finally touched the ground at the beginning of term, my university felt like a battlefield. I heard that Michael Pahl had been “reviewed” and then fired over the summer months. Others were being reviewed to see if they really did toe the doctrinal line, or if they were guilty of mind crimes against the thought police. And things didn’t get any better from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw the havoc that the Cedarville environment was wreaking on my mentors, friends, and their families. My leaders got rid of and harassed beloved members of my community, and then deceptively refused to own up to their nefarious actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fiatlux125.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://si0.twimg.com/profile_images/2786885016/098d40ad39a165603e09a1915c37f88a.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2013/01/13/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/&#34;&gt;I got angry. I spoke up&lt;/a&gt;. And I was convinced that my anger was righteous. Others were less convinced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some stayed poignantly and painfully silent throughout the chaos. Others repeatedly gave platitudes that everything was OK, that we were obligated to trust our leaders, that to question their actions was inherently disrespectful. And some from this latter group met my kind of anger with their own frustration and anger that I dared to criticize their beloved Cedarville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d love to say that I met this opposition with nothing but grace and equanimity, but that wouldn’t be true. I frequently lashed out against these types of people - when they sent me long messages to accuse me of causing unnecessary dissentious strife, or when they parodied us student activists as complete morons with nothing better to do than cook up conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My university’s behavior was sickening, but these people’s behavior was infuriating. I couldn’t comprehend how they could overlook the suffering I was witnessing and try to protect people who were clearly hiding the truth. So, at times, I lashed out in frustration. And I am convinced that my anger was unrighteous. But what’s the difference between these two types of anger?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 17:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Submissions from this form will go straight to my inbox, and I will reply as quickly as possible.
Grace and Peace,
~Josh</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Unforgettable Cedarville Experience (pt 2)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience-pt-2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 09:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience-pt-2-2/</guid>
      <description>Since my previous post, quite a few things have happened at my alma mater. Here’s a Storify overview of my crazy final year at Cedarville University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Farewell to Cedarville</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-farewell-to-cedarville/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 06:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-farewell-to-cedarville/</guid>
      <description>(Originally posted in The Ventriloquist. Go check out the rest of Issue 10!)
&amp;ldquo;A Farewell to Cedarville&amp;rdquo; - Joshua Steele
As what was once a vision for the future has become an agenda for returning to the past, the list of people who no longer fit the Cedarville mold is growing. I contacted former vice president of Student Life, Dr. Carl Ruby; former professor Dr. Michael Pahl; current professors Dr. TC Ham, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honors, Grace, and Generosity</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/honors-grace-and-generosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 22:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/honors-grace-and-generosity/</guid>
      <description>Yahweh and others have been too good to me.
Today I received two awards at Cedarville University&amp;rsquo;s 49th Annual Academic Honors Day Chapel.
The first: The Oxford University Press Award in Preseminary Bible, given to the graduating senior with the highest cumulative GPA in the preseminary major.
The second: The Daniel Award.
&amp;ldquo;Established in 2001 by David and Jean Heyd, this endowed award was created to honor their parents, Charles and E.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Building/Burning Bridges</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-buildingburning-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/on-buildingburning-bridges/</guid>
      <description>DISCLAIMER: there&amp;rsquo;s a fair bit about the Church that frustrates me.
However, I&amp;rsquo;d like to address those frustrations in a way that builds bridges, not burns them down. Especially since sin and justice are both relational. It does no good to flee the former for the latter in a way that creates more rifts than it heals.
Therefore, any criticisms I level against my sisters and brothers in Christ, (many of those criticisms coming from outside the walls of the Church), I&amp;rsquo;d like first to aim them at myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let There Be Light: My Resignation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/let-there-be-light-my-resignation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 16:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/let-there-be-light-my-resignation/</guid>
      <description>**Please read:Let There Be Light - Leadership Transfer** Until further notice, I hereby rescind my use of the Let There Be Light platform (including blog, Facebook, and Twitter) to protest recent changes at Cedarville University. The LTBL platform will now be exclusively alumni-run, and I encourage everyone interested in developments at the University to follow their posts and make subsequent judgments regarding Cedarville&amp;rsquo;s identity and vision.
My goal in all of this is to honor my Messiah by following him well and furthering his Kingdom with justice, unity, and true peace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Apology</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-apology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 23:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-apology/</guid>
      <description>To whomever the following concerns:
I&amp;rsquo;d like to apologize publicly to any persons I may have offended during the past few months of my student activism efforts at Cedarville University.
After all, I recognize that some of my statements/claims about the perceived injustices at my University have seemed quite shocking, especially without further context. So I apologize for the times when I put pithiness before precision and unwittingly ostracized many good people whom I was not intending to criticize at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For shame, Cedarville</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/2320/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 08:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/2320/</guid>
      <description>This is ridiculous and dangerous. For shame, Mr. Scharnberg and Dr. Gredy.
How dare you try and accomplish this (already concerning) return to fundamentalism in an unethical manner! How dare you sacrifice good men and their families on the altar of your own agenda, and then proceed to bathe your actions in lies!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oh Cedarville...</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/oh-cedarville/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 07:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/oh-cedarville/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been extremely frustrated with someone/thing you love?
That&amp;rsquo;s been my experience during my final year here at Cedarville University. See, I love this place. And that&amp;rsquo;s why I can&amp;rsquo;t stand it sometimes. There are still so many good and godly women and men here, so much potential for God&amp;rsquo;s Kingdom. And that&amp;rsquo;s why recent decisions made by Cedarville Admins and Trustees are so heartbreaking. I&amp;rsquo;ve written about this before (Open Letter).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Interpreting the Bible: Deuteronomy 6:1-15</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/deuteronomy-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 20:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/deuteronomy-6/</guid>
      <description>Deuteronomy 6:1-15 (NRSV) Now this is the commandment—the statutes and the ordinances—that the Lord your God charged me to teach you to observe in the land that you are about to cross into and occupy, 2 so that you and your children and your children’s children may fear the Lord your God all the days of your life, and keep all his decrees and his commandments that I am commanding you, so that your days may be long.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Reading Romans 13 Wrong! Here&#39;s How to Read It Correctly</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 07:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-13/</guid>
      <description>This study of Romans 13 rests upon a crucial presupposition: without context, words can mean anything and everything, and therefore mean nothing. It is only through the delimiting influence of context that words, phrases, sentences, and paragraphs are endowed with significance.
Although this concept seems simple and justified enough, it is often forgotten within the field of biblical exegesis. Due to influences as simple as our versification of the biblical text and as complex as the historical/theological developments which have dictated how we teach and interpret the Scriptures, many exegetes (wittingly or unwittingly) ignore context when trying to ascertain the meaning of particular biblical texts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter to Cedarville Admins and Trustees</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 21:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/</guid>
      <description>To my sisters and brothers in Christ, entrusted with the arduous task of leading and directing Cedarville University: greetings, grace, and peace.
Allow me to thank you all for your countless hours of service to this institution. I do not want to underestimate your care and concern for this place. In fact, I want to reassure you that I share your passion. Here at Cedarville I have been blessed with the opportunity of meeting, falling in love with, and marrying my wife.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Explanation</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/an-explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 17:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/an-explanation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read my previous two blog posts, &lt;a href=&#34;http://windowinthesky.wordpress.com/2012/09/20/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-1/&#34; title=&#34;Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 1)&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://windowinthesky.wordpress.com/2012/09/21/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-2/&#34; title=&#34;Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 2)&#34;&gt;pt. 2)&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; please go do so before reading this post.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging in order to raise awareness of Cedarville University&amp;rsquo;s recent dismissal of Dr. Michael Pahl from his teaching post. Using the University&amp;rsquo;s statement on Dr. Pahl, I&amp;rsquo;ve raised some uncomfortable questions that I believe need to be asked in this situation. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why were the five accolades attached to Dr. Pahl above ( &lt;em&gt;in the statement&lt;/em&gt;, orthodox, gospel, Scripture, scholar, teacher) not enough to keep him on the teaching faculty of Cedarville University?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t we want promising scholars and dedicated teachers who are committed to the gospel, to Scripture, and to orthodoxy at Cedarville University? If not, why not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing today because the responses I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to those posts and questions have been mixed. Some think I&amp;rsquo;m doing something that is both &lt;em&gt;righteous&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;necessary&lt;/em&gt;, respectfully raising awareness and asking uncomfortable-yet-necessary questions. Others think I&amp;rsquo;m being &lt;em&gt;un&lt;/em&gt;-biblical and &lt;em&gt;disrespectful&lt;/em&gt; in my approach, and that I should handle these matters privately (cf. &lt;a href=&#34;https://net.bible.org/#!l/bible%3AMatthew%2018%3A15-net_strongs__notes%3AMatthew%2018&#34;&gt;Matt 18:15-22&lt;/a&gt; and such).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit biased toward the first reaction. It&amp;rsquo;s always more pleasant to think of your actions as both righteous and necessary, after all. However, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t negate the careful line to walk in this situation. Several things must be held in Christ-honoring tension, such as &lt;strong&gt;boldness&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;respect&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;honesty&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;persistence&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;patience&lt;/strong&gt;, a hunger for &lt;strong&gt;justice&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; an even &lt;em&gt;stronger&lt;/em&gt; craving for &lt;strong&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s perfect &lt;em&gt;shalom&lt;/em&gt; peace&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 2)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 07:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>Read Part One
Further Questions, All Relating to the University Statement on Dr. Pahl&amp;rsquo;s Dismissal: If Dr. Pahl&amp;rsquo;s book, The Beginning and the End, was controversial enough to lead to his dismissal, why was the book allowed to be used as a textbook last school year?
Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we trust the Bible professors&amp;rsquo; judgment in their selection of the book as a text? If we should, then was it worth firing Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cedarville, Let there be Light. (pt. 1)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 15:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/cedarville-let-there-be-light-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-statement&#34;&gt;The Statement:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dr. Michael Pahl has been relieved of his teaching duties because he is unable to concur fully with each and every position of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cedarville.edu/About/Doctrinal-Statement.aspx&#34;&gt;Cedarville University&amp;rsquo;s doctrinal statement&lt;/a&gt;.  This decision was made following a review by the University administration and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cedarville.edu/Offices/Public-Relations/Board-of-Trustees.aspx&#34;&gt;trustees&lt;/a&gt; prompted by Dr. Pahl&amp;rsquo;s recent book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Beginning-End-Rereading-Revelations/dp/1608999270&#34;&gt;The Beginning and the End:  Rereading Genesis&amp;rsquo;s Stories and Revelation&amp;rsquo;s Visions.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Pahl&amp;rsquo;s orthodoxy and commitment to the gospel are not in question, nor is his commitment to Scripture&amp;rsquo;s inspiration, authority and infallibility.  He is a promising scholar and a dedicated teacher, and he will be missed by his colleagues and students.  Nevertheless, the University has determined this decision to be in the best interests of its constituency at this time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacrificing Scripture on the Altars of Our Own Agendas</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sacrificing-scripture-on-the-altars-of-our-own-agendas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 16:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sacrificing-scripture-on-the-altars-of-our-own-agendas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly the title of this blog post could be taken in hundreds of different directions. However, given recent developments close to home, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cedarville.edu/Offices/Public-Relations/CampusNews/2012/Cedarville-to-Host-Answers-in-Genesis-Conference.aspx&#34;&gt;the Answers in Genesis conference coming to Cedarville University on Sept. 23-24&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d like to get people thinking about Ken Ham, his organization&amp;rsquo;s agenda, and &lt;strong&gt;how Scripture might very well be getting abused for the sake of Young Earth Creationism&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say this as someone who used to be a zealous defender of everything that Answers in Genesis stands for. I viewed the Creationism vs. Evolution debate as central and foundational to the Christian life. I would sit for hours on end and listen to guys like Kent Hovind and their defenses of Young Earth Creationism&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and then I learned more about how to study the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 3)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 08:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/17/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/&#34; title=&#34;Creation and Doxology (pt. 1)&#34;&gt;Pt. 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/17/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/&#34; title=&#34;Creation and Doxology (pt. 2)&#34;&gt;Pt. 2&lt;/a&gt; first!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation-and-redemption-christ-and-new-creation&#34;&gt;CREATION AND REDEMPTION: CHRIST AND NEW CREATION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the New Testament, the main use of creation theology is to link creation with redemption, resulting in the praise of the Creator through the Creator-Redeemer, Jesus the Messiah. However, the linked concepts of creation and redemption have a rich OT history. For example, cited impetuses for keeping the Sabbath are Yahweh’s creative work (Exod 20:11) and his redemptive work (Deut 5:15), revealing a close connection between the two actions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn1&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; The logic behind this correlation is one of continued creation: Yahweh is personally invested in the success of his creative purposes, the functionality of his temple. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn2&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Sin and Death will not have the final word. The Creator will redeem by creating anew through his Son.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 2)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 20:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/17/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/&#34; title=&#34;Creation and Doxology (pt. 1)&#34;&gt;(Read Pt. 1 First!)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation-complexity-and-chaos&#34;&gt;CREATION, COMPLEXITY, AND CHAOS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the chaos in the universe can be ascribed to the infiltration of Sin and Death as described in Genesis 3. However, an oft-overlooked facet of biblical creation theology is the appropriate place of complexity and chaos within God’s creation. Even when the effects of the Fall are ignored, God’s temple is by no means a tame environment, nor is humanity the sole venue through which Yahweh receives glory. This facet is a crucial one, for it reorients a proper view of worship in an untamed temple, necessitating humility in the worship of the Creator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 1)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 17:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many conservative evangelical circles, biblical creation theology has been hijacked and eclipsed by the vitriolic debate between Young Earth Creationism and Neo-Darwinism. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn1&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; It is often difficult to see beyond this morass the beautiful tapestry of creation themes in biblical theology. Waltke summarizes the problem well: “Instead of metaphysical questions that shape culture, questions about dinosaurs, a young earth theory, and such dominate the evangelical landscape. This is unfortunate.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn2&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Nevertheless, there is an embarrassment of riches when it comes to Scripture’s use of creation themes, whether the evangelical community gives them appropriate attention or not. Unfortunately, a comprehensive analysis of biblical creation theology, a field fertile enough to provide lifetimes of work and study, far exceeds the purview of this essay. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn3&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; However, a brief analysis of the motifs of creation as temple, chaos, and redemption will show that the overarching use of creation theology in Scripture is to bring about the praise of the Creator. Biblical creation theology, properly understood, leads to doxology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation-as-gods-temple&#34;&gt;CREATION AS GOD’S TEMPLE&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Unforgettable Cedarville Experience</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 19:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-unforgettable-cedarville-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(The following is an expanded version of the speech I gave at this year&amp;rsquo;s CU Scholar Dessert Reception.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I ever decided about Cedarville University was that I would not, under any circumstances, attend. Since my administrator’s son, Drew Flamm, worked in admissions at CU, I had been inundated since before I could remember with calls to become a yellow-jacket, and out of sheer stubbornness of heart, I refused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost seven years later, and I stand before you all with the hopes of graduating next May. What changed? Well, for starters, God’s grace was, well, irresistible for even a stubborn high school student named Joshua Steele. While I don’t have time now to recount all the details, suffice it to say that receiving this scholarship was the final capstone of a tumultuous and miraculous college search process. I offer my sincerest thanks to the members of the selection committee. I stand before you now on nothing but a mountain of God’s grace, of which your generosity has been no small portion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I near the end of my Cedarville experience, two things have made my journey thus far particularly unforgettable and life-changing: **&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Vows: My Personal Take on the Traditional Version</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wedding-vows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 20:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/wedding-vows/</guid>
      <description>The Traditional Wedding Vows In case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, the &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; wedding vows - in English, at least - are found in the Book of Common Prayer.
In the 1662 Book of Common Prayer, the marriage vows read as follows:
I M. take thee N. to my wedded wife, to have and to hold, from this day forward, for better for worſe, for richer for poorer, in ſickneſs and in health, to love and to cheriſh, till death us do part, according to God’s holy ordinance; and thereto I plight thee my troth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Romans, Distilled and Paraphrased</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-distilled-paraphrased/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 14:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/romans-distilled-paraphrased/</guid>
      <description>The following is an attempt, written in 2012, to distill and paraphrase the main argument/message/story/logic of St. Paul&amp;rsquo;s Epistle to the Romans.
Romans 1:1-17 If you don’t catch anything else from what I’m about to say, remember this:
God is righteous. He is just. He is faithful.
God has proven himself faithful to his promises of restoring the world, working through his faithful Son, the Messiah, to bring about both our faith in and our faithfulness to him.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unity?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 19:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unity/</guid>
      <description>The more I study the New Testament, I become more convinced that the unity of the Church is of utmost importance to God.
What bothers me is that this has never been taught to me before. All of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned (specifically in my studies on Philippians, Galatians, and now Romans) about the importance of unity for the sake of the Gospel mission and the Kingdom of God have come as somewhat of a shock.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Good News of Christmas</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-good-news-of-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 13:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-good-news-of-christmas/</guid>
      <description>After reading The King Jesus Gospel: The Original Good News Revisited by Scot McKnight, who makes the claim that the gospel is the saving story of Jesus as Messiah, King, and Lord as the completion to the story of Israel, I started to notice some profound gospel messages in the Christmas carols we often sing during this season.
I have found that several of these carols go much deeper (much more biblical) than the personal salvation &amp;ldquo;gospel&amp;rdquo; of sin-management that we often preach and sing about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Church and State</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/church_and_state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 12:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/church_and_state/</guid>
      <description>(Note: for a more recent piece on the relationship between Church and State, see my essay: &amp;quot; Improvising Church and State.&amp;quot;)
I just read an article by Kevin DeYoung at The Gospel Coalition: &amp;ldquo;Thinking Theologically About Memorial Day&amp;rdquo;. Listen to his intro:
This post probably has something to make everyone unhappy. But here goes.
With Memorial Day on Monday (in the U.S.) and, no doubt, a number of patriotic services scheduled for this Sunday, I want to offer a few theses on patriotism and the church.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Bible Says About Poverty: The Book of Proverbs</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bible-poverty-proverbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 23:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/bible-poverty-proverbs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Poverty and Wealth In contrast to the affluence of mainstream American culture, poverty is a harsh and painful reality. It can be found in abundance in the urban centers of this country, and in countless other places around the globe.
Modern day slavery “more cruel than any beast of prey” (Wright 2005, 136), it traps human beings created in the image of God in a lifestyle of hunger, sickness, anger, and darkness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My High School Graduation Valedictorian Speech was a Poem</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-valediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 21:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-valediction/</guid>
      <description>My Valedictorian Address, a Poem The following is my valedictorian speech, delivered at my high school graduation in 2009. As you&amp;rsquo;ll see below, the majority of the speech was an original poem. Sure, I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to be a bit embarrassed by the poem today, but I&amp;rsquo;m also proud that I went for it. Let me know what you think!
GRADUATION! Such a mix of emotions comes with this simple word…</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From a Grateful Son: A Mother&#39;s Day Poem</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mothers-day-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 22:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/mothers-day-poem/</guid>
      <description>The following is an original Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day poem of mine, that I wrote for my mom (the best mom ever, of course) back in 2009. It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;From a Grateful Son,&amp;rdquo; and I hope that you enjoy it.
From a Grateful Son - A Poem for My Mother Thank you, Mom, for having me that day so long ago. Thank you, then, for holding me and now for letting go. Thank you, Mom, for giving me your patience, time, and care.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pages/ask-josh-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pages/ask-josh-anything/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/posts/want-to-learn-more-about-women-s-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/posts/want-to-learn-more-about-women-s-ordination-debates-within-anglicanism-start-with-these-resources/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
