<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <title>Reading on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
=======
    <title>reading on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 21:08:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/reading/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Shameless Request: Help Me Buy More Books?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 21:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After realizing just how easy it was to lose access to the physical books that I own (now sequestered in my library carrel at Wheaton), on a bit of a whim &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/donate/573962246651661/&#34;&gt;I created a fundraiser to help my upgrade my Logos Bible Software library&lt;/a&gt; to either the Anglican Gold ($216) or Anglican Platinum ($582) libraries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Upgrading would help me in my preaching, teaching, and writing roles (as a pastor-theologian and as the Managing Editor of AnglicanCompass.com). I’ve already benefited immensely from the Anglican Silver package I bought when I got into the Logos Bible Software ecosystem a couple years ago (mainly to gain easy digital access to Barth and Bonhoeffer’s writings for my dissertation). I plan to stick with Logos—especially for biblical commentaries, systematic theologies, and reference works—because it allows me to quickly research, prepare for sermons, answer questions from readers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</guid>
      <description>After realizing just how easy it was to lose access to the physical books that I own (now sequestered in my library carrel at Wheaton), on a bit of a whim I created a fundraiser to help my upgrade my Logos Bible Software library to either the Anglican Gold ($216) or Anglican Platinum ($582) libraries.
Upgrading would help me in my preaching, teaching, and writing roles (as a pastor-theologian and as the Managing Editor of AnglicanCompass.</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following Christ as a Hermeneutical Problem?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/following-christ-as-a-hermeneutical-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/following-christ-as-a-hermeneutical-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to puzzle out the meaning of the following paragraph from Bonhoeffer’s &lt;em&gt;Discipleship&lt;/em&gt; (DBWE 4).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally eliminating simple obedience introduces a principle of scripture foreign to the Gospel.&lt;sup&gt;[19]&lt;/sup&gt; According to it, in order to understand scripture, one first must have a key to interpreting it. But that key would not be the living Christ himself in judgment and grace, and using the key would not be according to the will of the living Holy Spirit alone. Rather, the key to scripture would be a general doctrine of grace, and we ourselves would decide its use. The problem of following Christ shows itself here to be a hermeneutical problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-christ-as-a-hermeneutical-problem/</guid>
      <description>I’m trying to puzzle out the meaning of the following paragraph from Bonhoeffer’s Discipleship (DBWE 4).
Fundamentally eliminating simple obedience introduces a principle of scripture foreign to the Gospel.[19] According to it, in order to understand scripture, one first must have a key to interpreting it. But that key would not be the living Christ himself in judgment and grace, and using the key would not be according to the will of the living Holy Spirit alone.</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What blogs are you reading?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m using the RSS readers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inoreader.com/&#34;&gt;Inoreader&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://reederapp.com/&#34;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe to the following blogs:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ayjay.org&#34;&gt;Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog&#34;&gt;Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://seths.blog&#34;&gt;Seth’s Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://calnewport.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Study Hacks – Decoding Patterns of Success – Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com&#34;&gt;James Clear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bakadesuyo.com&#34;&gt;Barking Up The Wrong Tree – How to be awesome at life.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://appademic.tech&#34;&gt;The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcsweeneys.net&#34;&gt;McSweeney’s Internet Tendency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com&#34;&gt;Lifehacker – Do everything better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are you reading?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</guid>
      <description>Right now, I’m using the RSS readers Inoreader and Reeder to subscribe to the following blogs:
Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise. Seth’s Blog Study Hacks – Decoding Patterns of Success – Cal Newport James Clear Barking Up The Wrong Tree – How to be awesome at life. The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds McSweeney’s Internet Tendency Lifehacker – Do everything better What are you reading?</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Reading this Fall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/what-im-reading-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/what-im-reading-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This upcoming semester, I’ll be taking a seminar on the Doctrine of Creation from my supervisor Marc Cortez. I’ll also be doing my “pedagogical experience” in a Christian Theology course—also with Marc Cortez.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, in case you’re interested, I thought I’d share what I’ll be reading for each course.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you read any of these works? If so, what did you think? What will &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; be reading this semester?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;doctrine-of-creation&#34;&gt;Doctrine of Creation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2OHhIGt&#34;&gt;Colin Gunton, The Triune Creator: A Historical and Systematic Study.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2OJjtmv&#34;&gt;Elizabeth A. Johnson, Ask the Beasts: Darwin and the God of Love.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2OGR0gX&#34;&gt;Catherine Keller, The Face of the Deep: A Theology of Becoming.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2nFuuK2&#34;&gt;Ian A. McFarland, From Nothing: A Theology of Creation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Miwlmx&#34;&gt;Jürgen Moltmann, God in Creation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ODx52y&#34;&gt;Arthur Peacocke, All That Is: A Naturalistic Faith for the Twenty-First Century.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2nLA2T9&#34;&gt;Norman Wirzba, From Nature to Creation: A Christian Vision for Understanding and Loving Our World.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;christian-theology&#34;&gt;Christian Theology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2MAHK0v&#34;&gt;Beth Felker Jones, Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2MoSrUI&#34;&gt;Tom McCall, Forsaken: The Trinity, the Cross, and Why It Matters.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2L1hGXJ&#34;&gt;Timothy C. Tennent (ed.), Theology in the Context of World Christianity: How the Global Church Is Influencing the Way We Think about and Discuss Theology.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2nLh6Ef&#34;&gt;Cornelius Plantinga, Not the Way It’s Supposed to Be: A Breviary of Sin.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: some of the links in this post are &lt;strong&gt;affiliate links&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that, if you click on the link and make a purchase, then, at no extra cost to you, I receive a small commission. I only ever recommend resources that I know will benefit my readers! If you’re interested in these resources, buying them through the affiliate links is a way that you can support my work!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-im-reading-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>This upcoming semester, I’ll be taking a seminar on the Doctrine of Creation from my supervisor Marc Cortez. I’ll also be doing my “pedagogical experience” in a Christian Theology course—also with Marc Cortez.
Anyways, in case you’re interested, I thought I’d share what I’ll be reading for each course.
Have you read any of these works? If so, what did you think? What will you be reading this semester?
Doctrine of Creation Colin Gunton, The Triune Creator: A Historical and Systematic Study.</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Questions to Ask While Reading Theology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While reading Beth Felker Jones’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2vLkeEo&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I came across the following list of extremely helpful questions to ask while reading theology (on page 29).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What are the key Christian teachings being articulated? What is the author’s driving concern or main theme?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What counts for the author as authoritative (Scripture, tradition, reason, experience…)? Is the author’s theological method implicit or explicit?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How does the author deal with the witness of Scripture?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;a. Implicitly? Explicitly?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;b. Does the witness of the Old Testament matter? The New?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;c. What biblical themes are privileged?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;d. What interpretive principles are at work?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How do these claims relate to other doctrines?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How does context (including gender, race, class, culture, and time) shape the theological voice? Is the theologian conscious of this? How does your context shape your evaluation of the piece?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Practice reading charitably. What is the best possible interpretation of how the piece reflects an attempt to be faithful to Jesus Christ?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How do these theological claims relate to the life of faith? Doe you bring other questions from your experience?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If this theological proposal were taken seriously, how would it shape Christian practice? Would it affect our participation in spiritual disciplines? Our understanding of faithful living? Our practice of evangelism? Our life as the church?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add this to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/&#34;&gt;1 simple trick to read faster&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/understand-remember-read-4-questions-ask-reading-book/&#34;&gt;4 questions to ask while reading a book&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/&#34;&gt;3 questions to ask while reading the Bible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</guid>
      <description>While reading Beth Felker Jones’ Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically, I came across the following list of extremely helpful questions to ask while reading theology (on page 29).
What are the key Christian teachings being articulated? What is the author’s driving concern or main theme? What counts for the author as authoritative (Scripture, tradition, reason, experience…)? Is the author’s theological method implicit or explicit? How does the author deal with the witness of Scripture?</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This One Simple Trick Helps Me Read Faster as a Ph.D. Student</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 06:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading is the closest thing that human beings have to a superpower. We can learn, from other minds, from other times, just by looking at symbols on a screen or a page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But, I mean, come on. Who has enough time to read? I don’t know about you, but I’ve got a stack of books a mile high that I’d like to work my way through.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, there’s a bunch of good advice out there about &lt;strong&gt;finding more time to read&lt;/strong&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fs.blog/2013/09/finding-time-to-read/&#34;&gt;this post from Farnam Street&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/26/how-to-read-more-books/&#34;&gt;this post from The Art of Manliness&lt;/a&gt;). In fact, finding more time to read is one of the main reasons why you should learn the basics of personal productivity and time management (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/category/productivity-and-time-management/&#34;&gt;my posts about productivity and time management&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
=======
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</guid>
      <description>Reading is the closest thing that human beings have to a superpower. We can learn, from other minds, from other times, just by looking at symbols on a screen or a page.
But, I mean, come on. Who has enough time to read? I don’t know about you, but I’ve got a stack of books a mile high that I’d like to work my way through.
Now, there’s a bunch of good advice out there about finding more time to read (see this post from Farnam Street and this post from The Art of Manliness).</description>
>>>>>>> parent of 304ec71 (Update site on Mon Sep 30 09:11:54 EDT 2024)
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
