<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>church-and-theology on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/church-and-theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in church-and-theology on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 15:27:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/church-and-theology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Justification and Sanctification</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/justification-and-sanctification/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 15:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/justification-and-sanctification/</guid>
      <description>For my &amp;ldquo;Pedagogical Experience&amp;rdquo; requirement at Wheaton, I&amp;rsquo;m helping to teach a masters-level Christian Theology course.
Yesterday, I got to teach a lesson on justification and sanctification. A lot to cover in a 95-minute class session!
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in what I covered, here are my slides (in PDF format).
Justification and Sanctification Slides
Download
And here is the handout (Word document).
Justification and Sanctification Handout
Download</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Theologies: A List (Help Me Update!)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/systematic-theologies-a-list-help-me-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 15:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/systematic-theologies-a-list-help-me-update/</guid>
      <description>SYSTEMATIC THEOLOGIES: A LIST I put together the following list, using the 10th edition of John Glynn&amp;rsquo;s Commentary and Reference Survey (Kegel, 2007) as a starting point.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be updating this list in the future, but I could use your help. If there&amp;rsquo;s something that needs included, please let me know in the comments!
Systematic Theologies Barth, Karl. Church Dogmatics, 5 vols. In 14 parts. (T&amp;amp;T Clark, [1932–1967] 1936–1969). Bavinck, Herman.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Theologians (Should) Do</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-theologians-should-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 14:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-theologians-should-do/</guid>
      <description>Kevin J. Vanhoozer, affectionately known by some as &amp;ldquo;KJV,&amp;rdquo; has written one of the best, briefest overviews of what theologians (should) do.
The entire piece is filled with gems like the following:
To become a theologian, you must be willing to bear true witness and call out false witnesses, casting down idols and ideologies. That’s the shadow side of theology, but the best part is speaking light and truth in astonished indications of God’s goodness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hermeneutical Implications of Scripture&#39;s Theological Location</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hermeneutical-implications-scriptures-theological-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 15:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/hermeneutical-implications-scriptures-theological-location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theological &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermeneutics&#34;&gt;hermeneutics&lt;/a&gt; – human understanding and interpretation in light of the identity and acts of the triune God – faces two problematic questions that, I believe, every biblical and/or theological scholar must be prepared to address. First, should the Bible be read in some special sense as divine revelation, or should we read the Bible like any other text? And second, should biblical and theological studies be one discipline, or two?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what follows, I propose that &lt;strong&gt;we can best account for both (1) the relationship between general and special hermeneutics and (2) the relationship between biblical and theological studies by first attending to Scripture’s theological location regarding its subject matter – the all-encompassing story, to which it bears witness, of how the triune God creates and redeems a people unto fellowship with himself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first section, I will argue that the Scripture plays an authoritative role in the all-encompassing story to which it bears witness. After briefly summarizing the subject matter of Scripture, I will explain Scripture’s role by explaining the relationships between Scripture and (1) God, (2) creation, and (3) God’s people. With respect to God, Scripture is the authoritative and inspired word of the triune God, which God uses to reveal himself and redeem his creatures. With respect to creation, because Scripture’s subject matter is all-encompassing, there is no domain outside of its purview. And with respect to God’s people, Scripture is unavoidably and irreducibly ecclesiological.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we clarify the relationship between Scripture and its subject matter, if the story to which Scripture bears witness is true, then the relationships between (1) special and general hermeneutics and (2) biblical and theological studies become much less problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second section, therefore, I maintain that, because Scripture plays a uniquely authoritative role within its all-encompassing subject matter, theological hermeneutics encompasses both special and general hermeneutics. This has implications for two related hermeneutical triads: the general hermeneutical triad of author, text, and reader, and the special hermeneutical triad of historical, literary, and theological analysis. My approach calls for giving theology pride of place in both triads. That is, the divine author, the Christ-centered text, and the Spirit-led interpretive community of the Church are of primary importance. Nevertheless, due to the historically particular way(s) in which the triune God has revealed himself and redeemed his people, a theological hermeneutic requires attending to the historical and literary particularities of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; authors, texts, and readers – especially to those involved in the interpretation of Holy Scripture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in the third section, I offer an account of biblical and theological studies as a single multifaceted discipline, one that includes both biblical studies and the various theological sub-disciplines of historical, systematic, and pastoral theology. Because Scripture’s subject matter is complex, unified, and irreducibly ecclesiological, biblical and theological studies need each other. This has, I believe, implications for how the contested and contentious fields of biblical theology and the theological interpretation of Scripture ought to relate to each other.  Furthermore, because the Church’s understanding of and participation in Scripture’s subject matter is historically, conceptually, and practically complex, the theological subdisciplines need each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frustrated with Church? You&#39;re the Problem!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-youre-the-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 17:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-youre-the-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I asked you &lt;a href=&#34;http://frustrated&#34;&gt;to join the Church if you, like me, are frustrated with the Church&lt;/a&gt;. The strongest critiques of religion come from within, not without, the Christian community. Plus, your frustrations are likely shared by many others within the Church!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s not enough to point the finger at others from your pew, instead of doing so from the public square. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a good first step, but another one is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;you---and-i---need-to-be-willing-to-take-ownership-for-the-churchs-failures&#34;&gt;You - and I - need to be willing to take ownership for the Church&amp;rsquo;s failures.&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frustrated with Church? Join the Club...</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-join-the-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 17:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/frustrated-with-church-join-the-club/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;and by &amp;ldquo;club&amp;rdquo; I of course mean &amp;ldquo;Church&amp;rdquo;!
What am I getting at? Am I calling the Church a mere &amp;ldquo;club&amp;rdquo;?
No. Although, unfortunately, it often feels that way, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?
A club full of hypocrisy, idolatry, indifference, and platitudes. A club full of power-plays, fear-mongering, and Bible-thumping. A club full of saints too afraid to admit that they are sinners. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;re sick of this &amp;ldquo;club,&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to leave, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t left already.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Recommendations? Barth&amp;#039;s &amp;#038; Bonhoeffer&amp;#039;s False Gods</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/reading-recommendations-barths-bonhoeffers-false-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 12:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/reading-recommendations-barths-bonhoeffers-false-gods/</guid>
      <description>Hi internet - especially all you Barthians and Bonhoefferians (-ites?) out there.
I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of compiling a reading list, and I could use your suggestions.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my goal: to explore the possible relationship between Barth&amp;rsquo;s critique of the &amp;ldquo;No-God&amp;rdquo;(Nich-Gott) and Bonhoeffer&amp;rsquo;s critique(s) of viewing God as a &amp;ldquo;stopgap&amp;rdquo; (Lückenbüßer) or &amp;ldquo;working hypothesis.&amp;rdquo;
As far as primary sources go, I plan to focus on the Romans commentary, Garrett Green&amp;rsquo;s recent re-translation of CD §17, and Letters and Papers from Prison.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvising Church &amp; State: Overaccepting as a Synthesis of Anglican and Anabaptist Approaches</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/improvising-church-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 11:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/improvising-church-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction-accepting-blocking-and-status&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION: ACCEPTING, BLOCKING, AND STATUS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the church’s perspective, is the state a promising offer, or a threatening one? At the risk of breathtaking oversimplification, Anglicans have tended to adopt the former perspective, leading to accommodation, and Anabaptists the latter, resulting in separation. &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Following Samuel Wells in his theological appropriation of terms from theatrical improvisation, the Anglican tradition has tended to respond to the promising &lt;em&gt;offers&lt;/em&gt; (invitations to respond) of the state by &lt;em&gt;accepting&lt;/em&gt; – maintaining the premise(s) of the state’s action(s). &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; The historical legacy of the Church of England has given Anglicanism, as Anderson notes, an “inheritance of a strong loyalty to the state and a conservatism that has led the church to promote the status quo more often than it agitates for reform.” &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn3&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; This inheritance from the established Church of England has coincided with a dual tendency to adopt a high &lt;em&gt;status&lt;/em&gt; (a strategy for getting one’s way), in terms of relative privilege and political optimism, and a low status, in terms of frequent subservience in church-state relations. &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn4&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For a[n attempted] summary of the Christian faith, see my essay: &amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/theology-outline/&#34;&gt;Theology in Outline: What do I Believe?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the Anabaptist tradition has tended to respond to the threatening offers of the state by &lt;em&gt;blocking&lt;/em&gt; – undermining the premise(s) of the state’s action(s). &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn5&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt; For many contemporary Anabaptists, as Joireman summarizes, “[T]he state has the function of ordering the social world, and the church should be the visible witness of believers, the primary affiliation of Christians, and separate from the state.” &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn6&#34;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt; Passively, blocking the state can be “a choice to shut oneself away and keep oneself unsullied by the world.” &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn7&#34;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt; Most often, drawing upon their sixteenth-century inheritance of facing persecution from Catholics and Protestants alike, Anabaptists have adopted a low status as somewhat of a fringe movement. Actively, however, blocking can be “a choice to take up arms,” as seen during the (admittedly rare) example of high status Anabaptist opposition during the Münster Rebellion of 1534. &lt;a href=&#34;#_ftn8&#34;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;questioning-givens&#34;&gt;QUESTIONING GIVENS&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentecost: Songs and Scripture</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pentecost-songs-and-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 15:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/pentecost-songs-and-scripture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://homebrewedchristianity.com/2015/05/18/pentecost-the-arrival-of-the-spirit-and-the-lectiocast/&#34;&gt;the first episode&lt;/a&gt; of the excellent new podcast, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jrdkirk.com/2015/05/14/lectiocast-a-lectionary-commentary-podcast/&#34;&gt;LectioCast&lt;/a&gt;, helped to orient my thoughts toward &lt;a href=&#34;http://lectionary.library.vanderbilt.edu/&#34;&gt;tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s readings&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.christiantoday.com/article/nine.key.things.to.know.about.pentecost/54344.htm&#34;&gt;Pentecost Sunday&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve reproduced the first lesson, psalm, second lesson, and Gospel reading below, but I&amp;rsquo;d also like to call your attention to three powerful songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;song-1-dry-bones-by-gungor&#34;&gt;Song #1: &amp;ldquo;Dry Bones&amp;rdquo; by Gungor&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first song is &amp;ldquo;Dry Bones&amp;rdquo; by Gungor. Read the Ezekiel passage and psalm below, and give it a listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ioMRzpmnl7U[/embed]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-lesson-ezekiel-371-14net-bible&#34;&gt;First Lesson: Ezekiel 37:1-14 (NET Bible)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-valley-of-dry-bones&#34;&gt;The Valley of Dry Bones&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be human?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-does-it-mean-to-be-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 22:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/what-does-it-mean-to-be-human/</guid>
      <description>What Does It Mean to Be Human? A clue to the answer lies in the asking of the question, for this act presupposes both a [human] subject and object in a dialectic of self-transcendence.
As Robert Jenson notes, “in asking this question, we somehow take up a vantage outside ourselves to make ourselves our own objects, get beyond ourselves to look back at ourselves.”1 The mystery of human existence is “that I am the subject of the object I am and the object of the subject I am.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disunity in the Church? Absurd!</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/disunity-in-the-church-absurd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 09:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/disunity-in-the-church-absurd/</guid>
      <description>Presented at Southeast ETS 2015.
DISUNITY AS ECCLESIOLOGICAL IMPOSSIBILITY:A BARTHIAN ANALOGY
Joshua P. Steele
INTRODUCTION Just as sin is ontological impossibility, disunity is ecclesiological impossibility. The tension between the undeniable reality of sin and Karl Barth’s theological definition of sin as an impossible possibility parallels the tension between the obvious reality of a fractured church1 and the theological definition of the church as the one body of the one Christ. Two excerpts from the Barthian corpus legitimize this connection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karl Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #1, Stones into Bread</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-1-stones-into-bread/</guid>
      <description>Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations isperenniallyinspiring, but particularly poignant during this season of Lent.
What does it mean for Christ to be the Perfect Penitent? And how should this influence our own repentance?
The following series of quotations comes from a lengthy small-print section in CD IV/1, 259-73 (§ 59 The Obedience of the Son of God; 2. The Judge Judged in Our Place). There Barth walks through the three wilderness temptations before masterfully connecting them to Christ&amp;rsquo;s experience in the Garden of Gethsemane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #2, Christendom&amp;#039;s Cost -- Worship Satan</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-2-christendoms-cost-worship-satan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-2-christendoms-cost-worship-satan/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I posted the beginning of Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations. He does a masterful job of explaining how Christ was tempted, not to violate the Law or commit a moral infraction, but to abandon his role as the obedient, Perfect Penitent. Put differently, Barth clarifies that Jesus&amp;rsquo; sinlessness is not a vague moral perfection, but rather obedience and repentance.
Christ&amp;rsquo;s first temptation was to turn stones into bread, thereby using divine power as a &amp;ldquo;technical instrument&amp;rdquo; to save and maintain his own life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth on the Wilderness Temptations: #3, The Leap of False Faith</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-3-the-leap-of-false-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/barth-on-the-wilderness-temptations-3-the-leap-of-false-faith/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reproducing Karl Barth&amp;rsquo;s magnificent exegesis of Christ&amp;rsquo;s wilderness temptations in Church Dogmatics IV/1.
It is a particularly appropriate discussion for this season of Lent, for Jesus was not tempted to break the Law or commit a moral infraction. Instead, he was tempted to abandon his role as the Perfect Penitent. For Barth, if Christ had capitulated to any of the temptations, he would have abandoned God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive mission. Jesus Christ had to persist in penitence in order to be &amp;quot; the Judge Judged in Our Place&amp;quot; (Barth&amp;rsquo;s most concise description of the atonement proper).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHITE NOISE, BHOPAL, AND THE HYPERREAL FEAR OF DEATH</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/white-noise-bhopal-and-the-hyperreal-fear-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 08:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/white-noise-bhopal-and-the-hyperreal-fear-of-death/</guid>
      <description>The following essay deals with the theme of the fear of death in White Noise, the novel by Don DeLillo (affiliate link).
It is better to go to a funeral than a feast. For death is the destiny of every person, and the living should take this to heart. [1]
Don DeLillo’s White Noise, “a paradigm of postmodern literature,”[2] yields the kind of cognitive dissonance that makes you wonder whether the author simply missed the mark, or if you are only confused because you suffer from the postmodern condition which DeLillo adroitly analyzes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Holy Trinity: What Is It? (Why) Is It Important?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/holy-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 21:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/holy-trinity/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: The Holy Trinity One God. Three persons. The Holy Trinity.The orthodox paradox of this Christian confession confounds many, due to its apparent contradictions, abstractions, and absence from Scripture. From Arius to Augustine and beyond, trinitarian debates have raged even among those who agree that God exists, that the Bible is true, and that it is therefore worthwhile to consider what the Bible says because it reveals the existent God. Although the best discussions of the Trinity begin with an acknowledgment of its inscrutable mystery which eludes the grasp of human reason&amp;rsquo;s highest reach, a sober analysis of the doctrine&amp;rsquo;s canonical presence and historical outworking may help to answer the charges that the Trinity is a nonsensical, unbiblical abstraction worthy of abandonment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miroslav Volf on Divine Violence</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/volf-on-divine-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 08:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/volf-on-divine-violence/</guid>
      <description>A couple relevant excerpts (given recent posts) from &amp;ldquo;Violence and Peace,&amp;rdquo; the final chapter of Miroslav Volf&amp;rsquo;s Exclusion and Embrace(my emphasis added in bold; paragraph breaks added where noted):
&amp;ldquo;God will judge, not because God gives people what they deserve, but because some people refuse to receive what no one deserves; if evildoers experience God&amp;rsquo;s terror, it will not be because they have done evil, but because they have resisted to the end the powerful lure of the open arms of the crucified Messiah.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 3)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 08:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/17/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/&#34; title=&#34;Creation and Doxology (pt. 1)&#34;&gt;Pt. 1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/17/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/&#34; title=&#34;Creation and Doxology (pt. 2)&#34;&gt;Pt. 2&lt;/a&gt; first!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation-and-redemption-christ-and-new-creation&#34;&gt;CREATION AND REDEMPTION: CHRIST AND NEW CREATION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the New Testament, the main use of creation theology is to link creation with redemption, resulting in the praise of the Creator through the Creator-Redeemer, Jesus the Messiah. However, the linked concepts of creation and redemption have a rich OT history. For example, cited impetuses for keeping the Sabbath are Yahweh’s creative work (Exod 20:11) and his redemptive work (Deut 5:15), revealing a close connection between the two actions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn1&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; The logic behind this correlation is one of continued creation: Yahweh is personally invested in the success of his creative purposes, the functionality of his temple. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn2&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Sin and Death will not have the final word. The Creator will redeem by creating anew through his Son.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 2)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 20:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2012/09/17/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/&#34; title=&#34;Creation and Doxology (pt. 1)&#34;&gt;(Read Pt. 1 First!)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation-complexity-and-chaos&#34;&gt;CREATION, COMPLEXITY, AND CHAOS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the chaos in the universe can be ascribed to the infiltration of Sin and Death as described in Genesis 3. However, an oft-overlooked facet of biblical creation theology is the appropriate place of complexity and chaos within God’s creation. Even when the effects of the Fall are ignored, God’s temple is by no means a tame environment, nor is humanity the sole venue through which Yahweh receives glory. This facet is a crucial one, for it reorients a proper view of worship in an untamed temple, necessitating humility in the worship of the Creator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and Doxology: A Portrait of Biblical Creation Theology (pt. 1)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 17:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/creation-and-doxology-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many conservative evangelical circles, biblical creation theology has been hijacked and eclipsed by the vitriolic debate between Young Earth Creationism and Neo-Darwinism. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn1&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; It is often difficult to see beyond this morass the beautiful tapestry of creation themes in biblical theology. Waltke summarizes the problem well: “Instead of metaphysical questions that shape culture, questions about dinosaurs, a young earth theory, and such dominate the evangelical landscape. This is unfortunate.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn2&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Nevertheless, there is an embarrassment of riches when it comes to Scripture’s use of creation themes, whether the evangelical community gives them appropriate attention or not. Unfortunately, a comprehensive analysis of biblical creation theology, a field fertile enough to provide lifetimes of work and study, far exceeds the purview of this essay. &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.github.io/Users/Josh/Downloads/CREATION%20(2).docx#_ftn3&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; However, a brief analysis of the motifs of creation as temple, chaos, and redemption will show that the overarching use of creation theology in Scripture is to bring about the praise of the Creator. Biblical creation theology, properly understood, leads to doxology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;creation-as-gods-temple&#34;&gt;CREATION AS GOD’S TEMPLE&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
