<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 16:22:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/reading/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Shameless Request: Help Me Buy More Books?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 21:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/a-shameless-request-help-me-buy-more-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After realizing just how easy it was to lose access to the physical books that I own (now sequestered in my library carrel at Wheaton), on a bit of a whim &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/donate/573962246651661/&#34;&gt;I created a fundraiser to help my upgrade my Logos Bible Software library&lt;/a&gt; to either the Anglican Gold ($216) or Anglican Platinum ($582) libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgrading would help me in my preaching, teaching, and writing roles (as a pastor-theologian and as the Managing Editor of AnglicanCompass.com). I’ve already benefited immensely from the Anglican Silver package I bought when I got into the Logos Bible Software ecosystem a couple years ago (mainly to gain easy digital access to Barth and Bonhoeffer’s writings for my dissertation). I plan to stick with Logos—especially for biblical commentaries, systematic theologies, and reference works—because it allows me to quickly research, prepare for sermons, answer questions from readers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After realizing just how easy it was to lose access to the physical books that I own (now sequestered in my library carrel at Wheaton), on a bit of a whim <a href="https://www.facebook.com/donate/573962246651661/">I created a fundraiser to help my upgrade my Logos Bible Software library</a> to either the Anglican Gold ($216) or Anglican Platinum ($582) libraries.</p>
<p>Upgrading would help me in my preaching, teaching, and writing roles (as a pastor-theologian and as the Managing Editor of AnglicanCompass.com). I’ve already benefited immensely from the Anglican Silver package I bought when I got into the Logos Bible Software ecosystem a couple years ago (mainly to gain easy digital access to Barth and Bonhoeffer’s writings for my dissertation). I plan to stick with Logos—especially for biblical commentaries, systematic theologies, and reference works—because it allows me to quickly research, prepare for sermons, answer questions from readers, etc.</p>
<h2 id="within-a-single-day-the-fundraiser-received-341-that-leaves-just-241-to-reach-the-582-platinum-goal">Within a single day, the fundraiser received $341!! That leaves just $241 to reach the $582 Platinum goal!</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/donate/573962246651661/">If you can give a few bucks, I’d be very grateful</a>! And, whether or not you give money to the fundraiser, please always feel free to send me any questions you have about Anglicanism, the Bible, Christian theology, Church history, etc.! I want to put my resources and training to good use!</p>
<p>In case you’re curious, here are some of the resources I’m most excited to own digitally in the Anglican Platinum library. I’d get 447 resources total, but here are the ones I’m most excited about:</p>
<ul>
<li>The complete Ancient Christian Commentary on Scripture (I have the NT now but would gain access to the OT)</li>
<li>The Ancient Christian Doctrine Series</li>
<li>The Pillar New Testament Commentary Series</li>
<li>The Encyclopedia of Ancient Christianity</li>
<li>The Oxford Dictionary of the Christian Church</li>
<li>N.T. Wright’s Christian Origins and the Question of God Series</li>
<li>The 10-volume Theological Dictionary of the New Testament</li>
<li>The 8-volume Dictionary of Classical Hebrew</li>
<li>Thomas Oden’s 3-volume Systematic Theology</li>
<li>Wolfhart Pannenberg’s 3-volume Systematic Theology</li>
<li>Braaten and Jenson’s 2-volume Christian Dogmatics</li>
<li>The Encyclopedia of Christianity</li>
<li>The Oxford Library of Practical Theology</li>
<li>The 7-volume Lancelot Andrewes Collection</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following Christ as a Hermeneutical Problem?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/following-christ-as-a-hermeneutical-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/following-christ-as-a-hermeneutical-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to puzzle out the meaning of the following paragraph from Bonhoeffer’s &lt;em&gt;Discipleship&lt;/em&gt; (DBWE 4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally eliminating simple obedience introduces a principle of scripture foreign to the Gospel.&lt;sup&gt;[19]&lt;/sup&gt; According to it, in order to understand scripture, one first must have a key to interpreting it. But that key would not be the living Christ himself in judgment and grace, and using the key would not be according to the will of the living Holy Spirit alone. Rather, the key to scripture would be a general doctrine of grace, and we ourselves would decide its use. The problem of following Christ shows itself here to be a hermeneutical problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m trying to puzzle out the meaning of the following paragraph from Bonhoeffer’s <em>Discipleship</em> (DBWE 4).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Fundamentally eliminating simple obedience introduces a principle of scripture foreign to the Gospel.<sup>[19]</sup> According to it, in order to understand scripture, one first must have a key to interpreting it. But that key would not be the living Christ himself in judgment and grace, and using the key would not be according to the will of the living Holy Spirit alone. Rather, the key to scripture would be a general doctrine of grace, and we ourselves would decide its use. The problem of following Christ shows itself here to be a hermeneutical problem.</p>
<p><cite> Dietrich Bonhoeffer, <a href="https://ref.ly/logosres/dbw04?ref=DBW.DBW+4:74&amp;off=794&amp;ctx=r+those+who+follow.%0a~Fundamentally+elimin"><em>Discipleship</em></a>, ed. Martin Kuske et al., trans. Barbara Green and Reinhard Krauss, vol. 4, Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2003), 82.</cite></p></blockquote>
<p>Here, Bonhoeffer appears to be contrasting the “simple obedience” required by a “costly grace” approach with a “paradoxical obedience” required by a “cheap grace” approach. The latter approach makes “a general doctrine of grace,” and not “the living Christ himself,” the “principle of scripture” (Schriftprinzip). And this general doctrine of grace, used in this way, results in a Schriftprinzip that is “foreign to the Gospel.”</p>
<p>Here’s editorial footnote 19:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><sup>[19]</sup> Bonhoeffer felt that this subject was so important that he added an entry on “principle of scripture and discipleship” to his subject index for the 1937 edition of <em>Discipleship</em>. See also Bonhoeffer’s 1925 term paper, “Is There a Difference between Historical and Pneumatic Interpretation of Scripture, and What Is the Point of View of Dogmatics?” (<em>DBW</em> 9:305–23).</p>
<p><cite> Dietrich Bonhoeffer, <a href="https://ref.ly/logosres/dbw04?ref=DBW.DBW+4:74&amp;off=794&amp;ctx=r+those+who+follow.%0a~Fundamentally+elimin"><em>Discipleship</em></a>, ed. Martin Kuske et al., trans. Barbara Green and Reinhard Krauss, vol. 4, Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2003), 82n19.</cite></p></blockquote>
<p>Incidentally, that 1925 term paper is *very* interesting. I don’t have time/space to summarize it here, but consider the following mention of “principle of scripture.” Bonhoeffer writes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The standard that must be preserved in the exegesis of scripture is handed to us along with the word that is the revelation and foundation of the Bible. This standard is taken from the Bible itself and is, as Luther noted, “what drives toward Christ.” What the content of revelation does not have is not canonical.<sup>8</sup></p>
<p><cite> Dietrich Bonhoeffer, <a href="https://ref.ly/logosres/dbw09?ref=DBW.DBW+9:320&amp;off=1827&amp;ctx=stle+Paul+himself.7%0a~The+standard+that+mu"><em>The Young Bonhoeffer: 1918–1927</em></a>, ed. Hans Pfeifer et al., trans. Mary C. Nebelsick and Douglas W. Stott, vol. 9, Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2003), 297.</cite></p></blockquote>
<p>He then adds in a footnote (this is Bonhoeffer’s footnote, not the editors’):</p>
<blockquote>
<p><sup>8</sup> Hereby we are criticizing Calvin’s Reformed principle of Scripture and its repristination by Barth, which places the concept of the canon above Luther’s individual statement. We know that Luther is taking a very bold step, but we also know that it is in the interest of Protestant faith for us to take it with him.<sup>[90]</sup></p>
<p><cite> Dietrich Bonhoeffer, <a href="https://ref.ly/logosres/dbw09?ref=DBW.DBW+9:320&amp;off=1827&amp;ctx=stle+Paul+himself.7%0a~The+standard+that+mu"><em>The Young Bonhoeffer: 1918–1927</em></a>, ed. Hans Pfeifer et al., trans. Mary C. Nebelsick and Douglas W. Stott, vol. 9, Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2003), 297n8.</cite></p></blockquote>
<p><em>(Footnote 90 there is not Bonhoeffer’s original, but the editors. They draw our attention to: “Barth, “Das Schriftprinzip,” 221ff. esp. 223.” This is: “Das Schriftprinzip der reformierten Kirche” (The scriptural principle in the Reformed church). Zwischen den Zeiten 3/3 (1925): 215–45.)</em></p>
<p>So far, so good. I think I’m tracking with Bonhoeffer, although I’m not sure whether or not this critique of a “principle of scripture” has anything to do with the critique in his 1925 seminar paper.</p>
<p>But, I’ve only quoted the first half of the paragraph in question from <em>Discipleship</em>!</p>
<p>Bonhoeffer continues:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But it should be clear to a Gospel-oriented hermeneutic that we cannot simply identify ourselves directly with those called by Jesus. Instead, those who are called in scripture themselves belong to the word of God and thus to the proclamation of the word. In preaching we hear not only Jesus’ answer to a disciple’s question, which could also be our own question. Rather, question and answer together must be proclaimed as the word of scripture. Simple obedience would be misunderstood hermeneutically if we were to act and follow as if we were contemporaries of the biblical disciples. But the Christ proclaimed to us in scripture is, through every word he says, the one whose gift of faith is granted only to the obedient, faith to the obedient alone. We cannot and may not go behind the word of scripture to the actual events. Instead, we are called to follow Christ by the entire word of scripture, simply because we do not intend to wish to violate scripture by legalistically applying a principle to it, even that of a doctrine of faith.<sup>[20]</sup></p>
<p><cite> Dietrich Bonhoeffer, <a href="https://ref.ly/logosres/dbw04?ref=DBW.DBW+4:74&amp;off=794&amp;ctx=r+those+who+follow.%0a~Fundamentally+elimin"><em>Discipleship</em></a>, ed. Martin Kuske et al., trans. Barbara Green and Reinhard Krauss, vol. 4, Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2003), 82.</cite></p></blockquote>
<p>Here’s editorial footnote 20:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><sup>[20]</sup> Tholuck preceded his interpretation of the so-called antitheses, Matt. 5:21–48, with “two hermeneutic canons” (i.e., rules of interpretation), “through neglect of which misunderstandings of a radical and practical nature have been occasioned. 1. In this section, as indeed everywhere, not the <em>literal</em>, but the <em>spiritual</em>, interpretation is the true one” (<em>Commentary</em>, 163). “2. Our Lord’s mode of address is that of the popular orator; … hence, we have no right to take the letter of what He says in a strict literal sense, and to press it unduly” (165). Both places are marked in Bonhoeffer’s copy. Bonhoeffer was thinking of such rules for “dealing with” the Sermon on the Mount (cf. below, page 181) when he wrote on October 24, 1936: “I hope to finish my book [<em>Discipleship</em>], and would really like to start writing a hermeneutics volume. It seems to me there is a huge deficit there” (<em>DBW</em> 14:257 [<em>GS</em> 1:47]).</p>
<p><cite> Dietrich Bonhoeffer, <a href="https://ref.ly/logosres/dbw04?ref=DBW.DBW+4:74&amp;off=794&amp;ctx=r+those+who+follow.%0a~Fundamentally+elimin"><em>Discipleship</em></a>, ed. Martin Kuske et al., trans. Barbara Green and Reinhard Krauss, vol. 4, Dietrich Bonhoeffer Works (Minneapolis, MN: Fortress Press, 2003), 82n20.</cite></p></blockquote>
<p>Taken out of context, I *think* I understand Bonhoeffer’s caution against placing ourselves too directly into the situation of Jesus’s original disciples. And this caution strikes me as significant, given Bonhoeffer’s penchant for moving rather <em>immediately</em>, let’s say, from the text to the present application of the text.</p>
<p>However, I *don’t* understand the connection between this caution and the warning against making a general doctrine of grace into a principle of scripture that’s foreign to the gospel. What does letting both the disciples’ questions and Jesus’s answers stand as the Word of God have to do with not making grace into a principle that we can then use to avoid simple obedience to Jesus’ commands?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What blogs are you reading?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 20:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/what-blogs-are-you-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m using the RSS readers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inoreader.com/&#34;&gt;Inoreader&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://reederapp.com/&#34;&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe to the following blogs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ayjay.org&#34;&gt;Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog&#34;&gt;Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://seths.blog&#34;&gt;Seth’s Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://calnewport.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Study Hacks – Decoding Patterns of Success – Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com&#34;&gt;James Clear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bakadesuyo.com&#34;&gt;Barking Up The Wrong Tree – How to be awesome at life.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://appademic.tech&#34;&gt;The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcsweeneys.net&#34;&gt;McSweeney’s Internet Tendency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.com&#34;&gt;Lifehacker – Do everything better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you reading?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Right now, I’m using the RSS readers <a href="https://www.inoreader.com/">Inoreader</a> and <a href="http://reederapp.com/">Reeder</a> to subscribe to the following blogs:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://blog.ayjay.org">Snakes and Ladders – by Alan Jacobs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fs.blog">Farnam Street — A Collection of Signal in a World Full of Noise.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://seths.blog">Seth’s Blog</a></li>
<li><a href="http://calnewport.com/blog/">Study Hacks – Decoding Patterns of Success – Cal Newport</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jamesclear.com">James Clear</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bakadesuyo.com">Barking Up The Wrong Tree – How to be awesome at life.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://appademic.tech">The Appademic » Technology, productivity and workflows for academics, students and other nerds</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.mcsweeneys.net">McSweeney’s Internet Tendency</a></li>
<li><a href="https://lifehacker.com">Lifehacker – Do everything better</a></li>
</ul>
<p>What are you reading?</p>
<p>If you haven’t given RSS readers a try, then <a href="https://feedly.com/">Feedly</a> is a good first RSS reader to try.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;m Reading this Fall</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/what-im-reading-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This upcoming semester, I’ll be taking a seminar on the Doctrine of Creation from my supervisor Marc Cortez. I’ll also be doing my “pedagogical experience” in a Christian Theology course—also with Marc Cortez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, in case you’re interested, I thought I’d share what I’ll be reading for each course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you read any of these works? If so, what did you think? What will &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; be reading this semester?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;doctrine-of-creation&#34;&gt;Doctrine of Creation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2OHhIGt&#34;&gt;Colin Gunton, The Triune Creator: A Historical and Systematic Study.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2OJjtmv&#34;&gt;Elizabeth A. Johnson, Ask the Beasts: Darwin and the God of Love.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2OGR0gX&#34;&gt;Catherine Keller, The Face of the Deep: A Theology of Becoming.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2nFuuK2&#34;&gt;Ian A. McFarland, From Nothing: A Theology of Creation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Miwlmx&#34;&gt;Jürgen Moltmann, God in Creation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2ODx52y&#34;&gt;Arthur Peacocke, All That Is: A Naturalistic Faith for the Twenty-First Century.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2nLA2T9&#34;&gt;Norman Wirzba, From Nature to Creation: A Christian Vision for Understanding and Loving Our World.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;christian-theology&#34;&gt;Christian Theology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2MAHK0v&#34;&gt;Beth Felker Jones, Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2MoSrUI&#34;&gt;Tom McCall, Forsaken: The Trinity, the Cross, and Why It Matters.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2L1hGXJ&#34;&gt;Timothy C. Tennent (ed.), Theology in the Context of World Christianity: How the Global Church Is Influencing the Way We Think about and Discuss Theology.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2nLh6Ef&#34;&gt;Cornelius Plantinga, Not the Way It’s Supposed to Be: A Breviary of Sin.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: some of the links in this post are &lt;strong&gt;affiliate links&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that, if you click on the link and make a purchase, then, at no extra cost to you, I receive a small commission. I only ever recommend resources that I know will benefit my readers! If you’re interested in these resources, buying them through the affiliate links is a way that you can support my work!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This upcoming semester, I’ll be taking a seminar on the Doctrine of Creation from my supervisor Marc Cortez. I’ll also be doing my “pedagogical experience” in a Christian Theology course—also with Marc Cortez.</p>
<p>Anyways, in case you’re interested, I thought I’d share what I’ll be reading for each course.</p>
<p>Have you read any of these works? If so, what did you think? What will <em>you</em> be reading this semester?</p>
<h2 id="doctrine-of-creation">Doctrine of Creation</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2OHhIGt">Colin Gunton, The Triune Creator: A Historical and Systematic Study.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2OJjtmv">Elizabeth A. Johnson, Ask the Beasts: Darwin and the God of Love.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2OGR0gX">Catherine Keller, The Face of the Deep: A Theology of Becoming.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2nFuuK2">Ian A. McFarland, From Nothing: A Theology of Creation.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2Miwlmx">Jürgen Moltmann, God in Creation.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2ODx52y">Arthur Peacocke, All That Is: A Naturalistic Faith for the Twenty-First Century.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2nLA2T9">Norman Wirzba, From Nature to Creation: A Christian Vision for Understanding and Loving Our World.</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="christian-theology">Christian Theology</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2MAHK0v">Beth Felker Jones, Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2MoSrUI">Tom McCall, Forsaken: The Trinity, the Cross, and Why It Matters.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2L1hGXJ">Timothy C. Tennent (ed.), Theology in the Context of World Christianity: How the Global Church Is Influencing the Way We Think about and Discuss Theology.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2nLh6Ef">Cornelius Plantinga, Not the Way It’s Supposed to Be: A Breviary of Sin.</a></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><em>Note: some of the links in this post are <strong>affiliate links</strong>. This means that, if you click on the link and make a purchase, then, at no extra cost to you, I receive a small commission. I only ever recommend resources that I know will benefit my readers! If you’re interested in these resources, buying them through the affiliate links is a way that you can support my work!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Questions to Ask While Reading Theology</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 15:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/8-questions-to-ask-while-reading-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While reading Beth Felker Jones’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2vLkeEo&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I came across the following list of extremely helpful questions to ask while reading theology (on page 29).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the key Christian teachings being articulated? What is the author’s driving concern or main theme?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What counts for the author as authoritative (Scripture, tradition, reason, experience…)? Is the author’s theological method implicit or explicit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the author deal with the witness of Scripture?&lt;br&gt;
a. Implicitly? Explicitly?&lt;br&gt;
b. Does the witness of the Old Testament matter? The New?&lt;br&gt;
c. What biblical themes are privileged?&lt;br&gt;
d. What interpretive principles are at work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do these claims relate to other doctrines?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does context (including gender, race, class, culture, and time) shape the theological voice? Is the theologian conscious of this? How does your context shape your evaluation of the piece?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice reading charitably. What is the best possible interpretation of how the piece reflects an attempt to be faithful to Jesus Christ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do these theological claims relate to the life of faith? Doe you bring other questions from your experience?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If this theological proposal were taken seriously, how would it shape Christian practice? Would it affect our participation in spiritual disciplines? Our understanding of faithful living? Our practice of evangelism? Our life as the church?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add this to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/&#34;&gt;1 simple trick to read faster&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/understand-remember-read-4-questions-ask-reading-book/&#34;&gt;4 questions to ask while reading a book&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/&#34;&gt;3 questions to ask while reading the Bible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While reading Beth Felker Jones’ <a href="https://amzn.to/2vLkeEo"><em>Practicing Christian Doctrine: An Introduction to Thinking and Living Theologically</em></a>, I came across the following list of extremely helpful questions to ask while reading theology (on page 29).</p>
<blockquote>
<ol>
<li>What are the key Christian teachings being articulated? What is the author’s driving concern or main theme?</li>
<li>What counts for the author as authoritative (Scripture, tradition, reason, experience…)? Is the author’s theological method implicit or explicit?</li>
<li>How does the author deal with the witness of Scripture?<br>
a. Implicitly? Explicitly?<br>
b. Does the witness of the Old Testament matter? The New?<br>
c. What biblical themes are privileged?<br>
d. What interpretive principles are at work?</li>
<li>How do these claims relate to other doctrines?</li>
<li>How does context (including gender, race, class, culture, and time) shape the theological voice? Is the theologian conscious of this? How does your context shape your evaluation of the piece?</li>
<li>Practice reading charitably. What is the best possible interpretation of how the piece reflects an attempt to be faithful to Jesus Christ?</li>
<li>How do these theological claims relate to the life of faith? Doe you bring other questions from your experience?</li>
<li>If this theological proposal were taken seriously, how would it shape Christian practice? Would it affect our participation in spiritual disciplines? Our understanding of faithful living? Our practice of evangelism? Our life as the church?</li>
</ol></blockquote>
<p>Add this to my <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/">1 simple trick to read faster</a>, <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/understand-remember-read-4-questions-ask-reading-book/">4 questions to ask while reading a book</a>, and <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/questions-to-ask-when-you-study-bible/">3 questions to ask while reading the Bible</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Note: some of the links in this post are <strong>affiliate links</strong>. This means that, if you click on the link and make a purchase, then, at no extra cost to you, I receive a small commission. I only ever recommend resources that I know will benefit my readers! If you’re interested in these resources, buying them through the affiliate links is a way that you can support my work!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This One Simple Trick Helps Me Read Faster as a Ph.D. Student</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 06:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/one-simple-trick-helps-read-faster-ph-d-student/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading is the closest thing that human beings have to a superpower. We can learn, from other minds, from other times, just by looking at symbols on a screen or a page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I mean, come on. Who has enough time to read? I don’t know about you, but I’ve got a stack of books a mile high that I’d like to work my way through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, there’s a bunch of good advice out there about &lt;strong&gt;finding more time to read&lt;/strong&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fs.blog/2013/09/finding-time-to-read/&#34;&gt;this post from Farnam Street&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/26/how-to-read-more-books/&#34;&gt;this post from The Art of Manliness&lt;/a&gt;). In fact, finding more time to read is one of the main reasons why you should learn the basics of personal productivity and time management (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/category/productivity-and-time-management/&#34;&gt;my posts about productivity and time management&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Reading is the closest thing that human beings have to a superpower. We can learn, from other minds, from other times, just by looking at symbols on a screen or a page.</p>
<p>But, I mean, come on. Who has enough time to read? I don’t know about you, but I’ve got a stack of books a mile high that I’d like to work my way through.</p>
<p>Now, there’s a bunch of good advice out there about <strong>finding more time to read</strong> (see <a href="https://www.fs.blog/2013/09/finding-time-to-read/">this post from Farnam Street</a> and <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/2018/02/26/how-to-read-more-books/">this post from The Art of Manliness</a>). In fact, finding more time to read is one of the main reasons why you should learn the basics of personal productivity and time management (see <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/category/productivity-and-time-management/">my posts about productivity and time management</a>).</p>
<p>However, even if you manage to find more time to read, it can be very helpful to <strong>improve your reading speed</strong>.</p>
<p>As a Ph.D. student, this is something that I’ve tried to get better at in recent months. I’d like to share my top tip/trick. Here it is:</p>
<h2 id="use-a-penpencilfinger-as-a-pacer-when-you-read">Use a Pen/Pencil/Finger as a Pacer When You Read</h2>
<p>That’s right. Whenever I read these days, I’m using <em>something</em> as a pacer, tracing under each line of text as I read it. (I’m usually also standing and pacing around to avoid falling asleep!)</p>
<p>It might seem stupidly simple tip, but it’s crazy how much using something – whether a pen, pencil, or just your finger – as a pacer can help you read faster. It cuts down on the number of times your eye bounces around on the page, and it enables you to read exactly as quickly as you’d like to – you can slow down or speed up at will.</p>
<p>I first considered using a pacer while reading after reading Tim Ferriss’s wildly popular blog post, <a href="https://tim.blog/2009/07/30/speed-reading-and-accelerated-learning/">“Scientific Speed Reading: How to Read 300% Faster in 20 Minutes”</a>. I encourage you to give that post a read if you’re interested.</p>
<p>Or, if you’d rather watch a video of Tim teaching his technique, check this one out:</p>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="422" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZwEquW_Yij0?feature=oembed" title="How to Speed Read | Tim Ferriss" width="750"></iframe>
<p>Anyways, I hope this simple tip helps you to read faster when you want to! Give it a try and let me know what you think.</p>
<h2 id="got-any-reading-tips-youd-like-to-share-post-them-in-the-comments-below">Got any reading tips you’d like to share? Post them in the comments below!</h2>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
