<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Reviews on Joshua P. Steele</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Reviews on Joshua P. Steele</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 16:09:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/tags/reviews/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Help, I'm Addicted to Mini Toolkits: The EDC Tool Struggle Is Real</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-addicted-to-mini-toolkits-the-edc-tool-struggle-is-real/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 16:09:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/help-im-addicted-to-mini-toolkits-the-edc-tool-struggle-is-real/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don’t know what it is about mini toolkits, but I love them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Actually, scratch that. I know why. It’s the same reason I love buying tools and books, more generally: the illusion of control. I like how having tools (and a great personal library) makes me feel like I’m ready for whatever life throws at me (ha!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s why I liked carrying around a pocketknife as a kid, and it’s why I’m into EDC (everyday carry) and tools as an adult.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Essential Reads for New Software Developers: The Effective Engineer and The Missing README</title><link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/essential-reads-for-new-software-developers-the-effective-engineer-and-the-missing-readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 21:08:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/essential-reads-for-new-software-developers-the-effective-engineer-and-the-missing-readme/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you stepping into the exciting world of software engineering, or considering whether to take that leap? You’re not alone. This field attracts countless individuals worldwide, fueled by an ever-increasing demand for technological solutions, the promise of high salaries, and a keen interest in problem-solving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, it’s essential to understand that coding and programming skills, while crucial, are just one part of a broader equation. Equally important is the bigger picture of how software development fits into the wider professional and business environment.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>