<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 08:40:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/categories/uncategorized/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6 Things I&#39;m Excited About (2024-08-04)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/6-things-im-excited-about-2024-08-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/6-things-im-excited-about-2024-08-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweater weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Losing weight with some help from Zepbound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Football season (pulling for the Detroit Lions and the University of Michigan Wolverines)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harbor Freight coming out with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/harborfreight/comments/17mj1sv/from_sema_2023_the_meme_mini_socket_set_is/&#34;&gt;version 2.0 of its “meme tool”&lt;/a&gt; – now with sockets! Hopefully out before the end of the year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3z6A93Y&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Widening of God’s Mercy: Sexuality Within the Biblical Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Christopher and Richard Hays when it comes out next week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning auto repair by working on my dad’s 1999 Dodge Ram 1500 (next up: replacing the governor pressure solenoid and sensor in the transmission, which will hopefully help with the truck getting stuck in low gear!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you excited about these days?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>Sweater weather</li>
<li>Losing weight with some help from Zepbound</li>
<li>Football season (pulling for the Detroit Lions and the University of Michigan Wolverines)</li>
<li>Harbor Freight coming out with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/harborfreight/comments/17mj1sv/from_sema_2023_the_meme_mini_socket_set_is/">version 2.0 of its “meme tool”</a> – now with sockets! Hopefully out before the end of the year</li>
<li>Reading <a href="https://amzn.to/3z6A93Y"><em>The Widening of God’s Mercy: Sexuality Within the Biblical Story</em></a> by Christopher and Richard Hays when it comes out next week</li>
<li>Learning auto repair by working on my dad’s 1999 Dodge Ram 1500 (next up: replacing the governor pressure solenoid and sensor in the transmission, which will hopefully help with the truck getting stuck in low gear!)</li>
</ol>
<p>What are you excited about these days?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem of Ecclesiastical Evil</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-problem-of-ecclesiastical-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 12:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/the-problem-of-ecclesiastical-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard of “the problem of evil” (if not, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Problem_of_evil&#34;&gt;here’s an overview&lt;/a&gt;). But there’s a specific version/aspect of it that I find even more devastating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If God is omnipotent (all-powerful), ommniscient (all-knowing(, and omnibenevolent (completely good)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Church is God’s main plan for the redemption of humanity and the cosmos (consider the “body of Christ” paradigm in the New Testament)…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the gospel of Jesus Christ has had ~2K years to percolate in and through the Church…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You’ve probably heard of “the problem of evil” (if not, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Problem_of_evil">here’s an overview</a>). But there’s a specific version/aspect of it that I find even more devastating.</p>
<p>If God is omnipotent (all-powerful), ommniscient (all-knowing(, and omnibenevolent (completely good)…</p>
<p>If the Church is God’s main plan for the redemption of humanity and the cosmos (consider the “body of Christ” paradigm in the New Testament)…</p>
<p>If the gospel of Jesus Christ has had ~2K years to percolate in and through the Church…</p>
<p>Whence so much evil, corruption, abuse, etc. in the Church?</p>
<p>Why hasn’t the Church, on the whole, produced better people (myself included)?</p>
<p>Sure, it’s <em>easy</em> to appeal to the Church as a “corpus permixtum” (mixed body) and say that it’s all just tares mixed in with the wheat (see Matthew 13:24-30, 36-43).</p>
<p>But doing so often feels like a “No True Scotsman” fallacy to me. <a href="https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/no-true-scotsman">Here’s what that means</a>.</p>
<p>(Also, sidebar: Notice how the “field” is the “world” in Matthew 13:38. Not the “kingdom” or the “church.” So, is the Church a mixed body? Or is the world a mixed body?)</p>
<p>Every time I read <a href="https://www.newadvent.org/fathers/2802.htm"><em>On the Incarnation</em> by Athanasius</a>, I’m struck by how much he is willing to stake the truth of the gospel on the actual observed behavior of Christians.</p>
<p>Here are some examples below, but go and read the entire “Answer to the Greeks” / “Refutation of the Gentiles” section (paragraphs 41–55). Note how often Athanasius argues for the truth of Christ by appealing to the changed behaviors of human beings:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When did human beings begin to abandon the worship of idols, except since the true God Word of God came among human beings?</p>
<p>Or when have the oracles amongst the Greeks and everywhere ceased and become empty, except since the Savior revealed himself upon earth?</p>
<p>Or when did those who are called gods and heroes by the poets begin to be condemned as merely mortal humans, except since the Lord erected the trophy over death and preserved incorruptible the body which he took, raising it from the dead?</p>
<p>Or when were the deceit and madness of the demons despised, except when the Power of God, the Word, the Master of all, even of these, condescended, because of the weakness of humans, to appear on earth? When did the craft and teachings of magic begin to be trampled underfoot, except when the divine manifestation of the Word took place among human beings?</p>
<p>And when, in short, did the wisdom of the Greeks become foolish (cf. 1 Cor 1:18–24) except when the true Wisdom of God revealed itself upon earth?</p>
<p>For formerly the whole inhabited world and every place were led astray by the worship of idols, and human beings regarded nothing else but idols as gods.</p>
<p>Now, however, throughout the whole inhabited world, human beings are deserting the superstition of idols, taking refuge in Christ, and worshipping him as God, and through him they know the Father, of whom they had been ignorant.</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §46</cite></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Now these things said by us are not merely words, but have the witness of their truth from experience itself. Let him who wishes come up and behold the proof of virtue in the virgins of Christ and in the youth who live a pure life in chastity, and the belief in immortality in so great a company of martyrs.</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §48</cite></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>And who thus delivered human beings from the natural passions, so that adulterers are chaste, murderers no longer take up the sword, and those overcome by cowardice are courageous? Or, in short, what persuaded human beings from the barbarians and the Gentile regions to lay aside their madness, and to mind peace, except the faith of Christ and that sign of the cross?</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §50</cite></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Who then among human beings, after death or even while alive, taught about virginity and did not think that this virtue was impossible among human beings? But our Savior and king of all, Christ, so prevailed in the teaching of this that even children not yet arrived at the lawful age profess the virginity that is above the law.</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §51</cite></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>To speak concisely, behold how the teaching of the Savior increases everywhere, while all idolatry and everything opposed to the faith of Christ daily diminish and weaken and fall.</p>
<p><cite>Athanasius, On the Incarnation, §55</cite></p></blockquote>
<p>I couldn’t make a similar argument in good faith today.</p>
<p>Instead, I believe the good news about Jesus <strong>in spite of</strong> how his Church has, on the whole, behaved.</p>
<p>Which, even though I know all of the theological pressure-release valves one can use here, bugs me quite a bit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Truth to Power</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/truth-to-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/truth-to-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark 6:13-29. John the Baptist lost his life for speaking truth to power. Are we willing to speak truth to power? To tell the truth about power and the power of truth? Or will we abandon the truth to obtain and maintain power?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mark 6:13-29. John the Baptist lost his life for speaking truth to power. Are we willing to speak truth to power? To tell the truth about power and the power of truth? Or will we abandon the truth to obtain and maintain power?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Questions Worth Asking (Self-Elicitation Questions)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/questions-worth-asking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/questions-worth-asking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are questions that are always worth asking yourself. For a list of questions I&amp;rsquo;m currently asking and investigating, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/questions&#34;&gt;my &lt;code&gt;/questions&lt;/code&gt; page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-minute-journal-questions&#34;&gt;Five-Minute Journal Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morning
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am grateful for…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would make today great?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily affirmations: I am…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evening
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are 3 amazing things that happened today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How could I have made today even better?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;morning-questions-5-minutes&#34;&gt;Morning Questions (5 minutes)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s one thing I’m grateful for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s one thing I’m excited about?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s one virtue I want to exhibit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s one thing I’m avoiding?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s the one thing I need to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evening-questions-5-minutes&#34;&gt;Evening Questions (5 minutes)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What were my biggest wins of the day?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I have any major realizations?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s on the agenda for tomorrow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bottleneck-breaker&#34;&gt;Bottleneck Breaker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s the biggest bottleneck to achieving my next goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why aren’t I working on it today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8020-analysis&#34;&gt;80/20 Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where am I feeling satisfied?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where am I feeling dissatisfied?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each of the above, what are the 20% of places, habits, people, beliefs, etc. that are responsible for 80% of the positive and negative results?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;compounding-projection&#34;&gt;Compounding Projection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I repeated every action from today for one year, where would I end up?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this the place I want to be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-correction-questions&#34;&gt;Course Correction Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I need to spend more time doing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I need to spend less time doing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I need to schedule?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I need to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I need to be more mindful of?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What unresolved issues am I overlooking?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What opportunities are in front of me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What obstacles are in my way?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I going in the right direction with my commitments?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I need to add?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I need to delete?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I need to expand?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I need to shrink?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What have I done well recently?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3FYbLCC&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Productivity Project&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-nine-questions-to-improve-your-results-by-josh-kaufman&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshkaufman.net/49-questions-better-results/&#34;&gt;Forty-Nine Questions to Improve Your Results&lt;/a&gt;, by Josh Kaufman&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-i-use-my-body-optimally&#34;&gt;Do I use my body optimally?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the quality of my current diet?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I get enough sleep?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I managing my energy well each day?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I manage daily stress?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I have good posture and poise?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can I do to improve my ability to observe the world around me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;do-i-know-what-i-want&#34;&gt;Do I know what I want?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What achievements would make me really excited?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What “states of being” do I want to experience each day?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are my priorities and values clearly defined?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I capable of making decisions quickly and confidently?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I consistently focus my attention on what I want vs. what I don’t want?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-am-i-afraid-of&#34;&gt;What am I afraid of?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have I created an honest and complete list of the fears I’m holding on to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have I confronted each fear to imagine how I would handle it if it came to pass?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I capable of recognizing and correcting self-limitation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I appropriately pushing my own limits?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;is-my-mind-clear-and-focused&#34;&gt;Is my mind clear and focused?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I systematically externalize (write or record) what I think about?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I making it easy to capture my thoughts quickly, as I have them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What has my attention right now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I regularly asking myself appropriate guiding questions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I spend most of my time focusing on a single task, or constantly flipping between multiple tasks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I spend enough time actively reflecting on my goals, projects, and progress?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;am-i-confident-relaxed-and-productive&#34;&gt;Am I confident, relaxed, and productive?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have I found a planning method that works for me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I “just organized enough”?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I have an up-to-date list of my projects and active tasks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I review all of my commitments on a regular basis?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I take regular, genuine breaks from my work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I consciously creating positive habits?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I working to shed non-productive habits?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I comfortable with telling other people “no”?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-i-perform-best&#34;&gt;How do I perform best?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I particularly enjoy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What am I particularly good at doing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What environment do I find most conducive to doing good work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I tend to learn most effectively?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I prefer to work with and communicate with others?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is currently holding me back?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-do-i-really-need-to-be-happy-and-fulfilled&#34;&gt;What do I really need to be happy and fulfilled?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How am I currently defining “success”?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there another way of defining “success” that I may find more fulfilling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How often do I compare myself to my perceptions of other people?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I currently living below my means?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I could only own 100 things, what would they be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I capable of separating necessity and luxury?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I feel grateful for in my life and work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing-the-impossible-17-questions-that-changed-my-life-by-tim-ferriss&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tim.blog/2016/12/07/testing-the-impossible-17-questions-that-changed-my-life/&#34;&gt;Testing the “Impossible”: 17 Questions That Changed My Life&lt;/a&gt;, by Tim Ferriss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if I did the opposite for 48 hours?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do I spend a silly amount of money on? How might I scratch my own itch?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would I do/have/be if I had $10 million? What’s my real TMI (Target Monthly Income)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the worst things that could happen? Could I get back here?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I could only work 2 hours per week on my business, what would I do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if I let them make decisions up to $100? $500? $1,000?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s the least crowded channel?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if I couldn’t pitch my product directly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if I created my own real-world MBA?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I need to make it back the way I lost it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if I could only subtract to solve problems?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What might I put in place to allow me to go off the grid for 4 to 8 weeks, with no phone or email?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I hunting antelope or field mice?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could it be that everything is fine and complete as is?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would this look like if it were easy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I throw money at this problem? How can I “waste” money to improve the quality of my life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No hurry, no pause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;useful-questions-for-reframing-derek-sivers-useful-not-true&#34;&gt;Useful questions for reframing (&lt;a href=&#34;https://sive.rs/u&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers, Useful Not True&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-something-goes-wrong&#34;&gt;When something goes wrong&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s great about this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I use this to my advantage?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this change the goal, or the path, or nothing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I reduce the downsides?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-changing-direction&#34;&gt;When changing direction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I was at my happiest, what was I doing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What have I strongly wanted for the longest time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What’s the opposite of what I usually do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which of my old beliefs are not serving me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forget me. What would be most helpful for others?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-stuck&#34;&gt;When stuck&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is my one top priority now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I begin without waiting for anything?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What advice would I love to hear from an all-knowing sage?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What am I doing that’s actually a distraction?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of avoiding mistakes, how can I make more to learn faster?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who can help?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;to-make-peace-with-whats-out-of-your-control&#34;&gt;To make peace with what’s out of your control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happens if I ignore it and do nothing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should I learn a lesson from this, or just move on?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I blame no one, and see this as nobody’s fault?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I be OK no matter what happens?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These are questions that are always worth asking yourself. For a list of questions I&rsquo;m currently asking and investigating, see <a href="/questions">my <code>/questions</code> page</a>.</p>
<h2 id="five-minute-journal-questions">Five-Minute Journal Questions</h2>
<ul>
<li>Morning
<ul>
<li>I am grateful for…</li>
<li>What would make today great?</li>
<li>Daily affirmations: I am…</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Evening
<ul>
<li>What are 3 amazing things that happened today?</li>
<li>How could I have made today even better?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="morning-questions-5-minutes">Morning Questions (5 minutes)</h2>
<ol>
<li>What’s one thing I’m grateful for?</li>
<li>What’s one thing I’m excited about?</li>
<li>What’s one virtue I want to exhibit?</li>
<li>What’s one thing I’m avoiding?</li>
<li>What’s the one thing I need to do?</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="evening-questions-5-minutes">Evening Questions (5 minutes)</h2>
<ol>
<li>What were my biggest wins of the day?</li>
<li>Did I have any major realizations?</li>
<li>What’s on the agenda for tomorrow?</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="bottleneck-breaker">Bottleneck Breaker</h2>
<ol>
<li>What’s the biggest bottleneck to achieving my next goal?</li>
<li>Why aren’t I working on it today?</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="8020-analysis">80/20 Analysis</h2>
<ol>
<li>Where am I feeling satisfied?</li>
<li>Where am I feeling dissatisfied?</li>
<li>For each of the above, what are the 20% of places, habits, people, beliefs, etc. that are responsible for 80% of the positive and negative results?</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="compounding-projection">Compounding Projection</h2>
<ol>
<li>If I repeated every action from today for one year, where would I end up?</li>
<li>Is this the place I want to be?</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="course-correction-questions">Course Correction Questions</h2>
<ul>
<li>What do I need to spend more time doing?</li>
<li>What do I need to spend less time doing?</li>
<li>What do I need to schedule?</li>
<li>What do I need to do?</li>
<li>What do I need to be more mindful of?</li>
<li>What unresolved issues am I overlooking?</li>
<li>What opportunities are in front of me?</li>
<li>What obstacles are in my way?</li>
<li>Am I going in the right direction with my commitments?
<ul>
<li>What do I need to add?</li>
<li>What do I need to delete?</li>
<li>What do I need to expand?</li>
<li>What do I need to shrink?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>What have I done well recently?</li>
<li>Source: <a href="https://amzn.to/3FYbLCC"><em>The Productivity Project</em></a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="forty-nine-questions-to-improve-your-results-by-josh-kaufman"><a href="https://joshkaufman.net/49-questions-better-results/">Forty-Nine Questions to Improve Your Results</a>, by Josh Kaufman</h2>
<h3 id="do-i-use-my-body-optimally">Do I use my body optimally?</h3>
<ul>
<li>What is the quality of my current diet?</li>
<li>Do I get enough sleep?</li>
<li>Am I managing my energy well each day?</li>
<li>How do I manage daily stress?</li>
<li>Do I have good posture and poise?</li>
<li>What can I do to improve my ability to observe the world around me?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="do-i-know-what-i-want">Do I know what I want?</h3>
<ul>
<li>What achievements would make me really excited?</li>
<li>What “states of being” do I want to experience each day?</li>
<li>Are my priorities and values clearly defined?</li>
<li>Am I capable of making decisions quickly and confidently?</li>
<li>Do I consistently focus my attention on what I want vs. what I don’t want?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="what-am-i-afraid-of">What am I afraid of?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Have I created an honest and complete list of the fears I’m holding on to?</li>
<li>Have I confronted each fear to imagine how I would handle it if it came to pass?</li>
<li>Am I capable of recognizing and correcting self-limitation?</li>
<li>Am I appropriately pushing my own limits?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="is-my-mind-clear-and-focused">Is my mind clear and focused?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Do I systematically externalize (write or record) what I think about?</li>
<li>Am I making it easy to capture my thoughts quickly, as I have them?</li>
<li>What has my attention right now?</li>
<li>Am I regularly asking myself appropriate guiding questions?</li>
<li>Do I spend most of my time focusing on a single task, or constantly flipping between multiple tasks?</li>
<li>Do I spend enough time actively reflecting on my goals, projects, and progress?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="am-i-confident-relaxed-and-productive">Am I confident, relaxed, and productive?</h3>
<ul>
<li>Have I found a planning method that works for me?</li>
<li>Am I “just organized enough”?</li>
<li>Do I have an up-to-date list of my projects and active tasks?</li>
<li>Do I review all of my commitments on a regular basis?</li>
<li>Do I take regular, genuine breaks from my work?</li>
<li>Am I consciously creating positive habits?</li>
<li>Am I working to shed non-productive habits?</li>
<li>Am I comfortable with telling other people “no”?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="how-do-i-perform-best">How do I perform best?</h3>
<ul>
<li>What do I particularly enjoy?</li>
<li>What am I particularly good at doing?</li>
<li>What environment do I find most conducive to doing good work?</li>
<li>How do I tend to learn most effectively?</li>
<li>How do I prefer to work with and communicate with others?</li>
<li>What is currently holding me back?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="what-do-i-really-need-to-be-happy-and-fulfilled">What do I really need to be happy and fulfilled?</h3>
<ul>
<li>How am I currently defining “success”?</li>
<li>Is there another way of defining “success” that I may find more fulfilling?</li>
<li>How often do I compare myself to my perceptions of other people?</li>
<li>Am I currently living below my means?</li>
<li>If I could only own 100 things, what would they be?</li>
<li>Am I capable of separating necessity and luxury?</li>
<li>What do I feel grateful for in my life and work?</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="testing-the-impossible-17-questions-that-changed-my-life-by-tim-ferriss"><a href="https://tim.blog/2016/12/07/testing-the-impossible-17-questions-that-changed-my-life/">Testing the “Impossible”: 17 Questions That Changed My Life</a>, by Tim Ferriss</h2>
<ul>
<li>What if I did the opposite for 48 hours?</li>
<li>What do I spend a silly amount of money on? How might I scratch my own itch?</li>
<li>What would I do/have/be if I had $10 million? What’s my real TMI (Target Monthly Income)?</li>
<li>What are the worst things that could happen? Could I get back here?</li>
<li>If I could only work 2 hours per week on my business, what would I do?</li>
<li>What if I let them make decisions up to $100? $500? $1,000?</li>
<li>What’s the least crowded channel?</li>
<li>What if I couldn’t pitch my product directly?</li>
<li>What if I created my own real-world MBA?</li>
<li>Do I need to make it back the way I lost it?</li>
<li>What if I could only subtract to solve problems?</li>
<li>What might I put in place to allow me to go off the grid for 4 to 8 weeks, with no phone or email?</li>
<li>Am I hunting antelope or field mice?</li>
<li>Could it be that everything is fine and complete as is?</li>
<li>What would this look like if it were easy?</li>
<li>How can I throw money at this problem? How can I “waste” money to improve the quality of my life?</li>
<li>No hurry, no pause.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="useful-questions-for-reframing-derek-sivers-useful-not-true">Useful questions for reframing (<a href="https://sive.rs/u">Derek Sivers, Useful Not True</a>)</h2>
<h3 id="when-something-goes-wrong">When something goes wrong</h3>
<ul>
<li>What’s great about this?</li>
<li>How can I use this to my advantage?</li>
<li>Does this change the goal, or the path, or nothing?</li>
<li>How can I reduce the downsides?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="when-changing-direction">When changing direction</h3>
<ul>
<li>When I was at my happiest, what was I doing?</li>
<li>What have I strongly wanted for the longest time?</li>
<li>What’s the opposite of what I usually do?</li>
<li>Which of my old beliefs are not serving me?</li>
<li>Forget me. What would be most helpful for others?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="when-stuck">When stuck</h3>
<ul>
<li>What is my one top priority now?</li>
<li>How can I begin without waiting for anything?</li>
<li>What advice would I love to hear from an all-knowing sage?</li>
<li>What am I doing that’s actually a distraction?</li>
<li>Instead of avoiding mistakes, how can I make more to learn faster?</li>
<li>Who can help?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="to-make-peace-with-whats-out-of-your-control">To make peace with what’s out of your control</h3>
<ul>
<li>What happens if I ignore it and do nothing?</li>
<li>Should I learn a lesson from this, or just move on?</li>
<li>How can I blame no one, and see this as nobody’s fault?</li>
<li>How can I be OK no matter what happens?</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mentor Me! 11 Questions I&#39;d Like You to Answer</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/mentor-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 20:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/mentor-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say what you will about Tim Ferriss, I’ve always really enjoyed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tim.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/17-Questions-That-Changed-My-Life.pdf&#34;&gt;questions that he asks himself&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://tim.blog/2017/10/03/tribe-of-mentors/&#34;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also really enjoy LEARNING as much as I can from other people. And so, with that in mind, I’d like to “open source” my search for mentors and &lt;strong&gt;invite you, dear reader, to answer at least one of the questions below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please comment your answers below&lt;/strong&gt; this post (that way others can benefit from your knowledge as well!). Or, if you’d like, send them to me via email (&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/contact/&#34;&gt;use my contact form here&lt;/a&gt;). Then, go ask these questions to others! Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Say what you will about Tim Ferriss, I’ve always really enjoyed the <a href="https://tim.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/17-Questions-That-Changed-My-Life.pdf">questions that he asks himself</a> and <a href="https://tim.blog/2017/10/03/tribe-of-mentors/">others</a>.</p>
<p>I also really enjoy LEARNING as much as I can from other people. And so, with that in mind, I’d like to “open source” my search for mentors and <strong>invite you, dear reader, to answer at least one of the questions below.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Please comment your answers below</strong> this post (that way others can benefit from your knowledge as well!). Or, if you’d like, send them to me via email (<a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/contact/">use my contact form here</a>). Then, go ask these questions to others! Cheers!</p>
<ol>
<li>What is the book (or books) you’ve given most as a gift, and why? Or what are one to three books that have greatly influenced your life?</li>
<li>What purchase of $100 or less has most positively impacted your life in the last six months (or in recent memory)?</li>
<li>How has a failure, or apparent failure, set you up for later success? Do you have a “favorite failure” of yours?</li>
<li>If you could have a gigantic billboard anywhere with anything on it — metaphorically speaking, getting a message out to millions or billions — what would it say and why? It could be a few words or a paragraph. (If helpful, it can be someone else’s quote: Are there any quotes you think of often or live your life by?)</li>
<li>What is one of the best or most worthwhile investments you’ve ever made? (Could be an investment of money, time, energy, etc.)</li>
<li>What is an unusual habit or an absurd thing that you love?</li>
<li>In the last five years, what new belief, behavior, or habit has most improved your life?</li>
<li>What advice would you give to a smart, driven college student about to enter the “real world”? What advice should they ignore?</li>
<li>What are bad recommendations you hear in your profession or area of expertise?</li>
<li>In the last five years, what have you become better at saying no to (distractions, invitations, etc.)? What new realizations and/or approaches helped? Any other tips?</li>
<li>When you feel overwhelmed or unfocused, or have lost your focus temporarily, what do you do? (If helpful: What questions do you ask yourself?)</li>
</ol>
<p>Source for these questions: <a href="https://tim.blog/2017/10/03/tribe-of-mentors/">Tim Ferriss, <em>Tribe of Mentors</em></a>.</p>
<p>Want more great questions? Check out <a href="https://www.curatedquestions.com/">Curated Questions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Haven’t You Torn The Sky Open Yet?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/why-havent-you-torn-the-sky-open-yet-sermon-first-sunday-of-advent-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/why-havent-you-torn-the-sky-open-yet-sermon-first-sunday-of-advent-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sermon preached on Saturday, November 28, 2020 (First Sunday of Advent) via Zoom at Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-audio&#34;&gt;&lt;audio controls=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Sermon112820.mp3&#34;&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;---
&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-there-are-two-things-i-hate-they-are-waiting-and-staying-awake&#34;&gt;If there are two things I hate, they are waiting and staying awake.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask anyone who knows me. I am absolutely horrible when it comes to delayed gratification. I’ve been known to open new boxes of cereal on the way home from the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I hate staying awake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Sermon preached on Saturday, November 28, 2020 (First Sunday of Advent) via Zoom at Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL.</em></p>
<figure class="wp-block-audio"><audio controls="" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Sermon112820.mp3"></audio></figure>---
<h2 id="if-there-are-two-things-i-hate-they-are-waiting-and-staying-awake">If there are two things I hate, they are waiting and staying awake.</h2>
<p>I hate waiting.</p>
<p>Ask anyone who knows me. I am absolutely horrible when it comes to delayed gratification. I’ve been known to open new boxes of cereal on the way home from the store.</p>
<p>And I hate staying awake.</p>
<p>Ask anyone who knows me. I’m convinced that nothing good happens after 10:00 o’clock at night. 9 o’clock, really, if I’m honest.</p>
<p>(Ahem, and my young children have driven this point home!)</p>
<p>Keeping watch all night long sounds like the worst thing in the world. I mean, unless you’re in the middle of a good book or an episode of Bake-Off, why not just go to bed?</p>
<ul>
<li>I hate waiting.</li>
<li>I hate staying awake.</li>
<li>I am impatient!</li>
<li>I am tired!</li>
</ul>
<p>And I’m wondering if Kevin or God assigned me this sermon on purpose!</p>
<p>Maybe it’s appropriate that I can literally see myself on the computer screen that I’m preaching to!</p>
<p>Friends, it’s been a long year. We last gathered in-person for Holy Communion on March 7th. I was the Celebrant. That was 266 days ago, but it feels like it’s been a few years.</p>
<p>I’m sure you’ve all been through a lot. On my end, while the Lord has proven faithful to provide glimpses of joy—including an addition to our family!—this has been one of the most difficult years of my life. I’ve recently decided to step away from my Ph.D. program for a year for the sake of my mental health.</p>
<p>It’s been a long year. And, I don’t know about you, but I am impatient and oh so tired.</p>
<p>As 2020 comes to a close, I’m tired of</p>
<ul>
<li>disease,</li>
<li>depression,</li>
<li>disruption,</li>
<li>deception,</li>
<li>division, and</li>
<li>death.</li>
</ul>
<p>And it’s very tempting to begin the new liturgical year today by skipping straight to Christmas and leaving all that unhappy junk behind us!</p>
<h2 id="but-advent-gets-in-our-way">But Advent gets in our way.</h2>
<p>As Fleming Rutledge puts it in her collection of Advent sermons,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“the season [of Advent] is not for the faint of heart.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Why? Well, to borrow another phrase from her,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Advent begins in the dark.”</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="you-see-advent-reminds-us-that-if-were-going-to-follow-jesus-we-need-to-stay-awake-and-wait-for-him-to-returnin-the-dark">You see, Advent reminds us that, if we’re going to follow Jesus, we need to stay awake and wait for him to return—in the dark.</h2>
<p>And yes, I’ll admit that “Stay woke, people, it’s dark outside!” is a hard word for the weary. But I think it’s a good word.</p>
<p>It’s certainly a much better word than “Everything’s fine, folks! Here, have some eggnog and, you know, try not to breathe on anybody!”</p>
<p>Because, here’s the thing: when Jesus tells us to watch and wait for his return to judge the living and the dead, he’s not telling us to sit down, shut up, and keep a stiff upper lip.</p>
<p>No! There are things to do.</p>
<h2 id="and-as-our-reading-from-isaiah-reminds-us-as-we-wait-for-the-lord-its-ok-if-weve-got-something-to-say-a-hard-word-of-our-own">And, as our reading from Isaiah reminds us, as we wait for the Lord, it’s OK if we’ve got something to say. A hard word of our own.</h2>
<p>Namely: “God, where are you? Why haven’t you torn the sky open yet? Why haven’t you come back to fix things?”</p>
<p>That’s how Isaiah 64 begins. It’s actually the second half of a lament prayer that begins by recalling how God rescued his people from slavery in Egypt. (Just like we just did in our sermon series on Exodus!)</p>
<p>The problem, of course, is that God’s people promptly rebelled against him before they even reached the Promised Land.</p>
<p>Then, once there, they continued to break their covenant commitments to God until they received the promised punishment of exile.</p>
<p>But Isaiah hasn’t forgotten the exodus or the covenant.</p>
<p>God has proven that he <em>can</em> save. And God has promised that he <em>will</em> save.</p>
<p>So, what gives?</p>
<ul>
<li>Where are God’s zeal and might?</li>
<li>Why is he withholding his tenderness and compassion from his people?</li>
<li>Why have enemies trampled down the sanctuary?</li>
<li>Why has God hidden his face?</li>
<li>Why has God given us over to our sins?</li>
<li>Is God going to keep silent and punish us by refusing to rescue us forever?</li>
<li>Doesn’t he know his reputation is on the line?</li>
</ul>
<p>But wait, that’s not quite right. And this is very important.</p>
<h2 id="this-is-not-a-lament-about-god-to-a-third-party-this-is-a-lament-to-god">This is not a lament ABOUT God to a third party. This is a lament TO God.</h2>
<p>Hard words, yes. But words spoken within the context of a relationship.</p>
<ul>
<li>Where are YOU, God?</li>
<li>We are YOUR people. Why haven’t YOU rescued us yet?</li>
<li>Don’t YOU know that YOUR reputation is at stake?</li>
</ul>
<p>Friends, if you’re feeling far away from God these days, might I suggest that you start praying this way, with brutal honesty? God knows how we really feel. Tell him! He can handle it.</p>
<h2 id="but-theres-something-else-we-need-to-be-brutally-honest-about-as-we-wait-for-the-lord-and-thats-our-own-sin">But there’s something else we need to be brutally honest about as we wait for the Lord, and that’s our own sin.</h2>
<p>Yes, as Isaiah 64:4-5 notes, God is a God who “who acts on behalf of those who wait for him.” And this means that he’s a God who comes “to the help of those who gladly do right, who remember [God’s] ways” (64:4–5).</p>
<p>Did you catch that? <strong>Waiting for God means “gladly doing right” and “remembering God’s ways” by living according to his will! We don’t “wait for God” by sitting around and twiddling our thumbs!</strong></p>
<p>But, I suppose, even thumb-twiddling would be better than what actually takes place! As Isaiah 64 goes on to describe, God’s people keep sinning despite God’s obvious anger. How, then, can we be saved?</p>
<p>Verses 6 and 7 read:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“All of us have become like one who is unclean, and all our righteous acts are like filthy rags; we all shrivel up like a leaf, and like the wind our sins sweep us away. No one calls on your name or strives to lay hold of you; for you have hidden your face from us and have given us over to our sins.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Yes, biblical lament gives us the space to air our grievances to God. But we shouldn’t stop there. We should continually confess our sins to God—both individually <em>and</em> communally.</p>
<p>Do you hear how Isaiah is speaking for the people here? There’s a solidarity between the prophet and the people that I think should also characterize the Church.</p>
<p>It’s not enough as Christians to say “not my problem” or “at least I’m not as bad as so-and-so!”</p>
<p>No, instead, as we wait for the Lord, we need to ask ourselves:</p>
<ul>
<li>What do I need to confess and repent of?</li>
<li>What does <em>our</em> church need to confess and repent of?</li>
<li>What does <em>the</em> church need to confess and repent of?</li>
</ul>
<p>In other words, we need to consider, in the words of our collect prayer, exactly what it looks like for us to “cast away the works of darkness, and put on the armor of light.”</p>
<p>And this is where the rubber meets the road, I think, when it comes to Jesus’s commands in Mark 13 to “Be on guard! Keep alert!” And “keep watch.”</p>
<p>He’s not talking about being paranoid, constantly checking the news, and what the kids these days are calling “doomscrolling” through Facebook and Twitter.</p>
<p>Yes, on the one hand, we need to make sure that we’re not selfishly ignoring the real suffering around us.</p>
<p>But, on the other hand, there’s a big difference between checking Twitter every hour to find out what we should be angry about and really listening to the heartbeat of the world’s pain.</p>
<p><strong>Friends, our problem isn’t that we’re starved for information and data. No, we’re starved for insight and discernment.</strong></p>
<p>So, if we’re going to read the news, we should first read our Bibles. And if we’re going to read our Bibles, we need to let the Bible read us.</p>
<p>Dietrich Bonhoeffer correctly diagnosed a persistent problem when he said that:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We no longer read the Bible seriously. We read it no longer against ourselves but only for ourselves” (DBWE 11:377-78).</p></blockquote>
<p>This particular facet of our sinfulness is called “confirmation bias.” Whether we’re reading the Bible or Facebook, we’re looking for things that confirm what we already think, feel, and do.</p>
<p>(And, in Facebook’s case, <em>it’s</em> showing us things that we tend to agree with!)</p>
<p>As we watch and wait for the Lord, we need to push back against this. We need to let judgment begin with the household of God (1 Pet. 4:17) and lead the way for the world in terms of confession and repentance.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, without the help of the Holy Spirit, we’re going to, at best, lead the way for the world in terms of self-righteousness and self-justification! Filthy rags, indeed.</p>
<h2 id="in-order-to-get-out-of-this-mess-we-desperately-need-gods-help">In order to get out of this mess, we desperately need God’s help.</h2>
<p>That’s why Isaiah is so indignant in his lament. Sure, it’s not God’s fault that we sin. But we sure can’t save ourselves!</p>
<p>As Psalm 80 reminds us, we need our Shepherd, the LORD God of Hosts, to “restore us” and “make your face to shine on us, that we may be saved.”</p>
<p>We can do our very best to keep watch, but, as Psalm 127:1 reminds us:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Unless the Lord watches over the city, the guards stand watch in vain.”</p></blockquote>
<p>But, of course, for Isaiah, that’s the problem! God has “hidden [his] face from us” and has “given us over to our sins” (64:7)?</p>
<p>“How then can we be saved?” (64:5)</p>
<h2 id="in-almost-every-biblical-lament-there-is-a-turn-in-isaiah-64-its-in-verses-8-9">In almost every biblical lament, there is a “turn.” In Isaiah 64, it’s in verses 8-9:</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>“YET you, Lord, are our Father. We are the clay, you are the potter; we are all the work of your hand.</p>
<p>“Do not be angry beyond measure, Lord; do not remember our sins forever. Oh, look on us, we pray, for we are all your people.”</p></blockquote>
<p>God is our Father. We are his children.</p>
<p>He may tarry, he may judge, he may allow us to experience consequences for our rebellion, but he will NOT “hold himself back” forever.</p>
<p>He will NOT “keep silent” forever and “punish us beyond measure.”</p>
<p>Why not?</p>
<h2 id="because-although-were-still-awaiting-his-final-return-and-judgment-god-has-in-fact-torn-open-the-heavens-and-come-down-since-isaiahs-lament">Because, although we’re still awaiting his final return and judgment, God has, in fact, torn open the heavens and come down since Isaiah’s lament.</h2>
<p>God has not kept silent.</p>
<p>In fact, as the book of Hebrews reminds us:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“In the past God spoke to our ancestors through the prophets [like Isaiah!] at many times and in various ways, but in these last days he has spoken to us by his Son” (1:1-2),</p></blockquote>
<p>…at whose baptism the heavens were torn open and the Spirit descended upon him like a dove (Mark 1:10).</p>
<p>And God has not punished us beyond measure.</p>
<p>In fact, as Isaiah 53:5 reminds us, in Christ, God himself</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“was pierced for our transgressions, he was crushed for our iniquities; the punishment that brought us peace was on him, and by his wounds we are healed.”</p></blockquote>
<p>You see, when Jesus’s body was torn upon the cross, the curtain in the Temple was torn in two, allowing us to enter the Holy of Holies with confidence by the blood of Christ!</p>
<p>Friends, this is what gives us confidence to stay awake and wait for the Lord’s return, even when it’s dark outside.</p>
<p>So, we can be brutally honest with God and we can confess our sins with confidence, even when the sun goes dark, the moon goes dim, and the stars fall from the sky.</p>
<p>We can gladly do right and remember God’s ways, even when the earth gives way and the mountains fall into the heart of the sea.</p>
<p>Why?</p>
<p>Because we are God’s children and God is our Father.</p>
<p>And so, we pray to Our Father:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Do not be angry beyond measure, Lord; do not remember our sins forever. Oh, look on us, we pray, for we are all your people” (Isa. 64:9).</p>
<p>“Restore us, Lord God Almighty; make your face shine on us [in the face of your Son], that we may be saved.” (Ps. 80:19)</p></blockquote>
<p>Amen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Letter to Fellow ACNA Clergy: On Anti-Racism and a More Diverse and Just Anglicanism</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/anti-racism-letter-to-fellow-acna-clergy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: As is our policy with &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; Anglican Compass content, we ask that you &lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com/republishing-guidelines/&#34;&gt;please submit a request before republishing content&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://adoc.church/a-letter-concerning-the-death-of-george-floyd-and-so-many-others/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;recently wrote&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care. Whether you’re ACNA clergy, a layperson, or a Christian leader outside the ACNA, we invite your consideration of the following and your &lt;a href=&#34;#sign&#34;&gt;signature&lt;/a&gt; in support.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>NOTE</strong>: As is our policy with <em>all</em> Anglican Compass content, we ask that you <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/republishing-guidelines/">please submit a request before republishing content</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Following the lead of bishops Jim Hobby, Todd Hunter, Stewart Ruch III, and Steve Wood, who</em> <a href="https://adoc.church/a-letter-concerning-the-death-of-george-floyd-and-so-many-others/"><em>recently wrote</em></a> <em>in response to the death of George Floyd, which gained support from a number of other bishops, we offer this open letter to our fellow ACNA clergy and to the churches under our care. Whether you’re ACNA clergy, a layperson, or a Christian leader outside the ACNA, we invite your consideration of the following and your <a href="#sign">signature</a> in support.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="our-context">Our Context</h2>
<p>Our province, The Anglican Church in North America (ACNA), was born as part of a global movement that features diverse leadership and reflects the churches and people of global Anglicanism. It is a manifestation of the universal power and eschatological <em>telos</em> of the Gospel of Jesus: “from every nation, from all tribes and peoples and languages, standing before the throne and before the Lamb” (Rev. 7:9).</p>
<p>Currently, the American population is about 38% non-white. By many projections, over the next 20 years, it will be increasingly composed of ethnic minorities. Our province, however, is far from representative of this emerging reality. The mission on our doorstep is clear: to reach North America, in all of its ethnic diversity, “with the transforming love of Jesus Christ.” We have the opportunity to proclaim the Gospel “to the whole creation” (Mark 16:15) and to be Jesus’ witnesses “to the ends of the earth” (Acts 1:8). We are called to reflect the ethnic diversity of the global movement of which we are a part, as well as the diverse locales in which we are present.</p>
<p>In order to more fully embody our Gospel witness, we must support, encourage, and empower the leadership of brothers and sisters of color in the ACNA to create more hospitable and welcoming spaces for people of color. This includes Black, Latino/a, Native, Asian, and other people groups. We must listen and respond to these voices in our midst and collectively seek to understand and address the historic and ongoing ways in which people of color continue to struggle under various expressions of injustice.</p>
<p>We see and grieve the racism and discrimination that exists and has a deep cultural and structural influence in our society, in our communities, and in our churches. The recent tragedies of Ahmaud Arbery, Breonna Taylor, and George Floyd are simply the latest in a long line of harrowing examples of these deeply embedded systemic realities. We see and grieve that our brothers and sisters of color, including many in our own dioceses and parishes, have been and continue to be profoundly affected by these realities.</p>
<p>Against this backdrop, we offer the following confessions and make the following commitments.</p>
<h2 id="confessions">Confessions</h2>
<p>We confess that we have failed to see, understand, and address the expressions of racism, both personal and systemic, that plague our society, communities, and churches.</p>
<p>We confess our slowness to listen to the dismay and discouragement of our brothers and sisters of color, especially those in our own province, and have neglected to cultivate hospitable spaces for them to flourish.</p>
<p>We confess that our ignorance, complacency, and silence have undermined our fidelity to the Great Commandment to love God and love our neighbor (Matt. 22:36-40), which fundamentally calls us into disciplines of anti-racism.</p>
<h2 id="commitments">Commitments</h2>
<p>We commit to listening to, learning from, and supporting leaders of color in their witness to our province.</p>
<p>We commit to partnering with these friends, and with organizations like</p>
<ul>
<li>the<a href="https://anglicanmultiethnic.org/"> Anglican Multiethnic Network (AMEN)</a>,</li>
<li><a href="https://www.caminemos-juntos.com/">Caminemos Juntos</a>,</li>
<li><a href="http://www.ammic.ca/">Asian &amp; Multicultural Ministries in Canada</a>, and</li>
<li>the<a href="http://etnn.org/"> Every Tribe and Nation Network</a></li>
</ul>
<p>that are working to promote, support, and invest in a more diverse and just Anglicanism.</p>
<p>And, in all of our different capacities and platforms, in our churches and in the world, we commit ourselves to investing in the work of anti-racism—in our catechesis, discipleship, preaching, ministry, advocacy, and reform.</p>
<p><em>(Editor’s note: You should also check out <a href="https://www.anglicanjusticeandmercy.org/home">the work being done by The Matthew 25 Initiative</a>.)</em></p>
<h2 id="the-road-ahead">The Road Ahead</h2>
<p>We are encouraged by the leaders, including the Archbishop, who have spoken out about the recent injustices, and we know that there are places within the province where there is movement toward realizing this vision of a multi-ethnic church, one that is unhindered by racism in all its forms, that can reach the entirety of North America.</p>
<p>However, there is significant work yet to be done. We hope that others will join us in our intentional commitment to partnering with leaders of color and the provincial organizations listed above in order to cultivate a diverse and just Anglicanism in North America.</p>
<p>We are a group of clergy committed to the ACNA and its mission. <a href="#sign">If you would like either to join us in these confessions and commitments or signal your affirmation of such work, we invite you to add your name to this letter.</a></p>
<p>Our ultimate goal, however, is not just signatures, but a collective public commitment towards diversity and justice for the sake of the gospel and our Kingdom witness.</p>
<p><em>Almighty God, you created us in your own image: Grant us grace to contend fearlessly against evil and to make no peace with oppression; and help us to use our freedom rightly in the establishment of justice in our communities and among the nations, to the glory of your holy Name; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and for ever. Amen.</em></p>
<p>Sincerely in Christ,</p>
<h2 id="authors">Authors</h2>
<p>Rev. Ryan Boettcher<br>
<em>Associate Clergy,</em> <a href="https://www.rezaustin.com/"><em>Resurrection Anglican South Austin</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Dr. Shawn McCain<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.rezaustin.com/"><em>Resurrection Anglican South Austin</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Seth Richardson<br>
<a href="https://www.teloscollective.com/"><em>The Telos Collective</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Dr. J.R. Rozko<br>
<em>National Director,</em> <a href="https://www.missioalliance.org/"><em>Missio Alliance</em></a> <em>&amp; Co-Lead Pastor,</em> <a href="http://www.firstchurchcanton.com/"><em>First Church of the Resurrection</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Ben Sternke<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.thetableindy.org/"><em>The Table Indianapolis</em></a> <em>&amp; Co-Founder,</em> <a href="https://gravityleadership.com/"><em>Gravity Leadership</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Matt Tebbe<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.thetableindy.org/"><em>The Table Indianapolis</em> </a><em>&amp; Co-Founder,</em> <a href="https://gravityleadership.com/"><em>Gravity Leadership</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Erik Willits<br>
<em>Host of</em> <a href="https://www.teloscollective.com/podcast/"><em>The Intersection Podcast</em></a> <em>Special Projects,</em> <a href="https://www.c4so.org/"><em>Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</em></a></p>
<h2 id="initial-signatories-click-here-or-scroll-down-to-sign">Initial Signatories (<a href="#sign">Click Here or Scroll Down to Sign</a>)</h2>
<p>Rev. Canon Dr. Dan Alger<br>
<em>Provincial Canon for Church Planting,</em> <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/index.php/main/Staff_Directory/"><em>Anglican Church in North America</em></a><br>
<em>Director,</em> <a href="https://www.always-forward.com/"><em>Always Forward Church Planting Initiative</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Gary Ball<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="http://www.redeemerasheville.com/"><em>Redeemer Asheville</em></a><em>, NC</em></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Taylor Bodoh<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.incarnationtallahassee.org/"><em>Incarnation, Tallahassee</em></a><br>
<em>Canon for Church Planting,</em> <a href="http://www.gulfatlanticdiocese.org/"><em>Gulf Atlantic Diocese</em></a><br>
<em>Leader in the</em> <a href="https://anglicanmultiethnic.org/"><em>Anglican Multiethnic Network (AMEN)</em></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Seth Cain<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://villageanglican.church/">The Village Anglican, Greenville</a></em><br>
</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Dan Claire<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://rezchurch.org/">The Church of the Resurrection, Washington, D.C.</a></em></span></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Greg Goebel<br>
<em>Editor-in-chief,</em> <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/"><em>Anglican Compass</em></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. David Martin Hanke<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://restorationarlington.org/">Restoration Anglican, Arlington</a></em><br>
</span></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Alan Hawkins<br>
<em>Chief Operating Officer,</em> <a href="http://www.anglicanchurch.net/index.php/main/Staff_Directory/"><em>Anglican Church in North America</em></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Thomas Hinson<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://adventdc.org/">Advent Anglican, Washington, D.C.</a></em></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">Rev. Hannah King<br>
<em>Associate Rector, <a href="https://villageanglican.church/">The Village Anglican, Greenville</a></em></span></p>
<p>Rev. Michael King<br>
<em>Associate Rector, <a href="https://villageanglican.church/">The Village Anglican, Greenville</a></em></p>
<p>Very Rev. Canon Dr. Kris McDaniel<br>
<em>Senior Pastor,</em> <a href="https://atltrinity.org/"><em>Trinity Anglican, Atlanta</em></a> <em>Canon for Church Development (Planting and Adoptions),</em> <a href="https://www.c4so.org/our-team/"><em>Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Canon Dr. Emily McGowin<br>
<em>Associate Lecturer of Theology,</em> <a href="https://www.wheaton.edu/academics/faculty/emily-mcgowin/"><em>Wheaton College</em></a><br>
<em>Canon,</em> <a href="https://www.c4so.org/our-team/"><em>The Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Ron McGowin<br>
<em>Interim Rector,</em> <a href="http://www.holycross-anglican.org/"><em>Holy Cross Anglican Church, Lake Villa, IL</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Lee Nelson<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.christchurchwaco.org/"><em>Christ Church, Waco</em></a></p>
<p>Very Rev. Rob Patterson<br>
<em>Rector, <a href="https://redeemeranglican.com/">Redeemer Anglican, Santa Cruz</a> Regional Dean, Northern California, <a href="https://www.c4so.org/">Diocese of Churches for the Sake of Others</a></em></p>
<p>Rev. Marty Reardon<br>
<em>Westside Worship Pastor,</em> <a href="https://westside.atltrinity.org/"><em>Trinity Anglican, Atlanta</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Erik Rogers<br>
<em>Assisting Clergy, <a href="https://www.rezaustin.com/">Resurrection Anglican South Austin</a></em></p>
<p>Rev. Canon David Roseberry<br>
<em>Publisher,</em> <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/"><em>Anglican Compass</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Joshua Steele<br>
<em>Managing Editor,</em> <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/"><em>Anglican Compass</em></a></p>
<p>Very Rev. Cliff Warner<br>
<em>Rector,</em> <a href="https://christchurchofaustin.org/"><em>Christ Church, Austin</em></a></p>
<p>Christine Warner<br>
<em>Director,</em><a href="https://www.anglicanjusticeandmercy.org/"> <em>Matthew 25 Initiative</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Tish Harrison Warren<br>
<em>Author,</em> <a href="https://amzn.to/2TTk7CT"><em>Liturgy of the Ordinary</em></a><br>
<em>Writer-in-Residence,</em> <a href="https://www.ascensionpittsburgh.org/our-leadership/"><em>Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Dr. Jonathan Warren Pagán<br>
<em>Associate Rector,</em> <a href="https://www.ascensionpittsburgh.org/our-leadership/"><em>Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Janna Ziegler<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://resurrectionla.org/"><em>Church of the Resurrection, Los Angeles</em></a></p>
<p>Rev. Jon Ziegler<br>
<em>Co-Rector,</em> <a href="https://resurrectionla.org/"><em>Church of the Resurrection, Los Angeles</em></a></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="sign-the-letter">Sign the Letter</h2>
<p><em>If you’re ACNA clergy, please use the first form. We’d also love for laypeople and Christian leaders outside of the ACNA to indicate their support. If you’re <strong>not ACNA clergy</strong>, please use the <strong>second</strong> form (scroll down).</em></p>
<p><em>(<strong>NOTE</strong>: Don’t worry if you don’t see your name appear below right away. There might be a bit of a lag. No need to submit twice.)</em></p>
<p>[emailpetition id=”2″]</p>
<h3 id="all-other-supporters">All Other Supporters</h3>
<p>[emailpetition id=”3″]</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="signatures">Signatures</h2>
<h3 id="acna-clergy">ACNA Clergy</h3>
<div class="wp-block-file">[ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter\_2022-08-15](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter_2022-08-15.csv)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter_2022-08-15.csv)</div>\[signaturelist id=”2″\]
<h3 id="all-other-supporters-1">All Other Supporters</h3>
<div class="wp-block-file">[Not-ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter-Here\_2022-08-15](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Not-ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter-Here_2022-08-15.csv)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Not-ACNA-Clergy-Sign-the-Anti-Racism-Letter-Here_2022-08-15.csv)</div>\[signaturelist id=”3″\]]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We switched Anglican Compass over from HostGator Shared to Bluehost VPS Hosting</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 15:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/we-switched-anglican-compass-over-from-hostgator-shared-to-bluehost-vps-hosting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As of this morning, it looks like everything for &lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicancompass.com/&#34;&gt;Anglican Compass&lt;/a&gt; has been successfully moved over from our HostGator shared hosting to Bluehost VPS hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping that this new arrangement works well for us! Although, to be honest, it’s still an open question in my mind whether or not managed WordPress hosting with WPEngine would be a better fit. I just can’t quite tell whether or not it would be worth the extra cost, given our current traffic and budget.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As of this morning, it looks like everything for <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">Anglican Compass</a> has been successfully moved over from our HostGator shared hosting to Bluehost VPS hosting.</p>
<p>I’m hoping that this new arrangement works well for us! Although, to be honest, it’s still an open question in my mind whether or not managed WordPress hosting with WPEngine would be a better fit. I just can’t quite tell whether or not it would be worth the extra cost, given our current traffic and budget.</p>
<p>What I would <em>really</em> love is for someone to sit down with me and give me a consultation on whether or not we’ve got things set up well for the following 3 websites on Bluehost:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">https://anglicancompass.com/</a> (this is our most important website right now, it gets the most traffic)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.leaderworks.org/">http://www.leaderworks.org/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://theevergreenproject.org/">https://theevergreenproject.org/</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Until now, I’ve only been involved with the backend of <a href="https://anglicancompass.com/">Anglican Compass</a>, so I’m not really sure of the ins and outs of how the other 2 websites are set up on the backend. But these three projects are going to be associated going forward, and I’d like to make sure that we’re set up for future success as our numbers increase!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;They laughed when I became an Anglican, but when I started to pray!&#34; 27 Anglican Headline Ideas</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 14:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/they-laughed-when-i-became-an-anglican-but-when-i-started-to-pray-27-anglican-headline-ideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading my way through &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2KdNASw&#34;&gt;the new (4th) edition of Robert Bly’s classic &lt;em&gt;The Copywriter’s Handbook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. On pages 33–36, Bly offers “38 Model Headlines for Your ‘Swipe File.&amp;rsquo;” Here are some headlines ideas that came to mind, all geared to an Anglican context (&lt;a href=&#34;https://anglicanpastor.com/&#34;&gt;due to my work at AnglicanCompass.com&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are Anglicans so angry?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I use the Book of Common Prayer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I become an Anglican?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do Anglicans believe?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why “Clarity &amp;amp; Charity” is the best way forward for the Church in a pluralistic age&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Announcing an ancient way to reclaim your days and years for God&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t become an Anglican!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now do the Daily Office with just this booklet and a Bible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 5 Anglican books you should own NOW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the BCP—Once difficult, now easy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A feast for the senses: The richness of Anglican worship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“I was about to give up on the Church when I was introduced to the Anglican tradition”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FREE booklet helps you pray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to avoid the biggest mistakes you can make when visiting an Anglican church&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The WORST Article in the Thirty-Nine Articles. Hint: It’s NOT what you think!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anglican clergy’s best-kept secret&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’re looking for people who want to leave Anglicanism better than they found it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s never too late to start doing the Daily Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sick of iChurch and McChurch? Give Anglicanism a try&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will your church pass the Word &amp;amp; Sacrament test?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 reasons why you should NOT become an Anglican Christian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why most people leave the Church—and what you can do about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crazy as it sounds, the Daily Office could save your marriage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 reasons why written prayers are better than extemporaneous prayers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7 questions to ask when you visit an Anglican church&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you can create a personalized discipleship plan—for FREE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where’s #27? Read the title for this piece.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m reading my way through <a href="https://amzn.to/2KdNASw">the new (4th) edition of Robert Bly’s classic <em>The Copywriter’s Handbook</em></a>. On pages 33–36, Bly offers “38 Model Headlines for Your ‘Swipe File.&rsquo;” Here are some headlines ideas that came to mind, all geared to an Anglican context (<a href="https://anglicanpastor.com/">due to my work at AnglicanCompass.com</a>).</p>
<ol>
<li>Why are Anglicans so angry?</li>
<li>How do I use the Book of Common Prayer?</li>
<li>How can I become an Anglican?</li>
<li>What do Anglicans believe?</li>
<li>Why “Clarity &amp; Charity” is the best way forward for the Church in a pluralistic age</li>
<li>Announcing an ancient way to reclaim your days and years for God</li>
<li>Don’t become an Anglican!</li>
<li>You can now do the Daily Office with just this booklet and a Bible</li>
<li>The 5 Anglican books you should own NOW</li>
<li>Using the BCP—Once difficult, now easy</li>
<li>A feast for the senses: The richness of Anglican worship</li>
<li>“I was about to give up on the Church when I was introduced to the Anglican tradition”</li>
<li>FREE booklet helps you pray</li>
<li>How to avoid the biggest mistakes you can make when visiting an Anglican church</li>
<li>The WORST Article in the Thirty-Nine Articles. Hint: It’s NOT what you think!</li>
<li>Anglican clergy’s best-kept secret</li>
<li>We’re looking for people who want to leave Anglicanism better than they found it</li>
<li>It’s never too late to start doing the Daily Office</li>
<li>Sick of iChurch and McChurch? Give Anglicanism a try</li>
<li>Will your church pass the Word &amp; Sacrament test?</li>
<li>3 reasons why you should NOT become an Anglican Christian</li>
<li>Why most people leave the Church—and what you can do about it</li>
<li>Crazy as it sounds, the Daily Office could save your marriage</li>
<li>5 reasons why written prayers are better than extemporaneous prayers</li>
<li>7 questions to ask when you visit an Anglican church</li>
<li>Now you can create a personalized discipleship plan—for FREE</li>
</ol>
<p>Where’s #27? Read the title for this piece.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Sermon on the Mount (Dissertation Dispatch 2020-02-04)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-sermon-on-the-mount-dissertation-dispatch-2020-02-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 18:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-sermon-on-the-mount-dissertation-dispatch-2020-02-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m still very much in the weeds, taking a closer look at how Bonhoeffer and Barth read the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the importance of the Sermon on Mount for Bonhoeffer’s life and work, I’m persuaded that there’s something important to be found here—something that will hopefully shed some light on the Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship re:their theological critiques of religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there are at least two other tidbits that have me interested in how Barth and Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m still very much in the weeds, taking a closer look at how Bonhoeffer and Barth read the Sermon on the Mount.</p>
<p>Given the importance of the Sermon on Mount for Bonhoeffer’s life and work, I’m persuaded that there’s something important to be found here—something that will hopefully shed some light on the Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship re:their theological critiques of religion.</p>
<p>Additionally, there are at least two other tidbits that have me interested in how Barth and Bonhoeffer read the Sermon on the Mount.</p>
<p><a href="https://relevantmagazine.com/culture/read-the-letter-dietrich-bonhoeffer-wrote-to-gandhi/">On October 17, 1934, Bonhoeffer wrote to Gandhi,</a> inquiring about the possibility of going to India in order to learn how to develop “a truly spiritual living Christian peace movement.” In that letter, Bonhoeffer writes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We are having great theologians in Germany—the greatest of them being in my opinion Karl Barth, whose disciple and friend I am happy to be—they are teaching us the great theological thoughts of the Reformation anew, but there is no-one to show us the way towards a new Christian life in uncompromising accordance with the Sermon on the Mount. It is in this respect that I am looking up to you for help.</p>
<p><cite>Bonhoeffer to Gandhi, October 17, 1934</cite></p></blockquote>
<p>On September 19, 1936, Bonhoeffer wrote the following to Karl Barth. He is commenting on their lack of communication since the fall of 1933.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are all sorts of reasons that I have not written since then. I always thought that if I were to write you, I would have to have something reasonable to say, but something reasonable in that sense was precisely what I never had, at least not such that I thought I might take up your time. And I still do not have that today. Besides, <strong>I also wanted to arrive at a certain point on my own with regard to the particular questions that emerged for me from Scripture and which constantly occupied me at the time; in the process I quite frankly repeatedly discovered that in several points I was probably moving away from what you yourself think about these questions. Basically the entire period was an ongoing, silent dispute with you, which is why I had to remain silent for a while. Primarily it involved questions concerning the interpretation of the Sermon on the Mount and the Pauline doctrine of justification and sanctification.</strong> I am currently working on this material and would very much have liked to ask you and hear your views on so many things.</p>
<p><cite>Bonhoeffer to Barth, September 19, 1936 (DBWE 14:252-253), <strong>emphasis added</strong>.</cite></p></blockquote>
<p>Now, what’s really intriguing to me is *why* Bonhoeffer would think, in 1934–36, that Barth’s interpretation of the Sermon on the Mount was insufficient. Was this just a general sense, based upon familiarity with Barth’s theology? Or did Bonhoeffer have some particular Barthian exegesis in mind?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quit claiming that we mutualists (egalitarians) don&#39;t take the Bible or tradition seriously.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/quit-claiming-that-we-mutualists-egalitarians-dont-take-the-bible-or-tradition-seriously/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 16:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/quit-claiming-that-we-mutualists-egalitarians-dont-take-the-bible-or-tradition-seriously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the ongoing debate about women’s ordination (in the Anglican realm and beyond), I keep hearing oversimplified claims from hierarchicalists (or “complementarians,” but that’s not the most helpful term in this debate) that they have the &lt;em&gt;entirety&lt;/em&gt; of the Bible and Church tradition on their side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we mutualists (or “egalitarians,” but that’s not the most helpful term in this debate), it is argued, have arrived at our positions for various reasons—perhaps capitulation to liberal cultural trends and hermeneutical methods—but not because we’ve read Scripture or studied the history of the Church very carefully.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the ongoing debate about women’s ordination (in the Anglican realm and beyond), I keep hearing oversimplified claims from hierarchicalists (or “complementarians,” but that’s not the most helpful term in this debate) that they have the <em>entirety</em> of the Bible and Church tradition on their side.</p>
<p>Therefore, we mutualists (or “egalitarians,” but that’s not the most helpful term in this debate), it is argued, have arrived at our positions for various reasons—perhaps capitulation to liberal cultural trends and hermeneutical methods—but not because we’ve read Scripture or studied the history of the Church very carefully.</p>
<p>(<em>Related: See <a href="https://www.patheos.com/blogs/jesuscreed/2017/06/19/egalitarians-take-bible-seriously/">J.W. Wartick’s post, “Do Egalitarians Take the Bible Seriously?,” over at Scot McKnight’s Jesus Creed blog.</a>)</em></p>
<p>This is patently false. It is a refusal to admit the complexities of this debate. It is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principle_of_charity">violation of the hermeneutical principle of charity</a>.</p>
<p>I would also suggest that this uncharitable claim that the mutualists don’t have a high view of Scripture or Church tradition is what Will Witt has labeled a <a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/non-theological-arguments-against-the-ordination-of-women/">“non-theological argument against the ordination of women.”</a></p>
<p>NOTE: I am *not* suggesting that hierarchicalist’s <em>Scriptural arguments</em> are non-theological. To do so would be exactly the same kind of uncharitable dismissal that I have a problem with. Each scriptural argument, each passage in question deserves careful debate.</p>
<p>But what I am claiming is that it is a serious mistake—one which derails the possibility for a legitimate conversation to continue—for hierarchicalists to simply ignore or impugn the careful work of mutualist biblical scholars and theologians.</p>
<p>Hierarchicalists ought not to claim that the mountain of biblical, historical, and theological work that’s been done in support of mutualism doesn’t at least represent an attempt to take the Bible and tradition seriously.</p>
<p>Consider, as a starting point, the mutualist work in the following resources.</p>
<p>First, if you don’t have a lot of time, then just look through Pierce and Groothius (editors), <a href="https://amzn.to/2ShMk6H"><em>Discovering Biblical Equality: Complementarity Without Hierarchy,</em></a> Second Edition (InterVarsity Press, 2005). That’s a good one-stop-shop if you’d like to actually engage with biblical and theological mutualist arguments, (instead of pretending like they don’t exist or impugning their motives).</p>
<p>Here’s what’s in the book:</p>
<ul>
<li>Introduction, Rebecca Merrill Groothuis and Ronald W. Pierce</li>
<li><strong>I. Setting the Stage (The Historical Backdrop)</strong>
<ul>
<li>1 The Changing Roles of Women in Ministry: The Early Church Through the 18th Century, <em>Ruth A. Tucker</em></li>
<li>2 Evangelical Women in Ministry a Century Ago: The 19th and Early 20th Centuries, <em>Janette Hassey</em></li>
<li>3 Contemporary Evangelicals for Gender Equality, <em>Ronald W. Pierce</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>II. Looking to Scripture (The Biblical Texts)</strong>
<ul>
<li>4 Equality With and Without Innocence: Genesis 1–3, <em>Richard S. Hess</em></li>
<li>5 From Old Testament Law to New Testament Gospel, <em>Ronald W. Pierce</em></li>
<li>6 Women Leaders in the Bible, <em>Linda L. Belleville</em></li>
<li>7 Jesus’ Treatment of Women in the Gospels, <em>Aída Besançon Spencer</em></li>
<li>8 Praying and Prophesying in the Assemblies: 1 Corinthians 11:2–16, <em>Gordon D. Fee</em></li>
<li>9 Learning in the Assemblies: 1 Corinthians 14:34–35, <em>Craig S. Keener</em></li>
<li>10 Male and Female in the New Creation: Galatians 3:26–29, <em>Gordon D. Fee</em></li>
<li>11 Mutual Love and Submission in Marriage: Colossians 3:18–19 and Ephesians 5:21–33, <em>I. Howard Marshall</em></li>
<li>12 Teaching and Usurping Authority: 1 Timothy 2:11–15, <em>Linda L. Belleville</em></li>
<li>13 A Silent Witness in Marriage: 1 Peter 3:1–7, <em>Peter H. Davids</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>III. Thinking It Through (Logical and Theological Perspectives)</strong>
<ul>
<li>14 The Priority of Spirit Gifting for Church Ministry, <em>Gordon D. Fee</em></li>
<li>15 The Nature of Authority in the New Testament, <em>Walter L. Liefeld</em></li>
<li>16 Biblical Priesthood and Women in Ministry, <em>Stanley J. Grenz</em></li>
<li>17 God, Metaphor and Gender: Is the God of the Bible a Male Deity?, <em>R. K. McGregor Wright</em></li>
<li>18 “Equal in Being, Unequal in Role”: Exploring the Logic of Woman’s Subordination, <em>Rebecca Merrill Groothuis</em></li>
<li>19 The Subordination of Christ and the Subordination of Women, <em>Kevin Giles</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>IV. Addressing the Issues (Hermeneutical and Cultural Perspectives)</strong>
<ul>
<li>20 Biblical Hermeneutics: Basic Principles and Questions of Gender, <em>Roger Nicole</em></li>
<li>21 Hermeneutics and the Gender Debate, <em>Gordon D. Fee</em></li>
<li>22 A Redemptive-Movement Hermeneutic: The Slavery Analogy, <em>William J. Webb</em></li>
<li>23 Gender Equality and Homosexuality, <em>William J. Webb</em></li>
<li>24 Feminism and Abortion, <em>Sulia Mason and Karen Mason</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>V. Living It Out (Practical Applications)</strong>
<ul>
<li>25 In Search of Holy Joy: Women and Self-Esteem, <em>Joan Burgess Winfrey</em></li>
<li>26 Marriage as a Partnership of Equals, <em>Judith K. Balswick and Jack O. Balswick</em></li>
<li>27 Nature, Culture and Gender Complementarity, <em>Cynthia Neal Kimball</em></li>
<li>28 Helping the Church Understand Biblical Equality, <em>Mimi Haddad and Alvera Mickelsen</em></li>
<li>29 Toward Reconciliation: Healing the Schism, <em>Alice P. Mathews</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Then, take a look at the following resources (although many more could be added to this list):</p>
<ul>
<li>Bauckham, Richard, <a href="https://amzn.to/2TlNrPZ"><em>Gospel Women: Studies of the Named Women in the Gospels.</em></a> Eerdmans, 2002.</li>
<li>Beck, James R. and Blomberg, Craig L., eds., <em>Two Views on Women in Ministry.</em> Grand Rapids: Zondervan, 2001. (See the <a href="https://amzn.to/2RXjl8U">Revised Edition, published in 2005</a>.)</li>
<li>Clouse, Bonnidell and Robert G., eds., <a href="https://amzn.to/2UtANyq"><em>Women in Ministry: Four Views.</em></a> Downers Grove: IVP, 1989.</li>
<li>Cohick, Lynn H. and Amy Brown Hughes, <a href="https://amzn.to/2Wu90Qp"><em>Christian Women in the Patristic World: Their Influence, Authority, and Legacy in the Second through Fifth Centuries</em></a>, Baker Academic, 2017.</li>
<li>Cooper, Kate, <a href="https://amzn.to/2WvkZx5"><em>Band of Angels: The Forgotten World of Early Christian Women.</em></a> The Overlook Press, 2013.</li>
<li>Fee, Gordon D., <a href="https://amzn.to/2SfZO2O"><em>1 &amp; 2 Timothy, Titus.</em></a> Baker Books, 2011.</li>
<li>Keener, Craig S., <a href="https://amzn.to/2WoeFaC"><em>Paul, Women &amp; Wives: Marriage and Women’s Ministry in the Letters of Paul.</em></a> Hendrickson Publishers,1992.</li>
<li>Kroeger, Catherine Clark and Richard Clark Kroeger, <a href="https://amzn.to/2DLEhal"><em>I Suffer Not a Woman: Rethinking I Timothy 2:11-15 in Light of Ancient Evidence.</em></a> Baker Book House, 1992.</li>
<li>Macy, Gary, <a href="https://amzn.to/2Uqfi1C"><em>The Hidden History of Women’s Ordination: Female Clergy in the Medieval West.</em></a> Oxford University Press, 2008.</li>
<li>Mickelsen, Alvera (editor), <a href="https://amzn.to/2UrIUf9"><em>Women, Authority &amp; the Bible.</em></a> InterVarsity Press, 1986.</li>
<li>Payne, Philip B., <a href="https://amzn.to/2DJ9Txf"><em>Man and Woman, One in Christ: An Exegetical and Theological Study of Paul’s Letters.</em></a> Zondervan, 2009</li>
<li>Peppiatt, Lucy, <a href="https://amzn.to/2GdKAVt"><em>Women and Worship at Corinth: Paul’s Rhetorical Arguments in I Corinthians.</em></a> Cascade Books, 2015.</li>
<li>Peppiatt, Lucy, <em><a href="https://amzn.to/359WBol">Rediscovering Scripture’s Vision for Women: Fresh Perspectives on Disputed Texts</a></em>. IVP, 2019.</li>
<li>Thiselton, Anthony C., <a href="https://amzn.to/2Wuf3V7"><em>The First Epistle to the Corinthians.</em></a> Eerdmans, 2000: in The New International Greek Testament Commentary).</li>
<li>Westfall, Cynthia Long, <a href="https://amzn.to/2RYQyRp"><em>Paul and Gender: Reclaiming the Apostle’s Vision for Men and Women in Christ</em></a>, Baker Academic, 2016.</li>
<li>Witherington, Ben (III), <a href="https://amzn.to/2WsBLNj"><em>Women in the Earliest Churches (Society for New Testament Studies Monograph Series)</em></a>, Cambridge, 1991.</li>
<li>Witherington, Ben III, <a href="https://amzn.to/2CU5ANV"><em>Conflict &amp; Community in Corinth: A Socio-Rhetorical Commentary on I and II Corinthians.</em></a> Eerdmans, 1995.</li>
<li>Witherington, Ben III, <a href="https://amzn.to/2DLQI5R"><em>Women and the Genesis of Christianity.</em></a> Cambridge University Press, 1990.</li>
<li>Wright, N.T., <a href="http://ntwrightpage.com/2016/07/12/womens-service-in-the-church-the-biblical-basis/">“Women’s Service in the Church: The Biblical Basis”</a></li>
<li>Wright, N.T., <em>1 &amp; 2 Timothy and Titus.</em> InterVarsity Press, 2009 [Here’s <a href="https://amzn.to/2GgEl3c">the commentary</a>. Here’s <a href="https://amzn.to/2Ga7zky">the study guide</a>.]</li>
</ul>
<p>Furthermore, <a href="http://willgwitt.org/a-guide-to-my-essays-about-womens-ordination/">Will Witt’s series of blogposts on the topic of women’s ordination</a> cannot be ignored.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-the-ordination-of-women/">Concerning the Ordination of Women: Preliminaries</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/non-theological-arguments-against-the-ordination-of-women/">Non-theological Arguments Against the Ordination of Women</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-the-argument-from-tradition-is-not-the-traditional-argument/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: The Argument “From Tradition” is not the “Traditional” Argument</a> (***This post is especially relevant for hierarchicalists who claim that they have the entirety of Church tradition on their side.***)</li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-hierarchy-and-hermeneutics/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Hierarchy and Hermeneutics</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-beginning-with-genesis/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Beginning with Genesis</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-disciples-of-jesus/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Disciples of Jesus</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-mutual-submission/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Mutual Submission</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-women%E2%80%99s-ordination-women-in-worship/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Women in Worship and “Headship”</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-speaking-and-teaching/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Speaking and Teaching</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-a-presbytera-is-not-a-priestess-part-1/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: A Presbytera is not a “Priestess” (Part 1: Old Testament Priesthood)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/womens-ordination-and-the-priesthood-of-christ-biblical-and-patristic-background/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Women’s Ordination and the Priesthood of Christ (Biblical and Patristic Background)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-and-the-priesthood-of-christ/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Women’s Ordination and the Priesthood of Christ (in persona Christi)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-the-argument-from-symbolism-part-1/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: The Argument From Symbolism Part 1 (God, Christ, Apostles)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-the-argument-from-symbolism-part-2/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: The Argument From Symbolism (Part 2: Transcendence, Immanence and Sexual Typology)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/womens-ordination-office/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Women’s Ministry in the New Testament (Office)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/concerning-womens-ordination-womens-ministry-in-the-new-testament-bishops-presbyters-deacons/">Concerning Women’s Ordination: Women’s Ministry in the New Testament (Bishops, Presbyters, Deacons) or a Presbytera is not a “Priestess” (Part 2)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://willgwitt.org/theology/womens-ordination/concerning-womens-ordination-conclusion/">Conclusion</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Are hierarchicalists free to disagree with the mutualists on particular points and texts? Of course!</p>
<p>As a mutualist, I will freely admit that this is a complicated debate. Because neither side has 100% certain, knock-down arguments for their position, both sides would benefit from charitable, robust engagement.</p>
<p>But, for the sake of that charitable, robust engagement, please quit claiming that we mutualists don’t care about the Bible or Church history. That’s every bit as unfair and uncharitable as if we mutualists claimed that all hierarchicalists are misogynists.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Deacon&#39;s Last Day</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/a-deacons-last-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 02:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/a-deacons-last-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Jesus, you are the Good Shepherd who cares for his flock: We ask you to bestow upon your Church the gifts of the Holy Spirit in abundance, and to raise up from among us faithful and able persons called to the ministries of Deacon, Priest, and Bishop. Inspire them to spend and be spent for the sake of the Gospel, and make them holy and loving servants and shepherds of the flock for whom you shed your most precious blood. Grant this for the sake of your love. Amen**.**&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Lord Jesus, you are the Good Shepherd who cares for his flock: We ask you to bestow upon your Church the gifts of the Holy Spirit in abundance, and to raise up from among us faithful and able persons called to the ministries of Deacon, Priest, and Bishop. Inspire them to spend and be spent for the sake of the Gospel, and make them holy and loving servants and shepherds of the flock for whom you shed your most precious blood. Grant this for the sake of your love. Amen**.**</p>
<p><cite>BCP 2019, 650.</cite></p></blockquote>
<p>I’m getting ordained to the priesthood tomorrow, and I’m both humbled and honored to serve Christ’s Church in this way.</p>
<p>Do I feel inherently worthy to be a <em>presbyter</em>? No.</p>
<p>Me, a 28-year-old, an <em>elder</em>?</p>
<p>But I do feel called.</p>
<p>I feel called to “spend and be spent for the sake of the Gospel.”</p>
<p>I feel called to preach the Word of God and administer the Sacraments.</p>
<p>I feel called to equip the saints for the work of ministry, to help make “every Christian a theologian” a tangible reality in local churches.</p>
<p>Would you join with me in praying that I would be a “holy and loving servant and shepherd of the flock for whom [Christ] shed [his] most precious blood”?</p>
<p>Would you borrow the following words from the Prayer Book and pray them for me, Joshua Steele, a sinner?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>…Give your grace, we humbly pray, to all who are called to any office and ministry for your people; and so fill them with the truth of your doctrine and clothe them with holiness of life, that they may faithfully serve before you, to the glory of your great Name and for the benefit of your holy Church; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you, in the unity of the Holy Spirit, one God, now and for ever. Amen.</p>
<p><cite>BCP 2019, 634.</cite></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s what I&#39;m committing myself to as a priest.</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-what-im-committing-myself-to-as-a-priest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/heres-what-im-committing-myself-to-as-a-priest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m getting ordained to the priesthood&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/ordination/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;this Saturday, November 02&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. For public/posterity’s sake, I wanted to post some of the main parts of the ordination liturgy (from the ACNA’s 2019 Book of Common Prayer).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-presentation&#34;&gt;The Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bishop and People sit. The Presenters, standing before the Bishop, present the Ordinand, saying&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reverend Father in God, we present &lt;em&gt;N.N.&lt;/em&gt; to be admitted to the Order of Priests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bishop:&lt;/em&gt; Has &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; been selected in accordance with the Canons of this Church? And do you believe &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; manner of life to be suitable to the exercise of this ministry?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>I’m getting ordained to the priesthood</em> <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/ordination/"><em>this Saturday, November 02</em></a><em>. For public/posterity’s sake, I wanted to post some of the main parts of the ordination liturgy (from the ACNA’s 2019 Book of Common Prayer).</em></p>
<h2 id="the-presentation">The Presentation</h2>
<p><em>The Bishop and People sit. The Presenters, standing before the Bishop, present the Ordinand, saying</em></p>
<p>Reverend Father in God, we present <em>N.N.</em> to be admitted to the Order of Priests.</p>
<p><em>Bishop:</em> Has <em>he</em> been selected in accordance with the Canons of this Church? And do you believe <em>his</em> manner of life to be suitable to the exercise of this ministry?</p>
<p><em>Presenters:</em> We certify to you that <em>he</em> has satisfied the requirements of the Canons, and we believe <em>him</em> to be qualified for this Order.</p>
<p><em>The Bishop shall then require the Ordinand to take the Oath of Conformity and the Oath of Canonical Obedience saying</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Canons require that no Deacon may be ordained a Priest in the Church before subscribing without reservation to the Oath of Conformity. It is also required that each Ordinand subscribe without reservation to the Oath of Canonical Obedience. In the presence of this Congregation, I now charge you to make your solemn declaration of these oaths.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>The Ordinand then declares</em></p>
<h3 id="the-oath-of-conformity">(The Oath of Conformity)</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>I, <em>N.N</em>., do believe the Holy Scriptures of the Old and New Testaments to be the Word of God and to contain all things necessary to salvation, and I consequently hold myself bound to conform my life and ministry thereto, and therefore I do solemnly engage to conform to the Doctrine, Discipline, and Worship of Christ as this Church has received them.</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="the-oath-of-canonical-obedience">(The Oath of Canonical Obedience)</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>And I do promise, here in the presence of Almighty God and of the Church, that I will pay true and canonical obedience in all things lawful and honest to the Bishop of _______, and his successors, so help me God.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>The Ordinand then signs the Oath of Conformity and the Oath of Canonical Obedience in the sight of all present.</em></p>
<p><em>All stand. The Bishop says to the People</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Dear Brothers and Sisters in Christ, you know the importance of this ministry, and the weight of your responsibility in presenting <em>N.N.</em> for ordination to the sacred Priesthood. Therefore if any of you know of any impediment or crime because of which we should not proceed, come forward now and make it known.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>If no objection is made, the Bishop continues</em></p>
<p>Is it your will that <em>N</em>. be ordained a Priest?</p>
<p><em>People:</em> <strong>It is.</strong></p>
<p><em>Bishop:</em> Will you uphold <em>him</em> in this ministry?</p>
<p><em>People:</em> <strong>We will.</strong></p>
<h2 id="the-exhortation">The Exhortation</h2>
<p><em>All are seated except the Ordinand, who stands before the Bishop.</em></p>
<p><em>The Bishop addresses the Ordinand as follows</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>You have heard, during the Church’s discernment of your vocation and in the Holy Scriptures themselves, how weighty is this Office to which you are called. I now exhort you, in the Name of our Lord Jesus Christ, to be a messenger, watchman, and steward of the Lord. You are to teach, to warn, to feed, and to provide for the Lord’s family, and to seek for Christ’s sheep who are in the midst of this fallen world, that they may be saved through Christ for ever.</p>
<p>Remember how great is this treasure committed to your charge. They are the sheep of Christ for whom he shed his blood. The Church and Congregation whom you will serve is his bride, his body. If the Church, or any of her members, is hurt or hindered by your negligence, you must know both the gravity of your fault, and the grievous judgment that will result.</p>
<p>Therefore, consider the purpose of your ministry to the children of God. Work diligently, with your whole heart, to bring those in your care into the unity of the faith and of the knowledge of God, and to maturity in Christ, that there may be among you neither error in religion nor immorality in life. Finally, equip and lead your Congregation to proclaim tirelessly the Gospel of Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>And seeing that the demands of this holy Office are so great, lay aside all worldly distractions and take care to direct all that you do to this purpose: read, mark, learn, and inwardly digest the Scriptures, that you may show yourself both dutiful and thankful to the Lord; and frame your conduct, and that of your household and those committed to your care, according to the doctrine and discipline of Christ. Know, however, that you cannot accomplish this of yourself; for the will and the ability needed are given by God alone. Therefore, pray earnestly for his Holy Spirit to enlighten your mind and strengthen your resolve.</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="the-examination">The Examination</h2>
<p><em>The Bishop then examines the Ordinand, saying</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>So that this Congregation of Christ’s Church may know your intent in these things, I charge you to answer plainly these questions, which I, in the Name of God and his Church, now ask:</p>
<p>Do you believe in your heart that you are truly called, according to the will of our Lord Jesus Christ, and according to the Canons of this Church, to the Order and ministry of the Priesthood?</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Answer:</em> I do so believe.</p>
<p><em>Bishop:</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Do you believe that the Holy Scriptures contain all things necessary for salvation through faith in Jesus Christ? And are you determined out of the Holy Scriptures to instruct the people committed to your charge, and to teach or maintain nothing as necessary to eternal salvation but that which may be concluded and proved by the Scriptures?</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Answer:</em> I do so believe, and I am so determined, the Lord being my helper.</p>
<p><em>Bishop:</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Will you then give your faithful diligence always so to minister the doctrine, sacraments, and discipline of Christ, as the Lord has commanded and as this Church has received them, according to the Commandments of God, so that you may teach the people committed to your charge with all diligence to keep and observe them?</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Answer:</em> I will, the Lord being my helper.</p>
<p><em>Bishop:</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Will you be ready, with all faithful diligence, to banish and drive away from the Body of Christ all erroneous and strange doctrines contrary to God’s Word; and to use both public and private admonitions and exhortations, to the weak as well as the strong within your charge, as need shall require and occasion shall be given?</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Answer:</em> I will, the Lord being my helper.</p>
<p><em>Bishop:</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Will you be diligent in prayer, and in the reading of Holy Scripture, and in such study as may further the knowledge of the same, laying aside all distractions of the world and the flesh?</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Answer:</em> I will, the Lord being my helper.</p>
<p><em>Bishop:</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Will you be diligent to frame and fashion your own <em>life</em> [and the <em>life</em> of your <em>family</em>], according to the doctrine of Christ, and to make <em>yourself</em> [and them, as much as you are able], a wholesome example and pattern to the flock of Christ?</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Answer:</em> I will, the Lord being my helper.</p>
<p><em>Bishop:</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Will you maintain and set forward, as much as you are able, quietness, peace, and love among all Christian people, and especially among those who are or shall be committed to your charge?</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Answer:</em> I will, the Lord being my helper.</p>
<p><em>Bishop:</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Will you reverently obey your Bishop and other chief Ministers who, according to the Canons of the Church, may have charge and authority over you, following with a glad mind and a good will their godly admonitions, and submitting yourself to their godly judgments?</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Answer:</em> I will, the Lord being my helper.</p>
<p><em>The Congregation may kneel, and prays silently for the fulfillment of these purposes.</em></p>
<p><em>The Bishop prays</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Almighty God, our heavenly Father, who has given you a good will to do all these things, grant you also the strength and power to perform them, accomplishing in you the good work which he has begun, that you may be found perfect and without reproach on the last day; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen**.**</p></blockquote>
<p><em>The Ordinand kneels or lies prostrate, facing the Bishop, with the priests present surrounding the Ordinand.</em></p>
<p><em>The Veni, Creator Spiritus is sung or said as a prayer for the renewal of the Church.</em></p>
<h2 id="veni-creator-spiritus">Veni, Creator Spiritus</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Come, Holy Ghost, our souls inspire,<br>
And lighten with celestial fire.<br>
Thou the anointing Spirit art,<br>
Who dost thy sevenfold gifts impart.</p>
<p>Thy blessed unction from above<br>
Is comfort, life, and fire of love.<br>
Enable with perpetual light<br>
The dullness of our blinded sight.</p>
<p>Anoint and cheer our soiled face<br>
With the abundance of thy grace.<br>
Keep far our foes, give peace at home;<br>
Where thou art guide, no ill can come.</p>
<p>Teach us to know the Father, Son,<br>
And thee, of both, to be but One;<br>
That, through the ages all along,<br>
This may be our endless song</p>
<p>Praise to thy eternal merit,<br>
Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="the-consecration-of-the-priest">The Consecration of the Priest</h2>
<p><em>All now stand as witnesses, except the Ordinand, who kneels facing the Bishop. The Bishop prays the following prayer, first saying</em></p>
<p>Let us pray.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Almighty God and most merciful Father, of your infinite love and goodness you have given your only Son Jesus Christ to be our redeemer and the author of everlasting life. After he had made perfect our redemption by his death and resurrection, and ascended into heaven, he sent into the whole world his apostles, prophets, evangelists, pastors, and teachers; by the Holy Spirit, through their labor and ministry, he gathered together a great flock to set forth the eternal praise of your holy Name. For these great benefits, and because you have called <em>this</em> your <em>servant</em> to the same office and ministry, we offer you our most hearty thanks; and we humbly ask that we may daily increase in the knowledge and faith of you and of your Son, and that by <em>this minister</em>, as well as by those entrusted to <em>his</em> care, your holy Name may for ever be glorified, and your blessed kingdom enlarged; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen**.**</p></blockquote>
<p><em>The Bishop with the Priests present lay their hands upon the head of each one to receive the Order of Priesthood. The Bishop says</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Receive the Holy Spirit for the office and work of a Priest in the Church of God, now committed to you by the imposition of our hands. If you forgive the sins of anyone, they are forgiven. If you withhold forgiveness from anyone, it is withheld. Be a faithful minister of God’s holy Word and Sacraments; in the Name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>The Bishop then prays the following over the Ordinand.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Send your heavenly blessing upon <em>this</em> your <em>servant</em>, that <em>he</em> may be clothed with righteousness, and that your Word, spoken by <em>his</em> mouth, may have such success that it may never be spoken in vain. Grant also that we may have grace to hear and receive what <em>he</em> shall deliver out of your most holy Word as the means of our salvation; that in all our words and deeds we may seek your glory and the increase of your kingdom; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you in the unity of the Holy Spirit, world without end.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>The People in a loud voice respond</em></p>
<p><strong>Amen.</strong></p>
<p><em>The new Priest may now be vested according to the Order of Priests.</em></p>
<p><em>As the Priest is vested with a stole, the Bishop says</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Take the yoke of the Lord, for his yoke is easy and his burden is light.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>As the Priest is vested with a chasuble, the Bishop says</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Receive this priestly garment which symbolizes charity; for God is well able to give you an increase of charity and a perfect work.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>The Bishop then anoints the hands of the new Priest with the Oil of Chrism, saying</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Grant, O Lord, to consecrate and sanctify these hands by this unction and by our blessing, that whatsoever they bless may be blessed, and whatsoever they consecrate may be consecrated and sanctified, in the Name of our Lord Jesus Christ. <strong>Amen.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><em>The Bishop then gives the new Priest a Bible in one hand and a chalice in the other hand saying</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Take authority to preach the Word of God and to administer the Holy Sacraments. Do not forget the trust committed to you as a Priest in the Church of God.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Prayer for Relatives and Friends</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/a-prayer-for-relatives-and-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/a-prayer-for-relatives-and-friends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O Loving Father, we commend to your gracious keeping all who are near and dear to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have mercy upon any who are sick, and comfort those who are in pain, anxiety, or sorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awaken all who are careless about eternal things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bless those who are young and in health, that they may give the days of their strength to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comfort the aged and infirm, that your peace may rest upon them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>O Loving Father, we commend to your gracious keeping all who are near and dear to us.</p>
<p>Have mercy upon any who are sick, and comfort those who are in pain, anxiety, or sorrow.</p>
<p>Awaken all who are careless about eternal things.</p>
<p>Bless those who are young and in health, that they may give the days of their strength to you.</p>
<p>Comfort the aged and infirm, that your peace may rest upon them.</p>
<p>Hallow the ties of kindred, that we may help and not hinder one another in all the good works that you have prepared for us to walk in; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</p>
<p><cite>The ACNA Book of Common Prayer 2019, pp. 76–77.</cite></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Why You Never See Your Friends Anymore&#34; (The Atlantic)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/why-you-never-see-your-friends-anymore-the-atlantic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 16:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/why-you-never-see-your-friends-anymore-the-atlantic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Judith Shulevitz offers up &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2019/11/why-dont-i-see-you-anymore/598336/&#34;&gt;a (depressing) eye-opening analysis of our overbusy lives&lt;/a&gt;. There is another way! But community and Sabbath both require sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas we once shared the same temporal rhythms—five days on, two days off, federal holidays, thank-God-it’s-Fridays—our weeks are now shaped by the unpredictable dictates of our employers. Nearly a fifth of Americans hold jobs with nonstandard or variable hours. They may work seasonally, on rotating shifts, or in the gig economy driving for Uber or delivering for Postmates. Meanwhile, more people on the upper end of the pay scale are working long hours. Combine the people who have unpredictable workweeks with those who have prolonged ones, and you get a good third of the American labor force.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Judith Shulevitz offers up <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2019/11/why-dont-i-see-you-anymore/598336/">a (depressing) eye-opening analysis of our overbusy lives</a>. There is another way! But community and Sabbath both require sacrifice.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Whereas we once shared the same temporal rhythms—five days on, two days off, federal holidays, thank-God-it’s-Fridays—our weeks are now shaped by the unpredictable dictates of our employers. Nearly a fifth of Americans hold jobs with nonstandard or variable hours. They may work seasonally, on rotating shifts, or in the gig economy driving for Uber or delivering for Postmates. Meanwhile, more people on the upper end of the pay scale are working long hours. Combine the people who have unpredictable workweeks with those who have prolonged ones, and you get a good third of the American labor force.</p>
<p>The personalization of time may seem like a petty concern, and indeed some people consider it liberating to set their own hours or spend their “free” time reaching for the brass ring. But the consequences could be debilitating for the U.S. in the same way they once were for the U.S.S.R. A calendar is more than the organization of days and months. It’s the blueprint for a shared life.</p>
<p><cite><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2019/11/why-dont-i-see-you-anymore/598336/">“Why You Never See Your Friends Anymore” (The Atlantic)</a></cite></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the most important theological terms that every Christian should know?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/what-are-the-most-important-theological-terms-that-every-christian-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 14:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/what-are-the-most-important-theological-terms-that-every-christian-should-know/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Which theological terms would make your shortlist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the list of terms found in “Jargon-Busting: A Glossary of Theological Terms,” at the back of &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2MjFFF7&#34;&gt;Alister E. McGrath’s excellent &lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2MjFFF7&#34;&gt;Christian Theology: An Introduction &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2MjFFF7&#34;&gt;(25th Anniversary Edition)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adoptionism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aggiornamento&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alexandrian School&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allegory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anabaptism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;analogy of being (analogia entis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;analogy of faith (analogia fidei)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anthropomorphism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Antiochene School&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anti-Pelagian writings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apocalyptic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apologetics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apophatic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apostolic era&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;appropriation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arianism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;atonement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barthian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beatific vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beatitudes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calvinism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cappadocian fathers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cartesianism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;catechism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;catharsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;catholic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chalcedonian definition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;charisma, charismatic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charismatic movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;circumincessio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conciliarism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;confession&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consubstantial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consubstantiation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;contemplation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dialectical theology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docetism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donatism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doxology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ebionitism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ecclesiology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enlightenment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eschatology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eucharist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evangelical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exegesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exemplarism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fathers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fideism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;filioque&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Five Ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fourth gospel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fundamentalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hermeneutics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hesychasm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;historical Jesus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;historico-critical method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;history of religions school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;homoousios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humanism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hypostatic union&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;icons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ideology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;incarnation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;justification by faith, doctrine of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kenoticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kerygma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;liberal Protestantism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;liberation theology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;liturgy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lutheranism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manicheism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;monophysitism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;neo-orthodoxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ontological argument&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;orthodoxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parousia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;patripassianism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;patristic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pelagianism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perichoresis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pietism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;postliberalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;postmodernism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;praxis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protestantism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quadriga&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;radical Reformation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reformed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sabellianism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sacrament&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;schism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scholasticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scripture principle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socinianism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;soteriology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;synoptic gospels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;synoptic problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;theodicy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;theopaschitism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;theotokos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thomism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;transubstantiation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trinity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;two natures, doctrine of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;typology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vulgate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zwinglianism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Which theological terms would make your shortlist?</p>
<p>Here’s the list of terms found in “Jargon-Busting: A Glossary of Theological Terms,” at the back of <a href="https://amzn.to/2MjFFF7">Alister E. McGrath’s excellent </a><em><a href="https://amzn.to/2MjFFF7">Christian Theology: An Introduction </a></em><a href="https://amzn.to/2MjFFF7">(25th Anniversary Edition)</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>adoptionism</li>
<li>aggiornamento</li>
<li>Alexandrian School</li>
<li>allegory</li>
<li>Anabaptism</li>
<li>analogy of being (analogia entis)</li>
<li>analogy of faith (analogia fidei)</li>
<li>anthropomorphism</li>
<li>Antiochene School</li>
<li>anti-Pelagian writings</li>
<li>apocalyptic</li>
<li>apologetics</li>
<li>apophatic</li>
<li>apostolic era</li>
<li>appropriation</li>
<li>Arianism</li>
<li>atonement</li>
<li>Barthian</li>
<li>beatific vision</li>
<li>Beatitudes</li>
<li>Calvinism</li>
<li>Cappadocian fathers</li>
<li>Cartesianism</li>
<li>catechism</li>
<li>catharsis</li>
<li>catholic</li>
<li>Chalcedonian definition</li>
<li>charisma, charismatic</li>
<li>Charismatic movement</li>
<li>Christology</li>
<li>circumincessio</li>
<li>conciliarism</li>
<li>confession</li>
<li>consubstantial</li>
<li>consubstantiation</li>
<li>contemplation</li>
<li>creed</li>
<li>Deism</li>
<li>dialectical theology</li>
<li>Docetism</li>
<li>Donatism</li>
<li>doxology</li>
<li>Ebionitism</li>
<li>ecclesiology</li>
<li>Enlightenment</li>
<li>eschatology</li>
<li>Eucharist</li>
<li>evangelical</li>
<li>exegesis</li>
<li>exemplarism</li>
<li>fathers</li>
<li>fideism</li>
<li>filioque</li>
<li>Five Ways</li>
<li>fourth gospel</li>
<li>fundamentalism</li>
<li>hermeneutics</li>
<li>hesychasm</li>
<li>historical Jesus</li>
<li>historico-critical method</li>
<li>history of religions school</li>
<li>homoousios</li>
<li>humanism</li>
<li>hypostatic union</li>
<li>icons</li>
<li>ideology</li>
<li>incarnation</li>
<li>justification by faith, doctrine of</li>
<li>kenoticism</li>
<li>kerygma</li>
<li>liberal Protestantism</li>
<li>liberation theology</li>
<li>liturgy</li>
<li>logos</li>
<li>Lutheranism</li>
<li>Manicheism</li>
<li>modalism</li>
<li>monophysitism</li>
<li>neo-orthodoxy</li>
<li>ontological argument</li>
<li>orthodoxy</li>
<li>parousia</li>
<li>patripassianism</li>
<li>patristic</li>
<li>Pelagianism</li>
<li>perichoresis</li>
<li>Pietism</li>
<li>postliberalism</li>
<li>postmodernism</li>
<li>praxis</li>
<li>Protestantism</li>
<li>Quadriga</li>
<li>radical Reformation</li>
<li>Reformed</li>
<li>Sabellianism</li>
<li>sacrament</li>
<li>schism</li>
<li>scholasticism</li>
<li>Scripture principle</li>
<li>Socinianism</li>
<li>soteriology</li>
<li>synoptic gospels</li>
<li>synoptic problem</li>
<li>theodicy</li>
<li>theopaschitism</li>
<li>theotokos</li>
<li>Thomism</li>
<li>transubstantiation</li>
<li>Trinity</li>
<li>two natures, doctrine of</li>
<li>typology</li>
<li>Vulgate</li>
<li>Zwinglianism</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here are all of William Witt&#39;s essays on Women&#39;s ordination, in a single PDF (with bookmarks!)</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/here-are-all-of-william-witts-essays-on-womens-ordination-in-a-single-pdf-with-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/here-are-all-of-william-witts-essays-on-womens-ordination-in-a-single-pdf-with-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over on his blog, “Non Sermoni Res,” Dr. &lt;a href=&#34;http://willgwitt.org/category/theology/womens-ordination/&#34;&gt;William Witt has written several excellent essays on the topic of women’s ordination&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://willgwitt.org/a-guide-to-my-essays-about-womens-ordination/&#34;&gt;the guide that Witt put together in order to orient readers to his essays&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I’ve done is to combine the blog posts into a single PDF, with bookmarks. Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-file&#34;&gt;[Witt\_Womens-Ordination-Essays](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Witt_Womens-Ordination-Essays.pdf)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Witt_Womens-Ordination-Essays.pdf)&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over on his blog, “Non Sermoni Res,” Dr. <a href="http://willgwitt.org/category/theology/womens-ordination/">William Witt has written several excellent essays on the topic of women’s ordination</a>.</p>
<p>Here’s <a href="http://willgwitt.org/a-guide-to-my-essays-about-womens-ordination/">the guide that Witt put together in order to orient readers to his essays</a>.</p>
<p>What I’ve done is to combine the blog posts into a single PDF, with bookmarks. Here it is:</p>
<div class="wp-block-file">[Witt\_Womens-Ordination-Essays](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Witt_Womens-Ordination-Essays.pdf)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Witt_Womens-Ordination-Essays.pdf)</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Outline of Karl Barth&#39;s Church Dogmatics</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/an-outline-of-karl-barths-church-dogmatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 15:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/an-outline-of-karl-barths-church-dogmatics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/BarthTimeline-2-1024x536-1024x536.png)&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-element-caption&#34;&gt;[Karl Barth’s Church Dogmatics Original Publication Dates, courtesy of PostBarthian.com](https://postbarthian.com/2016/04/21/karl-barths-church-dogmatics-original-publication-dates/).&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;If you’re trying to grasp the contours and contents of Karl Barth’s massive *[Church Dogmatics](https://www.logos.com/product/5758/barths-church-dogmatics),* it helps to have an outline! Here’s a helpful PDF version, with subheadings included, from Princeton’s [Center for Barth Studies](http://barth.ptsem.edu).
&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-file aligncenter&#34;&gt;[Barth\_Outline of Church Dogmatics](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Barth_Outline-of-Church-Dogmatics.pdf)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Barth_Outline-of-Church-Dogmatics.pdf)&lt;/div&gt;Below is a version that I’ve created from my Logos edition of *Church Dogmatics*. It’s the version found in the Index (CD V/1, 1–13).
&lt;p&gt;(Want to learn more about Karl Barth, but not quite ready to dive into the &lt;em&gt;Church Dogmatics&lt;/em&gt;? Check out Keith Johnson’s extremely helpful &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/45IDpg5&#34;&gt;The Essential Karl Barth: A Reader and Commentary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; [affiliate link].)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image">![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/BarthTimeline-2-1024x536-1024x536.png)<figcaption class="wp-element-caption">[Karl Barth’s Church Dogmatics Original Publication Dates, courtesy of PostBarthian.com](https://postbarthian.com/2016/04/21/karl-barths-church-dogmatics-original-publication-dates/).</figcaption></figure>If you’re trying to grasp the contours and contents of Karl Barth’s massive *[Church Dogmatics](https://www.logos.com/product/5758/barths-church-dogmatics),* it helps to have an outline! Here’s a helpful PDF version, with subheadings included, from Princeton’s [Center for Barth Studies](http://barth.ptsem.edu).
<div class="wp-block-file aligncenter">[Barth\_Outline of Church Dogmatics](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Barth_Outline-of-Church-Dogmatics.pdf)[Download](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/Barth_Outline-of-Church-Dogmatics.pdf)</div>Below is a version that I’ve created from my Logos edition of *Church Dogmatics*. It’s the version found in the Index (CD V/1, 1–13).
<p>(Want to learn more about Karl Barth, but not quite ready to dive into the <em>Church Dogmatics</em>? Check out Keith Johnson’s extremely helpful <em><a href="https://amzn.to/45IDpg5">The Essential Karl Barth: A Reader and Commentary</a></em> [affiliate link].)</p>
<h2 id="volume-i-introduction">VOLUME I: INTRODUCTION</h2>
<h3 id="1-the-task-of-dogmatics">§1 THE TASK OF DOGMATICS</h3>
<p>As a theological discipline dogmatics is the scientific self-examination of the Christian Church with respect to the content of its distinctive talk about God.</p>
<h3 id="2-the-task-of-prolegomena-to-dogmatics">§2 THE TASK OF PROLEGOMENA TO DOGMATICS</h3>
<p>Prolegomena to dogmatics is our name for the introductory part of dogmatics in which our concern is to understand its particular way of knowledge.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-doctrine-of-the-word-of-god">THE DOCTRINE OF THE WORD OF GOD</h2>
<h2 id="chapter-i-the-word-of-god-as-the-criterion-of-dogmatics">Chapter I: The Word of God as the Criterion of Dogmatics</h2>
<h3 id="3-church-proclamation-as-the-material-of-dogmatics">§3 CHURCH PROCLAMATION AS THE MATERIAL OF DOGMATICS</h3>
<p>Talk about God in the Church seeks to be proclamation to the extent that in the form of preaching and sacrament it is directed to man with the claim and expectation that in accordance with commission it has to speak to him the Word of God to be heard in faith. Inasmuch as it is a human word in spite of this claim and expectation, it is the material of dogmatics, i.e., of the investigation of its responsibility as measured by the Word of God which it seeks to proclaim.</p>
<h3 id="4-the-word-of-god-in-its-threefold-form">§4 THE WORD OF GOD IN ITS THREEFOLD FORM</h3>
<p>The presupposition which makes proclamation proclamation and therewith makes the Church the Church is the Word of God. This attests itself in Holy Scripture in the word of the prophets and apostles to whom it was originally and once and for all spoken by God’s revelation.</p>
<h3 id="5-the-nature-of-the-word-of-god">§5 THE NATURE OF THE WORD OF GOD</h3>
<p>The Word of God in all its three forms is God’s speech to man. For this reason it occurs, applies and works in God’s act on man. But as such it occurs in God’s way which differs from all other occurrence, i.e., in the mystery of God.</p>
<h3 id="6-the-knowability-of-the-word-of-god">§6 THE KNOWABILITY OF THE WORD OF GOD</h3>
<p>The reality of the Word of God in all its three forms is grounded only in itself. So, too, the knowledge of it by men can consist only in its acknowledgment, and this acknowledgment can become real only through itself and become intelligible only in terms of itself.</p>
<h3 id="7-the-word-of-god-dogma-and-dogmatics">§7 THE WORD OF GOD, DOGMA AND DOGMATICS</h3>
<p>Dogmatics is the critical question about dogma, i.e., about the Word of God in Church proclamation, or, concretely, about the agreement of the Church proclamation done and to be done by man with the revelation attested in Holy Scripture. Prolegomena to dogmatics as an understanding of its epistemological path must therefore consist in an exposition of the three forms of the Word of God as revealed, written, and preached.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-ii-the-revelation-of-god">Chapter II: The Revelation of God</h2>
<h2 id="part-i-the-triune-god">PART I: THE TRIUNE GOD</h2>
<h3 id="8-god-in-his-revelation">§8 GOD IN HIS REVELATION</h3>
<p>God’s Word is God Himself in His revelation. For God reveals Himself as the Lord and according to Scripture this signifies for the concept of revelation that God Himself in unimpaired unity yet also in unimpaired distinction is Revealer, Revelation, and Revealedness.</p>
<h3 id="9-the-triunity-of-god">§9 THE TRIUNITY OF GOD</h3>
<p>The God who reveals Himself according to Scripture is One in three distinctive modes of being subsisting in their mutual relations: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit. It is thus that He is the Lord, i.e., the Thou who meets man’s I and unites Himself to this I as the indissoluble Subject and thereby and therein reveals Himself to him as his God.</p>
<h3 id="10-god-the-father">§10 GOD THE FATHER</h3>
<p>The one God reveals Himself according to Scripture as the Creator, that is, as the Lord of our existence. As such He is God our Father because He is so antecedently in Himself as the Father of the Son.</p>
<h3 id="11-god-the-son">§11 GOD THE SON</h3>
<p>The one God reveals Himself according to Scripture as the Reconciler, i.e., as the Lord in the midst of our enmity towards Him. As such He is the Son of God who has come to us or the Word of God that has been spoken to us, because He is so antecedently in Himself as the Son or Word of God the Father.</p>
<h3 id="12-god-the-holy-spirit">§12 GOD THE HOLY SPIRIT</h3>
<p>The one God reveals Himself according to Scripture as the Redeemer, i.e., as the Lord who sets us free. As such He is the Holy Spirit, by receiving whom we become the children of God, because, as the Spirit of the love of God the Father and the Son, He is so antecedently in Himself.</p>
<h2 id="part-ii-the-incarnation-of-the-word">PART II: THE INCARNATION OF THE WORD</h2>
<h3 id="13-gods-freedom-for-man">§13 GOD’S FREEDOM FOR MAN</h3>
<p>According to Holy Scripture God’s revelation takes place in the fact that God’s Word became a man and that this man has become God’s Word. The incarnation of the eternal Word, Jesus Christ, is God’s revelation. In the reality of this event God proves that He is free to be our God.</p>
<h3 id="14-the-time-of-revelation">§14 THE TIME OF REVELATION</h3>
<p>God’s revelation in the event of the presence of Jesus Christ is God’s time for us. It is fulfilled time in this event itself. But as the Old Testament time of expectation and as the New Testament time of recollection it is also the time of witness to this event.</p>
<h3 id="15-the-mystery-of-revelation">§15 THE MYSTERY OF REVELATION</h3>
<p>The mystery of the revelation of God in Jesus Christ consists in the fact that the eternal Word of God chose, sanctified and assumed human nature and existence into oneness with Himself, in order thus, as very God and very man, to become the Word of reconciliation spoken by God to man. The sign of this mystery revealed in the resurrection of Jesus Christ is the miracle of His birth, that He was conceived by the Holy Ghost, born of the Virgin Mary.</p>
<h2 id="part-iii-the-outpouring-of-the-holy-spirit">PART III: THE OUTPOURING OF THE HOLY SPIRIT</h2>
<h3 id="16-the-freedom-of-man-for-god">§16 THE FREEDOM OF MAN FOR GOD</h3>
<p>According to Holy Scripture God’s revelation occurs in our enlightenment by the Holy Spirit of God to a knowledge of His Word. The outpouring of the Holy Spirit is God’s revelation. In the reality of this event consists our freedom to be the children of God and to know and love and praise Him in His revelation.</p>
<h3 id="17-the-revelation-of-god-as-the-abolition-of-religion">§17 THE REVELATION OF GOD AS THE ABOLITION OF RELIGION</h3>
<p>The revelation of God in the outpouring of the Holy Spirit is the judging but also reconciling presence of God in the world of human religion, that is, in the realm of man’s attempts to justify and to sanctify himself before a capricious and arbitrary picture of God. The Church is the locus of true religion, so far as through grace it lives by grace.</p>
<h3 id="18-the-life-of-the-children-of-god">§18 THE LIFE OF THE CHILDREN OF GOD</h3>
<p>Where it is believed and acknowledged in the Holy Spirit, the revelation of God creates men who do not exist without seeking God in Jesus Christ, and who cannot cease to testify that He has found them.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-iii-holy-scripture">Chapter III: Holy Scripture</h2>
<h3 id="19-the-word-of-god-for-the-church">§19 THE WORD OF GOD FOR THE CHURCH</h3>
<p>The Word of God is God Himself in Holy Scripture. For God once spoke as Lord to Moses and the prophets, to the Evangelists and apostles. And now through their written word He speaks as the same Lord to His Church. Scripture is holy and the Word of God, because by the Holy Spirit it became and will become to the Church a witness to divine revelation.</p>
<h3 id="20-authority-in-the-church">§20 AUTHORITY IN THE CHURCH</h3>
<p>The Church does not claim direct and absolute and material authority for itself but for Holy Scripture as the Word of God. But actual obedience to the authoritative Word of God in Holy Scripture is objectively determined by the fact that those who in the Church mutually confess an acceptance of the witness of Holy Scripture will be ready and willing to listen to one another in expounding and applying it. By the authority of Holy Scripture on which it is founded, authority in the Church is restricted to an indirect and relative and formal authority.</p>
<h3 id="21-freedom-in-the-church">§21 FREEDOM IN THE CHURCH</h3>
<p>A member of the Church claims direct, absolute and material freedom not for himself, but only for Holy Scripture as the Word of God. But obedience to the free Word of God in Holy Scripture is subjectively conditioned by the fact that each individual who confesses his acceptance of the testimony of Scripture must be willing and prepared to undertake the responsibility for its interpretation and application. Freedom in the Church is limited as an indirect, relative and formal freedom by the freedom of Holy Scripture in which it is grounded.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-iv-the-proclamation-of-the-church">Chapter IV: The Proclamation of the Church</h2>
<h3 id="22-the-mission-of-the-church">§22 THE MISSION OF THE CHURCH</h3>
<p>The Word of God is God Himself in the proclamation of the Church of Jesus Christ. In so far as God gives the Church the commission to speak about Him, and the Church discharges this commission, it is God Himself who declares His revelation in His witnesses. The proclamation of the Church is pure doctrine when the human word spoken in it in confirmation of the biblical witness to revelation offers and creates obedience to the Word of God. Because this is its essential character, function and duty, the word of the Church preacher is the special and immediate object of dogmatic activity.</p>
<h3 id="23-dogmatics-as-a-function-of-the-hearing-church">§23 DOGMATICS AS A FUNCTION OF THE HEARING CHURCH</h3>
<p>Dogmatics invites the teaching Church to listen again to the Word of God in the revelation to which Scripture testifies. It can do this only if for its part it adopts the attitude of the hearing Church and therefore itself listens to the Word of God as the norm to which the hearing Church knows itself to be subject.</p>
<h3 id="24-dogmatics-as-a-function-of-the-teaching-church">§24 DOGMATICS AS A FUNCTION OF THE TEACHING CHURCH</h3>
<p>Dogmatics summons the listening Church to address itself anew to the task of teaching the Word of God in the revelation attested in Scripture. It can do this only as it accepts itself the position of the teaching Church and is therefore claimed by the Word of God as the object to which the teaching Church as such has devoted itself.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="volume-ii-the-doctrine-of-god">VOLUME II: THE DOCTRINE OF GOD</h2>
<h2 id="chapter-v-the-knowledge-of-god">Chapter V: The Knowledge of God</h2>
<h3 id="25-the-fulfilment-of-the-knowledge-of-god">§25 THE FULFILMENT OF THE KNOWLEDGE OF GOD</h3>
<p>The knowledge of God occurs in the fulfilment of the revelation of His Word by the Holy Spirit, and therefore in the reality and with the necessity of faith and its obedience. Its content is the existence of Him whom we must fear above all things because we may love Him above all things; who remains a mystery to us because He Himself has made Himself so clear and certain to us.</p>
<h3 id="26-the-knowability-of-god">§26 THE KNOWABILITY OF GOD</h3>
<p>The possibility of the knowledge of God springs from God, in that He is Himself the truth and He gives Himself to man in His Word by the Holy Spirit to be known as the truth. It springs from man, in that, in the Son of God by the Holy Spirit, he becomes an object of the divine good-pleasure and therefore participates in the truth of God.</p>
<h3 id="27-the-limits-of-the-knowledge-of-god">§27 THE LIMITS OF THE KNOWLEDGE OF GOD</h3>
<p>God is known only by God. We do not know Him, then, in virtue of the views and concepts with which in faith we attempt to respond to His revelation. But we also do not know Him without making use of His permission and obeying His command to undertake this attempt. The success of this undertaking, and therefore the veracity of our knowledge of God, consists in the fact that our viewing and conceiving is adopted and determined to participation in the truth of God by God Himself in grace.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-vi-the-reality-of-god">Chapter VI: The Reality of God</h2>
<h3 id="28-the-being-of-god-as-the-one-who-loves-in-freedom">§28 THE BEING OF GOD AS THE ONE WHO LOVES IN FREEDOM</h3>
<p>God is who He is in the act of His revelation. God seeks and creates fellowship between Himself and us, and therefore He loves us. But He is this loving God without us as Father, Son and Holy Spirit, in the freedom of the Lord, who has His life in Himself.</p>
<h3 id="29-the-perfections-of-god">§29 THE PERFECTIONS OF GOD</h3>
<p>God lives His perfect life in the abundance of many individual and distinct perfections. Each of these is perfect in itself and in combination with all the others. For whether it is a form of love in which God is free, or a form of freedom in which God loves, it is nothing else but God Himself, His one, simple, distinctive being.</p>
<h3 id="30-the-perfections-of-the-divine-loving">§30 THE PERFECTIONS OF THE DIVINE LOVING</h3>
<p>The divinity of the love of God consists and confirms itself in the fact that in Himself and in all His works God is gracious, merciful and patient, and at the same time holy, righteous and wise.</p>
<h3 id="31-the-perfections-of-the-divine-freedom">§31 THE PERFECTIONS OF THE DIVINE FREEDOM</h3>
<p>The divinity of the freedom of God consists and confirms itself in the fact that in Himself and in all His works God is One, constant and eternal, and therewith also omnipresent, omnipotent and glorious.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-vii-the-election-of-god">Chapter VII: The Election of God</h2>
<h3 id="32-the-problem-of-a-correct-doctrine-of-the-election-of-grace">§32 THE PROBLEM OF A CORRECT DOCTRINE OF THE ELECTION OF GRACE</h3>
<p>The doctrine of election is the sum of the Gospel because of all the words that can be said and heard it is the best: that God elects man; that God is for man too the One who loves in freedom. It is grounded in the knowledge of Jesus Christ because He is both the electing God and elected man in One. It is part of the doctrine of God because originally God’s election of man is a predestination not merely of man but of Himself. Its function is to bear basic testimony to eternal, free and unchanging grace as the beginning of all the ways and works of God.</p>
<h3 id="33-the-election-of-jesus-christ">§33 THE ELECTION OF JESUS CHRIST</h3>
<p>The election of grace is the eternal beginning of all the ways and works of God in Jesus Christ. In Jesus Christ God in His free grace determines Himself for sinful man and sinful man for Himself. He therefore takes upon Himself the rejection of man with all its consequences, and elects man to participation in His own glory.</p>
<h3 id="34-the-election-of-the-community">§34 THE ELECTION OF THE COMMUNITY</h3>
<p>The election of grace, as the election of Jesus Christ, is simultaneously the eternal election of the one community of God by the existence of which Jesus Christ is to be attested to the whole world and the whole world summoned to faith in Jesus Christ. This one community of God in its form as Israel has to serve the representation of the divine judgment, in its form as the Church the representation of the divine mercy. In its form as Israel it is determined for hearing, and in its form as the Church for believing the promise sent forth to man. To the one elected community of God is given in the one case its passing, and in the other case its coming form.</p>
<h3 id="35-the-election-of-the-individual">§35 THE ELECTION OF THE INDIVIDUAL</h3>
<p>The man who is isolated over against God is as such rejected by God. But to be this man can only be by the godless man’s own choice. The witness of the community of God to every individual man consists in this: that this choice of the godless man is void; that he belongs eternally to Jesus Christ and therefore is not rejected, but elected by God in Jesus Christ; that the rejection which he deserves on account of his perverse choice is borne and cancelled by Jesus Christ; and that he is appointed to eternal life with God on the basis of the righteous, divine decision. The promise of his election determines that as a member of the community he himself shall be a bearer of its witness to the whole world. And the revelation of his rejection can only determine him to believe in Jesus Christ as the One by whom it has been borne and cancelled.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-viii-the-command-of-god">Chapter VIII: The Command of God</h2>
<h3 id="36-ethics-as-a-task-of-the-doctrine-of-god">§36 ETHICS AS A TASK OF THE DOCTRINE OF GOD</h3>
<p>As the doctrine of God’s command, ethics interprets the Law as the form of the Gospel, i.e., as the sanctification which comes to man through the electing God. Because Jesus Christ is the Holy God and sanctified man in One, it has its basis in the knowledge of Jesus Christ. Because the God who claims man for Himself makes Himself originally responsible for him, it forms part of the doctrine of God. Its function is to bear primary witness to the grace of God in so far as this is the saving engagement and commitment of man.</p>
<h3 id="37-the-command-as-the-claim-of-god">§37 THE COMMAND AS THE CLAIM OF GOD</h3>
<p>As God is gracious to us in Jesus Christ, His command is the claim which, when it is made, has power over us, demanding that in all we do we admit that what God does is right, and requiring that we give our free obedience to this demand.</p>
<h3 id="38-the-command-as-the-decision-of-god">§38 THE COMMAND AS THE DECISION OF GOD</h3>
<p>As God is gracious to us in Jesus Christ, His command is the sovereign, definite and good decision concerning the character of our actions—the decision from which we derive, under which we stand and to which we continually move.</p>
<h3 id="39-the-command-as-the-judgment-of-god">§39 THE COMMAND AS THE JUDGMENT OF GOD</h3>
<p>As God is gracious to us in Jesus Christ, He judges us. He judges us because it is His will to treat us as His own for the sake of His own Son. He judges us as in His Son’s death He condemns all our actions as transgression, and by His Son’s resurrection pronounces us righteous. He judges us in order that He may make us free for everlasting life under His lordship.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="volume-iii-the-doctrine-of-creation">VOLUME III: THE DOCTRINE OF CREATION</h2>
<h2 id="chapter-ix-the-work-of-creation">Chapter IX: The Work of Creation</h2>
<h3 id="40-faith-in-god-the-creator">§40 FAITH IN GOD THE CREATOR</h3>
<p>The insight that man owes his existence and form, together with all the reality distinct from God, to God’s creation, is achieved only in the reception and answer of the divine self-witness, that is, only in faith in Jesus Christ, i.e., in the knowledge of the unity of Creator and creature actualised in Him, and in the life in the present mediated by Him, under the right and in the experience of the goodness of the Creator towards His creature.</p>
<h3 id="41-creation-and-covenant">§41 CREATION AND COVENANT</h3>
<p>Creation comes first in the series of works of the triune God, and is thus the beginning of all the things distinct from God Himself. Since it contains in itself the beginning of time, its historical reality eludes all historical observation and account, and can be expressed in the biblical creation narratives only in the form of pure saga. But according to this witness the purpose and therefore the meaning of creation is to make possible the history of God’s covenant with man which has its beginning, its centre and its culmination in Jesus Christ. The history of this covenant is as much the goal of creation as creation itself is the beginning of this history.</p>
<h3 id="42-the-yes-of-god-the-creator">§42 THE YES OF GOD THE CREATOR</h3>
<p>The work of God the Creator consists particularly in the benefit that in the limits of its creatureliness what He has created may be as it is actualised by Him, and be good as it is justified by Him.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-x-the-creature">Chapter X: The Creature</h2>
<h3 id="43-man-as-a-problem-of-dogmatics">§43 MAN AS A PROBLEM OF DOGMATICS</h3>
<p>Because man, living under heaven and on earth, is the creature whose relation to God is revealed to us in the Word of God, he is the central object of the theological doctrine of creation. As the man Jesus is Himself the revealing Word of God, He is the source of our knowledge of the nature of man as created by God.</p>
<h3 id="44-man-as-the-creature-of-god">§44 MAN AS THE CREATURE OF GOD</h3>
<p>The being of man is the history which shows how one of God’s creatures, elected and called by God, is caught up in personal responsibility before Him and proves itself capable of fulfilling it.</p>
<h3 id="45-man-in-his-determination-as-the-covenant-partner-of-god">§45 MAN IN HIS DETERMINATION AS THE COVENANT-PARTNER OF GOD</h3>
<p>That real man is determined by God for life with God has its inviolable correspondence in the fact that his creaturely being is a being in encounter—between I and Thou, man and woman. It is human in this encounter, and in this humanity it is a likeness of the being of its Creator and a being in hope in Him.</p>
<h3 id="46-man-as-soul-and-body">§46 MAN AS SOUL AND BODY</h3>
<p>Through the Spirit of God, man is the subject, form and life of a substantial organism, the soul of his body—wholly and simultaneously both, in ineffaceable difference, inseparable unity, and indestructible order.</p>
<h3 id="47-man-in-his-time">§47 MAN IN HIS TIME</h3>
<p>Man lives in the allotted span of his present, past and future life. He who was before him and will be after him, and who therefore fixes the boundaries of his being, is the eternal God, his Creator and Covenant-partner. He is the hope in which man may live in his time.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-xi-the-creator-and-his-creature">Chapter XI: The Creator and His Creature</h2>
<h3 id="48-the-doctrine-of-providence-its-basis-and-form">§48 THE DOCTRINE OF PROVIDENCE, ITS BASIS AND FORM</h3>
<p>The doctrine of providence deals with the history of created being as such, in the sense that in every respect and in its whole span this proceeds under the fatherly care of God the Creator, whose will is done and is to be seen in His election of grace, and therefore in the history of the covenant between Himself and man, and therefore in Jesus Christ.</p>
<h3 id="49-god-the-father-as-lord-of-his-creature">§49 GOD THE FATHER AS LORD OF HIS CREATURE</h3>
<p>God fulfils His fatherly lordship over His creature by preserving, accompanying and ruling the whole course of its earthly existence. He does this as His mercy is revealed and active in the creaturely sphere in Jesus Christ, and the lordship of His Son is thus manifested in it.</p>
<h3 id="50-god-and-nothingness">§50 GOD AND NOTHINGNESS</h3>
<p>Under the control of God world-occurrence is threatened and actually corrupted by the nothingness which is inimical to the will of the Creator and therefore to the nature of His good creature. God has judged nothingness by His mercy as revealed and effective in Jesus Christ. Pending the final revelation that it is already refuted and abolished, God determines the sphere, the manner, the measure and the subordinate relationship to His Word and work in which it may still operate.</p>
<h3 id="51-the-kingdom-of-heaven-the-ambassadors-of-god-and-their-opponents">§51 THE KINGDOM OF HEAVEN, THE AMBASSADORS OF GOD AND THEIR OPPONENTS</h3>
<p>God’s action in Jesus Christ, and therefore His lordship over His creature, is called the “kingdom of heaven” because first and supremely it claims for itself the upper world. From this God selects and sends His messengers, the angels, who precede the revelation and doing of His will on earth as objective and authentic witnesses, who accompany it as faithful servants of God and man, and who victoriously ward off the opposing forms and forces of chaos.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-xii-the-command-of-god-the-creator">Chapter XII: The Command of God the Creator</h2>
<h3 id="52-ethics-as-a-task-of-the-doctrine-of-creation">§52 ETHICS AS A TASK OF THE DOCTRINE OF CREATION</h3>
<p>The task of special ethics in the context of the doctrine of creation is to show to what extent the one command of the one God who is gracious to man in Jesus Christ is also the command of his Creator and therefore already the sanctification of the creaturely action and abstention of man.</p>
<h3 id="53-freedom-before-god">§53 FREEDOM BEFORE GOD</h3>
<p>It is the will of God the Creator that man, as His creature, shall be responsible before Him. In particular, His command says that man is to keep His day holy as a day of worship, freedom and joy, that he is to confess Him in his heart and with his mouth and that he is to come to Him with his requests.</p>
<h3 id="54-freedom-in-fellowship">§54 FREEDOM IN FELLOWSHIP</h3>
<p>As God the Creator calls man to Himself, He also directs him to his fellowman. The divine command affirms in particular that in the encounter of man and woman, in the relationship between parents and children and outwards from near to distant neighbours, man may affirm, honour and enjoy the other with himself and himself with the other.</p>
<h3 id="55-freedom-for-life">§55 FREEDOM FOR LIFE</h3>
<p>As God the Creator calls man to Himself and turns him to his fellow-man, He orders him to honour his own life and that of every other man as a loan, and to secure it against all caprice, in order that it may be used in this service and in preparation for this service.</p>
<h3 id="56-freedom-in-limitation">§56 FREEDOM IN LIMITATION</h3>
<p>God the Creator wills and claims the man who belongs to Him, is united to his fellow-man and under obligation to affirm his own life and that of others, with the special intention indicated by the limit of time, vocation and honour which He has already set him as his Creator and Lord.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="volume-iv-the-doctrine-of-reconciliation">VOLUME IV: THE DOCTRINE OF RECONCILIATION</h2>
<h2 id="chapter-xiii-the-subject-matter-and-problems-of-the-doctrine-of-reconciliation">Chapter XIII: The Subject-Matter and Problems of the Doctrine of Reconciliation</h2>
<h3 id="57-the-work-of-god-the-reconciler">§57 THE WORK OF GOD THE RECONCILER</h3>
<p>The subject-matter, origin and content of the message received and proclaimed by the Christian community is at its heart the free act of the faithfulness of God in which He takes the lost cause of man, who has denied Him as Creator and in so doing ruined himself as creature, and makes it His own in Jesus Christ, carrying it through to its goal and in that way maintaining and manifesting His own glory in the world.</p>
<h3 id="58-the-doctrine-of-reconciliation-survey">§58 THE DOCTRINE OF RECONCILIATION (SURVEY)</h3>
<p>The content of the doctrine of reconciliation is the knowledge of Jesus Christ who is<br>
(1) very God, that is, the God who humbles Himself, and therefore the reconciling God,<br>
(2) very man, that is, man exalted and therefore reconciled by God, and<br>
(3) in the unity of the two the guarantor and witness of our atonement.</p>
<p>This threefold knowledge of Jesus Christ includes the knowledge of the sin of man:<br>
(1) his pride,<br>
(2) his sloth and<br>
(3) his falsehood—the knowledge of the event in which reconciliation is made:<br>
(1) his justification,<br>
(2) his sanctification and<br>
(3) his calling—and the knowledge of the work of the Holy Spirit in<br>
(1) the gathering,<br>
(2) the upbuilding and<br>
(3) the sending of the community, and of the being of Christians<br>
(1) in faith,<br>
(2) in love and<br>
(3) in hope.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-xiv-jesus-christ-the-lord-as-servant">Chapter XIV: Jesus Christ, the Lord as Servant</h2>
<h3 id="59-the-obedience-of-the-son-of-god">§59 THE OBEDIENCE OF THE SON OF GOD</h3>
<p>That Jesus Christ is very God is shown in His way into the far country in which He the Lord became a servant. For in the majesty of the true God it happened that the eternal Son of the eternal Father became obedient by offering and humbling Himself to be the brother of man, to take His place with the transgressor, to judge him by judging Himself and dying in his place. But God the Father raised Him from the dead, and in so doing recognised and gave effect to His death and passion as a satisfaction made for us, as our conversion to God, and therefore as our redemption from death to life.</p>
<h3 id="60-the-pride-and-fall-of-man">§60 THE PRIDE AND FALL OF MAN</h3>
<p>The verdict of God pronounced in the resurrection of Jesus Christ crucified for us discloses who it was that was set aside in His death, the man who willed to be as God, himself lord, the judge of good and evil, his own helper, thus withstanding the lordship of the grace of God and making himself irreparably, radically and totally guilty before Him both individually and totally.</p>
<h3 id="61-the-justification-of-man">§61 THE JUSTIFICATION OF MAN</h3>
<p>The right of God established in the death of Jesus Christ, and proclaimed in His resurrection in defiance of the wrong of man, is as such the basis of the new and corresponding right of man. Promised to man in Jesus Christ, hidden in Him and only to be revealed in Him, it cannot be attained by any thought or effort or achievement on the part of man. But the reality of it calls for faith in every man as a suitable acknowledgment and appropriation and application.</p>
<h3 id="62-the-holy-spirit-and-the-gathering-of-the-christian-community">§62 THE HOLY SPIRIT AND THE GATHERING OF THE CHRISTIAN COMMUNITY</h3>
<p>The Holy Spirit is the awakening power in which Jesus Christ has formed and continually renews His body, i.e., His own earthly-historical form of existence, the one holy catholic and apostolic Church. This is Christendom, i.e., the gathering of the community of those whom already before all others He has made willing and ready for life under the divine verdict executed in His death and revealed in His resurrection from the dead. It is therefore the provisional representation of the whole world of humanity justified in Him.</p>
<h3 id="63-the-holy-spirit-and-christian-faith">§63 THE HOLY SPIRIT AND CHRISTIAN FAITH</h3>
<p>The Holy Spirit is the awakening power in which Jesus Christ summons a sinful man to His community and therefore as a Christian to believe in Him: to acknowledge and know and confess Him as the Lord who for him became a servant; to be sorry both on his own behalf and on that of the world in face of the victory over his pride and fall which has taken place in Him; and again on his own behalf and therefore on that of the world to be confident in face of the establishment of his new right and life which has taken place in Him.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-xv-jesus-christ-the-servant-as-lord">Chapter XV: Jesus Christ, the Servant as Lord</h2>
<h3 id="64-the-exaltation-of-the-son-of-man">§64 THE EXALTATION OF THE SON OF MAN</h3>
<p>Jesus Christ, the Son of God and Lord who humbled Himself to be a servant, is also the Son of Man exalted as this servant to be the Lord, the new and true and royal man who participates in the being and life and lordship and act of God and honours and attests Him, and as such the Head and Representative and Saviour of all other men, the origin and content and norm of the divine direction given us in the work of the Holy Spirit.</p>
<h3 id="65-the-sloth-and-misery-of-man">§65 THE SLOTH AND MISERY OF MAN</h3>
<p>The direction of God, given in the resurrection of Jesus Christ who was crucified for us, discloses who is overcome in His death. It is the man who would not make use of his freedom, but was content with the low level of a self-enclosed being, thus being irremediably and radically and totally subject to his own stupidity, inhumanity, dissipation and anxiety, and delivered up to his own death.</p>
<h3 id="66-the-sanctification-of-man">§66 THE SANCTIFICATION OF MAN</h3>
<p>The exaltation of man, which in defiance of his reluctance has been achieved in the death and declared in the resurrection of Jesus Christ, is as such the creation of his new form of existence as the faithful covenant-partner of God. It rests wholly and utterly on his justification before God, and like this it is achieved only in the one Jesus Christ, but effectively and authoritatively for all in Him. It is self-attested, by its operation among them as His direction, in the life of a people of men who in virtue of the call to discipleship which has come to them, of their awakening to conversion, of the praise of their works, of the mark of the cross which is laid upon them, have the freedom even as sinners to render obedience and to establish themselves as the saints of God in a provisional offering of the thankfulness for which the whole world is ordained by the act of the love of God.</p>
<h3 id="67-the-holy-spirit-and-the-upbuilding-of-the-christian-community">§67 THE HOLY SPIRIT AND THE UPBUILDING OF THE CHRISTIAN COMMUNITY</h3>
<p>The Holy Spirit is the quickening power with which Jesus the Lord builds up Christianity in the world as His body, i.e., as the earthly-historical form of His own existence, causing it to grow, sustaining and ordering it as the communion of His saints, and thus fitting it to give a provisional representation of the sanctification of all humanity and human life as it has taken place in Him.</p>
<h3 id="68-the-holy-spirit-and-christian-love">§68 THE HOLY SPIRIT AND CHRISTIAN LOVE</h3>
<p>The Holy Spirit is the quickening power in which Jesus Christ places a sinful man in His community and thus gives him the freedom, in active self-giving to God and his fellows as God’s witness, to correspond to the love of God in which God has drawn him to Himself and raised him up, overcoming his sloth and misery.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="chapter-xvi-jesus-christ-the-true-witness">Chapter XVI: Jesus Christ, The True Witness</h2>
<h3 id="69-the-glory-of-the-mediator">§69 THE GLORY OF THE MEDIATOR</h3>
<p>“Jesus Christ as attested to us in Holy Scripture is the one Word of God whom we must hear and whom we must trust and obey in life and in death.”</p>
<h3 id="70-the-falsehood-and-condemnation-of-man">§70 THE FALSEHOOD AND CONDEMNATION OF MAN</h3>
<p>As the effective promise of God encounters man in the power of the resurrection of Jesus Christ, man proves himself to be a liar in whose thinking, speech and conduct his liberation by and for the free God transforms itself into an attempt to claim God by and for himself as the man who is bound in his self-assertion—a perversion in which he can only destroy himself and finally perish.</p>
<h3 id="71-the-vocation-of-man">§71 THE VOCATION OF MAN</h3>
<p>The Word of the living Jesus Christ is the creative call by which He awakens man to an active knowledge of the truth and thus receives him into the new standing of the Christian, namely, into a particular fellowship with Himself, thrusting him as His afflicted but well-equipped witness into the service of His prophetic work.</p>
<h3 id="72-the-holy-spirit-and-the-sending-of-the-christian-community">§72 THE HOLY SPIRIT AND THE SENDING OF THE CHRISTIAN COMMUNITY</h3>
<p>The Holy Spirit is the enlightening power of the living Lord Jesus Christ in which He confesses the community called by Him as His body, i.e., as His own earthly-historical form of existence, by entrusting to it the ministry of His prophetic Word and therefore the provisional representation of the calling of all humanity and indeed of all creatures as it has taken place in Him. He does this by sending it among the peoples as His own people, ordained for its part to confess Him before all men, to call them to Him and thus to make known to the whole world that the covenant between God and man concluded in Him is the first and final meaning of its history, and that His future manifestation is already here and now its great, effective and living hope.</p>
<h3 id="73-the-holy-spirit-and-christian-hope">§73 THE HOLY SPIRIT AND CHRISTIAN HOPE</h3>
<p>The Holy Spirit is the enlightening power in which Jesus Christ, overcoming the falsehood and condemnation of sinful man, causes him as a member of His community to become one who may move towards his final and yet also his immediate future in hope in Him, i.e., in confident, patient and cheerful expectation of His new coming to consummate the revelation of the will of God fulfilled in Him.</p>
<h3 id="the-foundation-of-the-christian-life">THE FOUNDATION OF THE CHRISTIAN LIFE</h3>
<p>A man’s turning to faithfulness to God, and consequently to calling upon Him, is the work of this faithful God which, perfectly accomplished in the history of Jesus Christ, in virtue of the awakening, quickening and illuminating power of this history, becomes a new beginning of life as his baptism with the Holy Spirit.</p>
<p>The first step of this life of faithfulness to God, the Christian life, is a man’s baptism with water, which by his own decision is requested of the community and which is administered by the community, as the binding confession of his obedience, conversion and hope, made in prayer for God’s grace, wherein he honours the freedom of this grace.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 16:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;john-websters-idea&#34;&gt;John Webster’s Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like so many others, I desperately wish that John Webster were still alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, my dissertation topic owes much to his essay: “Reading the Bible: The Example of Barth and Bonhoeffer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essay (previously published as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.utpjournals.press/doi/abs/10.3138/tjt.17.1.75&#34;&gt;‘“In the Shadow of Biblical Work:” Barth and Bonhoeffer on Reading the Bible,’&lt;/a&gt;and then published in &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Jlh1Ti&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Word and Church: Essays in Christian Dogmatics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) begins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two things at least are clear about the relationship of Barth and Bonhoeffer: that disentangling the history of their relation is of considerable importance for making sense of Bonhoeffer, if not of Barth; and that the disentangling is a rather delicate operation which involves some discriminating interpretation of the writings of two complex theologians. Much, for example, hangs on what we are to make of Bonhoeffer’s scattered remarks on Barth, revelation and non-religious interpretation in the prison writings, and of Barth’s puzzled response to them (87).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="john-websters-idea">John Webster’s Idea</h2>
<p>Like so many others, I desperately wish that John Webster were still alive.</p>
<p>After all, my dissertation topic owes much to his essay: “Reading the Bible: The Example of Barth and Bonhoeffer.”</p>
<p>The essay (previously published as <a href="https://www.utpjournals.press/doi/abs/10.3138/tjt.17.1.75">‘“In the Shadow of Biblical Work:” Barth and Bonhoeffer on Reading the Bible,’</a>and then published in <a href="https://amzn.to/2Jlh1Ti"><em>Word and Church: Essays in Christian Dogmatics</em></a>) begins:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Two things at least are clear about the relationship of Barth and Bonhoeffer: that disentangling the history of their relation is of considerable importance for making sense of Bonhoeffer, if not of Barth; and that the disentangling is a rather delicate operation which involves some discriminating interpretation of the writings of two complex theologians. Much, for example, hangs on what we are to make of Bonhoeffer’s scattered remarks on Barth, revelation and non-religious interpretation in the prison writings, and of Barth’s puzzled response to them (87).</p></blockquote>
<p>Here’s Webster’s suggestion for making sense of the Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>rather than pursuing questions about positivism of revelation or about the worldly and ethical, light can be shed on the relation of Bonhoeffer and Barth by looking at the place of the interpretation of Scripture in their respective theologies. Both give a thoroughly theological depiction of reading Scripture, that is, a depiction in which language about God is direct and operative; both, therefore, define the human act of interpretation as radical attentiveness and self-relinquishment to God’s saving self-communication through the instrumentality of Holy Scripture. This, I suggest, is one of the points at which these two church theologians come very close to each other, and offer much food for thought to church and theology now (88–89).</p></blockquote>
<p>He continues:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>My suggestion . . . is that an account of both Barth and Bonhoeffer, and equally an account of their relation, needs to give a good deal of attention to their writings on Scripture (90.)</p></blockquote>
<p>Oddly enough, despite the mountains of secondary literature on Barth, Bonhoeffer, and their relationship, “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” is still a gap! As Webster notes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Curiously, the significance of Scripture and its interpretation for understanding both Barth and Bonhoeffer has often been passed over rather quickly, and both have frequently been subjected to heavily conceptual interpretation (89).</p></blockquote>
<p>Nevertheless, it appears to me that Webster’s essay—despite its many strengths—falls prey to his own accusation.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong. Webster successfully (in my opinion) demonstrates that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Neither Bonhoeffer nor Barth were <em>wissenschaftlich</em> theologians; both were practical or pastoral theologians of the church of Jesus Christ. . . . Both, in short, were members of the guild, so despised by Kant and most of his heirs, of biblical theologians” (108–9).</p></blockquote>
<p>However, he does not address their expositions of specific biblical passages!</p>
<h2 id="my-idea">My Idea</h2>
<p>This, then, is what I would like to do.</p>
<p>I want to follow John Webster’s suggestion that, in order to understand Barth and Bonhoeffer, we need to take a closer look at how they read the Bible.</p>
<p>But I want to go beyond Webster’s essay in order to read specific biblical passages with Barth and Bonhoeffer. To get into the weeds, as it were, in the hopes of</p>
<ol>
<li>Clarifying the Barth-Bonhoeffer relationship (especially <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/to-be-or-not-to-be-religious-a-clarification-of-karl-barths-and-dietrich-bonhoeffers-divergence-and-convergence-regarding-religion/">the apparent differences in their theological critiques of religion</a>)</li>
<li>Learning how to read the Bible theologically for the benefit of the Church today.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="barth-bonhoeffer-and-the-bible-where-to-begin">Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible: Where to Begin?</h2>
<p>The main challenge of a “Barth, Bonhoeffer, and the Bible” project is limiting its scope.</p>
<p>After all, the quantity of Barth’s biblical material is massive. And, even though Bonhoeffer wrote much less, there’s still a fair amount of biblical material across his corpus!</p>
<h3 id="begin-at-the-beginning-genesis-13">Begin at the Beginning: Genesis 1–3</h3>
<p>Genesis 1–3 is perhaps the best place to begin. Not only is it the beginning of the biblical canon, but both Barth and Bonhoeffer wrote about Genesis 1–3 at length. Furthermore, Bonhoeffer’s interpretation of the <em>imago Dei</em> gets mentioned by Barth in the <em>Church Dogmatics</em>. And the various issues discussed in relationship to Genesis 1–3 are quite central to both theologians’ theological projects.</p>
<p>I have already demonstrated connections between (1) both theologians’ interpretations of Genesis 1–3 and (2) their theological critiques of religion. Furthermore, <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/the-tree-of-religion-karl-barth-and-dietrich-bonhoeffer-on-the-tree-of-knowledge-in-genesis-24-324/">I’ve explored the connections between (1) their interpretations of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil and (2) their similarities and differences when it comes to religion</a>.</p>
<h2 id="other-possibilities">Other Possibilities?</h2>
<p>However, there’s much more beyond Genesis 1–3 to consider!</p>
<h2 id="bonhoeffer-and-the-bible">Bonhoeffer and the Bible</h2>
<p>On the Bonhoeffer side of things, his lengthiest expositions are found in:</p>
<ul>
<li>Creation and Fall (Gen. 1–3)</li>
<li>Discipleship (Matt. 5–7, 10; Various Pauline texts)</li>
<li>Prayerbook of the Bible (Psalms)</li>
</ul>
<p>There are also two very significant texts in which Bonhoeffer discusses his approach to the Bible:</p>
<ul>
<li>“Paper on the Historical and Pneumatological Interpretation of Scripture” (DBWE 9:285ff.)</li>
<li>“Lecture on Contemporizing New Testament Texts” (DBWE 14:413ff.)</li>
</ul>
<p>Bonhoeffer’s numerous sermons and meditations are also worth considering:</p>
<ul>
<li>Address on Jeremiah 27–28—(DBWE vol. )9</li>
<li>Address on John 19—(DBWE vol.)9</li>
<li>Address on Luke 12:35ff.—9</li>
<li>Address on Matthew 21:28–31—9</li>
<li>Address on the Decalogue—9</li>
<li>Address on the First Commandment—9</li>
<li>Baptismal Homily on Joshua 24:15—13</li>
<li>Baptism Sermon on 1 John 4:16—11</li>
<li>Baptism Sermon on Ephesians 5:14—11</li>
<li>Bible Reading and Prayer on 1 Corinthians 4:20—13</li>
<li>Biblical Reflection: Morning—14</li>
<li>Catechesis in the Second Theological Examination on the Fifth Petition of the Lord’s Prayer—10</li>
<li>Catechetical Examination on Matthew 8:5–13—9</li>
<li>Catechetical Outline concerning the Second Article of Faith—9</li>
<li>Children’s Address on Psalm 24:7–9</li>
<li>Communion Homily on 1 Corinthians 15:55—15</li>
<li>Confession Homily on Micah 4:9—15</li>
<li>Confirmation—15</li>
<li>Confirmation Question</li>
<li>Confirmation Sermon on Mark 9:24</li>
<li>Confirmation Verses</li>
<li>Devotional Aids for the Moravian Daily Texts—16</li>
<li>Daily Text Meditation for June 7 and 8, 1944</li>
<li>Daily Text Meditation for Pentecost 1944</li>
<li>Devotions on John 8:31–32—11</li>
<li>Devotions on Luke 4:3–4—11</li>
<li>Devotions on Luke 4:5–8—11</li>
<li>Draft for a Catechism: As You Believe, So You Receive—11</li>
<li>Draft for a Liturgy, Remembrance Sunday—10</li>
<li>Draft for a Liturgy, Reminiscere (Memorial Day)—10</li>
<li>Opening Liturgy</li>
<li>Prayer</li>
<li>Draft for Worship Service on 2 Corinthians 2:14; 6:10; 6:1—15</li>
<li>Exegesis and Catechetical Lesson on Luke 9:57–62—9</li>
<li>Exegesis and Sermon on James 1:21–25—9</li>
<li>Exposition on Romans 9–11 (Student Notes)—14</li>
<li>Exposition on the First Table of the Ten Words of God—16</li>
<li>Fragment of a Wedding Sermon—13</li>
<li>Funeral Address on Luke 2:29–30—13</li>
<li>Funeral Liturgy and Homily on Proverbs 23:26 for Hans-Friedrich von Kleist-Retzow—16</li>
<li>Guide to Scriptural Meditation—14</li>
<li>Homily for the Children’s Service—10</li>
<li>Homily on Daniel 10:1, 8, 16–19—12</li>
<li>Liturgy for a Seminar Worship Service—12</li>
<li>Liturgy Fragment for Christmas—15</li>
<li>Marriage Sermon on Ruth 1:16–17—13</li>
<li>Meditation and Catechetical Lesson on “Honor”—9</li>
<li>Meditation and Sermon on Luke 9:51–56 for the Theological Examination—9</li>
<li>Meditation on Luke 9:57–62—13</li>
<li>Meditation on Psalm 119—15</li>
<li>Bonhoeffer’s Meditation (Fragment)</li>
<li>Two Structural Outlines of Psalm 119</li>
<li>Notes for a Young Man—10</li>
<li>Outline for a Homily for Personal Confession on Proverbs 28:13–14</li>
<li>Outline on Proverbs 3:27–33—14</li>
<li>Recommended Devotions on Jeremiah 16:21 and Ephesians 1:22–23—16</li>
<li>Sermon for Evening Worship Service on 2 Corinthians 12:9—13</li>
<li>Sermon for Evening Worship Service on Proverbs 16:9–13</li>
<li>Sermon for the Lector on Matthew 2:13–23—15</li>
<li>Sermon for the Second Theological Examination on 1 Thessalonians 5:16–18—10</li>
<li>Sermon (Fragment) on Deuteronomy 32:48–52—10</li>
<li>Sermon (Fragment) on Luke 12:49—10</li>
<li>Sermon (Fragment) on Matthew 7:1—10</li>
<li>Sermon (Fragment) on Song of Solomon 8:6b—10</li>
<li>Sermon Meditation on Isaiah 9:6–7—16</li>
<li>Sermon Meditation on Revelation 2:1–7—14</li>
<li>Sermon Meditations—15</li>
<li>Sermon Meditation on John 3:16–21 for the Second Day of Pentecost</li>
<li>Sermon Meditation on John 10:11–16 for Misericordias Domini Sunday</li>
<li>Sermon Meditation on John 14:23–31 for the First Day of Pentecost</li>
<li>Sermon Meditations on John 20:19–31 for Quasimodogeniti Sunday</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 Corinthians 2:7–10—13</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 Corinthians 12:27, 26—10</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 Corinthians 13:1–3—13</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 Corinthians 13:4–7—13</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 Corinthians 13:8–12—13</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 Corinthians 13:13—13</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 Corinthians 15:17—10</li>
<li>Pulpit Notes</li>
<li>Sermon</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 John 2:17—10</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 John 4:16—10, 11</li>
<li>Sermon on 1 Peter 1:7b–9—12</li>
<li>Sermon on 2 Chronicles 20:12—11</li>
<li>Sermon on 2 Corinthians 5:10—13</li>
<li>Sermon on 2 Corinthians 5:20—13</li>
<li>Sermon on 2 Corinthians 12:9—10</li>
<li>Sermon on Colossians 3:1–4—11</li>
<li>Sermon on Genesis 32:25–32; 33:10—11</li>
<li>Sermon on Exodus 32:1–8, 15–16, 18–20, 30–35—12</li>
<li>Sermon on Jeremiah 20:7—13</li>
<li>Sermon on John 8:32—11</li>
<li>Sermon on Judges 6:15–16; 7:2; 8:23—12</li>
<li>Sermon on Luke 1:39–56—14</li>
<li>Sermon on Luke 1:46–55</li>
<li>Sermon on Luke 12:35–40—11</li>
<li>Sermon on Luke 13:1–5—13</li>
<li>Sermon on Luke 16:19–31—11</li>
<li>Sermon on Luke 17:7–10—9</li>
<li>Sermon on Luke 17:33—10</li>
<li>Sermon on Luke 21:28—13</li>
<li>Sermon on Mark 9:23–24—13</li>
<li>Sermon on Matthew 5:8—10</li>
<li>Sermon on Matthew 8:23–27—12</li>
<li>Sermon on Matthew 11:28–30—13</li>
<li>Sermon on Matthew 16:13–18—12</li>
<li>Sermon on Matthew 18:21–35—14</li>
<li>Sermon on Matthew 24:6–14—11</li>
<li>Sermon on Matthew 26:45b–50—14</li>
<li>Sermon on Matthew 28:20—10</li>
<li>Sermon on Philippians 4:7—10</li>
<li>Sermon on Psalm 42—14</li>
<li>Sermon on Psalm 58—14</li>
<li>Sermon on Psalm 62:2—10</li>
<li>Sermon on Psalm 63:3—11</li>
<li>Sermon on Psalm 90—14</li>
<li>Sermon on Psalm 98:1—13</li>
<li>Sermon on Psalm 127:1—9</li>
<li>Sermon on Revelation 2:4–5, 7—12</li>
<li>Sermon on Revelation 3:20—10</li>
<li>Sermon on Revelation 14:6–13—14</li>
<li>Sermon on Romans 5:1–5—15</li>
<li>Sermon on Romans 11:6—10</li>
<li>Sermon on Romans 12:11c—10</li>
<li>Sermon on Romans 12:17–21—15</li>
<li>Sermon on Wisdom 3:3—13</li>
<li>Sermon on Zechariah 3:1–5—14</li>
<li>Supplements to the Monthly Letters from the Confessing Church Council of Brethren in Pomerania to Its Pastors—15</li>
<li>Meditation on Christmas</li>
<li>Meditation on Epiphany</li>
<li>Theological Reflection on the Lord’s Supper</li>
<li>Wedding Sermon from the Prison Cell—8</li>
<li>Wedding Sermon on 1 Thessalonians 5:16–18—14</li>
<li>Wedding Sermon on John 13:34—14</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="barth-and-the-bible">Barth and the Bible</h2>
<p>For Barth, first of all, there’s the entire “Abteilung I. Predigten” of Barth’s <em>Gesamtausgabe</em>.</p>
<h2 id="predigten-1913-ga-i8">Predigten 1913 (GA I.8)</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 und 5 Januar (Neujahr): Prediger 1,9</li>
<li>12 Januar: Matthäus 18,19</li>
<li>19 Januar: Johannes 2,13-17</li>
<li>26 Januar: Johannes 2,23-25</li>
<li>16 Februar: Markus 11,27-33</li>
<li>23 Februar: Johannes 12,36</li>
<li>2 März: Markus 12,13-17</li>
<li>9 März: Markus 13,1-2</li>
<li>16 März: 1 Korinther 11,23-26</li>
<li>21 März (Karfreitag): Hebräer 9,14</li>
<li>21 März (Konfirmation): Epheser 3,14-21</li>
<li>23 März (Ostern): Markus 13,31</li>
<li>13 April: Apostelgeschichte 17,26-28</li>
<li>20 April: Amos 3,3-8</li>
<li>27 April: Amos 3,1-2</li>
<li>1 Mai (Himmelfahrt): Exodus 33,12-23</li>
<li>4 Mai: Amos 5,21-24</li>
<li>11 Mai (Pfingsten): 2 Korinther 3,17</li>
<li>18 Mai: Amos 5,18-20</li>
<li>25 Mai: Amos 5,4</li>
<li>1 Juni: Matthäus 4,18-20 (I)</li>
<li>8 Juni: Matthäus 4,18-20 (II)</li>
<li>15 Juni: Matthäus 4,18-20 (III)</li>
<li>22 Juni: Apostelgeschichte 10,34-39</li>
<li>29 Juni: Apostelgeschichte 10,39-43</li>
<li>6 Juli: Matthäus 14,22-33</li>
<li>13 Juli: Matthäus 18,21-22</li>
<li>20 Juli: Matthäus 19,27-30</li>
<li>27 Juli: Markus 9,2-9</li>
<li>3 August: Matthäus 16,13-17</li>
<li>10 August: Matthäus 16,18-19</li>
<li>17 August: Matthäus 16,21-23</li>
<li>24 August (VIII Aargauischer Abstinententag): 1 Korinther 12,26</li>
<li>31 August: Psalm 95,6-8</li>
<li>7 September: Jesaja 55,8-9</li>
<li>14 September: Psalm 119,18</li>
<li>21 September (Bettag I): Psalm 62,12</li>
<li>21 September (Bettag II): Jeremia 29,7</li>
<li>28 September: Galater 4,16</li>
<li>5 Oktober: Sprüche 23,23</li>
<li>12 Oktober: 1 Korinther 13,6</li>
<li>2 November (Reformation): 2 Korinther 5,16</li>
<li>9 November: Matthäus 10,34</li>
<li>16 November: Jesaja 21,11-12</li>
<li>23 November: 1 Petrus 2,9</li>
<li>30 November (I Advent): Jesaja 65,17-25</li>
<li>7 Dezember (II Advent): Jeremia 31,3</li>
<li>14 Dezember (III Advent): Jesaja 54,7-8</li>
<li>21 Dezember (IV Advent): Jesaja 60,1-2</li>
<li>25 Dezember (Weihnacht): 1 Johannes 4,9</li>
<li>28 Dezember: Hebräer 13,14</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1914-ga-i5">Predigten 1914 (GA I.5)</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 Januar (Neujahr): Psalm 31,15-16</li>
<li>11 Januar: Römer 1,16 (I)</li>
<li>18 Januar: Römer 1,16 (II)</li>
<li>25 Januar: Römer 1,16 (III)</li>
<li>1 Februar: Römer 1,16 (IV)</li>
<li>8 Februar: Römer 1,16 (V)</li>
<li>15 Februar: Römer 1,16 (VI)</li>
<li>22 Februar: Matthäus 26,17-29</li>
<li>1 März: Matthäus 26,30-46</li>
<li>8 März: Matthäus 26,57-75</li>
<li>22 März: Matthäus 27,11-30</li>
<li>29 März: Matthäus 27,27-44</li>
<li>5 April: Matthäus 27,45-50</li>
<li>10 April (Karfreitag): Markus 15,37.39</li>
<li>10 April (Konfirmation): Markus 4,3-9</li>
<li>12 April (Ostern): Markus 16,1-4</li>
<li>19 April: Lukas 24,13-25</li>
<li>26 April: Matthäus 6,33 (I)</li>
<li>3 Mai: Matthäus 6,33 (II)</li>
<li>10 Mai: Matthäus 6,33 (III)</li>
<li>17 Mai: Matthäus 6,33 (IV)</li>
<li>21 Mai (Himmelfahrt): 1 Mose 28,10-19</li>
<li>24 Mai: Johannes 14,15-18</li>
<li>31 Mai (Pfingsten): Hesekiel 36,26-27</li>
<li>7 Juni: Psalm 8,5-10, Matthäus 16,26</li>
<li>7 Juni (Landesausstellung): Psalm 8,6-10, Matthäus 16,26</li>
<li>14 Juni: Psalm 103,2</li>
<li>21 Juni: Matthäus 23,37</li>
<li>28 Juni: 1 Mose 32,23-32</li>
<li>5 Juli: Hebräer 10,31, Psalm 16,11</li>
<li>12 Juli: Psalm 130,1-4</li>
<li>19 Juli: Psalm 130,5-8</li>
<li>26 Juli: Epheser 2,4-6</li>
<li>2 August: Markus 13,7</li>
<li>9 August: Philipper 4,6</li>
<li>16 August: Johannes 15,14-15</li>
<li>23 August: Offenbarung 6,4, Matthäus 10,28</li>
<li>30 August: Jesaja 30,15</li>
<li>6 September: Psalm 102,26-28</li>
<li>13 September: Matthäus 8,23-26</li>
<li>20 September (Bettag): Jeremia 22,29</li>
<li>20 September (Bettag): 2 Mose 14,14</li>
<li>11 Oktober: Markus 10,17-23</li>
<li>18 Oktober: Römer 8,38-39</li>
<li>25 Oktober: Psalm 119,142</li>
<li>1 November: Johannes 17,20-21</li>
<li>8 November: Matthäus 23,8</li>
<li>15 November: 1 Mose 12,1-4</li>
<li>22 November: Hebräer 4,9-10</li>
<li>29 November (I Advent): Jesaja 42,1-4</li>
<li>6 Dezember (II Advent): Jesaja 42,23-43,1</li>
<li>13 Dezember (III Advent): Jesaja 52,7-9</li>
<li>20 Dezember (IV Advent): Jesaja 54,9-10</li>
<li>25 Dezember (Weihnacht): Epheser 1,9</li>
<li>27 Dezember: Matthäus 2,1-12</li>
<li>Grabrede</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1915-ga-i27">Predigten 1915 (GA I.27)</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 und 3 Januar (Neujahr): Offenbarung 1,8</li>
<li>10 Januar: Markus 1,14-15</li>
<li>24 Januar: Matthäus 11,12</li>
<li>31 Januar: Matthäus 17, 14-20</li>
<li>7 Februar: Lukas 17,20-21</li>
<li>14 Februar: Lukas 12, 32, «Gottes Vorhut»</li>
<li>17 und 21 Februar (Friedensbettag): Epheser 2,14</li>
<li>28 Februar: Jesaja 52,13-15</li>
<li>7 März: Jesaja 53,1-3</li>
<li>14 März: Jesaja 53,4-5a</li>
<li>21 März: Jesaja 53,5b-6</li>
<li>28 März: Jesaja 53,7-9</li>
<li>2 April (Karfreitag): Jesaja 53,10-12</li>
<li>2 April (Konfirmation): Johannes 16,27</li>
<li>4 April (Ostern): 1 Korinther 15,25-26</li>
<li>25 April: 2 Petrus 1,19</li>
<li>2 Mai: Römer 8,18-22</li>
<li>9 Mai: Römer 8,24-25</li>
<li>13 Mai (Himmelfahrt): Kolosser 3,1-4</li>
<li>16 Mai: Markus 4,11-12</li>
<li>23 Mai (Pfingsten): Jeremia 31,31-34</li>
<li>30 Mai: Apostelgeschichte 2,5-11</li>
<li>6 Juni: Römer 2,14-16</li>
<li>20 Juni: Galater 3,13</li>
<li>27 Juni: Galater 3,23-25</li>
<li>4 Juli: Lukas 16,19-26</li>
<li>11 Juli: Lukas 13,10-13</li>
<li>18 Juli: Lukas 9,24</li>
<li>25 Juli: 1 Johannes 3,2</li>
<li>1 August (Nationalfeiertag): Matthäus 7,24-27</li>
<li>8 August: 2 Petrus 3,13</li>
<li>15 August: Matthäus 6,25-26</li>
<li>22 August: Apostelgeschichte 4,32-35</li>
<li>29 August: 2 Mose 17,8-15 (I)</li>
<li>5 September: 2 Mose 17,8-15 (II)</li>
<li>12 September: 2 Mose 17,8-15 (III)</li>
<li>19 September (Bettag I): 1 Mose 18,20-32</li>
<li>19 September (Bettag II): Lukas 15,3-7</li>
<li>26 September und 17 Oktober: Psalm 139,23-24</li>
<li>3 Oktober: Jesaja 40,28-31</li>
<li>24 Oktober: Matthäus 9,35-38</li>
<li>31 Oktober: Nehemia 8,1-12</li>
<li>7 November (Reformation): Matthäus 9,14-17</li>
<li>14 November: Psalm 18,29-30</li>
<li>21 November: Philipper 3,20-21</li>
<li>28 November (I Advent): Johannes 3,26-36 (I)</li>
<li>5 Dezember (II Advent): Johannes 3,26-36 (II)</li>
<li>12 Dezember (III Advent): Johannes 3,26-36 (III)</li>
<li>19 Dezember (IV Advent): Johannes 3,26-36 (IV)</li>
<li>25 Dezember (Weihnacht): Lukas 2,14</li>
<li>26 Dezember: Lukas 2,19</li>
<li>Kasualreden</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1916-ga-i29">Predigten 1916 (GA I.29)</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 Januar (Neujahr): Hebräer 13,8</li>
<li>2 Januar: Lukas 2,40</li>
<li>16 Januar: Psalm 14,7</li>
<li>23 Januar: Matthäus 13,44</li>
<li>30 Januar: Matthäus 13,31-32</li>
<li>6 Februar: Hesekiel 13,1-16 «Der Pfarrer, der es den Leuten recht macht»</li>
<li>13 Februar: Römer 14,10-12</li>
<li>20 Februar: Matthäus 10,1-4</li>
<li>27 Februar: Matthäus 10,5-8</li>
<li>5 März: Matthäus 10,12-13</li>
<li>12 März: Matthäus 10,16</li>
<li>13 März: 1 Mose 15,6 «Das Eine Notwendige»</li>
<li>26 März: Matthäus 10,17-20</li>
<li>2 April: Matthäus 10,21-22</li>
<li>16 April: Matthäus 10,24-33</li>
<li>21 April (Karfreitag): Matthäus 10,38</li>
<li>21 April (Konfirmation): Galater 5,13</li>
<li>23 April (Ostern): Lukas 20,38</li>
<li>30 April: 1 Johannes 1,1-4</li>
<li>7 Mai: 1 Johannes 1,5</li>
<li>14 Mai: 1 Johannes 1,6</li>
<li>21 Mai: 1 Johannes 1,7</li>
<li>28 Mai: 1 Johannes 1,8-10</li>
<li>1 Juni (Himmelfahrt): 1 Johannes 2,1-2</li>
<li>4 Juni: 1 Johannes 2,3-6</li>
<li>11 Juni (Pfingsten): Johannes 20,22</li>
<li>18 Juni: 1 Johannes 2,7-11 (I)</li>
<li>25 Juni: 1 Johannes 2,7-11 (II)</li>
<li>2 Juli: 1 Johannes 2,12-14</li>
<li>9 Juli: 1 Johannes 2,15-17</li>
<li>16 Juli: 1 Johannes 2,18-27</li>
<li>23 Juli: 1 Johannes 2,28-29</li>
<li>30 Juli: 1 Johannes 3,1-2</li>
<li>6 August: 1 Johannes 3,3-9</li>
<li>13 August: 1 Johannes 3,10-12</li>
<li>20 August: 1 Johannes 3,14</li>
<li>27 August: 1 Johannes 3,15-18</li>
<li>3 September: 1 Johannes 3,19-20</li>
<li>10 September: 1 Johannes 3,21-24</li>
<li>17 September (Bettag I): Jesaja 6,1-8</li>
<li>17 September (Bettag II): 1 Samuel 3,1-10</li>
<li>15 Oktober: Matthäus 7,7</li>
<li>22 Oktober: Lukas 18,1-8 «Er kann auch anders!»</li>
<li>29 Oktober: Lukas 18,9-14</li>
<li>5 November (Reformation): Lukas 18,15-17</li>
<li>12 November: Richter 5,23</li>
<li>19 November: Jesaja 44,21-23</li>
<li>26 November: Sacharja 8,23</li>
<li>3 Dezember (I Advent): Psalm 24,7-10</li>
<li>10 Dezember (II Advent): Psalm 73,1</li>
<li>24 Dezember (IV Advent): Psalm 37,7</li>
<li>25 Dezember (Weihnacht): Lukas 2,9</li>
<li>31 Dezember (Sylvester): Psalm 25,7</li>
<li>Kasualreden: Trauung von Willy und Elisabeth Spoendlin</li>
<li>Kasualreden: Hochzeit von Karl Guggenheim und Nelly Zollikofer</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1917-ga-i32">Predigten 1917 (GA I.32)</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 und 7 Januar (Neujahr): Psalm 25,14</li>
<li>21 Januar: 1 Mose 1,1-2</li>
<li>28 Januar: 1 Mose 1,3-5</li>
<li>4 Februar: 1 Mose 1,6-25</li>
<li>11 Februar: 1 Mose 1,26-31</li>
<li>18 Februar: Markus 10,32-34 «Über die Grenze»</li>
<li>25 Februar und 11 März: Markus 10,35-45 «Die andere Seite»</li>
<li>4 März: Markus 10,46-52</li>
<li>18 März: Markus 13,33-37</li>
<li>25 März: Markus 14,3-9</li>
<li>1 April: Markus 14,17-25</li>
<li>6 April (Karfreitag): Kolosser 2,14 «Vergebung der Sünden»</li>
<li>6 April (Konfirmation): Lukas 10,23-34</li>
<li>8 April (Ostern): Kolosser 2,15 «Ewiges Leben»</li>
<li>15 April: Johannes 21,15-22</li>
<li>29 April: 2 Petrus 3,12a</li>
<li>6 Mai: Psalm 69,33b</li>
<li>13 Mai: Psalm 65,10b</li>
<li>17 Mai (Himmelfahrt): Micha 2,13</li>
<li>20 Mai: Hebräer 4,14-16</li>
<li>27 Mai (Pfingsten): Lukas 11,9-13</li>
<li>3 Juni und 5 August: Jesaja 59,16</li>
<li>24 Juni: Jeremia 1,1-3</li>
<li>1 Juli: Jeremia 1,4-5</li>
<li>8 Juli: Jeremia 1,6-10 (I)</li>
<li>15 Juli: Jeremia 1,6-10 (II)</li>
<li>22 Juli: Jeremia 1,17-19 (I)</li>
<li>29 Juli: Jeremia 1,17-19 (II)</li>
<li>5 August: Jeremia 1,17-19 (III)</li>
<li>12 August: Psalm 42,2-6 «Wo ist nun dein Gott?»</li>
<li>19 August: Psalm 40,7 «Hören!»</li>
<li>26 August: Römer 12,21</li>
<li>2 September: Lukas 15,11-32</li>
<li>9 September: Lukas 10,30-35</li>
<li>16 September (Bettag I): Klagelieder 3,1-12</li>
<li>16 September (Bettag II): Lukas 14,16-24</li>
<li>23 September: Matthäus 7,13-14</li>
<li>30 September und 7 Oktober: Jeremia 7,14</li>
<li>14 Oktober: Matthäus 11,28</li>
<li>21 Oktober: Psalm 51,8</li>
<li>28 Oktober: Matthäus 7,21-23</li>
<li>4 November (Reformation): Titus 3,3-7</li>
<li>11 November: Matthäus 18,23-24</li>
<li>2 Dezember (I Advent): Jesaja 11,1-2</li>
<li>9 Dezember (II Advent): Jesaja 62,6-7</li>
<li>16 Dezember (III Advent): Lukas 1,5-23</li>
<li>23 Dezember (IV Advent): Lukas 2,1-7</li>
<li>25 Dezember (Weihnacht): Jesaja 42,5-7</li>
<li>30 Dezember: Psalm 77,5</li>
<li>Kasualreden: Taufe von Susanne Spoendlin</li>
<li>Kasualreden: Beerdigung von Arnold Hunziker</li>
<li>Kasualreden: Taufe von Marianne Schuler</li>
<li>Anhang: Vorworte zu «Suchet Gott, so werdet ihr leben!»</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1918-ga-i37">Predigten 1918 (GA I.37)</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 Januar (Neujahr): Psalm 96,1</li>
<li>6 Januar: Lukas 2,41-52</li>
<li>13 Januar: Lukas 3,1-20</li>
<li>27 Januar und 3 Februar: Lukas 3,21-22</li>
<li>10 Februar: Hiob 17,3</li>
<li>17 Februar: 1 Korinther 2,9</li>
<li>24 Februar: Epheser 2,12-13</li>
<li>3 März: Römer 12,1-2 I</li>
<li>10 März: Römer 12,1-2 II</li>
<li>17 März: Römer 12,1-2 III</li>
<li>24 März (Palmsonntag): Lukas 19,29-40</li>
<li>29 März (Karfreitag): Hebräer 5,5-9</li>
<li>29 März (Konfirmation): 1 Samuel 20,23</li>
<li>31 März (Ostern): 1 Korinther 15,19-20 (Entwurf)</li>
<li>31 März (Ostern): 2 Timotheus 1,10</li>
<li>7 April: Lukas 24,36</li>
<li>5 Mai: 5 Mose 30,11-14</li>
<li>9 Mai (Himmelfahrt): Matthäus 28,16-20</li>
<li>12 Mai: Apostelgeschichte 1,14</li>
<li>19 Mai (Pfingsten): Apostelgeschichte 2,1-4</li>
<li>26 Mai: 5 Mose 6,4-5</li>
<li>2 Juni: 3 Mose 19,18b</li>
<li>9 Juni: Sprüche 11,27</li>
<li>16 Juni: Galater 5,1</li>
<li>23 Juni: Psalm 55,23</li>
<li>30 Juni: Lukas 13,20-21</li>
<li>7 Juli: Lukas 13,20-21</li>
<li>14 Juli: Sprüche 4,18</li>
<li>18 August: Psalm 121</li>
<li>25 August: Matthäus 8,1-4</li>
<li>1 September: Matthäus 8,5-13</li>
<li>8 September: Matthäus 8,14-15</li>
<li>15 September (Bettag I): Matthäus 13,24-30.36-43</li>
<li>15 September (Bettag II): Philipper 1,9-10a</li>
<li>29 September: Matthäus 8,18-20</li>
<li>6 Oktober: Matthäus 8,21-22</li>
<li>13 und 20 Oktober: Matthäus 8,23-27</li>
<li>24 November: Matthäus 8,28-34</li>
<li>1 Dezember (I Advent): Johannes 1,1</li>
<li>8 Dezember (II Advent): Johannes 1,1-3</li>
<li>15 Dezember (III Advent): Johannes 1,1-4</li>
<li>22 Dezember (IV Advent): Johannes 1,1-5</li>
<li>25 Dezember (Weihnacht): Lukas 2,25-32</li>
<li>29 Dezember: Offenbarung 1,3</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1919-ga-i39">Predigten 1919 (GA I.39)</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 Januar (Neujahr): Psalm 23</li>
<li>5 Januar: Johannes 14,1</li>
<li>5 Januar: Johannes 14,1</li>
<li>12 Januar: Johannes 14,1-2</li>
<li>19 Januar: Johannes 14,1-3</li>
<li>26 Januar: Matthäus 9,1-8</li>
<li>2 Februar: Matthäus 9,9-13</li>
<li>9 Februar: Matthäus 9,14-15</li>
<li>16 Februar: Matthäus 9,16-17</li>
<li>23 Februar: Matthäus 9,20-22</li>
<li>9 März: Matthäus 9, 18-19.23-26</li>
<li>16 März: Matthäus 9,27-31</li>
<li>23 März: Matthäus 26,47-56</li>
<li>30 März: Matthäus 26,57-68</li>
<li>6 April: Matthäus 26, 58.69-75</li>
<li>13 April: Matthäus 27, 1-2.11-31</li>
<li>18 April (Karfreitag): Lukas 23, 33.39-43</li>
<li>18 April (Konfirmation): 1 Thessalonicher 5,24</li>
<li>20 April (Ostern): Lukas 24,2-3</li>
<li>27 April Lukas 24,36-43</li>
<li>4 Mai: Epheser 1,1-14</li>
<li>11 Mai: Epheser 1,15-23</li>
<li>18 Mai: Epheser 2,1-10</li>
<li>25 Mai: Epheser 2,11-22</li>
<li>29 Mai (Himmelfahrt): Epheser 3,1-13</li>
<li>8 Juni (Pfingsten): Epheser 3,14-21</li>
<li>15 Juni: Epheser 4,1-6</li>
<li>22 Juni: Epheser 4,7-16</li>
<li>29 Juni: Epheser 4,17-24</li>
<li>6 Juli: Epheser 4,25-5,2</li>
<li>13 Juli: Epheser 5,3-14</li>
<li>20 Juli: Epheser 5,15-20</li>
<li>3 August: Epheser 5,21-33</li>
<li>10 August: Epheser 6,1-4</li>
<li>17 August: Epheser 6,5-9</li>
<li>24 August: Epheser 6,10-17</li>
<li>31 August Epheser 6,18-20</li>
<li>7 September: Epheser 6,21-24</li>
<li>14 September: Psalm 103,8-13</li>
<li>5 Oktober: Psalm 84,10-13</li>
<li>12 Oktober: Matthäus 18,1-4</li>
<li>19 Oktober: Matthäus 18,5-9</li>
<li>26 Oktober: Matthäus 18,10-14</li>
<li>2 November: Matthäus 18,15-20</li>
<li>9 November: Matthäus 18, 21-35 I</li>
<li>16 November: Matthäus 18,21-35</li>
<li>23 November: Psalm 139,7-12</li>
<li>30 November (I Advent): Jesaja 48,18</li>
<li>14 Dezember (III Advent): Lukas 3,1-6</li>
<li>21 Dezember (IV Advent): Psalm 118,14-18</li>
<li>25 Dezember (Weihnacht): Psalm 118,19-26</li>
<li>28 Dezember: Matthäus 2,1-12</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1920-ga-i42">Predigten 1920 (GA I.42)</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 Januar (Neujahr): Jeremia 31,31-34</li>
<li>4 Januar: Sprüche 3,26</li>
<li>11 Januar: 2 Korinther 1,1-2</li>
<li>18 Januar: 2 Korinther 1,3-11 I</li>
<li>25 Januar: 2 Korinther 1,3-11 II</li>
<li>1 Februar: 2 Korinther 1,12-22 I</li>
<li>8 Februar: 2 Korinther 1,12-22 II</li>
<li>22 Februar: 2 Korinther 1,23-24, 2,1-4</li>
<li>29 Februar: 2 Korinther 2,5-11 «Ein schmaler Weg»</li>
<li>7 März: 2 Korinther 2,14-17 «Die Freiheit des göttlichen Wortes»</li>
<li>14 März: Johannes 3,1-8</li>
<li>21 März: Markus 10,35-45</li>
<li>28 März (Palmsonntag): Johannes 16,31-33</li>
<li>2 April (Karfreitag): Offenbarung 1,17b-18</li>
<li>2 April (Konfirmation): Philipper 2,12b-13</li>
<li>4 April (Ostern): 1 Korinther 15,50-58</li>
<li>11 April: Lukas 24,36-43</li>
<li>25 April: 2 Korinther 3,1-3</li>
<li>2 Mai: 2 Korinther 3,4-6</li>
<li>9 Mai: 2 Korinther 3,7-11</li>
<li>13 Mai (Himmelfahrt): Kolosser 3,3b</li>
<li>16 Mai: 2 Korinther 3,12-18</li>
<li>23 Mai (Pfingsten): Apostelgeschichte 2,1-13</li>
<li>30 Mai: 2 Korinther 4,1-6</li>
<li>6 Juni: 2 Korinther 4,7-15 «Der Einzelne»</li>
<li>13 Juni: 2 Korinther 4,16-18 «Der innere Mensch»</li>
<li>20 Juni: 2 Korinther 5,1-8 «Getroste Verzweiflung»</li>
<li>27 Juni: 2 Korinther 5,9-11</li>
<li>4 Juli: 2 Korinther 5,12-15</li>
<li>11 Juli: 2 Korinther 5,16-17</li>
<li>18 Juli: 2 Korinther 5,18-21</li>
<li>25 Juli: 2 Korinther 6,1-2 «Siehe jetzt!»</li>
<li>1 August: 2 Korinther 6,3-10</li>
<li>15 August: 2 Korinther 6,11-13; 7,2-4</li>
<li>12 September: 2 Korinther 7,5-16</li>
<li>19 September (Bettag I): Matthäus 11,28 «Die Buße»</li>
<li>19 September (Bettag II): Apostelgeschichte 16,30-31</li>
<li>26 September: Psalm 65,2</li>
<li>3 Oktober: Psalm 119,19</li>
<li>10 Oktober: Sprüche 1,7</li>
<li>17 Oktober: Sprüche 16,2</li>
<li>31 Oktober: Psalm 91,1-2</li>
<li>7 November (Reformation): Römer 5,8</li>
<li>21 November: Psalm 145,17</li>
<li>5 Dezember (II Advent): Lukas 12,49 «Feuer auf Erden!»</li>
<li>19 Dezember (IV Advent): Lukas 12,35-36</li>
<li>25 Dezember (Weihnacht I): Lukas 2,25-32</li>
<li>26 Dezember (Weihnacht II): Lukas 2,33-35</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1921-ga-i44">Predigten 1921 (GA I.44)</h2>
<ul>
<li>1 Januar (Neujahr): Offenbarung 21,1-7</li>
<li>9 Januar: Matthäus 20,1-16</li>
<li>23 Januar: Matthäus 21,12-17</li>
<li>23 Januar: Matthäus 21,12-17</li>
<li>30 Januar: Matthäus 21,23-27</li>
<li>6 Februar: Matthäus 21,28-31</li>
<li>20 Februar: Matthäus 22,15-22</li>
<li>27 Februar: Sprüche 16,2 «Das grosse ‹Aberï›»</li>
<li>6 März: Matthäus 22,23-33</li>
<li>13 März: Matthäus 24,1-14</li>
<li>20 März: Matthäus 24,29-31</li>
<li>25 März (Karfreitag): Offenbarung 7,9-17</li>
<li>25 März: (Konfirmation): 1 Johannes 2,12</li>
<li>27 März (Ostern): Romer 8,11</li>
<li>3 April: 1 Petrus 3,19-20</li>
<li>10 April: Psalm 104,2<a href="#">a</a></li>
<li>17 April: 1 Korinther 13,12<a href="#">b</a></li>
<li>24 April: 1 Korinther 13,8</li>
<li>1 Mai: 1 Korinther 13,1-3</li>
<li>5 Mai (Himmelfahrt): Aposfelgeschichte 1,9</li>
<li>15 Mai (Pfingsten): Apostelgeschichte 2,1-11</li>
<li>26 Juni: Matthäus 6,34</li>
<li>10 Juli: Matthäus 18,3</li>
<li>24 Juli: Matthäus 12,46-50</li>
<li>31 Juli: Markus 14,38</li>
<li>14 August: Lukas 10,38-42</li>
<li>21 August: Lukas 6,20-26</li>
<li>18 September (Bettag): Lukas 6,27-36</li>
<li>25 September: Matthäus 19,16-30</li>
<li>2 Oktober: Lukas 15,1-10</li>
<li>9 Oktober (Abschiedspredigt): 1 Petrus 1,24-25</li>
<li>Kasualrede</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1921-1935-ga-i31">Predigten 1921-1935 (GA I.31)</h2>
<ul>
<li>Jakobus 5,7-8 (1921)</li>
<li>Das ewige Licht, Jesaja 60,19-20 (1922)</li>
<li>Psalm 100 (1922)</li>
<li>Der Name des Herrn, Sprüche 18,10 (1922)</li>
<li>Der kleine Augenblick, Jesaja 54,7-10 (1923)</li>
<li>Genesis 17,1-3 (Traurede Ehepaar Siebeck, 1923)</li>
<li>Suchet was droben ist!, Kolosser 3,1-2 (1923)</li>
<li>Matthäus 18,21-35 (1923)</li>
<li>Barmherzigkeit, Lukas 1,78-79 (1923)</li>
<li>Psalm 50,15 (1924)</li>
<li>Psalm 36,10 (1924)</li>
<li>Markus 9,33-35 (1924)</li>
<li>Psalm 103,1-5 (1924)</li>
<li>Psalm 103,1 (1924)</li>
<li>Lukas 18,31-43 (1925)</li>
<li>Psalm 4,9 (1925)</li>
<li>Jakobus 1, 22-25 (Morgenandacht, 1925)</li>
<li>Der große Friede, Psalm 119,165 (1925)</li>
<li>Psalm 37,5 (1925)</li>
<li>Ich bin der Herr, Psalm 37,5 (1926)</li>
<li>Gottes Liebe, Jeremia 31,3 (1927)</li>
<li>1 Könige 17,8-16 (Abendandacht, 1927)</li>
<li>Lukas 5,1-11 (1927)</li>
<li>Gib dich zufrieden!, Matthäus 7,7-8 (Abendandacht, 1928)</li>
<li>Der Anfang von oben, Hebräer 4,14-16 (1928)</li>
<li>Vom rechten Beten, Psalm 80,20 (1929)</li>
<li>Eine reformierte Traurede, Hebräer 13,11-12 (Ehepaar Bockemühl, 1929)</li>
<li>Maria, Lukas 1,26-38 (1929)</li>
<li>Matthäus 6,11 (Traurede Ehepaar Scholz, 1930)</li>
<li>Es werden Zeichen geschehen, Lukas 21,25-36 (1930)</li>
<li>Der arme Lazarus, Lukas 16,19-31 (1931)</li>
<li>Der Arbeiter im Weinberge, Matthäus 19,27-20,16 (1932)</li>
<li>Das Evangelium von dem Reich, Matthäus 9,35-36 (1932)</li>
<li>Von Freude und Lindigkeit, Philipper 4,4-5 (1932)</li>
<li>Lukas 6,36-42 (1933)</li>
<li>Römer 15,5-13 (1933)</li>
<li>Johannes 10,11-13 (1934)</li>
<li>Johannes 10,14-16 (1934)</li>
<li>Lukas 5,1-11 (1934)</li>
<li>Kirche gestern, heute, morgen, 1 Samuel 12,15/Matthäus 26,41 (1934)</li>
<li>Matthäus 14,22-33 (1934)</li>
<li>Jeremia 17,5-10 (1934)</li>
<li>2 Petrus 1,3-11 (1934)</li>
<li>Psalm 16,1 (Abendandacht, 1935)</li>
<li>Johannes 2,1-11 (1935)</li>
<li>Römer 12,17-18 (1935)</li>
<li>Matthäus 8,23-27 (1935)</li>
<li>Psalm 119,67/Jakobus 4,6 (1935)</li>
<li>Exodus 20,4-6 (1935)</li>
<li>Vom christlichen Leben, Römer 12,1-2 (1926)</li>
<li>Öffne mir die Augen, daß ich sehe die Wunder an deinem Gesetz!, Psalm 119,18 (1926)</li>
<li>Vier Bibelstunden über Lukas 1 (1934)</li>
<li>Was ist Ostern? (1926)</li>
<li>Vom heiligen Geist (1926)</li>
<li>Die Fleischwerdung des Wortes (1926)</li>
<li>Auferstehung (1927)</li>
<li>Aufgefahren gen Himmel (1927)</li>
<li>Das Wunder der Weihnacht (1927)</li>
<li>Die Tat der Versöhnung (1928)</li>
<li>Vom Hören der Weihnachtsbotschaft (1928)</li>
<li>Fürchtet euch nicht! (1929)</li>
<li>Die Wirklichkeit der Versöhnung (1930)</li>
<li>Verheißung, Zeit – Erfüllung (1930)</li>
<li>Andachten für die Passions- und Osterzeit (1931)</li>
<li>… gib der Welt ein’ neuen Schein (1931)</li>
<li>Von der Sorge und von Gott (1932)</li>
<li>Verborgenheit (1933)</li>
<li>Offenbarung (1933)</li>
<li>Vorwort zu: Komm Schöpfer Geist (1924)</li>
<li>Vorwort zu: Weihnacht (1934/1957)</li>
<li>Vorwort zu: Die große Barmherzigkeit (1935)</li>
<li>Nachweis früherer Veröffentlichungen des Inhalts dieses Bandes</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1935-1952-ga-i26">Predigten 1935-1952 (GA I.26)</h2>
<ul>
<li>Matthäus 6,24-34 (1935)</li>
<li>Matthäus 21,1-11 (1935)</li>
<li>Psalm 100,4-5 (Morgenandacht, 1936)</li>
<li>Hebräer 12,1-2 (1936)</li>
<li>Apostelgeschichte 3,1-10 (1936)</li>
<li>Johannes 14,1 (1936)</li>
<li>Johannes 20,19-31 (1937)</li>
<li>Kolosser 3,1-4 (1937)</li>
<li>Johannes 2,23-3,21 (1937)</li>
<li>Johannes 17,24 (1937)</li>
<li>Psalm 3 (1937)</li>
<li>Matthäus 22,15-22 (1937)</li>
<li>Matthäus 11,2-6 (1937)</li>
<li>Johannes 9,13 (1938)</li>
<li>Johannes 9,4-5 (1938)</li>
<li>Johannes 9,6-7 (1938)</li>
<li>Markus 7,31-35 (1938)</li>
<li>Galater 6,7-8 (1938)</li>
<li>Matthäus 11,28-30 (1939)</li>
<li>Sacharja 4,6-7 (1939)</li>
<li>Der Grund unseres Bauens, 1 Korinther 3,11 (1939)</li>
<li>Epheser 3,14-21 (1939)</li>
<li>Matthäus 21,1-17 (1940)</li>
<li>Johannes 16,5-7 (1940)</li>
<li>Psalm 46,2-4.8 (1940)</li>
<li>1 Korinther 1,4-9 (1940)</li>
<li>Psalm 46,5-8 (1940)</li>
<li>1 Korinther 13,12 (Bestattung von Matthias Barth, 1941)</li>
<li>Matthäus 5,6-7 (1941)</li>
<li>Markus 14,32-42 (1941)</li>
<li>Hebräer 12,1-11 (1941)</li>
<li>Epheser 1,8 (1942)</li>
<li>Sprüche 30,1-6 (1943)</li>
<li>2 Timotheus 2,8 (1943)</li>
<li>Psalm 103,1-4 (1943)</li>
<li>Epheser 4,21b-32 (1943)</li>
<li>Klagelieder 3,21-23 (1944)</li>
<li>Lukas 17,5-6 (1945)</li>
<li>Johannes 8,31-32 (1946)</li>
<li>Psalm 138,3 (1946)</li>
<li>Sprüche 10,28 (1946)</li>
<li>1 Johannes 2,17 (1946)</li>
<li>Johannes 11,25 (Trauung Ehepaar Smith, 1947)</li>
<li>Psalm 55,23 (1947, erste Fassung)</li>
<li>Psalm 55,23 (1947, zweite Fassung)</li>
<li>Psalm 85,10 (1947)</li>
<li>Psalm 39,8 (Rundfunkandacht, 1947)</li>
<li>1 Johannes 5,4 (1947)</li>
<li>Matthäus 5,5 (1948)</li>
<li>Psalm 139,16 (1948)</li>
<li>Johannes 16,33 (1952)</li>
<li>Erwägungen zum Christfest (1935)</li>
<li>Streit in der Kirche (1937)</li>
<li>Die letzte Frage und Antwort (1938)</li>
<li>Dieses und das zukünftige Leben (1940)</li>
<li>Euch ist heute der Heiland geboren (1941)</li>
<li>Bettag (1942)</li>
<li>Wiederherstellung (1945)</li>
<li>Frohe Botschaft (1946)</li>
<li>Jesus Christus ist auferstanden (1947)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="predigten-1954-1967-ga-i12">Predigten 1954-1967 (GA I.12)</h2>
<ul>
<li>Dennoch bleibe ich stets bei dir, Psalm 73,23 (1954)</li>
<li>Euch ist heute der Heiland geboren, Lukas 2,10-11 (1954)</li>
<li>Ich lebe, und ihr werdet leben, Johannes 14,19 (1955)</li>
<li>Bestattung von Paul Basilius Barth, Johannes 21,18 (1955)</li>
<li>Durch Gnade seid ihr gerettet, Epheser 2,5 (1955)</li>
<li>Blicket auf zu Ihm!, Psalm 34,6 (1956)</li>
<li>Ich hoffe auf dich, Psalm 39,8 (1956)</li>
<li>Mitten unter euch – euer Gott – mein Volk!, 3 Mose 26,12 (1956)</li>
<li>Das Evangelium Gottes, Markus 1,14-15 (1956)</li>
<li>Die Übeltäter mit ihm, Lukas 23,33 (1957)</li>
<li>Alle!, Römer 11,32 (1957)</li>
<li>Gottes gute Kreatur, 1 Timotheus 4,4-5 (1957)</li>
<li>Der große Dispens, Philipper 4,4-5 (1957)</li>
<li>Er ist’s, 5 Mose 8,18 (1957)</li>
<li>Lehre uns bedenken …, Psalm 90,12 (1958)</li>
<li>Die Furcht des Herrn ist der Anfang der Weisheit, Psalm 111,10 (1958)</li>
<li>Der es mit uns hält, Lukas 2,7 (1958)</li>
<li>Tod – aber Leben!, Römer 6,23 (1959)</li>
<li>Gelobt sei der Herr!, Psalm 68,20 (1959)</li>
<li>Der Herr, dein Erbarmer, Jesaja 54,10 (1959)</li>
<li>Du darfst!, Jeremia 31,33 (1960)</li>
<li>Rufe mich an, Psalm 50,15 (1960)</li>
<li>Meine Zeit steht in deinen Händen, Psalm 31,16 (1960)</li>
<li>Der kleine Augenblick, Jesaja 54,7-8 (1961)</li>
<li>Bekehrung, 1 Johannes 4,18 (1961)</li>
<li>Was bleibt, Jesaja 40,8 (1961)</li>
<li>Doppelte Adventsbotschaft, Lukas 1,53 (1962)</li>
<li>Was genügt, 2 Korinther 12,9 (1962)</li>
<li>Vor dem Richterstuhl Christi, 2 Korinther 5,10 (1963)</li>
<li>Traget!, Galater 6,2 (1963)</li>
<li>Aber seid getrost!, Johannes 16,33 (1963)</li>
<li>Als sie den Herrn sahen, Johannes 20,19-20 (1964)</li>
<li>Wo der Geist des Herrn ist, da ist Freiheit (1957)</li>
<li>Das große Ja (1959)</li>
<li>Wo ist Jesus Christus? (1961)</li>
<li>Ein Wort zum Neuen Jahr (1962)</li>
<li>Gottes Geburt (1962)</li>
<li>Das Geheiminis des Ostertages (1967)</li>
<li>Vorwort zu: Den Gefangenen Befreiung</li>
<li>Vorwort zu: Gebete</li>
<li>Anhang 1: Bekehrung, 1 Johannes 4,18 (Wiedergabe der Predigt im gesprochenen Wortlaut)</li>
<li>Anhang 2: Aber seid getrost!, Johannes 16,33 (Wiedergabe der Predigt im gesprochenen Wortlaut)</li>
<li>Anhang 3: Martin Schwarz: Nachbemerkungen</li>
</ul>
<p>Then, from Barth’s Akademische Werke (Abteilung II of the GA):</p>
<ul>
<li>Das christliche Leben 1959-1961 (GA II.7)</li>
<li>Der Römerbrief 1919 (GA II.16)</li>
<li>Der Römerbrief (Zweite Fassung) 1922 (GA II.47)</li>
<li>Erklärungen des Epheser- und des Jakobusbriefes. 1919–1929 (GA II.46)</li>
<li>Erklärung des Johannesevangeliums 1925/1926 (GA II.9)</li>
</ul>
<p>From Barth’s Vorträge und kleinere Arbeiten (Abteilung III):</p>
<ul>
<li>Die ursprüngliche Gestalt des Unser Vaters, 1906 (GA III.21)</li>
<li>Die Missionsthätigkeit des Paulus nach der Darstellung der Apostelgeschichte, 1907 (GA III.21)</li>
<li>Das Wort Gottes als Aufgabe der Theologie, 1922 (GA III.19)</li>
<li>Menschenwort und Gotteswort in der christlichen Predigt, 1924 (GA III.19)</li>
<li>Das Schriftprinzip der reformierten Kirche, 1925 (GA III.19)</li>
</ul>
<p>And, of course, this is to say nothing of the copious amounts of biblical material found throughout the <em>Church Dogmatics</em>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Only the Suffering God Can Help</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/only-the-suffering-god-can-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/only-the-suffering-god-can-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/img_0297.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/img_0297.jpg"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn more about Rublev&#39;s Trinity icon [video]</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/learn-more-about-rublevs-trinity-icon-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/learn-more-about-rublevs-trinity-icon-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to learn more about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trinity_(Andrei_Rublev)&#34;&gt;Andrei Rublev’s famous icon of the Trinity&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re also curious, check out this video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-embed__wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;563&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1hEBSu4Xh1w?feature=oembed&#34; title=&#34;The icon of Trinity-Andrei Roublev Episode 1&#34; width=&#34;750&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve always wanted to learn more about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trinity_(Andrei_Rublev)">Andrei Rublev’s famous icon of the Trinity</a>. If you’re also curious, check out this video.</p>
<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="563" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1hEBSu4Xh1w?feature=oembed" title="The icon of Trinity-Andrei Roublev Episode 1" width="750"></iframe></div></figure>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
