<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>sermons on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/sermons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sermons on The Rev. Dev. Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 15:42:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/category/sermons/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Preparing the Way of the Lord in the Wilderness: Luke 3:1-6</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/preparing-the-way-of-the-lord-in-the-wilderness-luke-31-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 15:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/preparing-the-way-of-the-lord-in-the-wilderness-luke-31-6/</guid>
      <description>I’d like to pray this week’s collect again:
Merciful God, who sent your messengers the prophets to preach repentance and prepare the way for our salvation: Give us grace to heed their warnings and forsake our sins, that we may greet with joy the coming of Jesus Christ our Redeemer; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen.
Introduction It’s been a particularly difficult week here at Church of the Savior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take Up Your Tongue and Follow Jesus</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/take-up-your-tongue-and-follow-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/take-up-your-tongue-and-follow-jesus/</guid>
      <description>This sermon, on Mark 8:27-38 and James 3:1-12, was originally preached on September 16, 2018 at Christ Redeemer Anglican Church in Milwaukee, WI.
Introduction Would you pray with me?
O God, because without you we are not able to please you—especially in what we say!—mercifully grant that your Holy Spirit may in all things direct and rule our hearts, so that the words of our mouths and the meditations of our hearts might be acceptable in your sight, O Lord, our strength and our redeemer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It is Finished! So, Get to Work! - A Sermon on the Ascension</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20170613it-is-finished-so-get-to-work-an-ascension-sermon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 01:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20170613it-is-finished-so-get-to-work-an-ascension-sermon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following is an &amp;ldquo;It is Finished&amp;rdquo; sermon preached on Ascension Sunday, 2017. You can listen to the sermon here:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goodbyes-suck&#34;&gt;GOODBYES SUCK&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, if there’s one thing I hate, it’s goodbyes. Anyone else here hate goodbyes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and the fact that I hate them so much means I’m not really very good at goodbyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I get awkward and silent. Sometimes I get awkward and really chatty! Heck, sometimes I get awkward and I make poor choices, like the one time when I was getting ready to say goodbye to my family when they dropped me off at college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were looking forward to a final dinner with me, in the school cafeteria, before they left. But I was worried about the awkwardness of saying a tearful goodbye between packed tables and chairs, so I suggested that they just leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s just say that my family wasn’t very happy. And me? Neither was I. I ate my first college meal all alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodbyes suck. And I often suck at goodbyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I telling you this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, for one thing, this is my “goodbye” sermon here at St. Peter’s, and I wanted to give an excuse for this sermon, if it sucks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all seriousness, I do want to thank this congregation for being such a good place for Rachel and me to serve and grow alongside you. Thank you for loving Rachel and me as our brothers and sisters in Christ. We will miss you all very much as we move to Illinois this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I don’t want this goodbye to get TOO awkward, so I’d better keep on preaching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think that goodbyes are bad because they so often leave our stories unfinished.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we humans tend to hate unfinished business. It’s so much better when the story has an end! Sometimes, even a bad ending is better than no ending at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it, if you’re watching an important game on TV – say, Alabama vs. Auburn – would you rather see the ending, even if your team loses, or have the power go out and completely miss the final minutes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stories without endings are frustrating. And that’s why it’s so hard to say goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why Death – the ultimate goodbye, if you will – is so horrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not really an ending, not for those of us who go on living, anyways. Instead, Death leaves our stories hanging, with words left unsaid and promises left unfulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think here of parents in Manchester this week who were forced to say goodbye to their children all too soon, thanks to the suicide bombing. Or the Coptic Christians in Egypt forced to say goodbye to their loved ones too soon, thanks to the bus attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodbyes suck, because they leave our stories unfinished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note: For other sermons, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/sermons/&#34;&gt;my Sermons page&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-the-ascension-does-it-suck&#34;&gt;WHAT ABOUT THE ASCENSION? DOES IT SUCK?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the Ascension of Jesus Christ, then, just another awful goodbye?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lasting Supper - Luke 22:14-30</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 19:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is something special about last meals, isn’t there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to show you a series of photographs. These photographs, except for the last one – which I added, are from &lt;a href=&#34;http://henryhargreaves.com/no-seconds&#34;&gt;a piece called “No Seconds,” and they were put together by Henry Hargreaves&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to belabor the artwork with my commentary, so I’ll give you a few seconds to take each slide in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{ double-space-with-newline }} {{ double-space-with-newline }}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{ double-space-with-newline }} {{ double-space-with-newline }}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t know about you, but those pictures affect me deeply. The whole idea of a criminal’s last meal affects me deeply. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it’s because these last meals combine the familiar with the unfamiliar. They combine the expected and the unexpected. I mean, on one hand, you’ve got comfort food. On the other hand, heinous crimes. The stuff of life right next to life’s untimely end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Jesus of Nazareth was no common criminal, his so-called “Last Supper” with his disciples was a poignant combination of the expected and the unexpected. And when you take a look at the Last Supper, focusing on its unexpected elements, you find out that it’s really a Lasting Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, the Last Supper is not just a one-time event, some two-thousand years ago. Instead, Holy Communion, the Lasting Supper, is an ongoing meal, with profound implications for our past, our future, and our present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-meal&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Meal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let’s look at the original meal itself, the “Last Supper,” as described in our Gospel lesson (Luke 22:14-20).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ahead in God&#39;s Upside-Down Kingdom: An Appeal for a Consistently Pro-Life Ethic</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-ahead-in-gods-upside-down-kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 16:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-ahead-in-gods-upside-down-kingdom/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. [ MP3: Getting Ahead in God&amp;rsquo;s Upside-Down Kingdom]
[ PDF Sermon Manuscript: Getting Ahead in God&amp;rsquo;s Upside-Down Kingdom]
Opening Prayer God, our Refuge, I ask that your Holy Spirit would move in our lives, so that we would:
promote your justice embody your steadfast faithful love and humbly obey Your will, even if it costs us our reputations, and even if it costs us our lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Disappointing Christmas Homily</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-christmas-homily/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 14:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-christmas-homily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good morning! And Merry Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, let us pray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you make us glad by the yearly festival of the birth of your only Son Jesus Christ: Grant that we, who joyfully receive him as our Redeemer, may with sure confidence behold him when he comes to be our Judge; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, who wonderfully created us in your own image and yet more wonderfully restored us through your Son Jesus Christ: grant that, as he came to share our humanity, so we may share the life of his divinity; who is alive and reigns with you, in the unity of the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, they say that Christmas is the most wonderful time of the year. I’ve even heard it said that it’s the “hap-happiest season of all”!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, can I take a poll real quick?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please raise your hand if you’ve ever had a disappointing Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean a Christmas that didn’t live up to your expectations. You wanted it to be filled with love, happiness, and peace, and instead all you got was stress, anxiety, and loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;have-you-ever-had-a-disappointing-christmas&#34;&gt;Have you ever had a disappointing Christmas?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following Jesus Beyond the Bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-jesus-beyond-the-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 22:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-jesus-beyond-the-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(A chapel message in a Christian school.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things you should know about me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a student at a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; seminary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before that, I went to a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; college.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before that, I went to a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; high school, and a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; middle school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before that, I was home-schooled, and I grew up in a &lt;em&gt;Christian&lt;/em&gt; home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, also: I’m &lt;strong&gt;the world’s worst sports fan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m serious. The students in my youth group give me a hard time about it. Every week, they’re like, “Josh, did you see the game?!” “Josh, are you going to watch the game?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I’m like, “Game? What game? I don’t even know which sport’s season it is!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World’s. worst. sports fan. I’m telling you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one redeeming quality about my sports fandom is that I’ve stuck with one team through thick and thin: the University of Michigan Wolverines. Go Blue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know that the rivalry between the Wolverines and the Ohio State Buckeyes is but a pale imitation of the rivalry between Alabama and Auburn down here. But up North, this rivalry was and is a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it was really interesting, back when I was in middle school and high school, to observe what would happen each year in November when the Wolverines and the Buckeyes went at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m from Toledo, OH, which is on the border with Michigan, so the fan split was about 50/50 – Wolverines on one side, Buckeyes on the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And each year, on the day after the big game, you could tell who the true fans were…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the people still cheering for the team that &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Feast of St. James the Apostle: A Homily for Ministers</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-feast-of-st-james-the-apostle-a-homily-for-ministers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 22:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-feast-of-st-james-the-apostle-a-homily-for-ministers/</guid>
      <description>Readings: Psalm 34; Jeremiah 16:14-21; Mark 1:14-20
Like so many other feast days – scheduled, as they are, on the days of the namesakes’ deaths – the feast day of St. James the Apostle is a strong rebuke to our aspirations. To our aspirations as human beings, and especially to our aspirations as ministers of Christ’s Church.
James &amp;amp; John: Fishermen No More? You see, James started off as a mere fisherman.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Groom&#39;s Big Day</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grooms-big-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 20:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grooms-big-day/</guid>
      <description>[soundcloud url=&amp;ldquo;https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/256270902&amp;quot; params=&amp;ldquo;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;100%&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;166&amp;rdquo; iframe=&amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; /]
READINGS Ephesians 5:21-33 – Wives and Husbands Psalm 67 – May God Be Gracious to Us and Bless Us Revelation 19:6-10 – The Marriage Supper of the Lamb Matthew 25:1-13 – The Parable of the Ten Virgins HOMILY What makes a great wedding?
Is it the fragrance and color of the flower arrangements? The particular grandeur of the venue?
Is it the number and camaraderie of the guests?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Son of Man, Can Your Bones Live?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/son-of-man-can-your-bones-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 22:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/son-of-man-can-your-bones-live/</guid>
      <description>What would it have been like, on the first Holy Saturday? What would it be like, tonight, if Jesus has been dead for almost 33 hours?
All the hopes and dreams of tonight’s readings – shattered. Blown away by the cold winds of death. Jesus of Nazareth lies in a dark grave, and we, his shell-shocked followers, gather to make some sort of sense of this week’s events – to salvage some sort of hope from this week’s wreckage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Recent Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/three-recent-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 20:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/three-recent-sermons/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a grueling past few weeks at Beeson. Our Spring Break happens to coincide with Holy Week this year, and it can&amp;rsquo;t come quickly enough!
Part of the hard work has been preparing to preach three sermons for class. However, the opportunity to study and preach God&amp;rsquo;s Word is a joy that outweighs the burdens of preparation!
I have preached twice in the past month on Psalm 32. First, I delivered a sermon (&amp;ldquo;The Refreshment of Forgiveness&amp;rdquo;) designed for the Fourth Sunday in Lent, Year C, for Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sermon: The Challenge of Christmas Light</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sermon-the-challenge-of-christmas-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 20:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sermon-the-challenge-of-christmas-light/</guid>
      <description>There are better preachers out there. So, if you&amp;rsquo;re short on time, go and listen to them! However, if you&amp;rsquo;ve got 26 minutes to spare, I offer &amp;ldquo;The Challenge of Christmas Light&amp;rdquo; to you, and would love to hear your feedback.
I preached this sermon on December 27, 2015 at St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Anglican Church in Mountain Brook, AL, as we celebrated the Feast of St. John the Apostle and Evangelist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faithful Faith in a Faithful God: Romans 1.1-17</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/faithful-faith-in-a-faithful-god-romans-1-1-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 08:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/faithful-faith-in-a-faithful-god-romans-1-1-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[embed]https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=invos5n6zts[/embed]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-introduction-the-prodigal-son-part-2&#34;&gt;I. Introduction: The Prodigal Son, Part 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a relief, to get out of that house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordinarily, Jude would have scoffed at his father’s request to purchase farming equipment from the next city – a three-day journey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But ever since Ethan, that rascal (you might even say that &lt;em&gt;prodigal&lt;/em&gt;) brother of his, had returned, Jude could not stand to be in either man’s presence for long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So he relished the chance to forget about his family tension on this farming errand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now he was almost home, and the painful thoughts came rushing back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dad has &lt;em&gt;changed&lt;/em&gt;. Perhaps it was early-onset dementia that caused him to forget the blessed closeness of our years together, alone, when I was not just the firstborn, but the only son. Sure, I had never been perfect, but I thought that my father was finally proud of me. That, after years of hard lessons learned, I had become the man he wanted me to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then Ethan threw it all away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Prodigal Son, Part 2: Introduction to Romans</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-prodigal-son-part-2-introduction-to-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 01:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-prodigal-son-part-2-introduction-to-romans/</guid>
      <description>What a relief, to get out of that house.
Ordinarily, Jude would have scoffed at his father’s request to purchase farming equipment from the next city – a three-day journey! But ever since Ethan, that rascal (you might even say that prodigal) brother of his, had returned, Jude could not stand to be in either man’s presence for long.
So he relished the chance to forget about his family tension on this farming errand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: Mark 8.11-21</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-8-11-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-8-11-21/</guid>
      <description>A homily on Mark 8:11-21 (ESV):
The Pharisees came and began to argue with him, seeking from him a sign from heaven to test him.And he sighed deeply in his spirit and said, “Why does this generation seek a sign? Truly, I say to you, no sign will be given to this generation.”And he left them, got into the boat again, and went to the other side.Now they had forgotten to bring bread, and they had only one loaf with them in the boat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: Mark 1.29-45</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-1-29-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 22:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-1-29-45/</guid>
      <description>A homily on Mark 1:29-45 (ESV):
And immediately he left the synagogue and entered the house of Simon and Andrew, with James and John.Now Simon&amp;rsquo;s mother-in-law lay ill with a fever, and immediately they told him about her.And he came and took her by the hand and lifted her up, and the fever left her, and she began to serve them.That evening at sundown they brought to him all who were sick or oppressed by demons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: James 2.1-13</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-james-2-1-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 21:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-james-2-1-13/</guid>
      <description>A homily on James 2.1-13 (ESV):
&amp;ldquo;My brothers, show no partiality as you hold the faith in our Lord Jesus Christ,the Lord of glory.For if a man wearing a gold ring and fine clothing comes into your assembly, and a poor man in shabby clothing also comes in,and if you pay attention to the one who wears the fine clothing and say, “You sit here in a good place,” while you say to the poor man, “You stand over there,” or, “Sit down at my feet,”have you not then made distinctions among yourselves and become judges with evil thoughts?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus is Not Just &amp;quot;One of Us&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/jesus-is-not-just-one-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 21:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/jesus-is-not-just-one-of-us/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: The audio of the following sermon, preached on July 05, 2015 at St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Anglican Church in Mountain Brook, Alabama, can be found here. (I began with a bit of a mic issue. Ignore the garbled first 10 seconds or so!)
---
Introduction The &amp;ldquo;hometown,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;home court&amp;rdquo; advantage is a very real occurrence in many areas of life. Familiar fans and supportive surroundings help us humans to perform better at many tasks, from singing to sports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hope of the Holy Innocents</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-hope-of-the-holy-innocents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-hope-of-the-holy-innocents/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the audio element. (PDF: The Hope of the Holy Innocents)
Today is December 28 (2014) – just the third day since Christmas – a commemoration of what is often called “ The Slaughter of the Innocents,” the killing of the baby boys of Bethlehem by King Herod.
The Church’s regard for this day as a feast day is quite early, going back to at least the fifth century.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Sermon: Our Help</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-sermon-our-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 14:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-sermon-our-help/</guid>
      <description>Hey internet: I was recently given the chance to preach at my church, St. Peter&amp;rsquo;s Anglican, on the Second Sunday of Lent. The sermon audio is now online. If you&amp;rsquo;ve got 23 minutes to spare, give it a listen!
First, here are the passages:
Psalm 121 Genesis 12:1-4 Romans 4:1-5, 13-17 John 3:1-17 Then, make sure to ignore my two seconds of speech from 16:35-16:37 in the audio, I departed from my notes &amp;ndash; which ended at &amp;ldquo;Nicodemus then fades from the narrative,&amp;rdquo; (which he does in the passage at hand) &amp;ndash; and said that Nicodemus apparently never gets it and never shows up again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Un)Righteous Anger? - Yoda, Jonah, Nahum, and Us</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unrighteous-anger-yoda-jonah-nahum-and-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 21:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unrighteous-anger-yoda-jonah-nahum-and-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(TEXTS: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Jonah%203:5-10;%204:1-11;%20Nahum%201:1-8&amp;amp;version=NET&#34;&gt;Jonah 3:5-10; 4:1-11; Nahum 1:1-8&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/fear-leaeds-to-anger-yoda-quote-from-star-wars.jpg?w=590&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great green theologian of old claimed that anger is based on fear, that it leads to hatred, and results in suffering. And while I do not wish to disregard the wisdom of a long time ago in a galaxy far, far away, I would like to take a closer look at anger as discussed in Scripture, and to consider what makes certain instances of anger righteous or unrighteous, legitimate or illegitimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a question that has been on my mind throughout my final year at Cedarville University. After hearing of a few rumblings at the end of my Junior year, I left for the summer and got myself married. When my feet finally touched the ground at the beginning of term, my university felt like a battlefield. I heard that Michael Pahl had been “reviewed” and then fired over the summer months. Others were being reviewed to see if they really did toe the doctrinal line, or if they were guilty of mind crimes against the thought police. And things didn’t get any better from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw the havoc that the Cedarville environment was wreaking on my mentors, friends, and their families. My leaders got rid of and harassed beloved members of my community, and then deceptively refused to own up to their nefarious actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fiatlux125.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://si0.twimg.com/profile_images/2786885016/098d40ad39a165603e09a1915c37f88a.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joshuapsteele.com/2013/01/13/open-letter-to-cedarville-admins-and-trustees/&#34;&gt;I got angry. I spoke up&lt;/a&gt;. And I was convinced that my anger was righteous. Others were less convinced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some stayed poignantly and painfully silent throughout the chaos. Others repeatedly gave platitudes that everything was OK, that we were obligated to trust our leaders, that to question their actions was inherently disrespectful. And some from this latter group met my kind of anger with their own frustration and anger that I dared to criticize their beloved Cedarville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d love to say that I met this opposition with nothing but grace and equanimity, but that wouldn’t be true. I frequently lashed out against these types of people - when they sent me long messages to accuse me of causing unnecessary dissentious strife, or when they parodied us student activists as complete morons with nothing better to do than cook up conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My university’s behavior was sickening, but these people’s behavior was infuriating. I couldn’t comprehend how they could overlook the suffering I was witnessing and try to protect people who were clearly hiding the truth. So, at times, I lashed out in frustration. And I am convinced that my anger was unrighteous. But what’s the difference between these two types of anger?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
