<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Proverbs on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/proverbs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proverbs on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <image>
      <title>Joshua P. Steele</title>
      <url>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</url>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/images/default-social.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 16:22:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.com/tags/proverbs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What the Bible Says About Poverty: The Book of Proverbs</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.com/bible-poverty-proverbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.com/bible-poverty-proverbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-poverty-and-wealth&#34;&gt;Introduction: Poverty and Wealth&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast to the affluence of mainstream American culture, poverty is a harsh and painful reality. It can be found in abundance in the urban centers of this country, and in countless other places around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern day slavery “more cruel than any beast of prey” (Wright 2005, 136), it traps human beings created in the image of God in a lifestyle of hunger, sickness, anger, and darkness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="introduction-poverty-and-wealth">Introduction: Poverty and Wealth</h1>
<p>In contrast to the affluence of mainstream American culture, poverty is a harsh and painful reality. It can be found in abundance in the urban centers of this country, and in countless other places around the globe.</p>
<p>Modern day slavery “more cruel than any beast of prey” (Wright 2005, 136), it traps human beings created in the image of God in a lifestyle of hunger, sickness, anger, and darkness.</p>
<p>However, one can effortlessly go through daily life in middle class America without giving much thought or care to the billions of people living in poverty worldwide. Furthermore, one can even profess faith in Jesus Christ and regularly attend an average evangelical church in the United States without being prompted to pay the poor, underprivileged, and oppressed of this world any mind.</p>
<p>In this milieu of wealth and poverty existing side by side in an atmosphere of confusion and apathy, the book of Proverbs provides relevant insights into the nature of poverty, the nature of Yahweh, and how his people should respond to it.</p>
<p>(For more on how Christians should think about poverty and wealth, see my essay <a href="https://joshuapsteele.com/christians-and-wealth/">“Christians and Wealth.”</a>)</p>
<h2 id="descriptions-of-poverty-effects-and-causes">Descriptions of Poverty: Effects and Causes</h2>
<p>Many proverbs are devoted to describing the harsh realities of poverty, showing that the Hebrew sages were well aware of its existence and characteristics.</p>
<h3 id="effects">Effects</h3>
<p>These proverbs frequently describe the poor in direct contrast to the wealthy. Consider Proverbs 10:15:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“A rich man’s wealth is in his strong city; the poverty of the poor is their ruin.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The force of the antithetical parallelism of this verse is hard to overlook. Whybray explains that the main point “is that wealth protects the rich from the vicissitudes of life, while the poor, having no resources to fall back on, are easily vulnerable to total disaster” (1994, 165).</p>
<p>The word used for “poor” here is <em><strong>dal</strong>.</em> While Whybray states that this word is synonymous with the other Hebrew terms for “poor” (<em>˓ānı̂, ˒ebyôn,</em> and <em>rāš</em>)in Proverbs (1994, 165), <em>The Theological Wordbook of the Old Testament</em> (TWOT) differentiates <em>dal</em> from the other three, saying that “unlike <em>˓ānı̂</em>, <em>dal</em> does not emphasize pain or oppression; unlike <em>˒ebyôn</em>, it does not primarily emphasize need, and unlike <em>rāš</em>, it represents those who lack rather than the destitute.” <em>Dal</em> refers to <strong>the lack of both material and social resources</strong> (Harris, et al. 1999).</p>
<p>This lack of social resources can be seen in the proverbs that describe how poverty affects relationships. Proverbs 14:20 says that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The poor is disliked even by his neighbor, but the rich has many friends.”</p></blockquote>
<p>This same theme is reiterated in chapter 19:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Wealth brings many new friends, but a poor man is deserted by his friend” (19:4).</p></blockquote>
<p>Expanded across two verses, it reads:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Many seek the favor of a generous man, and everyone is a friend to a man who gives gifts. All a poor man’s brothers hate him; how much more do his friends go far from him!” (19:6-7a).</p></blockquote>
<p>These three proverbs contrast the social standings of the wealthy and the impoverished. Alden’s comment on 14:20 is apt when he says that “the unfortunate truth [is] that greed is a more compelling trait than generosity; people are more eager to have rich friends than poor ones” (1983, 114).</p>
<p>Proverbs 19:6-7a expands upon this, describing how people are naturally drawn to relationships that give them material benefit. It is rare, however, to find people who are drawn to relationships that would cost them materially. Even a poor man’s family members “hate him”!</p>
<p>Bridges says it well:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“As the winter brooks, filled from the opening springs and the torrents from heaven, are dried up and vanish before the summer heat; so these friends of the poor go far from him, cold, distant, and vanishing in the day of his calamity” (1987, cf. 1846, 312).</p></blockquote>
<p>Materially and socially, poverty wreaks havoc on the lives of those it entraps.</p>
<h3 id="causes">Causes</h3>
<p>Given the terrible effects and characteristics of poverty, Proverbs naturally contains many admonitions to avoid its causes.</p>
<p>Causes of poverty listed in Proverbs include (but are not limited to):</p>
<ul>
<li>a “slack hand” (laziness) (10:4),</li>
<li>ignorance of instruction (13:18),</li>
<li>endless talk (without toil/labor) (14:23),</li>
<li>hastiness (21:15),</li>
<li>the love of pleasure (21:17),</li>
<li>drunkenness and gluttony (23:21),</li>
<li>worthless pursuits (28:19),</li>
<li>and stinginess (28:22).</li>
</ul>
<p>Of particular interest is the repetition of the warning against excessive slumber if one is to avoid poverty (6:10-11; 20:13; 23:21; 24:33-34).</p>
<p>Proverbs 6:10-11 and 24:33-34 include the almost verbatim admonition:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“A little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to rest, and poverty will come upon you like a robber, and want like an armed man.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Sleep (as compared with labor) might give the initial benefits of rest and relaxation, but when developed into an excessive habit, it can have disastrous consequences.</p>
<p>John Chrysostom comments upon 6:11:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Is work at first difficult? Then look to its results. Is idleness sweet? Then consider what comes out of it in the end. So let us look not at the beginning of things, but let us also see where they end up” (Wright 2005, 50).</p></blockquote>
<p>This approach perhaps summarizes most of the practical warnings in Proverbs about avoiding poverty. <strong>What initially seems like the easiest and most comfortable choice will rarely, if ever, lead to success.</strong></p>
<p>Set apart from the practical warnings of avoiding poverty, however, is Proverbs 22:16:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Whoever oppresses the poor to increase his own wealth, or gives to the rich, will only come to poverty.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The verb “oppress” here is the term <em>˓ā∙šǎq</em>, meaning “mistreat, i.e., treat a disadvantaged member of society unjustly with the effect of causing one to suffer ill-treatment” (Swanson 1997).</p>
<p>Although the Hebrew of this verse is quite difficult and there is little concurrence among commentators as to its proper interpretation (Whybray 1994, 322-323), the sense of it seems to be that <strong>the end result of oppressing the impoverished for material gain is only further poverty</strong>.</p>
<p>Proverbs 30:14 comes to mind:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“There are those whose teeth are swords, whose fangs are knives, to devour the poor from off the earth, the needy from among mankind.”</p></blockquote>
<p>These verses make the transition from descriptions of poverty to responses to its existence, highlighting the uncomfortable truth that <strong>improper treatment of the poor can bring disaster</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="responses-to-poverty-yahweh-and-the-poor">Responses to Poverty: Yahweh and the Poor</h2>
<p>It is clear that Proverbs gives its readers a thorough understanding of the dreadfulness of poverty and the importance of avoiding it.</p>
<p>However, this understanding does little to inform the audience of <strong>how we should respond to the existence of poverty</strong>.</p>
<p>The surest foundation for a proper response to poverty is undoubtedly <span style="text-decoration: underline;">the character of Yahweh with regards to the oppressed and impoverished</span>.</p>
<p>Consider Proverbs 14:31:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Whoever oppresses a poor man insults his Maker, but he who is generous to the needy honors him.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The first line of this proverb is echoed in 17:5a, and the second (seemingly unrelated) line of 17:5, “he who is glad at calamity will not go unpunished,” has been taken by some commentators to refer to those who rejoice over not just calamity in general, but specifically the ruin of the poor (Whybray 1994, 255 and Clifford 1999, 164).</p>
<p>If this is the case, then these two proverbs taken together make the same point with both a positive promise and a negative warning. Clifford states the main point particularly well:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The dignity of each human being comes from being created by God. Contempt towards anyone insults the person’s maker. The example of the poor person, the type perhaps least likely to gain respect, is used to dramatize the point. Every human being, irrespective of wealth, is worthy of respect” (1999, 164).</p></blockquote>
<p>The same point is made in Proverbs 22:2, which states:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The rich and the poor meet together; the Lord is the maker of them all,”</p></blockquote>
<p>and also in 29:13:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The poor man and the oppressor meet together; the Lord gives light to the eyes of both.”</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Our treatment of the poor needs to be based upon the fact that they have been made in the image of Yahweh and are therefore worthy of dignity and respect.</strong> To deny them the treatment that each and every human being deserves is not just stinginess, it is <strong>an insult and an offense to the Creator.</strong></p>
<p>However, Proverbs goes further than appeals to imago Dei in its teachings about our treatment of the poor.</p>
<p>Atkinson says it well:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The oppression of the poor is both a violation of someone who should be respected because he or she bears the image of the Creator, and also an attitude which does not reflect the character of the Creator, who is himself on the side of the poor” (1996, 111).</p></blockquote>
<p>Proverbs 22:22-23 delivers a stunningly vivid warning:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Do not rob the poor, because he is poor, or crush the afflicted at the gate, for the LORD will plead their cause and rob of life those who rob them.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The reader is told to not take justice from the poor because they have the LORD as their defender at the gate (the site of legal proceedings). “The poor, by not having human protectors, have Yahweh as their protector. Paradoxically, their poverty gives them a more powerful protector than the rich could afford” (Clifford 1999, 207).</p>
<p>This gives a glimpse into a thematic truth of Scripture that has been called God’s “bias to the poor.” Atkinson quotes Karl Barth to further explain:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The human righteousness required by God and established in obedience – the righteousness which according to Amos 5:24 should pour down as a mighty stream – has necessarily the character of a vindication of right in favour of the threatened innocent, the oppressed poor, widows, orphans, and aliens.</p>
<p>For this reason, in the relations and events in the life of his people, God always takes his stand unconditionally and passionately on this side and this side alone: against the lofty and on behalf of the lowly; against those who enjoy right and privilege and on behalf of those who are denied it and deprived of it” (1996, 111-112, cf. Barth, <em>Church Dogmatics</em> II/1 [T.&amp;T. Clark, 1957], p. 387)</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>God’s heart for and even bias toward the poor extends well beyond the book of Proverbs</strong>. If one pays close attention, it is readily apparent that Scripture is saturated with it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Yahweh intervened to save his people from the oppression and poverty they suffered in at the hands of the Egyptians (cf. Exodus 3:7-9).</li>
<li>He made his frustration at his people’s improper treatment and distortion of the impoverished and the needy known through the prophets (cf. Isaiah 10:1-3; Jeremiah 5:26-29; 7:5-7; Amos 2:7; 4:1; 5:10-15; 6:4-7; Micah 2:2).</li>
<li>Jesus the Messiah cited his own mission as one that was inextricably tied to the poor and oppressed (cf. Luke 4:16-21).</li>
<li>The final judgment will be executed (at least partially so) with regards to the treatment (or mistreatment) of the poor and the needy (cf. Matthew 25:31-46).</li>
</ul>
<p>Scripture makes it abundantly clear that <strong>God’s heart is for the impoverished, destitute, and oppressed</strong>.</p>
<p>It is important to establish this truth well in order to rightly proceed in our actions and attitudes toward the poor and the oppressed. This is because <strong>it is entirely too easy to think of God’s actions and attitudes as being most closely aligned with people who are just like us.</strong></p>
<p>However, for the vast majority of Christians in the United States who live life in relatively extravagant comfort and ease, it comes as somewhat of a shock that God’s bias might actually be <em><strong>against</strong></em> us if we do not take this issue seriously!</p>
<p>Proverbs reflects that what is at stake here is much more than just our consciences, the minor twangs of guilt or moments of self-righteousness we too often experience in our infrequent interactions with the poor.</p>
<h2 id="responses-to-poverty-consequences-and-rewards">Responses to Poverty: Consequences and Rewards</h2>
<p>The teachings in Proverbs regarding the treatment of the poor can be divided into three categories:</p>
<ol>
<li>those that display negative consequences for improper treatment,</li>
<li>those that display positive rewards for proper treatment,</li>
<li>and those that juxtapose the two.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="negative-consequences">Negative Consequences</h3>
<p>Proverbs 21:13 states:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Whoever closes his ears to the cry of the poor will himself call out and not be answered.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The frightening reciprocity of this verse hits hard when, in our culture, we are too often distracted by other things which are “more important” than attending to the needs of the poor. When we find ourselves in a moment of dire need, how can we expect to be answered if we have not answered the needy when we were able to do so?</p>
<p>Another warning against mistreating the poor that includes a form of retribution against the offender is Proverbs 28:8:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Whoever multiplies his wealth by interest and profit gathers is for him who is generous to the poor.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Whybray claims that the word for “interest” refers to “interest which was levied by deduction from the original loan but which had to be repaid in full,” and that “profit” refers to “an additional charge levied on repayment” (1994, 391).</p>
<p>The point is that <strong>money taken from the poor will not do its wicked owner any good,</strong> and has the potential to end up in the hands of righteous men which will in turn help to meet the needs of the poor.</p>
<h3 id="positive-rewards">Positive Rewards</h3>
<p>In addition, Proverbs contains several verses that positively portray, and thereby encourage, generosity towards the poor and preservation of their justice.</p>
<p>Consider Proverbs 19:17:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Whoever is generous to the poor lends to the Lord, and he will repay him for his deed.”</p></blockquote>
<p>This proverb promises a reward to those who treat the poor with generosity. However, the main point is not to treat them with benevolence out of desire for a reward.</p>
<p>Whybray captures the point well:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“there is no idea here of a quid pro quo: no intention to encourage generosity simply for the reward which it will bring. The underlying thought is that generosity is characteristic of a person who is righteous; and the proverb reflects the basic belief that righteousness is, and ought to be, materially rewarded” (1994, 282).</p></blockquote>
<p>A virtually identical point is made in Proverbs 22:9:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Whoever has a bountiful eye will be blessed, for he shares his bread with the poor.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Furthermore, the well-known wise woman discussed in chapter 31 “opens her hand to the poor and reaches out her hands to the needy” (31:20). <strong>Giving generously to the poor is a mark of a righteous person, one whose life will be blessed by Yahweh.</strong></p>
<h3 id="combinations">Combinations</h3>
<p>Finally, some proverbs combine the negative and positive aspects of the previously mentioned verses through antithetical parallelism.</p>
<p>A prime example is Proverbs 14:21:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Whoever despises his neighbor is a sinner, but blessed is he who is generous to the poor.”</p></blockquote>
<p>This verse highlights the benefits of generosity against the backdrop of the consequences of scorning one’s neighbor.</p>
<p>In a similar fashion, Proverbs 28:27 says that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“whoever gives to the poor will not want, but he who hides his eyes will get many a curse.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Whether or not the curses come from the poor who have been denied assistance, or from Yahweh himself, the point remains that <strong>there are rewards in caring for the impoverished and consequences for not doing so.</strong></p>
<p>In addition to generosity, however, the Hebrew sages also expressed concern for the <strong>justice</strong> of the poor.</p>
<p>Proverbs 29:7 makes it clear that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“a righteous man knows the rights of the poor; a wicked man does not understand such knowledge.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The importance of justice for the poor is also stated later in the chapter in verse 14:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“If a king faithfully judges the poor, his throne will be established forever.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Given Yahweh’s “bias” toward the poor and their status as his image bearers, it would do one well to be concerned with their legal rights.</p>
<p><strong>It is not enough to simply not oppress the poor.</strong> Proverbs, along with the rest of Scripture, seems to mandate <strong>advocating for their justice.</strong></p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>In our current context of extravagant wealth and abject poverty existing side by side in a realm of confusion, apathy, and even malice towards the impoverished, Proverbs contains some timely and powerful teaching.</p>
<p>The Hebrew sages had a firm grasp on both the tempting causes and terrible effects of poverty. They, therefore, put a strong emphasis on <strong>avoiding it at all costs through diligence and hard work</strong>.</p>
<p>However, this did not lead them to <strong>abandon</strong> a proper view towards the poor, and they grounded all of their teachings about the proper treatment of the poor in <strong>the unchanging and perfect character of Yahweh, who is firmly committed to their protection and justice.</strong></p>
<p>The modern readers of this ancient book would do well to heed its teachings regarding poverty, and to proceed with attitudes and actions in imitation of Yahweh in their interactions with and opinions of the poor, destitute, and oppressed of this world.</p>
<h2 id="bibliography"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Bibliography</strong></span></h2>
<p>Alden, Robert L. <em>Proverbs: A Commentary on an Ancient Book of Timeless Advice.</em> Grand Rapids: Baker Book House, 1983.</p>
<p>Atkinson, David. <em>The Message of Proverbs: Wisdom for life.</em> Downers Grove, IL: InterVarsity Press, 1996.</p>
<p>Bridges, Charles. <em>A Commentary on Proverbs.</em> Southampton: The Camelot Press Ltd., 1987, cf. 1846.</p>
<p>Clifford, Richard J. <em>Proverbs: A Commentary.</em> Louisville, KY: Westminster John Knox Press, 1999.</p>
<p>Estes, Daniel J. <em>Handbook on the Wisdom Books and Psalms.</em> Grand Rapids: Baker Academic, 2005.</p>
<p>Harris, R. Laird, Robert Laird Harris, Gleason Leonard Archer, and Bruce K. Waltke. <em>Theological Wordbook of the Old Testament.</em> (electronic ed.). Chicago: Moody Press, 1999.</p>
<p>Swanson, James. <em>Dictionary of Biblical Languages With Semantic Domains: Hebrew (Old Testament).</em> (electronic ed.). Logos Research Systems, Inc. Oak Harbor, 1997.</p>
<p>Whybray, R. N. <em>New Century Bible Commentary: Proverbs.</em> Grand Rapids: William B. Eerdmans Publishing Co. , 1994.</p>
<p>Wright, J. Robert, ed. <em>Ancient Commentary on Scripture: Proverbs, Ecclesiastes, Song of Solomon.</em> Downers Grove, Illinois: InterVarsity Press, 2005.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
