<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sermons on Joshua P. Steele</title>
    <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/sermons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sermons on Joshua P. Steele</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.120.4</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:22:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://joshuapsteele.github.io/categories/sermons/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Haven’t You Torn The Sky Open Yet?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/why-havent-you-torn-the-sky-open-yet-sermon-first-sunday-of-advent-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/why-havent-you-torn-the-sky-open-yet-sermon-first-sunday-of-advent-2020/</guid>
      <description>Sermon preached on Saturday, November 28, 2020 (First Sunday of Advent) via Zoom at Church of the Savior in Wheaton, IL.
--- If there are two things I hate, they are waiting and staying awake. I hate waiting.
Ask anyone who knows me. I am absolutely horrible when it comes to delayed gratification. I’ve been known to open new boxes of cereal on the way home from the store.
And I hate staying awake.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who really cares about the Trinity in 2020?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 13:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/who-really-cares-about-the-trinity-in-2020/</guid>
      <description>(To listen to the audio of this sermon as it was preached on June 6, 2020, click here.)
Christians believe that there is one God in three persons—Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.
Or, as my daughter Eva put it recently after seeing a picture in her book, “Father, Son, and Bird.” We’re working on that…
We Christians have been taught that the Trinity is important. No one wants to be a heretic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing the Way of the Lord in the Wilderness: Luke 3:1-6</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/preparing-the-way-of-the-lord-in-the-wilderness-luke-31-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 15:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/preparing-the-way-of-the-lord-in-the-wilderness-luke-31-6/</guid>
      <description>I’d like to pray this week’s collect again:
Merciful God, who sent your messengers the prophets to preach repentance and prepare the way for our salvation: Give us grace to heed their warnings and forsake our sins, that we may greet with joy the coming of Jesus Christ our Redeemer; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen.
Introduction It’s been a particularly difficult week here at Church of the Savior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take Up Your Tongue and Follow Jesus</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/take-up-your-tongue-and-follow-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/take-up-your-tongue-and-follow-jesus/</guid>
      <description>This sermon, on Mark 8:27-38 and James 3:1-12, was originally preached on September 16, 2018 at Christ Redeemer Anglican Church in Milwaukee, WI.
Introduction Would you pray with me?
O God, because without you we are not able to please you—especially in what we say!—mercifully grant that your Holy Spirit may in all things direct and rule our hearts, so that the words of our mouths and the meditations of our hearts might be acceptable in your sight, O Lord, our strength and our redeemer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It is Finished! So, Get to Work! – A Sermon on the Ascension</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20170613it-is-finished-so-get-to-work-an-ascension-sermon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 01:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/20170613it-is-finished-so-get-to-work-an-ascension-sermon/</guid>
      <description>The following is an “It is Finished” sermon preached on Ascension Sunday, 2017. You can listen to the sermon here:
https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/05-28-17JS.mp3
GOODBYES SUCK You know, if there’s one thing I hate, it’s goodbyes. Anyone else here hate goodbyes?
Yeah, and the fact that I hate them so much means I’m not really very good at goodbyes.
Sometimes I get awkward and silent. Sometimes I get awkward and really chatty! Heck, sometimes I get awkward and I make poor choices, like the one time when I was getting ready to say goodbye to my family when they dropped me off at college.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lasting Supper – Luke 22:14-30</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 19:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/</guid>
      <description>https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/04-13-17JS.mp3
There is something special about last meals, isn’t there?
I’d like to show you a series of photographs. These photographs, except for the last one – which I added, are from a piece called “No Seconds,” and they were put together by Henry Hargreaves.
I don’t want to belabor the artwork with my commentary, so I’ll give you a few seconds to take each slide in.
[![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Slide2-150x150.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/slide2/) [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Slide11-150x150.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/slide11/) [![](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Slide10-150x150.jpg)](https://joshuapsteele.com/maundy-thursday-sermon-the-lasting-supper-luke-2214-30/slide10/) [!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ahead in God&#39;s Upside-Down Kingdom: An Appeal for a Consistently Pro-Life Ethic</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-ahead-in-gods-upside-down-kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 16:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/getting-ahead-in-gods-upside-down-kingdom/</guid>
      <description>https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/01-29-17JSGeetingAheadinGodsUpsideDownKingdom.mp3
[MP3: Getting Ahead in God’s Upside-Down Kingdom]
[PDF Sermon Manuscript: Getting Ahead in God’s Upside-Down Kingdom]
Opening Prayer God, our Refuge, I ask that your Holy Spirit would move in our lives, so that we would:
promote your justice embody your steadfast faithful love and humbly obey Your will, even if it costs us our reputations, and even if it costs us our lives.
I ask that this transformation would begin with me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Disappointing Christmas Homily</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-christmas-homily/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 14:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/a-christmas-homily/</guid>
      <description>Good morning! And Merry Christmas!
Together, let us pray:
O God, you make us glad by the yearly festival of the birth of your only Son Jesus Christ: Grant that we, who joyfully receive him as our Redeemer, may with sure confidence behold him when he comes to be our Judge; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever. Amen.
Almighty God, who wonderfully created us in your own image and yet more wonderfully restored us through your Son Jesus Christ: grant that, as he came to share our humanity, so we may share the life of his divinity; who is alive and reigns with you, in the unity of the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following Jesus Beyond the Bandwagon</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-jesus-beyond-the-bandwagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 22:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/following-jesus-beyond-the-bandwagon/</guid>
      <description>(A chapel message in a Christian school.)
There are a few things you should know about me:
I am a student at a Christian seminary. Before that, I went to a Christian college. Before that, I went to a Christian high school, and a Christian middle school. Before that, I was home-schooled, and I grew up in a Christian home. Oh, also: I’m the world’s worst sports fan.
I’m serious. The students in my youth group give me a hard time about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Feast of St. James the Apostle: A Homily for Ministers</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-feast-of-st-james-the-apostle-a-homily-for-ministers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 22:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-feast-of-st-james-the-apostle-a-homily-for-ministers/</guid>
      <description>Readings: Psalm 34; Jeremiah 16:14-21; Mark 1:14-20
Like so many other feast days – scheduled, as they are, on the days of the namesakes’ deaths – the feast day of St. James the Apostle is a strong rebuke to our aspirations. To our aspirations as human beings, and especially to our aspirations as ministers of Christ’s Church.
![Saint James the Greater *oil on canvas *92.1 x 74.9 cm *signed b.r.: Rembrandt f.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Groom&#39;s Big Day</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grooms-big-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 16:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-grooms-big-day/</guid>
      <description>[soundcloud url=”https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/256270902″ params=”color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false” width=”100%” height=”166″ iframe=”true” /]
READINGS Ephesians 5:21-33 – Wives and Husbands Psalm 67 – May God Be Gracious to Us and Bless Us Revelation 19:6-10 – The Marriage Supper of the Lamb Matthew 25:1-13 – The Parable of the Ten Virgins HOMILY What makes a great wedding?
Is it the fragrance and color of the flower arrangements? The particular grandeur of the venue?
Is it the number and camaraderie of the guests?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Son of Man, Can Your Bones Live?</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/son-of-man-can-your-bones-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 22:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/son-of-man-can-your-bones-live/</guid>
      <description>What would it have been like, on the first Holy Saturday? What would it be like, tonight, if Jesus has been dead for almost 33 hours?
All the hopes and dreams of tonight’s readings – shattered. Blown away by the cold winds of death. Jesus of Nazareth lies in a dark grave, and we, his shell-shocked followers, gather to make some sort of sense of this week’s events – to salvage some sort of hope from this week’s wreckage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Recent Sermons</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/three-recent-sermons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 20:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/three-recent-sermons/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a grueling past few weeks at Beeson. Our Spring Break happens to coincide with Holy Week this year, and it can’t come quickly enough!
Part of the hard work has been preparing to preach three sermons for class. However, the opportunity to study and preach God’s Word is a joy that outweighs the burdens of preparation!
I have preached twice in the past month on Psalm 32. First, I delivered a sermon (“The Refreshment of Forgiveness”) designed for the Fourth Sunday in Lent, Year C, for Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sermon: The Challenge of Christmas Light</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sermon-the-challenge-of-christmas-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 15:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/sermon-the-challenge-of-christmas-light/</guid>
      <description>There are better preachers out there. So, if you’re short on time, go and listen to them! However, if you’ve got 26 minutes to spare, I offer “The Challenge of Christmas Light” to you, and would love to hear your feedback.
I preached this sermon on December 27, 2015 at St. Peter’s Anglican Church in Mountain Brook, AL, as we celebrated the Feast of St. John the Apostle and Evangelist.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faithful Faith in a Faithful God: Romans 1.1-17</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/faithful-faith-in-a-faithful-god-romans-1-1-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 08:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/faithful-faith-in-a-faithful-god-romans-1-1-17/</guid>
      <description>I. Introduction: The Prodigal Son, Part 2 What a relief, to get out of that house.
Ordinarily, Jude would have scoffed at his father’s request to purchase farming equipment from the next city – a three-day journey!
But ever since Ethan, that rascal (you might even say that prodigal) brother of his, had returned, Jude could not stand to be in either man’s presence for long.
So he relished the chance to forget about his family tension on this farming errand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Prodigal Son, Part 2: Introduction to Romans</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-prodigal-son-part-2-introduction-to-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 21:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-prodigal-son-part-2-introduction-to-romans/</guid>
      <description>What a relief, to get out of that house.
Ordinarily, Jude would have scoffed at his father’s request to purchase farming equipment from the next city – a three-day journey! But ever since Ethan, that rascal (you might even say that prodigal) brother of his, had returned, Jude could not stand to be in either man’s presence for long.
So he relished the chance to forget about his family tension on this farming errand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: Mark 8.11-21</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-8-11-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-8-11-21/</guid>
      <description>A homily on Mark 8:11-21 (ESV):
The Pharisees came and began to argue with him, seeking from him a sign from heaven to test him. And he sighed deeply in his spirit and said, “Why does this generation seek a sign? Truly, I say to you, no sign will be given to this generation.” And he left them, got into the boat again, and went to the other side.
Now they had forgotten to bring bread, and they had only one loaf with them in the boat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: Mark 1.29-45</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-1-29-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 18:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-mark-1-29-45/</guid>
      <description>A homily on Mark 1:29-45 (ESV):
And immediately he left the synagogue and entered the house of Simon and Andrew, with James and John. Now Simon’s mother-in-law lay ill with a fever, and immediately they told him about her. And he came and took her by the hand and lifted her up, and the fever left her, and she began to serve them.
That evening at sundown they brought to him all who were sick or oppressed by demons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Prayer Homily: James 2.1-13</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-james-2-1-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 17:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/morning-prayer-homily-james-2-1-13/</guid>
      <description>A homily on James 2.1-13 (ESV):
“My brothers, show no partiality as you hold the faith in our Lord Jesus Christ,the Lord of glory. For if a man wearing a gold ring and fine clothing comes into your assembly, and a poor man in shabby clothing also comes in, and if you pay attention to the one who wears the fine clothing and say, “You sit here in a good place,” while you say to the poor man, “You stand over there,” or, “Sit down at my feet,” have you not then made distinctions among yourselves and become judges with evil thoughts?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus is Not Just &amp;quot;One of Us&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/jesus-is-not-just-one-of-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 21:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/jesus-is-not-just-one-of-us/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: The audio of the following sermon, preached on July 05, 2015 at St. Peter’s Anglican Church in Mountain Brook, Alabama, can be found here. (I began with a bit of a mic issue. Ignore the garbled first 10 seconds or so!)
—
Introduction The “hometown,” “home court” advantage is a very real occurrence in many areas of life. Familiar fans and supportive surroundings help us humans to perform better at many tasks, from singing to sports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hope of the Holy Innocents</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-hope-of-the-holy-innocents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 09:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/the-hope-of-the-holy-innocents/</guid>
      <description>(PDF: [The Hope of the Holy Innocents](https://joshuapsteele.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/holy-innocents-matthew-21.pdf)) Today is December 28 (2014) – just the third day since Christmas – a commemoration of what is often called “The Slaughter of the Innocents,” the killing of the baby boys of Bethlehem by King Herod.
The Church’s regard for this day as a feast day is quite early, going back to at least the fifth century. In the fourth century, Chromatius described these babies as the first martyrs of Christ – the first counted worthy to die on Christ’s behalf.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Sermon: Our Help</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-sermon-our-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 14:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/my-sermon-our-help/</guid>
      <description>Hey internet: I was recently given the chance to preach at my church, St. Peter’s Anglican, on the Second Sunday of Lent. The sermon audio is now online. If you’ve got 23 minutes to spare, give it a listen!
First, here are the passages:
Psalm 121 Genesis 12:1-4 Romans 4:1-5, 13-17 John 3:1-17 Then, make sure to ignore my two seconds of speech from 16:35-16:37 in the audio, I departed from my notes — which ended at “Nicodemus then fades from the narrative,” (which he does in the passage at hand) — and said that Nicodemus apparently never gets it and never shows up again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Un)Righteous Anger? – Yoda, Jonah, Nahum, and Us</title>
      <link>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unrighteous-anger-yoda-jonah-nahum-and-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 21:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://joshuapsteele.github.io/unrighteous-anger-yoda-jonah-nahum-and-us/</guid>
      <description>(TEXTS: Jonah 3:5-10; 4:1-11; Nahum 1:1-8)
INTRODUCTION A great green theologian of old claimed that anger is based on fear, that it leads to hatred, and results in suffering. And while I do not wish to disregard the wisdom of a long time ago in a galaxy far, far away, I would like to take a closer look at anger as discussed in Scripture, and to consider what makes certain instances of anger righteous or unrighteous, legitimate or illegitimate.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
